I'm obsessed with every 90 days asking
myself
one key question.
What does
my dream week look like?
You know,
if you're not intentional about
designing your week, it kind of just
gets designed for you.
For me,
I know
Well, first off, I like to take 10 days
every month to go and escape
on some sort of soul trip in the nature.
Now, my dream week typically consists
of Monday. That's when I like to do
different, you know, creative, could be
writing, could be shooting different
YouTube videos.
Tuesdays are my meeting days and
sometimes a little bit on Wednesday.
And the rest of the week, I like to
focus it
on typically just whatever other
creative tasks I have on my plate.
Not getting lost in just a sea of
meetings, I'm intentional about blocking
my time. Right? So, on a given
Wednesday, I may be going and doing a
little bit of copywriting.
On a Thursday, I may be going and
mentoring a few founders.
And then on Friday, kind of just
wrapping up the week. And then getting
ready, hopefully, for a nice little road
trip on the weekend.
And so,
if you're watching this,
I want you to ask yourself, what does
your dream week look like? Go and write
that down and start to make the little
tweaks necessary to start actually
living it.