OpenAI finally released Atlas and people
are saying that it's a Google killer.
With Atlas, you can actually go and use
Chat GBT and interact with the pages
that you're viewing. So, let me show you
an example of this on YouTube. Here we
can see my YouTube channel. We've been
growing this to over 204,000 subs, but
I'm looking to go and dial in so I can
go and prompt this thing. I want you as
a YouTube strategist to go and analyze
my YouTube here and go and come up with
a 100red viral videos that you think
will get my YouTube channel to a million
subs by June 30th of 2026. chatbt atlas
is going to go and analyze my YouTube
page and go and come up with specific
examples based on what it's seeing here.
So, just like that, right? You know,
it's doing a great job of kind of giving
me an endless stream of content ideas
that I can now go take to the team and
go and