There's a simple way you can force
yourself to be consistent [music] and do
hard things. It's not about having more
motivation or discipline. It's about
building the right system. At 22, I was
working 15-hour days, but I wasn't
growing or getting things done. [music]
Fast forward to today, and I've built
four successful companies and
accumulated over 14 million people.
>> [music]
>> In this video, I'll show you how to
design a system that makes consistency
automatic, so even on the hardest days,
you're still able to follow through and
get things done. [music] To build the
system, you'll need to master the three
levels of consistency. Level one, design
the system. Level two, become the
system. And level three, scale the
system. Each of these [music] has its
own set of habits that will set you up
for success. The math of consistency is
really simple, right? 1% better every
day is 37 times better in a year. Humans
have a hard time really fathoming what
compounding looks like, cuz in any given
day, it doesn't sound like you're really
moving that much, but suddenly, when you
take a step back, over 30 days, a year,
you're amazed at how much you've
accomplished. Most people aren't bad
because of motivation. They're bad
because of the math. Right? When people
go and see their small changes [music]
that they're making in the right
direction, they get down on themselves
because they feel like they should be so
much further along in life. The truth
is, you're probably just riding out that
long, boring, growing slope to gradually
really hitting the compounding success
you're after. You got to embrace the
gap. The gap between [music]
where you are now and the effort you're
putting in and really hitting that
inflection point. If you only remember
one thing, it's this. Small daily
efforts beat massive bursts of effort.
Right? It's those small daily wins that
when you stack that up, will build you
something you're proud of. Embrace
[music]
those small wins that you can do now
that are in your control, and have trust
that when [music] you just stay
consistent with that stuff, you'll
accomplish great things. The second part
of designing your system is engineering
your environment. When I first started
building my companies, my workspace
[music] was chaos. Slack notifications
all over the place, my phone constantly
buzzing, social media all sprinkled in
throughout my day, answering emails five
times a day, my desk was a mess, my life
was a mess. I was using [music]
different substances to cope with the
stress. The reality is, if your
workplace and your environment is a
mess, [music]
well, your business is going to be a
mess. If your mind is a mess, you know,
your life is a mess. And so, [music] you
need to go and declutter all of your
environment, right? Deletion equals
simplification. Now, what I learned over
time building businesses is the
importance of creating frictionless
[music] focus. You want your environment
to be incredibly conducive to you just
being the best version of yourself. When
you look at your bedroom, is it
something that's [music] conducive to an
amazing sleep at night? You know, when
you wake up, do you have your gym
clothes packed and ready for that nice
morning workout that sets your day off
to that winning stride? We create our
environments as humans, [music] but
those environments also create us. So,
create your environment intentionally.
[music]
So, here's how you do it. You got to
audit your environment for friction.
First things first, look around [music]
you. You know, there's probably
different aspects on your workspace that
are a mess. Clean it up. Think about the
core habits and [music] the core things
that you're trying to become, you know,
maybe successful in business. Maybe
you're trying to be well-rested. You
want to have good energy. You want to
have good health. What are the different
things that you can do with your
environment that would help make that
success inevitable? Step three is to
plan over your mood. Years ago, I'd wake
up and, you know, just go with the day
and see what the day was going to bring
me. You know, I'd gradually go and make
a plan in the morning roughly of what I
wanted to do. And I started to wonder,
you know, why did the progress feel so
slow? You know, on many days, I'd
wonder, did I even get anything done?
>> [music]
>> You know, months would go by, and I felt
like my life was stalling. What I
realized through just some trial and
error was that you really win the day
the night before. A lot of people think
they need motivation to take action, but
the truth is that action creates
motivation. [music]
When you finally just start getting
after something, gradually the momentum
builds, right? [music] And before you
know it, you're hitting goals, you're
making strides, things start to all kind
of fall into place. [music] The key to
executing your plan is really taking
that minimum viable action that's going
to move you forward to where you're
looking to go. You know, I'll see
sometimes someone go and say, "Oh, you
know, I need to write an article
tomorrow." Well, that article as an
example could be broken down into figure
out the headline, do the research, make
an outline, begin writing the intro,
finish the script, [music] edit the
script. If we can take a project and
break it down into more subtasks,
[music]
not only does it make it easier to get
started, but it also will give you a
feeling of momentum as you go through
and you check off each of these things.
Focus on tasks, not projects, and break
[music] things down to the minimum
viable action. If you can handle all
that, you've passed level one, and
you're ready for the next level. Level
two, become the system. And you do this
by strengthening the mind-body
connection. When I was younger, I
thought that working out was optional.
You know, you do it a few times a week,
you're good to go. The reality is,
though, I think we're all different, but
for me at least, if I'm not going and
breaking a sweat every day, I don't feel
right. You know, they have done studies
at Harvard showing that, you know,
breaking a sweat is like better than
Zoloft at fighting things like
depression and anxiety. And so, you
know, getting a nice jog in, a good run,
a row, you know, some yoga, whatever, is
great to do not sometimes, but doing
something every day of the week. At the
end of the day, a lot of life is about
your energy, right? It takes energy to
get things done. Takes energy to take
action. Takes energy to become the best
version of yourself. And if your energy
is low, well, your momentum's probably
going to be low in life as well. So, if
you want to be consistent with your
work, start with your body. You start to
feel good, you look [music] good, you
know, you're feeling more confident,
your self-esteem goes up, and people can
tell because your energy in a room, you
know, is more captivating. You feel
confident, right? You're not shying away
in a corner. You're totally fine getting
in front of a group of people getting
after it. Because the truth is that, you
know, the same muscles you're kind of
working in the gym psychologically are
oftentimes those same muscles that you
need to work to be consistent. The same
thing that's telling you to give up when
you're on that eighth rep with a really
heavy set of weights is that same sort
of voice in your head that's telling you
to stop when you've done a couple hard
tasks and telling you to not do that
third one. Really, more than just
working your body, you're working your
mind. Next step is an absolute
requirement after the last one, and it's
to recharge like a pro. Early in my
career, I thought that rest was a
weakness. In fact, I thought it was like
a badge of honor if I was pulling
all-nighters, working 18 hours a day. I
thought this [music] was the way. I was
finally living like a successful
entrepreneur. What I've learned is
that's actually the opposite of what it
should look like. Taking time to rest,
to recharge, is much needed. You know,
for me, I know one of the most important
activities that I can take is every six
weeks doing a soul trip. You know, doing
some kind of four or seven-day little
retreat in nature, going for a hike,
going snowboarding, going downhill
mountain biking, whether it's in the
Dolomites, Sequoia, Yosemite, wherever.
Doesn't matter. But just getting out
into nature. You know, most founders and
creators that I know, they treat rest as
optional, and they [music] self-sabotage
themselves. That founder that allows
themselves to go and work so hard that
they become really hard to be around.
You know, they start [music] kind of
making a mess in their company, four
employees quit, suddenly now they're
finding themselves trying to dig
themselves out of a hole, but just
constantly kind of digging their own
grave. You know, I know this because
I've been there, right? I've been that
founder that was burning the midnight
oil, difficult to be around, and slowly
was causing my company to collapse. You
know, it's rest [music]
that brings clarity. The last part of
becoming your system is remembering that
your friends are your future. In my
early 20s, I wasted a ton of time
surrounded by a group of people that
weren't great influences. You know, I
found myself partying, [music] on
substances, doing dumb and I
realized that I needed to do a bit of a
friend audit. Start to cut the people
that were bad influences, remove those
people that were energy vampires just
bringing me down, and start to get much
more curated about the people that I
really wanted to be around so that I
could become the ultimate version of
myself. You need to make sure that
you're surrounding yourself with people
that reflect those dreams. [music]
Because at the end of the day, the five
people you surround yourself with are
going to largely dictate your own
success. So, choose wisely. Level three,
scale the system. Up until this point,
I've shown you how to become more and
more consistent, [music] but these next
three steps are going to help you become
super successful. Starting with setting
up accountability. A year and a half
ago, I decided I was going to write a
book. And one of the first actions that
I took was to announce it to everyone
[music] I knew. The reason that I did it
is because I knew all these people
around me were going to hold me
accountable to actually writing this
damn book. This sort of way of doing
kind of a public accountability
exercise, [music]
of actually announcing to people like,
"Hey, I'm doing this thing." has become
incredibly motivating cuz now I got to
fulfill on that promise that I've given
so many people. Most people avoid
accountability because they fear
embarrassment, but that's [music] the
whole thing. Your fear of embarrassment
isn't going to cause you to actually do
the thing. [music] The moment you make a
promise in public, you're putting your
reputation on the line.
>> [music]
>> And at that point, you will do anything
to actually do what you committed to.
That's [music] not pressure to avoid,
that's pressure to leverage. So, if you
want to be consistent, set up your
accountability in three steps. Number
one, publicly announce that you're going
to do the thing. Number two, go and
update those group of people every
single week. And number three, start
building an audience of these kind of
people that you've committed to now. Use
this as the momentum you need to stay
after it. This is what's holding most
people back from achieving their goals.
When I launched FounderOS, actually, it
was called Soulful Entrepreneur. Yeah,
it basically sounded like a yoga studio.
[music] You know, this thing was messy.
The site was janked together on Kajabi,
the branding was all over the place, the
color scheme was ugly as hell, but guess
what? I just launched it. Looking back
on that experience four years ago, I
don't regret a thing. [music] Because
it's going and putting yourself out
there and launching at 80% that allows
you to go and make progress, to learn,
and learn, and then figure it out.
That's what allowed me to create the 180
powerful systems that we now offer
inside [music]
of Founder OS, which is the community of
high-growth founders that I've created.
None of that would have been possible
though if I hadn't have just launched
the messy first draft. And so in your
own life, what does that look like?
What's that thing that, you know, you've
had [music] it, you know, sitting there
in your folders or on your desktop or,
you know, in draft mode for far too
[music] long. You know, this is your
sign to just launch the damn thing. What
matters the most is your velocity of
learning. Are you putting things out
there, getting feedback, incorporating
that feedback into what you're doing,
learning from it, doubling down,
stopping the things that aren't working,
and keeping [music] that cycle going.
It's the fastest learners that are the
biggest winners. Now that you're
consistent, well, what do you do with
it? You compound it. Over seven years
ago, I struggled with alcohol, you know,
drinking at least four nights a week,
and it had become a pattern in my life,
a rhythm that I knew needed to stop. And
so sure enough, I got some help, I got a
coach, got a therapist, [music] and
stacked up seven days of sobriety, 30
days of sobriety, and then now seven
years. Along that journey, I also
started stacking different habits. I
started to then journal, just a half a
page every morning. That then led to
three pages every morning, [music]
and then led me to sharing some of that
work on the platforms like Twitter and
LinkedIn. That gradually led up to
building an audience of over 3.2 million
people around my personal brand, and
that then led to the creation of Founder
OS. I tell you all this, and I'm
definitely skipping some of the details,
just to show you that sometimes it's
those most innocent little changes that
we make that stack up to create some of
the biggest impacts in our lives. And so
when I think about going and building
leverage these days, one of the most
important things that I do is four hours
of Founder Flow every single morning.
Now,
>> [music]
>> for you, what you want to think of is,
you know, what's that big thing that
you're trying to get done in your life,
and then break it down to what you need
to do today to get there. [music] The
biggest mistake that a lot of founders
make though is that they view
consistency as a daily grind. When it is
the consistent actions that you take
daily that really create the person
you're trying to become. Discipline
builds momentum, but leverage builds
freedom. And when you combine both, you
stop working for your consistency, and
your consistency starts working for you.
I went and created a comprehensive guide
called Consistency OS, so in the next 30
days you could go and master consistency
in your life and [music] business. If
you're interested in going and checking
that out, go get it for free via the
link in the description. It's a free
guide that's going to help you, your
team become way more consistent day
after day. If you liked this video,
don't forget to like and subscribe, and
go and watch this video, which is how I
build a business that runs without me.