I have been writing this freaking book
for 3 years now.
3 years.
Before this project,
I would tell myself,
"I am not a perfectionist.
I am so good at shipping."
And this project has taught me
that there are certain things in life
that I am a perfectionist about.
And honestly,
I think it's going to be worth it.
But this project
has been a Let me tell you.
Hardest part of this
project was finding an amazing editor.
Shout out Krista.
And
now that we're rocking, this project's
feeling real spicy.
And so,
I think it's also about giving yourself
permission in life, right? To have those
certain projects that are special to
you, that that's your art project,
right? And you're allowed just to be
that perfectionist about it.
But then, you know, majority of things,
you know, having that shipping muscle,
right? And just shipping that
Cuz great artists ship.
So, book
coming very soon.
One day.
Maybe a couple more years, but one of
these days.