want to master the mindset of a
million-dollar entrepreneur read these
five books grit by Angela Duckworth
you'll learn why passion and
perseverance are critical for success
and how to cultivate those qualities the
obstacle is the way by Ryan holiday this
book will show you that obstacles are
not what they seem they're actually
critical assets on your path to success
die with zero by Bill Perkins rethink
your relationship with time and money
and learn why reaching the end with zero
is actually a great goal give and take
by Adam Grant you'll learn why being a
giver in a world of takers and matchers
can set you on a path to unparalleled
success the war of art by Steven
pressfield this is your battle plan to
conquer inner creative battles teaching
you how to overcome resistance and
Unleash Your Best creativity