If Da Vinci was an entrepreneur, this
would be his masterpiece. These are the
34 people behind Founder OS and the 38
systems that glue all of these pieces
together. If you've ever wondered how to
build a successful 7figure business, you
want to actually build a peer behind the
scenes of a real successful business.
And that's what we're about to do here.
You're going to get the systems, tools,
playbooks, frameworks, and some personal
stories to help you go and understand
the glue behind my companies and then go
and take this and implement it into your
business. And without all of this gone
and seamlessly connected, there's no way
that I could run Founder OS while also
just living the dream life that I'm able
to live. Traveling the world, hanging
out with friends, being able to remove
myself from operations while also having
a business that's well on track to do
over 8 figures a year. Success leaves
clues. And what I've tried to go and do
is dig up every single clue I've got,
put it here into this neurob so you can
go and steal it and implement it into
your business. We're going to go and
dive into all the core aspects here
across the finance area of the business,
the sales department, customer success,
all the way over to creative direction
and how I run the studios department,
marketing, and lastly, technology.
Before we get into the org chart, let's
just start with the CEO and the role
there. Where I like to get started is
first figuring out, well, what is my
icky guy? Icky guy is a Japanese term
that stands for your reason for being.
Your icky guy is at the intersection of
what you love, what the world needs,
what you can be paid for, and what
you're great at. And so here you can see
on the screen my icky guy which includes
things like building a teams design
building systems which is really at the
core of everything for founder OS
traveling the world coaching founders
building communities building in
distribution from day one because
firsttime founders focus on tech second
time founders focus on distribution. My
goal is really with any of the
businesses that I create to over time
create an autonomous empire where I can
remove myself from my business for a
month and come back to a business that's
stronger than when I left. Once you've
got your icky guy nailed down, now I
really am able to go and every single
day with every core action that I make,
make sure that I'm further optimizing
for my icky guy. And when I find that
there's stuff that's outside of that
that just doesn't fire me up, that's the
kind of stuff that I'm either going to
automate, eliminate, or delegate. The
next aspect here as a founder, as a CEO,
you got to always be learning from
mentors, masterminds, books, coaches,
and courses. Those five areas have been
responsible for about 95% of my success.
The more I level up, the more my
business levels up. You can see here
some books like the 21 irrefutable laws
of leadership by John C. Maxwell,
Scaling Up by Vern Harish, 10X is easier
than 2X. I use Read Wise, hook it up to
notion so that when I'm reading
different books, say on my Kindle, if I
go and highlight any key lines that I
like in that given book, it's going to
automatically go and sync that from my
Kindle over to notion so I can easily
refer back to this stuff. It's also
super useful to come up with great
content ideas because I can see the sort
of ideas, references, inspiration that I
have in all this reading that I'm doing
to then come up with amazing content
ideas, YouTube ideas, newsletter ideas,
you get it. Next key principle that I
think is really important and it's been
instrumental in my success over the last
15 years is really having a clear
vision. You know, without a vision,
you're going to go nowhere. So, here you
can see a taste of my vision for Founder
OS. Let's keep moving along here. Your
vision is all good, but the key thing is
then how does that vision translate to
your day-to-day? And that's exactly
where the personal board meeting comes
in. I've always thought, you know, it's
kind of crazy that as public companies,
there's these things called board
meetings where the CEO is held
accountable to the board and to
shareholders, but that doesn't exist in
private companies. I turned all that
around 10 years ago when I invented the
personal board meeting, and it
completely transformed my businesses and
my life. I get into my mission, my
vision, and this is something that I
revisit every single day. I actually
have it printed off in my notebook. I
revisit this every morning and every
night, which really hones in my
subconscious to help me accomplish this
vision at a blistering pace. 95% of the
decisions that you make in life are
subconscious. And by reviewing your
vision and your board meeting daily, you
really start to accelerate your momentum
in life. So, I've got my icky guy in
there. I've got my personal 30-day
goals. I've got my business 30-day goals
here. I've also got my personal vision
in life, which is quite a bit different
actually than the business vision. We're
always reverse engineering those 10 year
goals, threeear goals into one-year
plans, 90-day plans, and then getting
after it. And then a key part of each
month is I'm also reflecting on what
went well, what didn't go well, and what
did I learn. And this process of
constant reflection allows me to
continue to learn where my gaps are,
what I need to be learning, and then
kind of evolving from there. The next
aspect is the 5-year reflection.
Founder-led businesses, from my
perspective, it's pretty simple. You're
a founder plus a creator. If you don't
go and think about this right, what
you'll quickly find is that you're in an
idea drought and you're on a content
hamster wheel. We want to avoid that at
all costs. Now, the cool thing here is
that when you combine your icky guy with
the 5-year reflection, it becomes really
easy to go and come up with endless
content ideas and ways to share your
vision and your mission with your
community. I go and include questions in
here, right? Like reflecting on the past
5 years, what were the kind of things
that I wish I had known 5 years ago? and
I just speak to my younger self and the
combination of thinking about you know
what have I learned what are the
problems I've solved what are the
different stories that have changed me
these are the sort of things including
the systems that I have that I just
openly share with my audience content in
a sense becomes effortless because I'm
not having to go and manufacture a bunch
of stuff I'm simply just building stuff
internally in my businesses and then
open-sourcing that stuff to the founders
that I serve as we keep rolling here
let's start with the finance side of
things. Now, there is one system that
I've implemented here that when founders
implement it, I know for a fact it
completely transforms their business.
It's called the CEO scorecard. Years
ago, when I was building businesses, I'm
more of a creative type. I'm a marketing
type and sometimes the finance side of
the business can get a bit neglected
because it's not my favorite thing. The
cool thing is with this CEO scorecard,
it makes it effortless for me to
understand the health of the businesses
that I'm operating. My CFO essentially
every single week sends me a text
message of the core elements of the
business I need to know about so I can
understand the health of my different
portfolio companies. I'm going to see
things like our revenue, our cost of
goods sold, profit margin, cash in bank,
and things like our different sales
metrics like show rate and close rate.
What this allows me to do is instantly
see a snapshot of how my business is
performing. Hayden's also then going to
send me generally three to five bullet
points. If he was in my shoes, what
would he be focused on implementing the
next week? Now, when I see this CEO
scorecard text come through on my phone
before I even sign off for the weekend,
I'm going to make sure that every single
one of those points are implemented
before I even sign off and then wake up
on Saturday. Absolute gamecher. Highly
recommend you get ripping with your own
CEO scorecard and put your CFO to work
already. So on the finance manager side,
I got the legend Georgie. And so he's
just taking care of things like
invoices, payments, general accounting,
simple stuff. So my CFO can focus on
stuff that only he can do. Now, as you
see here, CRO Matt, well, that's me. As
I've gone and built this founder brand,
I've learned that there's a lot of
aspects of the company that I just like
to be involved in myself. The sales team
is first off one of my strengths. I've
been running sales teams for the past 15
years in my businesses. I like to
actually be in the mix. When you have
the right systems in place, the right
people in place, and you've been doing
this long enough, it's actually
relatively easy. We've got a team of
absolute weapons. I meet with them twice
a week, once on Monday, once on Friday.
We have projections. They send me end of
day reports. And so, it's pretty easy
just to run that system and know what's
going on. The other major hack is that
when you're involved in sales, you're
hearing what your customer is asking for
and you're also understanding their
objections and you can use this intel to
then go and formulate where your product
or service should be evolving into. It's
a super helpful aspect of things to kind
of keep your finger on the pulse of your
business and the customer tastes and
preferences. Part of this too, right, is
we've got the founder journey all laid
out. Understanding your customer journey
or in our case the founder journey is a
critical system to have in place. It's
not only useful for your sales team to
understand post sale exactly what the
customer should be expecting, but
obviously it's really important for the
actual customer themselves. So if you
have that meticulously laid out in terms
of the next 12 steps, they have clarity
and your team has clarity on all the
systems, all the steps that are
necessary to create an exceptional
customer experience. The next system
here is my offer stack. There's a
massive misconception amongst founders
around their offer. Most founders
believe that there's only one offer that
they're selling, and that's just not the
case. You have an offer stack. When you
think about this, you likely have like
three, four, maybe up to seven offers
that exist across your product journey.
It is an offer, as an example, in your
Instagram bio to get someone to go and
follow you. It's then an offer on your
newsletter page to make it enticing to
get someone to leave their email and
sign up for your newsletter. Inside of
your newsletter, then you likely have a
CTA or an offer to drive people then to
a sales call and speak with someone on
your team. Then you likely have an offer
that you present to people on a sales
call to get them to actually convert to
your product or service. As you can see
here, every single one of those offers
along that offer stack need to be
labeled. the copy, the scripting needs
to be dialed in. And when you get this
right, what happens is that you create a
slippery slope. You make it virtually
seamless from someone hearing about what
you do to suddenly joining your
newsletter and eventually going and
purchasing from you. When this is done
right, people just end up almost
mistakenly kind of ending up in your
funnel in a way. And before you know it,
you know, two weeks after, maybe
someone's watched a YouTube video, they
find themselves in your community or in
your product or buying your SAS product
because that journey is just so damn
smooth. So that's what we've done at
Founder OS. And this is one of the many
things that we help implement in
founders businesses inside of Founder
OS. Here's an example of my offer stack.
The average person's social bio converts
about 5% of people to followers across
my platforms. My bio converts around 20%
of page visitors to followers. This is
the power of viewing your bio as an
offer. Similarly, the average person
goes and probably sees about a.5%
conversion in their newsletter. We see a
5% conversion. Again, 10x the average.
bringing that level of detail, that
level of copywriting, and making sure
that all of these little pieces word by
word, sentence by sentence, are all
planned out meticulously and
specifically allows you to go and
achieve these sorts of conversion rates.
As we go and we start to then look at
the actual squad um that is comprised,
there are two aspects on the sales team
to think about. Number one are the
setters or in some businesses this is
called your sales development reps or
SDRs. These are the people that are
hunting for leads. The beautiful thing
at Founder OS is we get inundated with
leads. So, we don't need to hunt. We are
actually just having these folks
screening founders to make sure that
we're not going and accepting anyone
into Founder OS that doesn't meet our
high bar. We're essentially trying to
create like a Harvard for
entrepreneurship. And so, we only want
to accept people into Founder OS that we
believe are the perfect fit. Moving on
here, we have our brand strategists.
These are the folks that help founders
actually go and join Founder OS. These
are folks that I've worked with for a
long time. I love this team to be
honest. All of them super skilled with
our founder marketing philosophy which
as you can see here are comprised of
these four things, right? Number one, we
live the founders's journey, right? We
understand their challenges, dreams, and
aspirations better than anyone. You
know, our goal is to be a founders's
best friend. We want to have your back
like a brother or a sister. The next
aspect here is focus, right? We create
unparalleled value. Next is impute.
Right? People are going to go and judge
our product, our content, our process as
a reflection of what founder OS is all
about. It's important that from day one
when founders even see my personal brand
or see a piece of content or read a
newsletter that they are impressed by
that because that is indicative of our
product in the back end. This kind of
attention to detail is a continuous
theme. Lastly, we believe that every
single touch point, it's a statement.
We're pushing around 80 million plus
organic views per month on our content
across all platforms. That's a lot of
freaking people. I'm from Canada. I
think that's like twice the population
of the country every month. For many
people, they ignore those details. But I
think for us, we love those details. You
know, I get probably more jazzed up than
any human in the world on just a tiny
detail being done right. you know, the
right pixel, the right button, the right
newsletter. These things bring me a
weird amount of joy. So, let's move
along here because I could get into
details forever. The next aspect here is
like making sure that the entire team
understands our brand positioning, which
is really thinking about your thesis,
the two to three core parts of that
thesis, and then the core mechanism that
helps you deliver on that. So, for us at
Founder OS, our whole belief is that the
best way to build an online business is
to grow your personal brand. And the
best way to grow a personal brand that
is systemized, beautiful, and hyperp
profofitable, you got to be creating
organic content. And if you're watching
this and you're not yet creating organic
content, now is the time to get going.
And when you're looking to go and create
organic content and build amazing,
profitable personal brand, the most
powerful system I've ever discovered is
called the content GPS, which is going
to help you go scale your audience,
convert those people to emails, and then
drive them to revenue. on the sales side
because your sales team has so many
touch points, right? One person's having
200 conversations a month and you have
five people. That's a thousand
conversations going down. Sometimes I
see founders go and focus so much on a
detail that maybe only touches like 20
customers in a given month. Meanwhile,
they go and ignore the actual sales
scripts that they have their sales
people using. Your sales team is one of
your greatest marketing engines. We've
gone and meticulously gone and created
our sales script, payment plans,
follow-up sequences, HubSpot
automations, and honestly, that's not
even scratching the surface. So, making
sure that all of those different words
that founders are hearing from us on
sales calls, all of the different ways
that we talk about our product, our
service are all dialed in and consistent
so that we maintain this immaculate
brand positioning. As we continue here,
the most important part, I would argue
to Founder OS is our founder success
area. We go and help founders install
content GPS's in their business. In
order to do that right and provide an
insane level of service, it's important
that we have everything systemized. The
content GPS here is all about going and
helping founders scale on platforms like
X, LinkedIn, Tik Tok, Instagram, and
YouTube. We have OSS for every single
one of these platforms to help you scale
and then drive people through core CTAs
to things like newsletters into
workshops and then drive people to your
actual product. We help people across
any industry implement this content GPS
whether you're a course creator, SAS
business, coach, consultant, agency, it
doesn't matter. This system works no
matter what industry you're in. And so
this has gone and meticulously gone and
systemized and we then have a process by
which we can go and create content GPS's
for every single founder that we serve.
And our goal is that when you join
Founder OS, 4 weeks later, we've gone
and implemented this content GPS in your
business. The next aspect here are
things like the founder OS90. This is
just one of over 180 systems we have
behind the scenes in the founder success
area. We're helping founders with things
like their posts, their CTAs, and DM
sequences. They essentially have a
robust infrastructure so that over 90
days they're driving predictable growth
in their company. The next aspect is
things like launch OS, right? Right? So,
an operating system to make sure that no
matter what launch you have throughout
the year, you're going and being able to
launch products the same way that we
launch products. And launches are things
that I've really perfected over the last
15 years, building multiple sevenfigure
and 8 figureure businesses. And I think
it's really comprised of these eight
areas. Getting your landing page dialed
in, making sure you have your social
media growing, your newsletters
funneling people to your launch, you
have your funnel mapped out, your
metrics, your assets, your workshop, and
your emails. When you have this stuff
dialed in, your launch can't fail. Next
here, you are a media company. And when
you think about building a media
company, you should probably be the CEO
of it. What we do here is we have all
the SOPs, the goals, the training, the
onboarding, all of the different systems
necessary to build an amazing team, an
amazing workflow, so you can create your
own personal media company. Next, we go
and have systems for things like
workshops so that people can go and
drive folks from their audience to
sales. And then we have things like the
founder s content idea machine which
helps founders go and come up with 30
content ideas in just 30 minutes by
going and writing things and coming up
with ideas around tools, facts, systems,
guides, playbooks, quotes, stories,
reasons. When you go and implement this
sort of idea machine in your business,
you can't help but be overflowing with a
sea of high converting and compelling
content ideas. And lastly, just like I
talked about how I've gone and figured
out my icky guy in my business, we
really go and help founders hone in on
their icky guy. Too many founders are
working on a business that they hate.
And I think it's one of the saddest
things to see. Founders need to move
from a state of being in a scarcity
mindset to being in an abundance
mindset. And your icky guy and when
you've unlocked your calling really
helps transform that. So, it's something
I'm just more passionate about helping
founders with. The squad on this side,
we have four founder success managers on
our team. I'm going and running two
meetings with them as well a week. We're
doing different call reviews. We're
actually watching them coach different
founders and then giving them advice on
where they could have improved, what the
gaps were. We're also looking at
different systems that founders may be
bubbling up that we don't yet have in
founder OS because there's always more
we can build. One of the most underrated
aspects of your product is your proof.
People don't buy what you sell, they buy
what others want to buy. And so a core
aspect that we're constantly going and
generating at Founder OS almost
effortlessly are testimonials around
what we do. The key thing here is that
you want to have that systemized, right?
When founders go and they're achieving
success, you want to make sure that
success actually becomes great marketing
collateral so that you're going and
capturing those testimonials on a tool
like Trustpilot. I also use
testimonial.to for this and it helps us
go and scale up that proof um so that
people are hearing about the good work
we're doing. Next here is the creative
director side of things. At Founder OS
and with my personal brand, my goal is
to create this Pixar for founders. My
kind of core purpose in life, screw
business, is I really view myself as
more of an artist than an entrepreneur.
And my goal is to every day be unlocking
as much of my creative potential as
possible. To constantly just like find
different references, push the needle,
and try to create the most inspiring
founder content in the world. I think we
got a long way to go. But that said,
this is something that you can probably
tell we're really passionate about and
you should stay tuned to this channel
because we got a lot of cool stuff on
the way. So, what the hell is a creative
director anyways? A creative director is
one part taste and one part details.
Taste, my belief is that it's the
ultimate competitive advantage. And the
key thing there is to have a strong
brand identity. Now, on the details
side, I really see the CEO and creative
director as the chief detail officer. So
over here you can go and see some of the
core metrics and the core data points
that I'm looking at every single week to
understand the details of our creative.
How things are performing, how things
are growing. The details matter and in
your business these are the kind of
metrics you should be tracking on a
weekly basis so you can continue to be
learning, developing, coming up with
banger ideas and then going and adding
those to your personal media company.
the squad here to keep it simple. You
know, we got a few editors, O on the
short form side, Tatiana doing animated
videos, Sarah doing long form videos, we
got Memo doing long form videos as well,
Diego as our YouTube producer who's
coming up with ideas, packaging, he's
filming as well and even doing the
string outs and edits himself. We have
motion designer John who goes and
creates all of our motion graphic
guidelines. So, we have folks like Cat
and Rocks that are doing our graphic
design and making sure that the brand
identity translates through any images
that we have. Diego making sure that
that brand is translated through video.
And then John making sure that that
brand is translated through motion
graphics. The brand when it's done right
should almost feel like it's coming just
from one person. We're all translating
that brand through the same aesthetic,
the green, the kind of ways our
animations come up, the color grading on
our videos, the B-roll that we use.
These are core aspects that we want to
make sure that we're programming into
our audience so that it's recognizable
and it stands out. Some of the details
that really matter to us are the
branding of thumbnails. There are a
thousand ways you can make thumbnails.
And I think one of the most popular
these days are these cringe clickbaity
thumbnails. We like them to look a
little more aesthetic. We want to create
something that's tasteful, a brand
that's memorable. And so you can see
here a little bit of that visual
direction. The next aspect here is then
the elements of viral titles. Here you
can see things like curiosity, intrigue,
you know, we're trying to go and amp
that up and everything that we do to
really encourage people to take that
click. You know, 90% of the success of
any YouTube video is the packaging. From
there, we use tools like Thumbnail Test
and TubeBuddy to go and test that
packaging. We generally go and create
around 15 thumbnails per video. We run
that through AI. After the video is
posted, we're running thumbnail tests
for the next 6 months to make sure that
we're constantly dialing in the
packaging of videos. Constantly
iterating on that, I think, is a key
aspect of building a great founder
studios here um at our company. So, a
couple tools that I think you need to
know about, right? Thumbnail test,
no-brainer. You definitely need to know
about that. YouTube Studios is really
the backbone of everything that we do.
giving you a clearer picture into the
views, your audience, the other kinds of
videos on YouTube that your audience is
interested in. So you can constantly
just be deepening your knowledge of your
audience, serving them to the greatest
of your ability. And I think that
naturally the growth kind of just stems
from there. One of 10.com. This thing is
magical. Essentially, it's going and
looking across all of YouTube for
outliers, outlier thumbnails, and
outlier titles. And what you can do is
you can go and scroll through the
platform. It's created the best of the
best packaging on YouTube. You can go
and save those the different bookmarks
into the platform and then use that for
inspiration for your own YouTube ideas.
I absolutely love this. I nerd out on
this even in my spare time. I just love
checking out different packaging that's
cranking it on the platform and then
using that to come up with banger ideas
for our YouTube. So, you'll love it too.
Go check that one out. Here you can see
our content waterfall system which
allows me to go and turn one X thread
into 24 other pieces of content. X is a
great place for us to test our ideas.
I'll just go and whip up a tweet, put
that out, and sure enough, you'll see
stuff that really performs. And then you
understand that, oh maybe we
should go and turn that into a
newsletter, an IG reel, a Tik Tok, a
YouTube short, a long form YouTube
video. All because we learned from X
that that idea had some steam. The next
aspect here is showing you kind of our
YouTube workflow. I spend a good amount
of time on ideiation. Then I'm going and
actually writing out the scripts for
ideas so that they're meticulously
planned out. I'm obviously involved in
the filming of it as a founder brand. I
am one part creator, one part founder.
But after that part, the post-p
production is completely delegated.
Editing, publishing, repurposing, all of
that is managed by Diego and Nick on my
team. And I get to remove myself from
all of that. So, I can just get back to
business. The video workflow looks
something like this. You got ideation
here. I'm coming up with ideas. The
calendar is all planned out by our
social manager, Nick. From there,
packaging is primarily managed by Diego.
Our recording then happens just like
this right now. And then the
distribution, the editing, the
performance is all managed by others on
my team. This video workflow, we have
experimented with so many different
kinds and this one is a beast. And so if
you're setting up your own video team,
even if it's just you to start, start to
think about your workflow in these
different stages. As you start to scale
it up, pay attention to the parts of it
that you're like, damn, I hate
scripting. Cool. Delegate that part. You
know, you hate editing, which is
probably the first part you're going to
want to delegate. and go and find
yourself a badass editor on a site like
ytjob.co. Let's keep ripping here. We
got some momentum. We talked about my
design team, Cat Rocks, my social
manager, Anna, event coordinator Danny,
because we're running founder retreats
twice a year right now. Next one's in
Austin, and we're starting to ramp those
up to four a year and eventually 12 a
year when we have the retreat center in
the Doommites. That whole team is
responsible for my CTA system, which
essentially you can think of your CTAs
as like a net that goes and captures
your audience across social. So, we have
different call to actions across the
different platforms on my Instagram bio,
Instagram stories, link LinkedIn
featured section, my cover photos, the
end of my expost, the end of my LinkedIn
post, and my YouTube descriptions. There
are about 16 of these core locations
across each platform that when you
implement this right, this is how we're
going and driving around 20,000
newsletter subscribers per month, all
while spending zero dollars on ads. And
this has helped us grow the Founder us
newsletter to over 172,000 subscribers
in just two years. Along the way, this
team is responsible for setting up our
profitable profiles, right? It's not
enough just to go and set up your ex
account, set up LinkedIn, and let it
run. Screw that. Because you don't own
LinkedIn, you don't own X. You don't own
Instagram. You don't own YouTube. And
so, you need to make sure that you're
driving that rented audience on those
platforms to your owned audience in your
newsletter. When you go and push a
LinkedIn post, as an example, maybe only
10% of your audience goes and sees that
post if you're lucky. When you go and
push a newsletter to all 172,000
subscribers you may have, you're
probably looking at like 63% of those
people seeing that post, right? Which is
pretty insane. And every single person's
going to get it in their inbox. Much
more control and much more powerful
distribution. Next aspect here are
things like our footage organization. A
key part of Founder OS Studios is the
fact that we have amazing B-roll. We
want to have the best founder B-roll in
the world. And so, as I'm traveling the
world, we're shooting a bunch of
content. And we're meticulously
organizing this into a Google Drive
folder with all the different folders
for things like driving, eating,
masterminds, reading, all this good
stuff. So that in our short form and
long form video content, we constantly
have organized folders that we can pull
from to do some effective video
storytelling. Last aspect here, and then
we're going to move on to the next area
of my business, is my content calendar.
You probably want to go and pause this
video, take a screenshot of this. This
content calendar is a beast. When done
right, I think this is the quantity that
you need to be posting on each platform.
I wouldn't post any more than this. I
think the thing to focus on after this
is just raising your bar of quality. You
can see that on X, I'm posting twice a
day. LinkedIn once a day, YouTube, I'm
posting every day shorts, and then
posting long form videos every other
week. On Instagram, we're posting a real
a day and a carousel a day. And on Tik
Tok, one short form video a day. That is
the content mix that's going to help you
become omniresent. Let's keep rolling
here. Next aspect is marketing. So
Nicholas on my team, an absolute goat,
runs the marketing side of things. And
underneath Nick are, you know, Niels on
the newsletter side. Niels helps me go
and create the Foundest newsletter,
which is the only newsletter you need to
build a profitable personal brand. Now,
the cool thing about our newsletter,
right, is that it's not just some
run-of-the-mill twice a week newsletter,
but we have an entire amount of logic
behind our newsletter as well that has a
bunch of different email sequences based
on what people are clicking on. We have
this whole email infrastructure that
exists that I think is probably the most
powerful part of our entire marketing
engine. If you don't have your email
funnel really ripping with tons of
sequences around all the different logic
that you have across your customer, you
are missing out and leaving a ton of
money on the table. From there, I have
my book editor Neva book coming soon
helping founders with a bunch of the
stuff that I always talk about in much
more detail though. Lastly, here we got
the man, the legend, Dawn. Dawn is
probably the biggest character on my
team. He is the chief technology
officer, a Florida man who currently
lives in the Philippines. Absolute goat.
And underneath Dawn, he has a web flow
engineer because the founder.com website
is built on web flow. And then he's got
two VAS underneath him. Don's core role
is making sure that HubSpot is running
like an absolute machine. So much logic
is loaded into HubSpot, which then
allows us to program different emails,
make sure that the customer is being
served, and track people all the way
from awareness through to transaction
through to renewal, referrals, and
testimonials. And so basically the
entire business is all tracked inside of
HubSpot. That is the 34 person team, 38
systems. I'm going to go and give you a
download of every single one of these
systems in the lead magnet that's below
in the description of this video. Give
this away. Honestly, that lead magnet is
probably worth like 10 grand, but we
said it. We love you guys and we want to
do anything that we can to support the
founder freedom movement. So don't miss
out on that. I don't know how long we're
going to leave it up for. That was a
lot, but I hope you got a lot out of it.
Like and subscribe and welcome to the
founder freedom movement.