If you want to win in the content
creation game, you need this system.
[music] It's called the content
waterfall system. So, the content
waterfall system is how I go and take
one piece of content and turn it into 20
other strategic pieces of content. And
so, the key thing is you want to [music]
make sure you get the maximum amount of
bang for your buck by actually making
sure that that one YouTube video becomes
things like multiple LinkedIn posts,
carousels for LinkedIn. It becomes
Instagram posts, things like Instagram
reels, YouTube [music] shorts, and Tik
Tok videos. What ends up happening is
when you go and you distribute this,
right, [music] you're just doing smart
repurposing of your content, allowing
the distributed content oftentimes to
get more views combined than [music] the
actual original video itself, maximizing
your output while minimizing the amount
of energy you have to put into creation.