What I want to show you is how I go and
hook up the project knowledge. I want to
show you how I go and prompt this. Let's
start with the prompting here. So, here
you can see my YouTube goat prompt. My
approach to this is simply to give it as
much detail as possible. Inside of the
project knowledge here now is I have my
entire book outline, my entire book
transcript of over 300,000 words. I have
transcribed my six most popular YouTube
videos ever. I've uploaded as well our
dream client avatar, which is super
super important. Who are you actually
looking to target with your content? My
dream client avatar as an example is an
operator that's looking to go and build
their own well-oiled machine, be able to
remove themselves from operations, and
scale up their business. They want more
of their time back and want to be able
to build a personal media company around
what they do that they're doing. I've
also gone and uploaded all of my
different offers here as well, and a lot
of my core languaging. So, things like
words like personal media company, the
four Ws, controlling where you work,
when you work, what you work on, who you
work with, so that it has all of my
languaging. From there, I can simply go
and put in here, I need you to go and
create a YouTube concept around the
title below using all of the copy and
stuff that I've created previously in my
book, in my YouTube videos, and in all
the stuff in the project knowledge. Now,
I place paste in the title we have
there, which is why 99% of founders burn
out and the 1% who build systems
instead, and then let it rip. We have
gone and based this title off of my
channel using Poppy AI. We have the
project knowledge all updated with
probably around 500,000 words that I
have written. We're actually getting it
to go and create content based on my
work, some of my best stuff that I've
ever made, and then packaging it away
that fits this title. What this is doing
is just saving me time.