Most of you have productivity completely
backwards. I hear from people all the
time in the online community I built,
you know, how do I focus? How do I get
more productive? But the reality is
performance at the leader level isn't
motivation, it's neuroscience. There's a
mental state called flow where your
brain becomes 500% more productive
automatically. In this video, I've gone
and detailed my 26-page protocol. So,
you can go and take a look at it and
implement some of these protocols in
your life. So, let's get into it. What
I'm going to get into here is what I
call founder flow and how to tap into
your flow state. As you can see, this is
the 4hour deepwork protocol that has
absolutely transformed my productivity
over the last decade. And I want to help
unlock that level of productivity of
growth for you. First off, what is flow
state? Well, it's really this mental
state of complete immersion. Everything
around you gets blocked out. You're
totally lost in the task at hand. you
kind of lose all other distractions and
there's a sense of control on the moment
on the given thing in front of you.
Neuroscience really supports this,
right? When you're in flow, that inner
critic, that inner voice in your mind,
it shuts off. You know, your brain waves
even shift to alphatheta frequencies,
which simply just means that your brain
is dialed in to get your most important
work done. As founders, our main goal,
right, is that we want to be pushing
forward the biggest needlemoving tasks
daily that get us towards what we're
really trying to do with our business
and in our life. I'd argue that there's
probably no more important critical task
for you than making sure that you are
tapping into your founder flow state
every single day. The performance
benefits of flow from my research are
undeniable, right? But we're talking
like 200 to 500% increase in
productivity. One day of being in
founder flow is like another person
working for 5 days disorganized and all
over the place. So just think about
that, right? The benefits if you could
tap into this every single day for a
week. You may get more done than most
people get done in a month or two and
you stack that up over years. You can
imagine, you know, you're doing circles
around anyone else in your space. Some
of the triggers here as you start to
think about you know flow on the
psychological side it's intense focus.
You want to keep your mind singularly
focused on one important task. You want
to have clear goals. You know as an
example this is my notebook for the day.
It's all mapped out. I know exactly what
I need to get done and that way I can
just go and get after it. From there too
you want to make sure that ideally
you're working on stuff that's
challenging but not too challenging.
Where I see some people get tripped up
is they try to work on a project that's
way too large. And what can happen is
you end up running into procrastination
and putting it off. You want to kind of
find stuff that is at that optimal
difficulty level. It's hard, but it's
not too hard. Filming two YouTube videos
today is going to be tricky, but it's
not going to be impossible. So, my brain
can kind of settle in and get in to the
right mode. On the environment side, I'm
going to tell you that humans, we create
our environments, but you don't want to
lose fact of the reality that your
environment is going to create you as
well. If you look around me at my space
right now, it's clean. It's not
cluttered. You know, every Sunday, I'm
making sure my place is insanely just
tidy, right? My desk has no clutter on
it. I'm just in my optimal mode. I feel
good. I went for a workout already this
morning. I got my iced americanos. I'm
feeling good, right? No clutter here. I
got, you know, my YouTube stuff ready to
go. You know, funny enough, too, I got
my little vision board here. These are
little things that just help me just
settle in, feel good, and get after it.
So, on the social trigger side, right,
it's important that as a team or, you
know, your friend group, but probably
your team, you guys are all aligned on
the importance of flow, right? You don't
want people interrupting you all the
time or calling your phone and all that.
You know, I put my phone in do not
disturb mode. um and make sure that no
one's able to reach me so I can just
dial it in. In addition to that, find
new ways of making flow fun, right? By
working on different kinds of tasks, um
encouraging myself to enjoy the art of
it all, not just make it feel like work.
I'm always trying to find different ways
of linking things that I've done, right?
So maybe I read a book over the weekend
and then that relates to a YouTube video
that I made that also relates to a
Pinterest board that I have. And when
I'm in that flow state, because there's
no distractions, I'm able to link all
these disperate concepts to create
something that's amazing. Let's talk
about how flow feels. The flow cycle for
many of you, you get tripped up in phase
one, which doesn't even allow you to get
to the further phases, which is where
the real magic happens. So phase one is
the struggle phase. We sit down
sometimes to do work, the first 15 to 20
minutes, it's like, "Oh man, I'm not
feeling like this or I can't quite
connect the dots." That is normal,
right? That feeling of frustration, of
overwhelm. We all go through that.
That's kind of your brain settling into
the work at hand. You got to push
through that. Phase two now is the
release. This is suddenly where you let
go and you start to relax into the
process. You're allowing your
unconscious to start processing things
and now you are transitioning into the
flow state. Phase three is where the
magic happens. Flow. I'm spending about
2 to four hours in that state every
single day. This is where you just get
completely absorbed in the task at hand.
My belief is that one hour of flow
equals 8 hours of distracted work. Time
starts getting distorted. You kind of
almost forget yourself and you just get
completely immersed into the task at
hand. Now, phase 4 is something that
people often times skip. Recovery. It's
important that you actually celebrate
what you just got done, right? that it's
not just work, work, work, work, work
work. You know, that's not the recipe
for greatness. You know, you got to have
the kind of circular motion where you're
essentially doing the flow. You're
recovering, kind of celebrating the work
you just got done. Maybe it's with a
walk. Maybe you go reward yourself with
it, some exercise, maybe you go for a
nice lunch, whatever that may be for
you. Then you take time to kind of
prepare for your next session the next
day. And then repeat this cycle. So, you
end up at this lifestyle that's just
beautiful. It's peaceful. It's
enjoyable. So, let me peel behind the
curtains here and show you guys my
4-hour deep work protocols. On the
environment side, all about a dedicated
workspace. My great spot here, no
phones, no notifications, right? It's
optimized for comfort. I got my nice
comfy chair here. I got this place cold
as hell if I'm going to be honest,
right? I'm Canadian, so I like the
Arctic. On the technology side, I don't
want you to overthink this, okay? The
key to flow is not a bunch of tools, but
if there's some that you're interested
in, one is the brick device. Okay, this
device essentially goes and blocks all
social media on my phone. No YouTube, X,
LinkedIn, Instagram, Tik Tok, none of
that stuff. So, this little device
allows me to make sure that even if I
cave to those urges and pick up my phone
and I'm like, "Oh, I'm just going to
check Instagram quick." Instagram isn't
going to turn on because this handy
device blocks it. On the noise side, you
know, if you're into music while you're
working, which sometimes I like to do,
right, just make sure you have a nice
pair of headphones. I personally use
wired headphones. I like to make sure
there's nice light hitting me as well.
So, right now, I'm overlooking the ocean
here in Lisbon, Portugal. I can see
ships go by. If I need to ponder
something or just think about something
deeply, there's no better sight than
just looking out to the ocean. When it
comes down to then the ritual, right, I
think it's really important that you're
doing this at the same time every single
day. I like to just go and and get
prepped, get my coffee, and then kind of
just get after it. I'm also using the
same space all the time. So, as you can
tell, I'm just reducing the variables.
Same space, same time, same routine,
same notebook, same water, all the
things. You want to keep the routine
insanely simple. So, hour one, right,
can be that struggle phase. Sometimes
you're getting into it a little bit
tripped up over some of the problems
you're trying to solve, but you need to
push through that initial resistance.
Now, hour two is when you start to
finally release. You're now getting into
that core focused mode around the real
work you got to get done. For me, that
could include things like exceptional
content creation, strategic decisions in
the company, hiring folks, structuring
new resources. At this point, I'm now
diving into the flow phase. I'm
connecting the different dots, getting
things done, and this is where the real
magic happens. Hour four is where I'm
starting to now integrate everything.
This is how you start to build leverage
from that flow state. If I've gone and
created some social strategy now that's
really solid and made a bunch of new
conclusions, I'm going to go and make a
Loom video and go and share that with my
social team so they're now in the loop
and they're up to speed. You know, I
remember talking to my executive coach a
few weeks ago and one thing that we came
up with is that I should never be really
working alone. I should always aim to
bring people around me into the room
with me. As a founder, we have the
opportunity to work on stuff that only
we can do. But it's important that
others on our team start seeing that
work so we can also help them level up
and we can create maximum leverage and
alignment across our team so that not
everything comes back to us. So you
don't want to be working alone for 4
hours. Move your business forward in a
big way, but leave your team behind. So,
a big thing you can be doing then is
sharing whatever you completed with the
relevant stakeholders on your team so
that you're all moving forward together.
I would actually say, you know, Meg,
many things. The Super Bowl is one and
the preeason and your flow routine is
one the night before. The preflow
routine, you're getting clear on your
one primary objective. I'm generally
focusing on the one domino that when I
hit that thing over, it makes everything
else easier or unnecessary. From there,
I'm making sure that my list of things
is good to go. I'm setting my intention,
which you know, you can kind of see some
of these intentions here. But I am
getting a good sleep. I know that if I
get like 5 6 hours of sleep, my flow is
probably going to be 50% less flow than
I would if I got my 7 to 9 hours of
sleep, which is generally what I need to
be feeling like a rock star the next
day. In the morning, sometimes I get
exercise. Some days I just choose to get
right into it at my desk doing work from
around, you know, 7 to 8:00 a.m. for 4
hours. Now, on the flow maintenance
system, right, your attention
management, one thing that is important
is one priority at a time. I see a lot
of founders think that they can
multitask a thousand things at once.
That's not the case. So, make sure
you're ideally checking through your
list of stuff. And sometimes I'll even
go and rank them. So, it's like I go
through the first thing, then the
second, then the third, then the fourth,
and I don't need to think during my flow
state of, oh, what do I need to get
done? No, it's already there on a list
in front of me, and I'm just checking
through that stuff. No distractions. My
team knows that in the morning, don't
call me. There's no meetings. My meeting
days are all gone and sandwiched on my
Tuesdays, leaving me the rest of the
week for flow. On the energy management
side, some things just to be aware of. I
don't eat any sugar in the morning. I
cly don't eat till about 100 p.m. eating
windows generally between 1 and 7 and
the rest of it I'm fasting. You do you.
The point is like I'm not eating like
some bread in the morning before flow or
I'm not eating a donut because you do
those kind of things. I think your blood
sugar starts to get all out of whack and
you start to wonder why why am I so
distracted? Well, because your diet is
Now, on the hydration side, one
other hack that I use from Huberman is a
lot of people, they think that hydration
is key for focus, but oftentimes you're
a little bit deficient in salt. So,
sometimes what I'll do is just put a bit
of salt in my hand, like, yay, knock
that back. I've come to really love it,
to be honest. That's probably some weird
obsession. And then just chug some water
back. What's really going on sometimes
is your brain is just deficient in
electrolytes. So, you get a little bit
of salt in you, your brain's ripping. By
the way, if you're enjoying this, this
whole document is going to linked in the
description. You can go and download it
and go and start applying these
principles to your life and your daily
founder flow state immediately. So, go
check this out via the link in the
description. Now, some deep work
amplifiers on the biological side. All
right, again, sleep, guys. Sleep, sleep,
sleep. I've done all the productivity
things over the years, and I can tell
you sleep is by far the number one. So,
make sure you're getting like 7 to n
hours ideally. That's going to help also
regulate your cortisol. Make sure that
you're not tired during this and that
you can actually lock in for four hours.
On the nutrition side, I personally
don't even like to eat before getting
into flow. I just got my salt, I got my
water, and I got my two americanos.
That's what works for me. Do what works
for you. On the sleep side, what this
looks like is I don't bring any screens
to bed. I'll sometimes watch my little
documentary or I'll read a book or
whatever, but then when I go to my room,
it's pitch black, just me and that
sleep, right? So, it's deep, it's
restorative, and I'm prepared for the
next day. The other thing, like I
mentioned, is before I go to bed, I've
got my list of things I'm getting done
the next morning so that I just wake up
and I get after it. Now, amplifier
number two is cognitive enhancement.
Right? Meditation is one of the greatest
things you can do to be able to enter a
flow state even better. taking 10
minutes just to be in silence or maybe
it's listening to a guided meditation.
You choose whatever works for you,
right? But the point is when you
meditate sometimes it helps you get into
this practice much more easily and
develop your attention on the memory
phase. Developing your memory, I think
the key thing for me at least over the
years has been sobby, right? I don't
smoke, don't drink. Um, and that just
helps me and my memory. On the
creativity side, I think it really comes
down to approaching flow state like
play. I think that entrepreneurs are
like athletes and flow is like the sport
we're playing. And so every day from 7
to 11:00 a.m. you're blocking off that
time. And sometimes you want to ask
yourself like what would this look like
if it were fun? I think that boosts your
creativity and causes you to make it
enjoyable. I don't want it to feel like
something I dread. I think if you have
that state when entering flow, you're
probably doing something wrong. So ask
yourself, what would this feel like? Or
what would this look like if it were
fun? Or how could I make this feel like
play? And so on amplifier 3, which is
emotional regulation. Okay, you may find
yourself getting disturbed at some
point. You maybe, yeah, you see a slack
message come through and it distracts
you. Let's just say try and work on that
state of just calmness, right? Just come
back to where you're at. Breathing
techniques like a box breathing of four,
four, four, four. Inhale, hold it for
four, exhale for four, and repeat can be
a useful technique for just kind of
grounding yourself. On the motivation
side, for me, like I've mentioned you
guys, my biggest mission in life is to
help you unlock your creative potential.
Hence why I'm sharing my founder flow
state cuz it's one of the core protocols
I've got. That to me is enough
motivation. Every single day, I'm just
here to serve you guys and help you guys
out. And that's motivating as hell for
me and gets me to jump out of bed every
morning. What's that thing that's
getting you to jump out of bed every
morning? So that when you're in flow
state and say you hit something and you
get tripped up, you can always come and
be centered around what is your why. It
should be something that energizes you
and fires you up on the confidence
building side, right? What's going to
happen here is over a month too, you're
going to have a hell of a lot of wins to
look back on. The beauty is then you
start to stack those wins and you get
the proof that your flow routine is
working. That's when things get awesome.
You know, I'm 35 now, but when I was 23
and started implementing this stuff, it
was amazing. Then when I could start
getting done in a month, getting done in
two months, and everything around me
started to transform. I was able to exit
my first business, was able to start my
second business at record speed, and
just started getting more clarity, more
momentum, started surrounding myself
with better people, started building
better systems, way more leverage around
me. Not just, you know, the people, but
the tech and the media that was possible
was insane. I can't wait to see what you
do in your flow state. Amplifier 4,
right, is your social environment. First
off, don't surround yourself with
scrubs. Make sure your team, they are
locking in as well. You should have a
culture of flow. Each person in your
team should respect one another's flow
because at the end of the day, that's
everyone's zone of genius. And the more
you can all be building a culture of
flow where everyone is in flow, the more
your company's probably going to grow.
And so on the isolation side, a lot of
flow, a lot of productivity isn't about
adding things. It's deleting things. So
delete the distractions. Delete the
people around you. Delete the meetings.
Delete the whatever the light that you
get annoyed by. Whatever the hell it is,
deletion will leave you with nothing but
what you need to get done. And that way,
you're just locked in and ready to go.
On the troubleshooting side, there's
some problems that I hear you guys all
the time cuz you message me about this.
So you're probably even going to put it
down below. So I'll save you your
effort. Problem one, you can't enter
flow state. Yes, you can. I want you to
go and download this resource via the
link in the description. Go and read
through it and then go and trying to
implement three aspects of this in your
life today. Start building up those easy
wins with some easy tasks. Problem two,
you think that your flow state breaks
too easily. Like anything, right? Flow
is like a muscle. So, you may have to
build up to 4 hours. That's okay, right?
Focus on at least just getting into
place and doing 30 minutes a day, an
hour a day, an hour 15 a day, an hour 27
minutes a day. It's just like lifting
weights at the gym. Look at things like
meditation, making sure that you're also
relaxing, taking care of your health,
you're working out, you're getting
10,000 steps, whatever it is that keeps
you feeling good. You feel good, flow
starts to become more effortless.
Problem three is that your flow state
doesn't last. Well, welcome to the club.
Some days my flow lasts for 5 hours.
Honestly, some days flow can only last
for an hour and a half. And I just trust
my own flow. I'm not here to beat myself
up on a day that I just couldn't lock in
for more than an hour and a half. You
got to be forgiving yourself. You got to
give yourself grace. If you're not going
to be your own best friend, who else is
going to be? Now, problem four could be
your flow state feels forced. It
probably will be if you're just getting
started. The same way that going to the
gym when you first start going feels
forced. or when you're learning the
piano at first it feels forced. any new
thing is going to feel forced initially,
but as you get into the process and you
trust it, you start to go and, you know,
build up that momentum and it starts to
feel like just a regular thing that you
do, right? So, when you're thinking
about, well, what the heck should I even
do when I'm in flow state? No worries, I
got you. So, number one is strategic
planning. Thinking about your vision,
different problems that are coming up.
What's that one thing that you could
work on that would make everything else
easier or unnecessary? Thinking about
different outcomes you want, right?
Right? Is it hiring that new person? Is
it building this new YouTube strategy?
Is it scaling up your ex presence? Is it
building a newsletter strategy? Is it
creating a funnel from awareness to
transaction to 3x the profit in your
business? You inevitably know what the
highest leverage things are that you can
go and get done in your business. The
things that are in your zone of genius,
the stuff that you're great at, you love
to do, and that can make the biggest
impact in the cash flow of your
business. The intersection of those
three pieces is likely the exact stuff
you should be working on while in your
flow state. The second aspect is product
development. Inevitably, a great product
solves most things. There's no better
way to market than just having a great
product in the first place that everyone
wants to talk about. You know, what
aspects of your product could you be
improving? The user experience, looking
at the flow from someone coming to you
to onboarding to getting the product to
then telling their friends. Which area
of that needs improving? In addition to
that, right, it's things like team
leadership. You know, do you have the
right structure for your team? Do you
need to hire people, fire people, you
know, compensate people differently?
Right? A lot of that stuff takes that
deep focus. And that's exactly what to
do in your founder flow. And one added
benefit I gave you is I created a 30-day
flow state challenge. You can go and
download this doc, like I said, in the
link in the description, and go and
start this challenge yourself and get
your team onto this challenge, too. Step
one, share this document with your
entire team. That is a no-brainer
because then you're dialed in for flow
and you've got your whole team dialed in
for flow. What's more high lever than
that? The next aspect is your flow state
community. I would actually say this is
probably your most important aspect
because as humans, we are mimedic,
right? We copy those around us. And so,
if you're around a bunch of people that
are unproductive, you're probably going
to be unproductive. This is exactly why
I created Founder OS. It's a community
of like-minded individuals that are all
focused on unlocking unparalleled growth
for themselves and for one another.
There's such big collaboration benefits,
right? Being around people that are
dialing in their routines so you can
learn the tips, tricks, systems to dial
in your routine. I've given you my
90-day journey, how I've gone and
approached this so you can do the same.
And I've also gone and outlined things
like the compounding benefits of
unlocking your flow. The one thing you
can do right now to get started is
number one, download the doc. Two, share
it with your team. And three, go and set
a time tomorrow to go and unlock your
flow state. Thanks for watching and
let's win