my goal is to visit every country in the
world before I die and to make massive
amounts of money doing it I'm in year 15
of traveling the world and building my
portfolio of eight figure businesses and
so far it's been awesome I've been to 38
countries Colombia Spain Italy Japan
Saudi Arabia Oman and Mexico and 27
other incredible destinations the
purpose of this video is not to make
travel look sexy but instead I'm going
to break down how I make this kind of
travel possible while building a
business that makes me $1 13.8 million a
year that's right these Adventures
aren't Breaking the Bank they're making
it if you want to build a business you
love make millions and travel the world
you've clicked on the Right video and
the blueprint for Success boils down to
these systems that unlock the four
ultimate freedoms allowing you to work
where you want when you want on what you
want with whoever you want it's taken me
10 years to perfect these
systems and in this video I'm here to
save you those 10 painful years of
learning the hard way so like subscribe
and welcome to the founder Freedom
Movement let's get started with
unlocking the first ultimate Freedom
location freedom freedom to choose where
you work forget the current factors
limiting your freedom if you could
travel the world work remote and scale
an online business where would you go
when I first said I'm going to travel
the world I pictured myself in Bali
exploring volcanoes and Raiden forests I
imagine being able to be in a new exotic
location every 2 months and feel
constant inspiration and awe it made me
feel like I was truly living and excited
to wake up every day I enjoy scaling my
businesses going on tons of Adventures
and experiencing the world there are two
essential systems you need to implement
so you can enjoy the world and not be
chained your desk a Time audit system
and a core team system will give you the
ability to work on your business not in
your business let's break down each one
the time audit system is your path to a
more intentional energized and balanced
life I used to work 15 hours a day
buried in tasks that drain me so I
developed a Time audit system with the
time audit system I was able to take
control of my time and accelerate my
path to $5 million in annual profit
while focusing on work that gave me
energy rather than stuff that just
drained it the system is simple and it's
powerful here's what it looks like first
you need to do an audit of your calendar
and your to-do list for the last 30 days
and place every single task that you've
been working on into the First Column
from there go and do an energy audit by
determining what tasks are giving you
energy which ones are draining your
energy and which ones you just feel
neutral about armed with these insights
from your audits you now can make
decisions on what tasks to automate
eliminate and delegate this is where
strategic thinking comes into play
focusing on efficiency and energy
preservation versus just hustling 24/7
if you want to have the freom freedom to
travel the world and scale high growth
businesses you need to only work on
what's essential and automate as much as
possible and delegate whatever other
task to Legends on your team this simple
audit helped me free up hours in my day
and focus only on what really matters
you can build a business that lets you
hike the volcanoes in Mexico while
scaling your businesses to Millions the
time audit system is designed to
re-evaluate where your energy is best
used and this next system is all about
how to best use the energy of the people
around you your core team systems to
truly unchain yourself from a single
desk you'll need to set up a Powerhouse
team it's everything you need High
performers in every area of your company
and the systems to recruit them hire
them onboard them and then scale your
people and culture I measure team
candidates using eight criteria and I
call this my core team system grit this
one's a non-negotiable Relentless
resourcefulness some people find a way
no matter how impossible it seems
optimism having optimistic people on
your side is a massive mental boost
constant learning in a fast-moving World
Learning and adapting is essential zero
ego it might sound simple but it's vital
fun to be around hire people who bring a
positive energy growth mindset find
people who Embrace challenges as growth
opportunities enjoys responsibility find
people who take ownership no one who
doesn't have seven out of these eight
traits makes it onto my team now that
you know where your energy belongs and
how to leverage the energy of
specialists around you it's time to
unlock the second ultimate Freedom time
freedom freedom to choose when you work
and the key ingredient to power this
next system is right under all of our
thumbs every day content the content
funnel system if you want to break from
a schedule stuck in time you need to own
your wisdom and you need to make it
Immortal and it all starts with Organic
content this is the heartbeat of my
businesses my content funnel brings in
leads while I'm scaling mountains or
escaping into nature so how does the
content funnel work pick two social
platforms to dominate make the highest
quality content possible at the highest
quantity possible that that platform can
take creating the content is an entirely
separate system so you're going to need
to subscribe to this channel for when
that video drops but it would never be
so powerful if you didn't understand its
function drive people to a landing page
to get a lead magnet and then join your
newsletter and capture their email and
phone number in that process so you own
these people now use those emails to
drive people to sales calls and then
through a proven sales pitch you can
close those folks it's that simple and
the content funnel system continues to
grow my businesses on my own schedule
when I'm asleep in a desert Hideway when
I'm in some comfortable first class
cabin flying over an Amazon jungle or
when I'm scaling one of the most active
volcanoes on Earth holy bro and the
content funnel system just keeps
chugging along the content funnel is a
literal ATM for the audience that you've
created ATM stands for a audience T
targeted content engine M money you
control it and you control your time it
kills me to see so few Founders
leveraging social media to their
benefits it's a literal gold mine at
your fingertips I've grown an audience
of over 16 million people all through
organic content and this audience feeds
my businesses I've never paid a dime for
ads I repeat I've never paid a dime for
ads this proven system seamlessly drives
people from social media to sales calls
and the best part it can be managed
inhouse by just one person in as little
as 30 minutes a day but with great time
comes great responsibility and that is
when my dream week system becomes my
superpower years ago I architected my
dream week system and it's allowed me to
get intentional about how I spend my
time here's how it looks and how it
works one go and set guard rails for
your week my guard rails include things
like no morning meetings no Monday
meetings no energy vampires Tuesday is
for sales calls Wednesday is to Mentor
Founders Thursday I'm scaling my team
and creating content and Friday to
Sunday well that's my Adventure
Time with guard rails like these I own
my time instead of letting it own me and
these are my non-negotiables my team
knows them so the entire ecosystem
around me is in sync with my schedule
the dream week system is designed to
help you craft your ideal week every
week while balancing your business
growth and personal fulfillment
perfectly two you want to batch core Tas
batching core task is the most efficient
way to prevent a single objective from
smothering your entire week it makes no
sense to go and book a 1hour sales call
five times a week that is a massive
amount of mental drainage each week
instead batch 8 hours of sales calls one
day a week that way you're in the zone
and you're ripping through those sales
calls one at a time and then you're
cleared up the rest of the week in the
next 10 days here in Mexico as an
example I'm going to go and get a potent
dose of Nature and complete about five
YouTube videos for my channel this is
the art of intentional living just
because you're now free to work wherever
you want it doesn't mean you can just
take it easy you need to be ruthless
with your days and a Savage with your
hours to maximize the time you dedicate
to Growing your business now that you
control where and when you work let's
talk about what you work on it's easy to
get lost working on things that drain
you but to build a life of Freedom you
need to align your work with what really
lights you up this next system is
designed to give you undeniable Clarity
on what that work should be focused on
and it's actually ancient it's your icky
guy and we are going to do it together
right now iy guy is a Japanese term that
stands for your reason for being it sits
at the intersection of what you're good
at what the world needs what you can be
paid for and what you love to do here's
my iy guy at the center of Building
Systems traveling the world helping
Founders and designing products that
impact millions of lives ask yourself
what truly excites me what would I do
for free what do I lose track of time
doing and what does the world need that
I can uniquely offer find the Synergy at
the intersection of these answers that
is your icky guy only give your
dedicated time to your iy guy and have
the courage to say no to everything else
once you find your icky guy you'll see
that working on what you love isn't just
some luxury it's a system for Life 80%
of success in your life is choosing what
you should be working on you need to
find your calling life and stop caring
about what others think you have one
life to live live it on your terms and
last but not least with who you want to
share it with level four freedom to
choose who you work with 90% of our
happiness comes from who we surround
ourselves with so how do you build a
team and client base you genuinely enjoy
working with as you're scaling your
business and people you need to ensure
you have the right people in the right
seats across all these core areas of
your business sales marketing email Tech
design growth hiring creative and
content everyone on your a team should
be a systems owner it's your
responsibility to keep those systems and
their owners organized and sharp when
you plant the right people in the right
places of your business and life things
begin to flow the ultimate test of the
freedom in your business is the one
month test the ability to walk away from
your business for 1 month and return to
a business that's stronger than when you
left it and the most tactical system in
this entire ultimate Freedom ecosystem
Powers this privilege the company Wiki
The Company Wiki is the foundation of
any systemized Empire it is the brain of
your company here every part of your
business needs to be documented every
step every person involved every
timelight associated with progress every
measurement of success every deliverable
every detail it is all in your company
Wiki here is my notion Company Wiki for
founder OS I use Loom to record all my
tasks in detail and give my entire team
full access to understand every angle of
the system and my standards of execution
we have systems for everything Community
Management content YouTube growth
onboarding newsletters you name it it's
all in the wiki and organized impeccably
strong Founders build strong systems if
you want my free Company Wiki template
go to the link in the description to go
get it this is how you go from surviving
to running a scalable business that one
day can be sold because now your offer
is baked into repeatable and buyable
technology combine all of these systems
and you have it my friend the
combination of the ultimate
freedoms the freedom to work where you
want when you want on what you want with
who you want this is how I travel the
world build an Empire and make Millions
on my terms it's not magic it's not
hustle it's systems systems free you to
work on your business and travel the
world outside of your business My Hope
Is that you're not just watching this
but that you're inspired to take Massive
Action start with one system today
design one piece of your freedom at a
time this isn't just about money it's
about creating a life you actually want
to live if you want my exact templates
and systems to start your own Journey
check the link in the description
because there's a whole world out there
and it's waiting for you like And
subscribe and welcome to the founder
Freedom Movement