LinkedIn is one of the most
underestimated platforms there are out
there. In the last 3 years, I've grown
my presence to over 846,000
followers in just 36 months. All without
spending a scent on ads. [music] I was
going collaborating with my team and we
thought that we should go and put
together a deck of 80 slides that go and
detail out that entire strategy, the
playbook, all the different tactics and
systems we use so you could go and hand
this off to your team to grow [music]
your presence. Let's get into it. So, my
LinkedIn drives over 59 million organic
views every single month without
spending a dime on ads. Here you can
see, [music] you know, I was ranked by
Taplio, a third party platform, as the
fastest growing creator on LinkedIn just
last year. And so, what I want to show
you here is the process behind those
846,000 followers. because there is an
intricate and detailed process for
scaling this big this fast. And so some
quick stats for you here. I've grown at
upwards of 102,000 followers per month.
Now have over 846,000 followers, but it
did take me 36 months to get to this
point. So [music]
this didn't happen overnight. In
addition to that, it drives over 59
million organic views every month.
Again, without spending a dime on ads.
And so what I want to share with you
here in this video is how I've gone and
created viral content that [music]
actually converts to my portfolio of
online businesses because we're not just
looking to grow a bunch of followers
here. We want to actually make dollars.
Now, I'm also going to show you how to
build a profitable personal brand using
some core strategies that I see most
people miss on LinkedIn. In [music]
addition to that, I'm going to show you
how to go and get high quality leads
from creating the right kind of content
and setting up your profile the right
way. And then lastly, [music]
how to go and scale your business using
LinkedIn. I've gone and created a deck
with all the core aspects I'm showing
you right now. So, you can go and fill
this out and indicate all the core
aspects you need to get in place to
scale your LinkedIn presence. You can go
and get that deck and all the templates
via the link in the description. This is
what I see most people getting wrong
when they look to scale on LinkedIn.
They just start posting random content
all the time without any [music]
core system behind what they're doing.
They're using it almost like a resume
instead of really approaching LinkedIn
as if it's a really powerful sales
engine. They don't actually get any
engagement on their content, which
doesn't allow them to hijack the
LinkedIn algorithm the way that you can
and should if you're looking to really
scale on the platform. And they have no
clear conversion strategy because
they're just focusing all day, every day
on just a bunch of vanity metrics and
not what actually matters. What you want
to be doing instead are really three
things. And these are the three parts to
your LinkedIn domination. Number one, a
profitable profile. Making sure you're
setting it up right so you're converting
all of that attention you get to your
product or your service. The next piece
is then having an engagement machine.
Your content on LinkedIn won't go
anywhere if it's not driving real
engagement. Things like [music] reposts,
which are the ultimate metric that trick
the LinkedIn algorithm into pushing your
content to more and more people's news
feeds. In addition to that, you need to
have the right content system in place
because the last thing that you want is
to just be spinning your tires day after
day and end up on some content treadmill
where you know, fast forward a year,
you're just bound to give up because
you're just putting a lot of effort in
and seeing very little results. Step one
here, your profitable profile. Here you
can see my profile and we're going to
break down some [music] of the key
aspects here that allow me to go and
convert so many visitors of my profile
to followers. The key thing there is as
you convert them to followers, you have
people following you now for the next 2
3 years [music] and it's only inevitable
at some point there are going to convert
and so first things first you need
things looking clean, right? So a nice
clean [music] cover photo that instantly
captures someone's attention. From
there, I have a oneliner. In my case,
systems I use to grow faster. Now,
[music] it's memorable, number one, and
number two, it's embedding the word
systems into the visitor's mind. So,
when [music] they think systems, they
think of me. You see this very much
popularized across the internet, whether
it's stoicism and Ryan Holiday,
productivity and Ali Abdal, habits and
James Clear, right? What word do you
want to own in the mind of your end
customer? [music]
that should likely be in your oneliner.
Now, from there, also having a clear
value prop. In my case, proven systems
to grow a profitable audience with
organic content. So, your LinkedIn
profile, right, it's very much your
storefront these days. [music] You know,
it's packed with people that are doing
real things, you know, people looking to
do business and looking to connect with
others. And the truth is that storefront
never [music] closes. And so, here's how
I updated my profile. First off,
compelling banner. You got a clear call
to action, right? I actually have
multiple on my profile. If you see
things like my featured section, you see
the cover photo. You even see the links
that I put inside of the posts and the
CTAs in each post I put out. I have the
valuedriven headline. So, within seconds
of hitting my profile, people know
exactly what I do and why they should
follow me. In addition to that, we have
a strategic featured [music] section
that goes and drives people to my
newsletter as well as to Founder OS. So
[music] they can either join the only
newsletter that's built for helping
people with their personal brands or
they can go and join Founder OS where I
help founders with proven systems build
their founder brand and remove
themselves from operations. So LinkedIn
really rewards posts with valued dense
images. [music]
The image essentially is the algorithm
juice that's going to go and push it to
more and more people. It essentially
acts almost like a YouTube thumbnail for
your given post. And so here you can see
this image caused this particular post
on LinkedIn to get over 24 million
organic views without spending a dime on
ads. I went and simply visualized and
handwrote all of the pieces from the
main post into this image so that it was
highly sharable. Man, [music] I even had
folks going and telling me that they
went and printed this off afterwards.
That's how valuable they found it. And
so there are four [music] types of posts
that I've primarily used to go and grow
my following on LinkedIn. Number one is
behindthe-scenes content, [music] right?
Using words like I, I've, when, or if,
and describing [music] some real stories
from my background of building
businesses for the last 15 years, the
trials, tribulations, peaks, values,
obstacles, challenges, wins, and
everything in between. When you actually
share your own story, right, you get
past all the pathy, cringe on
LinkedIn and just share the stuff that's
actually true to you. And it also helps
people know that there's not just some
AI behind what you're writing. The
second aspect again is valuep packed
images which we just spoke about. The
third is deep work systems. So I like to
go deep into the what [music] and the
how I do things. So I'm not just simply
putting out highle stuff. I know that
people are going and following me
because they want to see the details.
They want to know exactly how I do what
I do. And so it's exactly what I give
them. Fourth is personal stories.
[music] Right? We all have a unique
background. You have a unique story. in
your story is your competitive
advantage. And so opening up around the
kind of things you've been through, you
know, what you learned last year, um
your challenges, the different
approaches you take to things like
hiring and firing and selling and
marketing, right? It's those personal
stories that give it that personal touch
and again get you out of the cringe area
of LinkedIn. So the next aspect here,
right, is your call to actions or your
CTAs. What's the science behind what's
going on in this CTA? Well, first off,
we're prompting people to go and repost
it to their network. A repost on
LinkedIn is one of the leading
indicators of LinkedIn that they should
push your post to more people. So,
[music]
reposts lead to way more views. So, the
next aspect here is I'm getting people
to go and follow [music] me. So, they go
and click my name, follow me, and good
to go. But you got to actually prompt
people to do that if you want to
generate a lot of followers. And then
the next aspect is something that most
people miss. [music] So the question
that I use there will go and relate to
whatever the post is that I'm sharing.
So as an example, if it's a post around
deep work, I may go and have a CTA that
says, "Want my deepwork checklist?"
[music]
Or, you know, if it's on my top 10 tools
to capitalize [music] on the AI wave, I
may say, you know, want my complete 56
tool [music] list, you know, join my
newsletter, get it. So, the lead magnet
or the thing that I'm offering to give
away is tightly [music] coupled with the
subject matter of the post it appears
in. This is super critical if you want
to increase [music] your click-through
rate and the amount of leads you acquire
from the platform. [music] Here's how I
drive my newsletter signups. Here you
can see, you know, my newsletter landing
page. There is no place for people to
navigate, right? We have no header. It's
just [music] simply build trust, share
your expertise, and stay visible. People
can then go and get this framework. And
when they enter in their name, their
email, and their phone number, they go
and they get [music] this lead magnet
for free. And so when I'm going and
creating any given [music] post on
LinkedIn, it really comes down to your
first three lines. Okay? If you can't
stop the scroll in those three lines,
you've lost them. And so, what do you
got to do to keep [music] people's
attention? Well, number one, you have to
create curiosity. And so, here you can
see I just read about a study I can't
stop thinking about, right? It instantly
hooks me and gets me insanely curious.
[music] What's the study? The next line
then drives action. Right? Introverts
are more effective leaders according to
Harvard. [music] So I'm using data. I'm
also using identity to go and call out a
specific subset of people instantly
getting a reaction. The next aspect then
is I promise immediate value. So
conventional wisdom says extroverts make
the best leaders. They are [music]
decisive, outgoing and dominant. And so
instantly people are probably going to
agree or disagree with this statement.
[music] And the other thing that's going
on is that we all either are introverts
or extroverts and we have other
introverted or extroverted friends.
[music] So this topic is highly sharable
and contagious. Now there are nine other
elements, okay, of viral content that
I've noticed that I want to share with
you so you can also go and blow up your
LinkedIn. [music] So number one,
personal stories, right? Open up. Get
real with the sort of advice that you'd
love to have given yourself. 5 years
ago. What have you learned? What have
you been through? What are the crucibles
of leadership that you've learned that
you want to share now? Open up. Right?
Your vulnerability is your superpower.
The next is your proven systems. Right?
When you look at your company or when
you look at your life, what are the
principles, the habits, the [music]
systems, blueprints, you know,
everything that you've learned that you
think would be valuable to a large group
of people on LinkedIn. The third is
valuebombing people, which I think of it
as like your value per second. You know,
if someone's spending 2 minutes on one
of your LinkedIn posts, how much value
are you giving them? And are those
people [snorts] so enthralled, so
inspired that they can't help but go and
share it with their colleagues or go and
share it with their team in Slack? That
should be your goal. [music] Fourth is
you want to keep it tasteful. We both
know LinkedIn is probably one of the
cringiest platforms there are out there.
And so when you have taste, it really
can be your competitive advantage, your
way to stand out. That's why I'm
constantly going and putting a lot of
effort into things like my cover photo,
the images I'm sharing. I'll even have
designers on my team put really
beautiful graphics together. [music] So,
we're inspiring people with our elevated
design and our obsession around quality.
Then, like I'd mentioned, there are four
powerful words you can use, which are
when, what, I, [music] I, and how. Well,
those are five, but you get it. The
point just being going deep in the value
you're trying to give away, right? when
you use words like you know [music] when
I was 15 something something happened
you know what I've learned or I or I've
or how I accomplished something
something right these words when used in
your hooks are [music] great ways to go
and formulate content that's going to be
uniquely valuable on the platform and
[music] helps you stand out versus 99%
of other accounts every 30 days I review
my content and all other high performing
content on the platform and then really
formulate my own strategy for LinkedIn
Okay, my goal is to be the strongest and
[music] best creator on the platform.
So, it takes studying the patterns of my
top 10% of content and doubling down on
it as well as looking across all other
players on the platform, looking at
[music] what formats, what copywriting
is working best, and being a student of
the game. you know, it's really about
learning from the best of the best, even
being mentored by them, having them in
WhatsApp groups and ask them questions,
formulating kind of this mastermind
around other LinkedIn creators that are
also growing fast so that I could do the
same. And so from there, a big thing as
well that I've talked about [music] is
making sure you have your engagement
machine set up. You need to make sure
that within 45 minutes of a post going
live, you have [music] 30 plus people
that are engaging with that post, right?
So, I have about 25 folks that are
engaging with my content within just
about 30 minutes of it going out, which
helps it then get pushed to more and
more people in the algorithm. [music]
Now, one way to do this, right, is to
make sure that you keep creating content
for a certain subset of people. For my
page, as an example, it's founders
looking to scale with peaceful, calm
systems and that have aspirations to
eventually remove themselves from the
operations of their business. And so I
just keep on hitting the drum beat of
what matters to these people. They want
organic content systems, you know, they
want revenue [music] systems. They want
to be able to remove themselves from
their companies. And I just keep talking
about this sort of cloud of concepts. So
you want to think about not just the
word that you're engrading in someone's
mind, but who are you looking to target
[music] and what are the content
categories you're going to go and focus
on most. So, when it comes to my
LinkedIn growth checklist, okay,
updating your banner with a clear CTA,
no-brainer, crafting a valuedriven
headline, adding [music] two featured
pieces of content to your featured
section, having followed 20 relevant
creators, and setting up off-platform
relationships where they're supporting
your content in the background. While
many think LinkedIn is just a single
player game, I can tell you from
experience having grown to 846,000
followers, that it's very much a
multiplayer game and it's useful to have
a community around you. From there, you
want to make sure you have many people,
ideally 30 plus, engaging with your
content in the first 45 minutes. Track
your top post, the subject matter, the
words, the hooks, and double down on
what works. In addition to that, you
want to make sure that you're reviewing
your analytics every single month,
right? And looking at the patterns,
what's [music] going well, what's not
going well, so you can keep on learning,
right? If you put 100 posts out there,
[music] and with each post you get 10%
better each time, that's over 18,000
times better by the 100th post you put
out. So, it's really that dedication to
constant [music] improvement. Even if
you get started on LinkedIn and you're
not doing that well or you're not
getting that much traction, focus on the
velocity at which you're learning and
improving because that is the leading
indicator to you growing on the
platform. Post your first piece. If
you're watching this and you're not, you
know, following [music] the guidelines
of valued post with an amazing image,
awesome CTA with engagement on it, well,
it's time to get [music] implementing
your first post with those criteria. You
want to then go and share your profile
below. I'd love to go and check it out
via the comments. So, if you want to go
check that out, I'll be doing some
different audits of people's posts,
[music] posting some Loom video
breakdowns as well. And then if you want
my help and my team's help going and
helping you with your LinkedIn, you can
go and apply to Founder OS via the link
in the description. In addition to that,
you know, if you're looking for more
systems to scale across all the
different platforms, well, you should
also go and subscribe to this channel.
So, are you ready to go and see my
complete system so you can take
advantage of LinkedIn and all the
platform has to offer? Well, you should
go and check out Founder S where I share
my complete playbook for going and
tapping into the fullest potential that
LinkedIn has to offer. It [music] has
templates, SOPs, communities, support,
mentorship for me and my team. So, go
and check that out via the link in the
description and let's continue to win