before you do anything else go lock
yourself in a room and read these seven
marketing books it'll change your life
the one thing by Gary Keller use the
simple powerful Concept in this book to
focus on what matters most in your
personal and work life over subscribe by
Daniel Priestley learn how to get people
lining up to do business with you sales
pitch by April Dunford craft a story to
stand out and win $100 million leans by
Alex Heros this book contains the
playbooks that took heroi from sleeping
on a gym floor to owning a portfolio of
companies that generate $200 million a
year in less than a decade Doom Secrets
by Russell Brunson learn the underground
playbook for growing your company online
with sales funnels made to stick by chip
and Dan Heat this book reveals the
anatomy of ideas that stick and explains
ways to make ideas stickier the one-page
marketing plan by Alan dib get new
customers make more money and stand out
from the crowd dib reveals a marketing
implementation breakthrough that makes
creating a market plan simple and fast