raise your right hand and repeat this
founder Manifesto we reject that
business is the purpose of living and
yet we build the best businesses in the
world through creating systems and
hiring amazing people we are able to
grow beyond what most people think is
possible with only a fraction of the
work we deny that quantity is more
important than quality and we produce
some of the best products and services
on Earth we relentlessly focus on
quality over quantity and on velocity
over speed we understand that life is
for living and business is for making
life better no more and work nights no
more missing life's moments we build
systems that scale businesses and
nourish Souls our Mantra automate
delegate liberate at founder OS we're
redefining success it's not just profit
it's freedom