Steve Jobs once said, "Making something
simple is way harder than making it
complex." Steve Jobs got fired from his
own company because people thought he
was too obsessed with perfection. When
he finally went and returned Apple,
people called him crazy. He took a
product line of 150 products and
narrowed it down to just three. And
simplicity isn't just about what you're
saying yes to. It's being comfortable
saying no to 97% of things so you can
say hell yes to the 3% that are actually
going to move the needle forward for
you. Now, Steve Jobs was notorious for
ignoring customer feedback, surveys, and
focus groups. He preferred much more to
lean into his own product intuition.
Sometimes when you just rely on everyone
else's opinion, you get clouded. But
when you listen to that like inner voice
that you have and trust that signal,
you're able to distill things down to
one simple