here are five steps to make an extra
$10,000 profit per month and do what
brings you Joy get a pen and paper out
step one start with your icky Guy this
is the intersection between your innate
talents and interests and fulfilling an
unmet audience need step two choose a
sticky name that clearly defines the
category your championing like Shopify
for e-commerce or cly for appointment
scheduling step three provide unmatched
value create invaluable resources like
howto guides case studies templates and
courses that Empower your Niche audience
build a community step four spread your
influence guest post on industry blogs
get featured on podcasts host Live
Events run webinars speak at conferences
the more people you get talking about
you the more your brand becomes the
automatic leader in your category and
step five stay Nimble the category
Champion spot belongs to those bold
enough to constantly reinvent themselves
keep your finger on the pulse of your
Niche and stay ahead of the trends the
competition won't know what hit them
because you've exited the competition
altogether