first had to realize you are not your
company. When people ask what do you do,
they're asking because what we do is
often our best approximation for who we
are and our work naturally becomes our
identity. This is more true for
entrepreneurs than anyone else. Your
business can be all-consuming. Your
identity, your baby, the reason you get
up in the morning. I felt this way
completely when I built my first
business. From the outside, it looked
like a phenomenal success, but from the
inside, I felt like I poured my
whole life and identity into this
company and once it was gone, it felt
like the biggest part of me was lost.
What's worse is that when I lost the
company, I lost all the systems and
effort that I put into the company to
get it to where it was. That's when I
accidentally discovered CEO mindset
number one when I turned on a TV and saw
businessman and hedge fund manager Carl
Icon on an HBO documentary. This was a
man who ran a $4 billion enterprise and
unlike me didn't seem stressed or burnt
out. He was one of the happiest people
that I'd ever seen running a company. As
he spoke, I realized that he didn't
think of himself as being any of his
companies. Instead, he was Carl. He
considered himself to be an asset
manager. And his identity was
diversified among his assets instead of
pouring everything into just one thing
in life. And if a company was shuttered
or sold, he didn't lose sleep because
they were just one small piece of his
identity. No more did I invest 100% of
myself in a company, grow it, sell it,
then lose my identity in it. Instead, I
started building my most important
business asset and the one I'll always
benefit from, my personal brand. I like
to think of it as a holding company
named Gray Enterprises. And as I grow my
personal brand, any company I build
under that Gray Enterprises umbrella is
built to benefit me, my ambitions, my
vision, and my goals. This didn't just
help me, it helped my companies thrive,
too. When a company faces a struggle,
loses key clients or talent, or doesn't
hit a growth target we set, it doesn't
mean I failed as a human being. Instead,
as an asset manager, those challenges
are just lessons I can learn from, adapt
to, and keep winning. When you align
your personal brand with your
businesses, you'll benefit in these
three ways. First, your mental health
improves. You are no longer out of sync
with the impact your company aims to
generate. There will be less dissonance
as you pour time, energy, and money into
your company. It will nourish your
mental state rather than drain it.
Entrepreneurship has been disconnected
from the pursuit of freedom it used to
be. It's become a romanticized
nightmare. By creating a sustainable
relationship between your personal brand
and your business, you can pursue it
with intensity, but leave enough in the
tank for your own personal fulfillment.
Second, your companies improve because
your identity and values are now aligned
with your companies. It feels better to
build with this perspective and your
bandwidth opens up in ways that didn't
seem possible before when your soul in
the business were arm wrestling for a
commitment from you. Third, your brand
thrives. When Bitmaker sold, I barely
existed online and all my credibility
was tied to the one thing outside of me.
Today, I have 2.2 2 million followers
across the Matt Grey brand and that
credibility extends to any future
project or initiative that I launch. And
it goes with me no matter what happens
to my portfolio of assets. And what's
more, people want to connect with other
people more than ever. When you build a
community of raving fans, that feeds
attention into your current or future
businesses. CEOs that view themselves as
asset managers instead of companies not
only grow their companies faster, but
also get to have their lives back. This
unlocks limitless energy and fuel to
push themselves even further in their
business and their lives. This leads us
to lesson number two, the ROI
rule. Last year, I joined a mastermind
program for entrepreneurs at a similar
stage of business. Over the course of
several days, I met with other founders,
talked through challenges and other
businesses, and listened to a few
presentations by the organizer. This
privilege cost me $68,000 for just 3
days. Here's the deal. Top 1% CEOs don't
focus on cost as their primary factor
for decision-making. Cost is just a
number. Money is a lever. Warren Buffett
put it this way. Price is what you pay.
Value is what you get. If you can spend
$68,000 or even a million somewhere in
your portfolio, but then get $2 million
of benefits elsewhere. You've traded up.
You can think of it in one of two ways.
In terms of costs or in terms of return.
As a result of that mastermind, I will
add $5 million of value to my business
within the next 3 years. The connections
I made I wouldn't have found anywhere
else. The sticker price of the
mastermind only meant entrepreneurs
making eight figures or more could
attend. And those connections have
already led to valuable partnerships,
knowledge, and hires that I never would
have found anywhere else. I realized
areas I was getting stuck on, which of
my plans had the highest leverage, and
what new higher leverage opportunities I
hadn't even been considering. Setting
aside this time and investment forced me
to slow down and think about the
business as a whole. If I just kept
cruising and reacting to the business,
there were massive product and market
opportunities I would have ignored. But
I never would have unlocked those
opportunities if I thought in terms of
cost. Instead, I switched my lens to
value. Use this lens when it comes to
your business. When it comes to hiring,
can you spend 3x more on a higher salary
to recruit a team member who brings 100x
results? When it comes to education, can
you invest $3,000 today to learn an
insight that will bring you six figures
to your bottom line in the next 12
months? When it comes to systems, can
you invest the time, money, and energy
today into building your personal brand
and then be able to benefit from that
decades to come? It's easy to see
$68,000 of cost as a good return on
investment after the results come in.
But it's hard to see it upfront before
those returns are even realized. That's
why you have to pair the ROI rule with
the third level of thinking of top CEOs,
which I call the 18-month rule.
[Music]
CEOs are impatient. We want to conquer
the world right now. There are so many
opportunities to pursue. So, if we pick
one and it isn't showing immediate
return, it's tempting to declare that
thing a failure. That happened to me
when I began transitioning to building
my personal brand and thinking of myself
as an asset manager. I got on LinkedIn.
I joined X. I started posting my
insights. But at first, I barely saw any
movement in my numbers. I watched the
data every day. If something got
traction, I was excited. But most of the
time, things were flatlined or even
moving backwards. I've been posting for
10 days, then 30 days, then 50 days, and
it didn't seem like it was getting any
easier. So, I asked my network, "What
was I doing wrong?" And the people with
hundreds of thousands or even millions
of social followers looked at what I had
done, and they gave me the same advice.
Stop focusing on the results you see
today. Start focusing on the results
you'll see in 18 months. Top 1% CEOs
don't judge the results of their efforts
on the same time scale. They extrapolate
years down the line to hit their goals.
If you can't commit to working on
something for 18 months, don't work on
it at all. After 2 years of committing
to my social plan, as of today, I've
grown to over 2.2 million followers.
I've grown past the folks I initially
asked for advice from. But if I had
given up my efforts in month two, I
never would have seen any return on
them. Anything worth doing is worth
doing for 18 months. So don't focus on
today's outcome. Focus on the things you
can control. Be relentless in your
commitment to action and improvement in
all aspects of your business over the
longest time horizon possible. That's
how CEOs win. And there's no area where
this matters more in your business than
on the next topic, hiring. Level four,
thinking of a CEO is what I call the
bozo
bar. One of the greatest paradoxes of
growing your business is that if left
unchecked, your hiring will get worse,
not better, over time. Steve Jobs
described this process in a lecture he
was giving. Over time, if you aren't
careful, you're going to hire folks who
are lower quality than your original
team. He pointed out in particular the
risk of hiring professional managers,
people without functional experience who
have more power to hire even more people
below themselves. Steve calls these
people bozos. When you hire bozos,
they'll hire even worse bozos, lowering
your talent's average quality until it
falls below the bozo bar. Great CEOs
have to build mechanisms into their
business to avoid talent quality falling
below the bozo bar, at which point it
becomes hard to reverse and then
decline. Instead, model your hiring
process after another 1% CEO, Jeff
Bezos. At Amazon, Bezos instituted a
practice that still continues to this
day, the idea of a bar raiser. For any
new hire, Amazon appoints a bar raiser.
An employee who assesses if a new hire
will raise the average bar of
performance or lower it. Bar raisers
from all over the company will be a key
part of the hiring process and ensure
that any new staff are 50% more skilled
than someone in a similar role. This is
a deliberate way to keep the company's
bozo meter in check and instead hire A+
performers that increase your
effectiveness. Spending time
interviewing multiple candidates and
coming up with objective measures to
evaluate their skill level is
timeconuming, but it is a high ROI
activity. For every hour you spend
finding a great candidate, you'll save
hundreds of hours not dealing with B or
C players who will not actively help
your business and may actually lower
your chances of accomplishing your
long-term goals. The next level of CEO
thinking is known as the Pinterest
effect.
Before you can raise the standard of
anything in your business, you have to
raise it for the information you
consume. Your attention is a scarce
resource. So, you must spend it
strategically. Identify the areas of
your business that move the needle.
Then, make a strategy of documentation
and curation of best-in-class resources
for improving those specific areas. It's
almost like you're creating a Pinterest
board of business insights and
inspiration. By default, information is
scattered, distracting, and will likely
slow you down more than it's going to
help you. If you intentionally capture
information and then restructure it
based on your goals, you can use that
and then turn it into future standard
operating procedures for your own team.
This allows you to develop your taste
and then scale it across your
organization in every function. Open-
source blueprints exist all over the
internet. This channel has hundreds of
frameworks, mindsets, and operating
systems to grow your business. Use tools
like Readwise, My Mind, and Notion to
capture the best information available.
And then, whether it's public or lock
behind some paid resource, you can then
curate that to use it in your own
business. It's going to help you a lot
faster than consuming the same
information at a slower pace, spread out
over more resources. You will build a
bank of wisdom to draw on whenever you
need insights in any category of your
business. If you'd like to download my
own personal Pinterest board of business
insights every week, sign up for the
founder US newsletter via the link in
the description. I'll share with you one
core system to help you go and capture
and accelerate your own founder journey
every single week. So, go check that
out. Which leads us to the topmost level
of CEO thinking.
As entrepreneurs, you quickly realize
that effort is the lifeblood of your
business, especially early on. If you
aren't getting something done, it
doesn't happen. The equation looks like
this. Effort equals outcomes. If you add
more effort, you get more results. When
we face any challenge, our first
instinct is likely to pour more energy
and more energy and more effort into
those businesses. We make more content,
book more prospect calls, and launch
more products until one day we're burnt
out with nothing left to give. We got
more outcome. Sure. But is that the
point? When I pulled my community of
thousands of founders, the number one
reason they started their company wasn't
getting rich for its own sake. It was
freedom. Freedom to control your
schedule and what you work on. Freedom
to take care of your mind and body.
Freedom to spend time with friends,
family, and loved ones. Effort gets you
results as long as you keep pushing. It
doesn't get you freedom. You're stuck in
this equation forever. Let's rework it.
Over time, we want to apply our effort
into two things. Building teams and
building systems. The new equation is
this. Effort plus team times systems
equals outcomes. This is what I call the
freedom
equation. At first, it'll still feel
like mostly effort as you're starting to
build a team and you're just starting to
clarify your systems. But eventually the
team can drive outcomes themselves and
our systems start to drive outcomes too.
We start to apply the same effort or
even less but our returns keep going up.
This is why this is the most important
level of CEO thinking because if you can
apply it to all five other levels, you
can use that effort to build systems
that work outside of you. And once you
have those teams and the systems in
place, you become a top 1% CEO. not
doing it all alone, not pouring your
whole identity into a company, not
fixated on cost. Instead, you get what
you were probably aiming for in the
first place, a life of founder freedom,
putting your time and energy into living
a full life doing what you care about
most. For my full system on becoming a
top 1% founder, check out the link in
the description. Like, subscribe and
welcome to the founder freedom movement.