It's actually pretty easy to get ahead
of 99% of people with AI. In fact, the
top 1% are cashing out on the biggest
opportunity in decades. I've spent over
400 hours mastering AI systems so I
never have to worry about money again.
And in this video, I'm giving it all
away for free. I'll share with you the
only five AI tools you need, as well as
my hypersp specific prompts so you can
unlock new levels of growth in this AI
era. Before we get tactical, we need to
understand where we are now and what the
current state of AI actually looks like.
AI prompting is going to turn just the
average person into an absolute weapon
if you know how to do it right. But the
issue is that most people use prompts
that are nine words max, which is
leaving out a massive opportunity. The
truth is, when you're prompting, you
need to be as detailed as possible.
Prompting is the ultimate form of
leverage. Let's get into it. Number one,
use Chad GBT as your master negotiator.
I trained Chad GBT to negotiate like
Jerry Jones, the billionaire owner of
the Dallas Cowboys who turned that into
a 9 billion empire. We've all been
there, right? You're going and
negotiating whether it's your salary, a
new job position, an Airbnb, a discount
on some software, and you want to go and
get some end result, but you're not sure
how to get from point A to point B. That
is where the Jerry Jones prompt and GPT
comes in. So you're going to go and
start a new project in chat gt. We can
call it Jerry Jones. Create the project.
And what we're going to do is then go
and create the instructions here on
exactly what we want. So I'll use
whisper flow. Go and you are the best
negotiator in the world times 100. I
want you to go and get the better deal
in the above negotiation I'm in. That is
10 times better than Jerry Jones would
negotiate with it. I want you to
guarantee that we get the best result. I
want you to be firm. Um, be kind to the
person, but get the best end result by
both getting the best transaction and
making sure that you negotiate hard to
get what I need here. All right. So,
there we go. We've got the instructions
in there. Let's say I'm looking to get a
20% discount on some software I'm buying
right now. I'm negotiating some
software. I need to get a 20% discount
on this. Please go and send an email
that I can use that goes and sends a
request to the company and guarantees I
get the result I need. So now I have
this project set up where I can go and
use this for any negotiation needs I
have, saving me a ton of time and a
bunch of headache. So there we go. So
we're not being overly aggressive here,
but we're laying out the key points that
we need to see. And it took me 2 seconds
instead of muddling around this in my
head for 2 days. Number two, I use Poppy
AI to make viral YouTube videos better
than 90% of humans. So, here's how it
works. Inside of Poppyai, I have my
YouTube goat script writing board, which
has everything that I need to go and
create an insane script in minutes.
Okay, so inside of this, we've got all
of my title research from legends like
April and Alter, Mr. Beast, and then I
feed that to its own AI prompt using
Claude AI. Here you can see that it's
going and analyzing these key videos to
then go and synthesize the most
important takeaways like being hyper
specific, delivering insane amounts of
value and getting the structure right of
hook promise and specificity. Now from
there I've gone and synthesized the best
thumbnail research, all of the best
intro research as well as script writing
research. And then the magic comes from
actually going and dropping in all of my
most popular YouTube videos. What I love
most about it is it's able to go and
transcribe every single word from those
videos to then go and come up with my
own unique YouTube guidelines. So from
there, I can go and also feed it all of
the course systems I've developed by
going and synthesizing the best title,
thumbnail, and intro research, which you
can see here, and then feeding that into
research around my channel, as well as
uploading some of my key documents, so
that the videos that we're making and
the concepts that we draft sound
authentically like me using my actual
core phrases and frameworks. And so what
I can then do here is then feed it all
of this info and then have Poppy AI
leverage the newest Claude Sonnet to go
and build out YouTube concepts for me. I
know that the biggest YouTube channels
out there have an AI researcher or a
content researcher on their team, but
with Poppy AI, I can have a lean mean
team and make banger videos twice per
week. So here you can see as an example,
I've gone and plugged in, you know, go
and make me a script based on all the
research that we have. And here it goes,
right? and it's able to go and look at
my channel and then go and output, you
know, an introduction that sounds just
like me, go and set up the problem for
the video and then reveal some core
systems all throughout that again fit my
voice, my systems. And then it also
knows to also include a call to action
which then typically leads to a core
system that I leave below in the
description. And if you're looking for
this entire board, you can go and find
it, well, you guessed it, via the link
in the description. Here's the reason
that all this matters, right? And at the
end of the day, as one founder or
creator, you can only do so much. And
there's always this tug and pull of
should I scale my team or do I just need
to scale my own time and invest even
more in it. But with this tool in the
YouTube script writing board I just
showed you, you don't need to make those
trade-offs anymore. You can go and
empower this board to be your content
researcher and help you come up with
titles, scripts, and researched concepts
that are good to go, saving you hours of
time and helping you create content at
the content cadence you're looking to
nail it. Number three, use Claw to get
customers. Even if you don't have a
business yet, this still works. You can
use Claw to go and create an email that
will land your very first clients. So,
if you're looking to go and scale up a
business or even start it, one thing
that you should definitely have in place
is a 5day email miniourse compiled with
a 5day FOMO series, which stands for
fear of missing out. That's going to go
and sell people more on exactly what you
do and convert them into customers. Now,
going and building this out can go and
take if not, you know, 20 plus hours of
work because there's a lot of
intricacies to write like the best
copywriters in the world. But the cool
thing is is with the prompt and the
project I'm about to go and show you
inside of Claude, you can do this in
minutes instead of hours. Let me go and
show you how to go and create this for
your business. What I've gone and
created here is a Claude project called
email courses. Inside of the
instructions, you can see I've created
this master prompt. You are an expert
email course copyriter who generates
billions of views for the best
entrepreneurs in the world. make Matt's
email sequence around this topic a
thousand times better than any other
YouTube video or content that has ever
been made around the topic. Now, this
just keeps on going and if you want this
entire prompt, you can go and find it
via the link in the description. But,
you know, you can see that I'm getting
into details around exactly what I need
to have here, exactly the content
inspiration it should be utilizing, the
criteria for the kind of people I'm
looking to target with this, and exactly
what dictates amazing content for this
email course. So, what I can do is go
and type in, you know, go and create an
educational email course around getting
going with YouTube and getting to your
first thousand subscribers. So, there we
go. We're using Whisper Flow to go and
input that text. Click enter here and
we're off and going. Now, keep in mind
in the project knowledge inside of
Claude as well, I've put all of the core
documentation across Founder OS and my
personal brand so that Claude's not just
reinventing the wheel or using some
generic BS. It's actually using real
words, systems, frameworks, and
blueprints that I've invented so that
this email course sounds uniquely like
me. And so, here it goes. It's going and
using the entire project knowledge to go
and synthesize the best stuff to go and
help make YouTube accessible for
beginners. And here we go. So, the
YouTube operating system, 0 to a,000
subscribers in 90 days. And so, email
one, the $47 million YouTube secret that
nobody knows about. And so it's going
and creating beautiful emails. As you
can see here, it's showing them my
content waterfall system. Turning one
YouTube video into four YouTube shorts,
six Instagram posts, six X threads,
three LinkedIn carousels, one newsletter
deep dive, and 10 quote graphics from
one video. So it's giving away the
sauce, right? And the goal here is for
people to go and get those five emails
over 5 days and be mind blown by the
value. And if the free is that
good, well then they know that whatever
is inside of Found must be even better,
which is the goal and exactly the
promise we live to deliver on. So all of
that heavy lifting is being done without
me, which saves me hours of time. And if
you want my entire Claude prompt here,
as well as how I go and think about
structuring a project knowledge, you can
go and check that out. Yeah, you guessed
it, in the link in the description.
Number four, using nitn to understand
what people want to buy before my
competition does. So this is our Reddit
voice of customer intelligence. This is
actually insane. We go and get this to
crawl Reddit on all of the posts that
make sense given our core target
demographic. Reddit is a gold mine for
customer insights. And just a side note,
even if you're just starting a business,
this thing will work for you as well.
Here's how this works. It's going to go
and target your dream clients inside of
the different subreddits that they exist
in. It's going to go and comb through
every single post and not just the posts
themselves, but all of the nested
comments within those posts. Every
single piece of content then passes
through our AI, which we call the angle
finder, which is going to go and find 13
different marketing angles to go and hit
people with based on the different
insights that we gather from these
subreddits. It literally extracts word
for word quotes that you can then use in
your marketing. But this is where it
gets really interesting. It's going to
go and remove all spam comments and
things that are irrelevant and then go
and pass through the most valuable
insights through the relevant AI. So,
GPT4 for more technical content, and
then Gemini for the more emotional side
that we're looking to tap into. At the
end of each run, you get a full
technical report with all of the key
insights, the emotions you're trying to
tap into, the key words that you want to
drive, and the overall content topics
that you should be going and creating to
go and drive conversions to your
product. And the coolest thing is that
everything is stored in a database over
time. And so you're getting this massive
database of customer sentiment and how
the trend line of your customers is
changing so that you have the most
up-to-date strategies every given month
and are tapping into the core things
people are talking about and inserting
your brand into those conversations. So
this isn't just pulling comments though,
right? This is using Reddit to then go
and transform your content into a 24/7
salesperson. Let me show you what I mean
here. So inside of NAND, we got this
idea that, you know, building your
personal media company is the new moat.
And so what I can then go and do is take
that concept and put it into an
Instagram reels project that I've
created in Claude. So you know, create a
reel around personal media company being
the new moat. Here you can see I have
instructions in here that really dial in
this project to go and create reels that
are better than the best reels that have
ever been made around this given topic.
So here we go and we're getting ripping
here. So putting cloud to work again.
You can go and see it's going and
analyzing the project knowledge for my
voice style and content approach so it
can go and create this Instagram real
concept over the NAND research we got
from subreddits on Reddit. And here we
go. So, personal media company, the new
moat. So, last week I was on a call with
a founder doing 40k a month. Smart guy,
great product, profitable business, but
he was completely invisible. You can see
it just keeps going down all of the
script I need to go and create this
reel, as well as giving me pacing, you
know, the text, the hook, the engagement
triggers, and all of the key
differentiators that will make this more
viral than anything else on that topic.
And so now I've got the research from
Reddit. I've got Claude going and
pumping out the script to go and riff my
own Instagram reel and share that with
my audience of 950,000 on Instagram. So
all of the different content that we
have is data backed by what we've
researched here on Reddit. So it's no
more guesswork. It's actually based on
what people are saying in our target
market. this becomes a real competitive
advantage because it's like a
salesperson that runs 24/7 and going and
giving you a market research team at
your fingertips. If you want to learn
how this architecture works under the
hood, well, you guessed it, you can also
go and find all of the details behind
how I set up this NAN flow in the link
in the description. Number five, clone
yourself. I created a bespoke AI
chatbot. Her name is Arya. Well,
actually, she named herself. And I use
this for the customer service across all
of my companies. And even if you don't
have a business, I promise you, you can
go and train an AI agent on everything
you do. Whether you're in real estate,
education, parenting, hacks, you name
it, you can go and train that thing on
all the knowledge you know, and then go
and sell access to it. So, let me go and
show you how valuable this is for my
company, Founder OS. The cool thing is
that Arya, for most of our founders,
lives inside of our Founder OS Slack
community. So you can either be
interacting with the community in there,
you can be talking to my team inside of
our Slack, or you can just go and chat
directly with Arya and get answers in
seconds. It's kind of a one-stop shop to
get the answers you need in your pocket.
You know, our goal is to give founders
clarity. It's to give them the simple
systems to help them go and build their
businesses. And Arya is a key part of
our competitive edge. It's just like
having an AI coach that knows exactly
where you're at in your journey. And
Arya just isn't tier aware, knowing
where different customers are coming
from and the different tiers they're in
inside of founder OS. It's also
dissatisfaction score aware. So it knows
when people are really struggling with a
certain problem or a certain challenge
and it's going to go and know based on
our entire database of solutions what
way it should be directing people based
on what they're currently struggling
with. Most importantly, she scales
without me. You know, without Arya, I'd
be stuck in Slack answering the same old
questions day after day. But because of
this AI agent, I'm able to spend way
more of my time on higher leverage tasks
like hiring people, strategy, and
building exceptional content. You can do
the same in your business. Whether
you're a freelancer looking for a side
project, you know, you're looking to
scale a big business. You know, having
an AI agent that's trained on all of
your core documentation, systems, and
blueprints is a gamecher. Let me know in
the comments if you want me to do a deep
dive video on Arya. And if you want to
go and get your own access to Arya, you
should definitely go and check out
Founder OS via the link in the
description. You know, what we've done
here is build a custom agent that suits
our exact business needs. It has a full
extensive knowledge on everything I do
so that you get a polished version out
the gate and eliminate all the guesswork
in growing your productized business. If
you like this video and want more videos
on AI, be sure to check out this video,
which is a deep dive on how to create a
viral YouTube video with AI.