These are the five biggest ways you can
change your life in the next 30 days.
Number one, delete every app on your
phone that makes you feel like
Does Instagram make you feel poor?
Delete it. Does LinkedIn make you
compare yourself to others? Delete it.
Does X make you feel a little bit
depressed? Delete it. Number two, is
fire your worst client. You know that
client that's constantly bugging you,
not sticking to your guidelines around
your service or product? Well, it's time
to get rid of them. Number three, start
saying your price without flinching.
Most founders are underpricing their
product or service. Right now, you can
go and increase your profit by 30% by
simply just increasing your prices by
30% and charging what you're worth.
Number four, block two four-hour chunks
a week for deep work, the big
needle-moving tasks. And when you stack
this up over 52 weeks in a year, you'd
be amazed at what you can accomplish.
Number five, book something
irreversible. Change up your
environment. Go take that spontaneous
soul trip for 10 days to somewhere that
you've always wanted to go. It's these
moments that, when you stack them up,
will allow you to get the creative
juices that you're probably really
searching for to create the masterpiece
you deserve. Start with number one
today.