The easiest way to succeed in anything
is to find your unfair advantage. When
people ask me, "How did you learn
content?" Well, the truth is, I've
learned it over the last 16 years
[music]
building multiple brands and businesses.
At first, I was honestly pretty scared,
you know, putting my face out there with
something new, right? I'd hidden behind
brands for many, many years. Slowly but
surely, you know, my own style emerged,
right? This kind of systematized
founder. I want to build an amazingly
vibrant business, an amazing community
around it, and just enjoy my life. And I
feel like there were millions of
founders that felt like online they
resonated with that general message and
mission, and you know, they wanted to be
a part of it. And so, in some weird way,
you know, I was able to start connecting
the dots looking backwards and seeing
how all this experience that I had
gotten was almost the perfect ingredient
to put out the kind of content I was now
sharing with the world.