Everyone asks, "How did you actually
make money from content?" It wasn't ads,
it wasn't UGC, it wasn't brand deals, it
was alignment. Here's what you need to
do, right? Go and pay attention to the
people that are most engaged with what
you're putting out there. Look at the
DMs, the people with longer comments,
the people that are texting you after,
and start to ask them, you know, "What's
the piece of content that has most
resonated with you so far? And what's
your biggest challenge right now? And
what's the biggest thing I could help
you with?" This sort of feedback that
you get from those, you know, super fans
of you, that will give you a general
direction as to where you should go with
your content, and it will likely also
inform where you need to go with your
brand and your products.