I think we've been like in circles in a
branch and now you gave us the whole
tree.
>> If you're stuck at 50K and not sure how
to get your business to the next stage,
it's often times because you're not
surrounding yourself with the right
people and you don't have clarity on the
right system or framework to get through
to that next evolution of where you're
supposed to go. Leadership is the cap on
your success. Probably the main reason
that you guys are not at 250K. Wow. In
this video, I'm going to break down a
couple frameworks and help my friend
Manuela get to that next stage. It's
good to be here in Lisbon with you guys.
Why don't you guys just tell us a bit
about where you guys at the business
like and currently like main objectives?
>> We've been stuck at 80K per month for
the past
>> year. Year. Yeah. One year. We scaled
pretty fast from nothing to 80K and then
we plateaued. So we have the main course
that is helping people how to free their
time 60% of their time and build
systems. That's the main product and
it's 5K.
>> Who are you serving with that?
>> We we help architect founders today.
>> Okay.
>> So that's our niche today.
>> Okay. So you're stuck at 80K and how
many products do you have total?
>> Five.
>> Okay. So five products. Cool. And then
the goal, what's like the main objective
here? objective is getting a clear road
map to get road map sorry to get from
80k to 250k.
>> All right. A lot of founders have big
ambitions of getting to 250,000 a month,
500 grand or even more. But the key
thing is if you're looking to get to
that level, you need to have clarity
around the exact road map to get from
where you are today to where you're
looking to go. And often times some of
the most important things you need to
get right are counterintuitive. It's
sometimes changing or even doing the
opposite of what you think you should be
doing. That is what gets you through to
that next level of growth. So, in this
video, I'm going to give them two
frameworks that are going unlock that
next level of growth. Even if you're not
at 50K yet, or even if you've actually
scaled past that, you're going to find
these two frameworks enormously
beneficial to help you go and unlock
that next stage of growth. If you want
to go and apply these systems in your
business today, you can find the offer
stack pyramid via the link in the
description. Let's just do a bit of a
deep dive on like where we are now for a
second. One thing that would help is
kind of to basically just like look at
like an offer stack pyramid. So I'll
illustrate this and then we can fill it
in a bit. So the first logical place to
start here is with the offer stack
pyramid. Understanding what is that
entry-level offer that you have the core
offer and then that upsell from the core
offer. Often times within this current
framework there are a lot of lowhanging
fruit. Do you have your pricing right?
Do you have your people right? And are
the rhythms between each stage super
efficient and effective? On the left
side here, we'll put like now to
understand things like the pricing of
each of these. We'll get into also like
the close rate of each of these as well.
>> Our uh core offer, our entry offer is um
5K.
>> You have no $900 stuff.
>> Okay, cool. And then we have two uh like
upselles uhish that are 3K each.
>> Okay. And what are those?
>> Finances like to organize the finances
of the studio and client acquisition.
>> Okay. So you have an acquisition sort of
upsell.
>> Yeah.
>> Mhm. And it's like 40% of the people
that buy the core offer would buy
>> one of the two
>> one of finance or precision. So, what is
this $5,000 thing?
>> We help them to build systems and free
their time. It's 120 days,
>> four months. Yeah.
>> They have um like videos, they have a
CSM, they have like five calls,
oneonone,
>> continity partners, and they have
one-on- ones with them
>> and chat between us and them
>> and uh the group calls
>> and then what happens after 4 months?
>> 40% of them would buy finance or
acquisition. one of those and the other
60 are free in our community enjoying
the
>> the content they paid for. Yeah,
>> like the content we they keep watching
the content. They still have access to
the community to the challenges to
everything we do.
>> So, we've got this 5K sort of like
entry/core and then you got this 20k
inner circle.
>> Mhm. you're converting 20% of people
from your audience to the 5k thing and
then in the 5k you have 100 people in
there converting roughly 2% of them back
up to the 20k but it is new and the
business is currently doing 80k so the
percentage is like you're basically like
whatever 95% of your business is this
right now
>> yeah as I went and uncovered this for
Nacho and Manuela it was very obvious
that there were some key pieces missing
in certain areas it was super chaotic in
other areas I could only understand why
a customer would just be confused as to
where they should go. And so when this
is successful, it's simple. It's
logical. Honestly, it's not chaotic at
all. It should be seamless from one
person going from an entry- level offer
to a core to the inner circle. And so
what we're going to go is map out where
this has been and then where this needs
to go so that this next stage of growth
is virtually inevitable. Again the major
thing to do in this like call this like
the new approach is the actual
structure and like delivery of it right
you have 4 months there I think we can
leave that but we have to start
enforcing that and so you have 4 months
here
>> have a new new department enforcing
department
>> it just got to be the actual case and so
you currently have CSMS right
>> cool your CSMs are essentially in a
model like this, right? They're like
often times the backend setter. So, your
CSMs, right, are going to be setting
folks for what we call like backend
upsells. You have folks coming into the
5,000. They're being serviced. They're
getting systemized. They're, you know,
learning like the different aspects to
free up their time and get more of it
back over say 2 months, 3 months. The
key when you're thinking about upsells,
it's not just a success that you're
looking for. Like you're also looking
for like to upsell people when their
energy is highest. Say 2 months and 20
days someone's been in your program.
You've gone and saved them a bunch of
time and they're flying high and they're
like starting to ask like what goes on
after the 4 months here. that CSM is
probably going to go and sit down with
them, chart out a bit of a road map now,
then pass that on to a closer, and then
get them on a call with the closer to
then get them closed up into the
mastermind at that point.
>> Mhm.
>> If you want to go and apply these
systems in your business today, you can
find the offer stack pyramids via the
link in the description.
>> You bring a closer over to close that uh
upsell.
>> There's two ways to think about it. You
can either have CSM's closing or you can
have closers closing. I've tried a bunch
of different ways. I think just
typically say in a business like this,
you have CSMs that are really good at
like modeling out people's businesses
and helping them systemize it and are
really good at becoming like kind of
like friends with the founders and
building these like great relationships.
If you then have that person close them,
sometimes what I've seen as a pattern is
it just that's not what they do. They're
there to service the folks, but they're
not there to like then suddenly like put
on the hat of like I'm going to
objection handle you and convince you
that this is the move and all that.
Whereas a closer that's all they do,
right? They specialize in just like
getting on calls, doing discovery,
pitching people the thing, and then
working through the obstacles to then
get it across the line. And that's all
they do 8 hours a day, 5 days a week,
365 days a year kind of thing.
>> And how do you present that call to the
to your client?
>> What I would do is I would have the CSM.
They're monitoring someone's progress
obviously cuz they've been assigned
certain people that are in it. as you
start to approach 3 months, they're
aware like this person's coming up. We
need to make sure that people in the
program are being hit from multiple
directions and are aware that their time
is coming up and that there is this
other thing. So, a common mistake I see
from so many people is that they create
this super high ticket offer at the top
of the offer stack pyramid, but the
issue is is that within the actual
community they're building, no one even
knows that it exists. And what I call
that is an awareness problem. How do you
solve an awareness problem? Well, you
need to integrate the communication
around that super high ticket offer into
the lower rung of that offer. So, in the
core offer here, the onboarding, the
sales calls, the different pieces of the
community and the support they're
giving, they need to constantly be
mentioning that, hey, there is this
higher tier thing that we have. And in
there, we go so much deeper. You have so
much more proximity to us. And that's
where the real heavy hitters are. But
the issue here is that for their
business currently there's very little
awareness. And so we're going to get
into the details of to how to go and
bridge that gap so that people are going
and upselling at a much higher rate. So
step one is like awareness, right? Like
ideally when people are even being sold
into the core offer, they're aware that
it's almost like a holding pattern where
we're putting you in this for now
because you're not quite ready for this
thing yet, but over the course of the
next 4 months, we're going to get you
more of your time back, free it up, and
then get you ready for our real thing,
which is the inner circle. And that sort
of thing is being massaged constantly
while they're in this core offer. So
even on the weekly group sessions you
do, you're kind of maybe sharing like a
success story that someone had in inner
circle. So people are constantly like,
damn, I can't wait to get access to that
or get the invite to that. And it's just
this natural obvious progression that
someone's in when they're inside of this
community. To answer your question now
directly like how do you position it?
Well, the way I would consider it cuz
you say you do a lot of road maps
helping these architects get more of
their time back. The CSM could go and
understand, okay, what's your current
objectives? What are your current
challenges? have a good discussion and
make sure like that person's kind of
like fired up on basically like a
setting call, but what it is is just a
really good vibe call.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Say I'm the CSM, I'm with the
founder. I'm going to go and I'm going
to help them kind of chart out, okay,
you've been in this for 3 months. We've
been doing a great job. Look at all
these wins we've had. Now, as we look
out through the rest of 2025, moving
into 2026, what are the kind of real
things that you're looking to get after
with your brand and your business? I'm
understanding those. What are the
current challenges that you have there?
I understand those. I'm going to kind of
like talk to them about it, lend a few
insights, and I'm going to go listen,
I'm going to go take this back with
Manuela and Nou. We're going to go dive
into this a little bit. We're going to
go and build a bit of a custom road map
for you, and then I'm going to get you
on a call with Mike, who's the one that
originally got brought you into this.
You remember Mike? Yeah. Yeah, I
remember Mike. Mike was great. Cool.
Mike's going to get on a call. We're
going to go through the road map that
Andella, Nacho, and Mike all prepared,
and help you through this. And they're
like, "Oh, amazing." And so then you a
week later is this like the what is a
closing call but it could be framed as a
road map call and essentially at that
point it's okay you're bringing the road
map that the team has gone and worked on
and then bringing that forth to then run
them through it and say like hey this is
this awesome road map we've created.
>> Mhm.
>> This is like where we see things going
over the next year. you're jamming with
them around it, providing insight,
showing them that you can see around
corners because inevitably what people
are looking for is like your ability in
a space to be able to see further than
they can their own challenges. They can
only see the next two. I always think
about strategy kind of like Gary
Kasparov, the you know grandmaster chess
dude is like strategy to him was like
always being able to see 17 steps ahead.
And so if you can go and show people,
hey, you have this challenge and this
challenge, but you're not thinking about
this. And then when you do actually go
hire that team, you're going to deal
with this. And then when that team comes
on board and now they're looking for
raises, you need to make sure you have
this in place or whatever that road map
is for your given area. The big thing is
making sure that people that go through
these 100% of them need to be aware of
this and 100% of people that are in this
need to be aware of this. Automated
emails that go out to them. You're 2
months out. Let us know how you've exper
how your experience has been to so far.
You're 6 weeks out. just letting you
know that this is coming up. You're 4
weeks out, you're 2 weeks out, you're
one week out, you're about to expire in
2 days. Like they need to be aware that
like it's coming up. Maybe not with that
many, but you get it. Like they So
that's email. Then there's the group
sessions. They need to know about their
CSM if they're on separate calls or the
group calls need to be kind of talking
about this thing. Every 100% of people
need to be aware of that and you can hit
them from a couple different directions
when you just think about the things
that they're already on.
>> So here's the deal. When you're going
and building out a team in this kind of
business, the thing I like to think
about is making sure that my team is
always in the money and that there's
always a way for us to serve our
customer. One thing I'm big on with like
the teams I build, the products I build,
is especially for like sales, customer
success, and all the companies, it's
like I always want to keep people in the
money. So, what I mean by that is like
any single call you're on as a
salesperson, if that person can afford
something big, we sell them something
big. If they can afford the core, we're
going to sell them something core. If
they can't afford that, there's
something to downell them to. You're
never in this situation where it's like,
I don't have something for you.
>> Okay?
>> So that they're just always in the
money. And then what happens is it's
like, oh, you're with an architect and
they can't afford the 5K thing and like
you've like gone through like the
objection handling and all that. Well,
no worries. Like you have a $1,000 thing
that gets them in the door. Maybe they
get some of the materials. they get in
there and then, you know, like 2 months
later, hey, once they've gone through
it, I'm going to check in and see if
they're now ready to get ascended to the
$5,000 thing. But I'm not just letting
these like leads come in and like
letting say price, if they can't hit 5K,
be a blocker for getting them in the
door on anything.
>> Truth is that when you've solved a
customer's problem and you've given them
finally a solution to that thing, often
times that next stage of growth for your
customer has new problems. Because as we
all know, the journey of building a
business is basically just a journey of
problems. So as an example, if you help
someone go and hire an amazing chief of
staff, well, their next problem is how
do I onboard this person? And that sort
of rhythm just keeps on going. And your
job as a business owner is to see around
corners for your customer and to have
that leadership where you can already
see where they're going to be going. The
problems they're going to be
experiencing and then have offers
created around those next stages. What
I'm seeing here is these two upsells are
not working like upsells. They're like
add-ons way. You you even you didn't see
them as products at first. There's clear
clearly an issue there. But the other
thing is the core offer is so so
thorough that we're not leaving anything
else to for example like the the inner
circle. The only difference is going to
be like uh the contact with us. We were
focusing on that as being like like the
main commodity we were trading our like
time with them. Seeing this I think yeah
we we're focusing it like we're thinking
about it the wrong way. But my question
is, should we start taking things away
from the core offer into the inner
circle so that the core offer is not as
strong and the strong offer is the inner
circle. Am I getting that right? I'll be
real without knowing all of the details
there. It's hard to answer that as like
honestly and I think it deserves a level
of detail. So with these offers, right,
there's a few things to play with,
right? There's the education piece,
there's the CSM, there's the proximity
to you, and there's things like
experiences or events. As an example,
like typically in something like this,
you would limit in the core offer the
proximity to you guys. Is there
currently a lot of proximity to you?
>> No,
>> that's good. So part of it is like
really position this like you no longer
just have like a CSM like you're getting
access to like the real people, right?
So in this example, if I was doing this,
it maybe be like you don't get any
access to me. like you have to first get
into this pool and like get your stuff
systemized and then when it's at a good
state then you get access to Matt to
help you with higher level stuff and you
kind of position it like that. Hence
also why having like your own founder
brands like you're doing is so valuable
cuz then it's like people really want
access to you. It's like cool you got to
just get some of this stuff done
initially and then you get access to us
to help you. The second piece is like do
you guys have like events, experiences
any of that? It's okay if not I'm just
curious. We're going the first do the
first one in June on November.
>> In November.
>> Cool. So yeah, I would just make that
for these people. That's how I would
think about it. And I would start to use
the event to start attracting people to
pull the trigger on this. So if you only
have like two people in the event,
that's fine. Like you don't need to just
open it up as an add-on to these people.
That's a reason for these people to join
this thing. And don't have it as a
separate 2K cell. Have it as like that
is part of the deliverables of this. And
so we're going to use that like, hey, by
the way, the event's coming up. You get
all this in here. The event's on, you
know, October 15th. You don't want to
miss it. You know, let's use that to
like be a forcing function to get people
into this versus again a separate thing
where you have you're basically getting
people into here and you're kind of
paralyzing them with too many offers
versus just, hey, the only direction for
you is this way. and things like finance
acquisition and the event could all be
pulled into this. In this next bit, I go
over exactly how they should be thinking
about their offer evolution so that each
time they solve a problem for a given
customer, they're already ready to
present that next solution and make
money from it. And the idea of always
being in the money, the thing I I have
basically is like a waterfall of offers.
That's kind of what we're building right
now. Okay, so we've got this 20K. We're
gonna push people from this 5K into
this. But if someone's unwilling, they
don't want to be in the six month 20k.
>> We should have a downell for them off of
that, too. Okay. So, here what you may
do, some ways to think about it back and
is if someone's willing to spend $5,000
for 4 months, they'd probably also be
willing to spend, as an example, $15,000
for 12 months.
>> It's the same math. So what you could
say is listen why don't we as an example
you can't afford this for 6 months cool
we'll leave you in this then for like
another 6 months uh for say 10k as an
example we can always play with the
pricing but it's like a downell
that you can stay in the core until
you're ready we'll give you another say
6 months a 10k right to get your [\h__\h]
right and then after 6 months we're
going to get you into this but the key
thing right now right is what you're
doing is you're getting people into
this, you're just leaving them into
this. You're not getting them. There's
no reason for them to join this. Their
only options in this model are either
get into this or get into this. But
either way, you've basically either
quadrupled their lifetime value or
doubled their lifetime value.
>> And I've got a question in the in the
20k that is 6 month for example, if they
are willing to do it less because maybe
doing acquisition and finance at the
same time, it's a lot. I wouldn't do
that. Don't let them divide stuff. It's
not a it's not a alocart menu. It's an
it's this. The thing is too, you you
give them all this stuff, but inevitably
like they do what's right for them,
right? So, it's not like, oh, you have
to this is all in there and you don't
need finance. Cool. Then don't do it.
It's okay. Like we have it there in case
you need it or if a teammate wants
access to it, they can use it. They have
three options after these four months.
They either go away, right, and then
they're on their own, which like that's
not a good solution for them at all. The
next one is that they stay in it because
they're not ready for this or they move
into this. So that's it.
>> But there is no more like just staying
and chilling in here. When you're
building a business, I got some good
news for you and some bad news.
Inevitably, each stage of growth
ultimately comes down to you. The good
news is is that you control your ability
to get to that next stage. The bad news
is is that you probably need to look
yourself in the mirror and figure out
which aspects you need to fix. And on
the leadership side, what do you think
the main thing is there? being leaders
of 250k.
>> Yeah, I think I think we're lacking a
lot there. What you said is very true.
Like we are not currently 250k leaders.
We're not. But yeah, I think we need to
tighten the uh the way we're leading. I
think we're being way too too lenient,
way too relaxed.
>> Do you guys hang out with a lot of
people that are making 250,000 a month?
>> Yeah, that's a that's a good one as
well.
>> Yeah, I think that's a big thing, too.
Like on a personal level, like you guys
need to have more friends that are like
making that level of money a month
because you'll just learn from osmosis
through like a thousand little micro
interactions. What they do in their
spare time, how they approach things,
how they build a team, how they live
their lifestyle, who they fired, who
they hired. There's like a lot of just
like little things, right, that you pick
up on if you're just around these people
more often. Then you don't need to try
so hard about making, you know, becoming
this $250,000 a month leader. You kind
of just become it pretty quick cuz
you're just around people all the time.
So that would be one thing is I would
look at your circle. I mean the second
thing just to help you guys out is like
I do think it's like just stick to keep
it simple you need to get the close rate
from 20% to 30% of the core thing like
that is like a leadership thing and you
need to get your close rate of your
upsell from 2% to 20% plus and like
everyone needs to focus on that in this
case with Manuel and Nacho I think the
big thing is rigor the reality is is
that you need to start working like a
$250,000
founder you need to start having systems
like a $250,000 founder founder and you
need to start requiring out of your team
the 250k a month type founder stuff. So
what does that mean exactly? You need to
have clarity around the goals for your
team. You need to have the right meeting
structures in place. And you need to be
showing up with the right level of
leadership. And I learned this from John
C. Maxwell. Leadership is the cap on
your success. If you're a five out of 10
leader, you're probably only going to be
three out of 10 successful. On the other
side of things, if you're a 10 out of 10
leader, you're organized. You're planned
outright. You've got your systems there.
you know, you're going and motivating
people, you're prepared, you are going
to get a 9 out of 10 level of success.
And so, what does this mean? It likely
means if you're running a sales team, as
an example, you're focused on the
energy. You've got bonuses mapped out
for people. You've mapped out what the
subjects of each of those meetings are
going to be. You're keeping people
accountable and you're putting the right
people in the right seat and you're
firing people that are underperforming.
This is what it looks like to get to
that next stage. But if each call you're
showing up nonprepared, you don't have
the right people in place, and the
energy, the vibe is not there on your
sales team, well, yeah, that's exactly
why you're stuck. So, what I go and
outline is the mentality needed to be
that next level leader. Let's get into
it. And the main thing for you as a
sales manager, we talked about energy,
but the other thing is like you got to
be [\h__\h] prepared. This is not some
like game of like winging it and
winning. If you're doing this really
right, I almost think of it like you're
building a curriculum for a sales team,
right? So like you could map out and you
can use like chat GBT for this as well.
You could upload your entire offer and
all this stuff in your business model
and go map out I have three meetings a
week with my sales team. I want you to
go map out across like these different
categories. What are we going to cover
every single meeting for the next 4
months? And you don't necessarily need
to like follow that like a Bible, but at
least you have a curriculum you can
default to unless you have better ideas.
But the point is you're never not
prepared. And what happens too is while
entrepreneurs, we don't necessarily need
structure. We're good on the fly. The
team needs structure. And this team on a
sales side especially, they'll respect
structure. You know, this is where we're
going. This is what we're doing. This is
the offer. This is what we're doing
today. This is the thing. It's like,
okay, [\h__\h] things start to get tight
and disciplined versus it feeling kind
of like, oh, I didn't make that offer
because of this, and oh, I didn't know
if they right. No, no, no, no, none of
that. Right? the the tighter you are um
on the leadership side, I always say to
you guys like leadership is the cap on
your success. So yeah, probably the main
reason that you guys are not at 250K is
that you're not $250,000 leaders, right?
And so what leadership looks like at
this level in sales is like just a whole
new way of doing things. And you're
probably going into next week and people
can just feel like, okay, wo, there's a
new level of like rigor, a new approach
here. Yeah. the quality of your sales
meetings or the quality of your revenue.
Cuz if the team starts closing at 50%
and you start getting upsells at 30%,
you've won. You've you've moved way
beyond this metric. It's really that
simple. That's the main domino. And so
if everyone's just like maniacally
focused on how do we [\h__\h] get this
close rate ripping, get the upsell rate
going, get the offers cleaned up the way
like you're going to be fine. And it's
going to take a while. Like this may
take this may be like a year-long
journey of like really really cranking
this stuff, like really getting that
upsell rate ripping, right? really
getting the close rate going consistent
across all closer consistent. And that's
okay. It's really that simple though. We
bring complexity to these things, right?
Well, oh well, maybe this thing or maybe
we do this thing over there and it's
then you waver and then the team then
gets off track cuz they're not sure what
the focus is and that's where everything
just gets messy, right? You kind of want
to set these things and then just keep
hammering towards it. I think the
hardest part of all of this is now going
to be the focus required to actually
just go and do this. You know, too many
founders are guilty of shiny toy
syndrome. You know, sure enough, we map
everything out and they know the one
thing their company needs to focus on
and two weeks later they're all
scattered all over again. The real thing
that's necessary is not just the
systems, not just the people, not just
your leadership, but is discipline.
Discipline to just focus. Cut out the
97% of distractions that come up
dayto-day to go deep on the thing that's
actually going to go and move the needle
forward in your business. If you want to
be in the room and be just like these
founders, getting help, getting clarity,
and understanding the systems they need
to get to that next level, well, you
love Founder OS. This is exactly what we
do across our membership, support, and
access to me. And if you're interested,
you can go and apply via the link in the
description. Thanks for watching and
I'll see you in the next