Most founders don't have a leadership
problem. They have a sales problem.
People start going and creating all this
amazing content. They got their
marketing out there. They're creating
videos, but they can't go and convert
all that attention they're driving to
actual cash flows. [music] And what this
leads to is a circle of burnout. You're
running an amazing team, but you just
can't monetize it. And so, sure enough,
you end up finding yourself in [music]
founder prison, right? Running a
business that just isn't scaling and
that you're not enjoying. So, in this
video, I break down what it actually
takes to go and build a high-performance
sales team. This isn't tactics or random
hacks or stupid sales scripts. This is
the actual details of what I've learned
building sales teams over the last 20
years. The session you're about to watch
is from a founder retreat I was running
with 30 high growth founders in Bali,
Indonesia, showing them some core
systems that will help them go and scale
to the next level. These are founders
for the most part that are looking to
scale their businesses to $500,000 in
revenue a month with simple systems,
support, and [music] access to me. If
you're interested in being in the room
with me for the next one of these
sessions and joining Founder OS, you can
definitely go and check it out via the
link in the description. We'll get on a
call with you, learn what systems
currently keeping you stuck in your
business, and we'll let you know how we
can help. So, go and book that call.
Enjoy this session and much love. sales.
So, you know, we got to raise the energy
in here. You know, it's got to be like
Wolf of Wall Street.
[laughter]
Okay, let's first talk about when do you
even need a sales team? I think the most
simplistic way that I think about this
is that if you have a high ticket offer,
right, which I would say is an offer
above $2,000 and it's proven, you've
sold this thing yourself, when you sell
it yourself, you're doing above a 30%
close rate. And when you look at where
you're looking to scale it to, number
one, you don't want to be in sales for
the next two, three years of your life.
You're kind of getting tired of being on
these sales calls. And number two, you
have a proven offer and you're looking
to sell enough of it, you could afford
to bring on someone then to start
selling it for you. So you didn't have
to keep doing that thing. Now, the
assumption here too is that you have
enough capacity of what you're selling
and enough demand for it that someone
could in fact, you know, make a living
being a salesperson for you. But for
many of the people here, you know, you
do have a high ticket thing. You have
been selling quite a bit of it. It is
proven. You're looking to scale it more.
Um, and you want some help doing that.
Maybe the next step goes to then, well,
how the hell do you structure and pay a
sales team? Let's say, right? Cuz some
of you guys get curious on like
compensation and all that. There's a lot
of different compensation models, but
one that is common in the sort of high
ticket space for closers, the
compensation often times is between 7.5%
to 10%. We pay 10% at Founder OS, just
to be transparent. Often times you have
setters, which could be folks that are,
you know, DM setters and IGDMs setting
up those sales calls. They could be
folks that are inbound setters, so the
ones that, you know, when someone's
looking to book an initial call, see if
they're even right for your program.
someone's getting on a call with them
maybe and you have enough of demand that
you just have a setter first get on a
15-minute call, sus out if that person's
even in the pocket for what you're
doing. And then if they are in fact, you
know, in the right kind of buying
pocket, the right kind of persona, all
that sort of stuff, would then set them
on a call with a closer, which is more
in-depth. And what you're trying to do
there is block and tackle any people
that may not be in the pocket from just
wasting a closer time. So setters
typically make between say 3%
and 5% of cash collected. Just what I
mean by that on the cash collected side
is say you sold something that was
$40,000 and it was over fourmonth
payment plan. You know a closer or a
setter would make you know 10 or 5%
respectively each of the months of those
four months, right? They wouldn't make
it all upfront. So their percentage is
based on when the cash comes in. At
found we pay 5%. So, when you were
asking about some of those percentages
this morning on the finance side as to
the breakdown of like the different
departments, I had mentioned to you that
sales was around 18%. Because you got
your 15% here and then maybe roughly 3%
on like a sales management or sales ops
side as well. This is just how we choose
to do things, but you can structure
these things any way you want. The nice
thing about this is that there's no base
salary in terms of how we structure it.
like they win when we win versus they're
feeling like there's a massive base
going out, but sales are plummeting,
let's say, and then suddenly you have
this massive overhead that you got to
support. Your alignment is kind of
misaligned. You know, you're trying to
go and sell more and try to get the team
to hustle to like make [\h__\h] happen.
Meanwhile, they're kind of like just
chilling cuz they're on like a fat-based
salary and they're not very motivated.
The good news is that in the high ticket
space, this is a common comp model. The
more demand you have for your offer, the
more proven it is and the better the
commission, the higher level people you
can get to come work for you. So, who do
you want to come work for you? You know,
we talked this morning about really
getting folks that align with your
values, right? So, that all remains
true. I talked about also people that
have great competencies on the sales
side and a proven track record. I think
proven track record is probably the most
important like in terms of like, you
know, yes, people that fit your values,
but also, you know, they've done this
[\h__\h] before at a high level. The two
things that I think are like the signs
you're looking for in people that is
true no matter, you know, what you do is
number one that they're coachable. The
reality is like you've been running your
offer for some time. You know all the
depth of it. Someone coming in isn't
going to know all the intricacies of
teaching people English in the French
market or teaching founders operating
systems and how to run their business
less chaotically. So, they're going to
have to be a student of the game and be
willing to really learn a lot about the
offer, watch a lot of successful sales
calls, learn about the different kinds
of objections that come up, and really
be hungry to go and solve that stuff.
Which leads to the second part of it too
is they need to be hungry as hell. You
need people that are driven. You know,
all of us know how like much it sucks to
be rejected in life. And no one gets
rejected more than sales folks. They
basically wake up and take like five
rejections a day. That's what they eat,
sleep, breathe is just people saying,
"No, not now." and they've got to be
hungry enough, have that kind of like
internal fire to just want to keep on
kind of showing up, learning, serving,
helping folks, being a student of the
game. And you want them to have that
kind of like internal engine because
what I've learned is like you can't
really teach that. All things
considered, those two things are the
most important. Coachability and hunger.
All right, let's get into now the kind
of core three that are super important
when you're managing a sales team. When
you're going and hiring salespeople,
typically what I'd recommend you do is
hire two people to get going with.
Number one, it causes them both to
compete against one another. What it
allows too is like if someone's raising
some excuse like, "Oh, you know, I'm
selling this thing, but like the price
is too high." First off, you should know
that the price is not too high because
you've sold the thing before. So, you
can tell them, "No, that's not true. Go
and watch the 20 calls I've done where
I've sold the thing at this price."
That's not the issue. Let's go and
review your calls. The second thing is
you're going to have another person
selling the offer. They're going to be
closing deals. it kind of polices things
a little bit, right? Because you have
two folks getting out there. If both
people are running into some sort of
obstacle, maybe it's real. But if it's
just one person, it may just be some
sort of like limiting belief or some
sort of coachable thing that you can
improve in that person. So, three things
to consider, the stuff that I don't
think most people think about, but you
need to have this in place when you're
running a sales team. Number one, at
least three times a week, meetings.
We'll get into how to run those. Two is
projections. every single week on
Monday, closers and setters on the
meeting setting their projections for
the week. Closers saying how much cash
collected they're going to get that
week. Setters saying how many closed
sets or sorry, how many sets they're
going to get that week. The third thing
here is end of day and end of week
reports. There's a lot more, you know,
that goes into like the intricacies of
this stuff, but these three things make
up 80% of what's going to help the team
start to get its rhythm. So, three times
a week meetings. All right. So, we got
Monday, Wednesday, Friday. The big thing
with a sales team, right, is you've got
to have good leadership. There's a lot
of different teams and dynamics across a
company. What I've learned across sales
is like sales people can smell weak
leadership. They need to feel confident
that like you know the offer, you
believe in it, right? You're confident
that like you can sell this thing. So,
sometimes we, you know, get hit with
different imposttor syndrome or we don't
feel confident in ourselves as a
founder. These things come up. You got
to kind of show a level of confidence
with these people because they're
essentially going to war for you like
kind of every day getting on like seven
calls, seven hours of just tons of
different energies of people and such,
right? That they need to feel a level of
sturdiness with you as a leader to then
be able to go out there and all these
conversations and feel solid. Also
considering that 100% of their
compensation is commission based, you
know, you got to make these people feel
confident that like the founder doesn't
feel confident in what's going on or
doesn't seem like they know what they're
doing. How the hell am I going to go
and, you know, look my wife in the eye
at the end of the day and say, "Yeah,
you know, I'm going to sell this thing."
And I know there's no money guaranteed
here, but we're going to be just fine.
You got to really like help these guys
out. Help the people out on your team
feel that confidence, that leadership.
So, this Monday, Wednesday, Friday
meeting rhythm really matters. Now, in
terms of how you're running those, the
default is the stuff I went over with
you this morning, right? Starting with
wins. Then, we're going to get into
ideally some training. You should be
thinking through the kinds of things
they need to be trained on, which could
be things like your offer. It could be
new updates that you're putting out to
the community. You could even play them
some recent wins that have happened
amongst people just to give them
confidence that like what they're out
there selling is like something that's
like actually working for people.
Examples of this is like, you know,
inside Founder OS in our Slack
community, we have a client wins channel
where we're constantly sharing like all
the wins that are happening every day
across all the communities and it's
inspiring them and they know that like
anytime they get out there, they're on a
call. It's like they know what we're
doing at Founder Us is legit and that if
someone's a good fit, like you can feel
confident you're selling them into
something that's like amazing. Another
thing that you do on these calls often
times are call reviews. You can ask
different closers like, "Hey, let me see
a call that you want some coaching on.
Could be one that you did really well on
that we want to make an example of or
one that you think you could have done
better on and you want some coaching
on." Pull up the Zoom, share the sound
with everyone, and everyone's basically
watching game film together as if you're
a bunch of NFL players learning what you
did wrong on the field. So, we'll
sidetrack there for a sec. little side
quest. There are three parts to a sales
call. Number one, the discovery. That's
20 minutes back and napkin. Number two,
the pitch. That's 20 minutes back and
napkin. And the third part is objection
handling, which is the final 20 minutes
of a sales call. When you're booking
sales calls, don't book 30 minute sales
calls. Make sure you all lot 1 hour. One
hour is what's needed to at least ensure
that you have the time on the calendar
if needed to properly like both
understand the prospect and what's going
on. Understanding context there so you
can even determine if what you do and
what you offer is even right for this
human. The second aspect then is like
giving yourself time to go over likely
kind of the three main parts of your
offer. Simply breaking it down into we
do this, this, and this. and having the
space to kind of describe those three,
but pause after each one and ask them
like, "Does that make sense? Do you have
any questions on that?" So like in
Founder OS, we have 180 simple systems
all the way from helping you drive
awareness on social to helping you
convert that awareness into an owned
audience using your content GPS to
driving it to your own offer. Doesn't
matter the industry you're in. I'll
pause for a second. Do you have any
questions on that? You know, anything we
can dive into there? Cool. All right.
The next aspect is we hope this these
epic founder retreats all over the
world. three days with me, my seuite,
jamming on your business in a customized
setting, yada yada yada. Any questions
on that? You know, can I clear anything
up? They may have questions on those.
You're kind of clearing them up as you
pitch it. In the final 20 minutes,
you've probably dropped at this point,
saying, "Hey, is there any final
questions here?" They're like, "No,
pretty sure that's it." You want to make
sure you flushed all the questions out
around the offer, around anything that's
come up throughout the whole 39 minutes
of the call up to this point. And then
just simply say, "Okay, cool. Well, how
this typically works, it's 29K, annual
membership, however your thing works,
and then just be quiet after one or two
sentences, and then see what comes up.
That's where there's typically four
kinds of objections to things. Pricing
objections, timing objections, spouse
objections, or partner objections,
meaning business partner objections.
Your closers will feel those based on
the training that you've given them.
You're giving them time, too, in those
final 20 minutes to work through that
stuff. Why we call these people closers,
I mean, typically is like my thinking on
that and what I've heard is that closing
begins when objections begin. And you
should assume that whenever you're
selling someone anything, there are
going to be objections. It's just
natural, right? People have questions or
they're curious or is this really for me
or who else have you worked with or have
you worked with my industry before or
I'm not sure like, you know, I'm going
to wait a few months. I'm not sure if
the right the timing right now is right
for me. And these are all common things
that come up no matter what humans are
buying. And it's not that we need to
pressure them into buying now. And I'm
not encouraging us to use some like
crazy sales tactics or sell our soul
here. It's not about that. But it is
about like you've created something.
There's probably someone that's maybe
been following you on social media for
like 8 months at this point. They're on
a call. They've learned it's really
right for them and they're and they're
curious to get started and they may just
need some like almost coaching there a
little bit to help them think through
it, you know, make the decision that's
right for them. So amidst that whole
60inute sequence that we just talked
about, there's a lot of aspects in there
that can go wrong or that people need
help with or they're not sure about and
the devil's in the details because you
essentially have a team of people that
are just going through that process 30
times a week per closer 90 times across
the team if you have three of them 360
times a month. If that dance that goes
on every month 360 times or in a year
4,500 times, like you want to make sure
that dance is done in a way that's
pleasant that you know the most
rewarding thing I see when I feel like
this is done right is that I'll get
messages from folks on Instagram as an
example or get bubbled up in the client
wins channel and it's from someone
that's like, "Hey, listen. Found isn't
right for me right now, but I just want
to say I was on a call with Ben. That
was the best call I've had all month.
That guy's a legend. Thanks for setting
me up on that call." I'm like, like
that's what we want to hear. They didn't
feel pressured. They didn't feel any
weirdness. They're like, "No, this was
awesome. Like, I got on this call. I
learned more. It ain't right, but like
your team's legit." And we get those
kind of messages all the time because of
the level of talent that we bring on the
team and the level of training that we
do, the people that are on boarded in
terms of like how we approach sales,
which isn't the same way that everyone
else does. It's the kind of sales that's
in line with our values. We keep it
simple. We obsess over quality. We
dazzle founders. It should have a soul
to it and we want to make sure that the
level of hospitality that we're showing
people is unreasonable, right? Going
above and beyond just to serve them,
help them out whether or not they work
with us. So that's kind of our approach.
All right, projections. On the
projection side, the core thing here,
it's super simple. Closers are simply
setting probably a cash collected goal
per week and setters are setting the
number of sets they're doing in a week.
The reason why this is important is that
you're basically on Mondays getting
folks to kind of like shoot their shot,
developing a degree of like public
accountability across the team, right?
It just creates a level of like I don't
know, running it more like a sports
team, right? Than just like another day
at the office. What happens over time
too is like you have like multiple
closers like one guy's projecting like
20K, let's just say for the week, right?
the other guy maybe he says 20k too or
maybe one guy was thinking 15 but then
the other guy says 20 and the other
guy's like oh all right [\h__\h] it I'll
match it just starts to create this like
again this camaraderie on the team and
again there's a level of accountability
because each week then we're looking on
the next Monday okay how did you do last
week and we're kind of like rapidly
measuring performance when I was younger
the feedback loops I would have in my
companies was like once a quarter review
what someone had said oh you know I'm
going to you know on social media we're
going to grow this much by the end of
the quarter the end of Q1 comes around
it's April But one, it's like, damn, we
didn't even grow near that. You have a
conversation with them and then you wait
how they do three more months. And the
issue is like the feedback loops there
are way too long. When you kind of
shorten the cycle of things, that's how
you start to tighten up the growth in
your company. So similarly here, I'm not
having one sales meeting a week. I'm
having three a week. I'm not asking for
projections over a month. I'm asking it
for a week. So everything we're doing is
shortening the cycles. And the same
pattern goes again for every department
in your company. If you're ever looking
to go and make something run faster,
shorten the cycles. So, as an example,
if I start to find there's a tech
bottleneck in the company, I may just go
for a month and increase the tech
meetings to three per week and asking
the tech team like, "What are you
committing to today that you'll have
done by Wednesday? Wednesday for
Friday." So, we're just shortening the
cycles and keeping things way more
tightly accountable. End of day and end
of week reports are simply just a
summary of like what were the calls that
you were on today, what came up, and
what were the next steps? and going and
sending that in Slack as an end of day
report, keeping them accountable. It
also informs the rest of the team as to
like where people are coming from, what
were their challenges. The rest of the
team can look at these reports and as a
sales manager, you should be looking at
these reports to kind of understand like
what are the patterns that are coming
up. Are a lot of people running into
timing objections? Okay, cool. Maybe we
should train the team on that. Are a lot
of my leads coming from YouTube? Okay,
[\h__\h] Something's going on on YouTube
here. People really resonated with that
content we put out 2 weeks ago. I should
maybe go and make more videos like that.
Which leads me to just one quick pattern
there too that I look at because
obviously I'm involved in the sales
team, but I primarily see myself as like
the marketer behind the company. That's
at least like my own approach is that
I'm constantly looking for signals that
are coming from sales to inform what I'm
going to go create and how my
performance is on the marketing side.
Cuz my goal is to try and persuade
people that by the time they're on sales
calls, they're already ready to join.
I'm constantly trying to understand from
the sales team what's working. What are
people saying when they're coming to
you? What were they watching beforehand?
Are you seeing any patterns here? And
then using that as a flywheel that I put
back into the content strategy. End of
week reports isn't all that different.
You're basically just getting people to
report on, okay, they projected a
certain amount by end of week. Did they
hit it? And if they didn't, why not? And
what are they going to do next week to
get back on track if they're off track?
Whether it's you guys selling or you
have a team selling, but I'll talk about
it as a team because that's how I look
at it these days. Is okay, these people
are trying to make a living, right? and
them making a living is really important
to me. The one piece when I think about
selling something on the kind of cohort
evergreen vibe, right, is like if I was
managing a team, I want anytime
someone's on a call, like and I'm
talking from my team standpoint, I want
them to be able to make money period.
And I want them to like be in the money
9 hours a day cuz that's what I would
want in their shoes. I would want to
know that like I'm getting on a call and
every call that I'm on, I have a damn
good chance at like making a living for
my family. And like with everything,
I'll just remind us like this is just
what we do. Some of this you're like,
"Oh, that's a good idea. I like that."
Other parts of it you're like, "Gh, I
hate that." It's like, "Good."
Everyone's got their own approach,
right? I think that what's useful here
is like to show you a little bit behind
the curtain like the general thinking
and then you can like steal stuff or
adapt stuff or throw out stuff based on
what you want to do cuz this certainly
is a blend of that too, right? I've just
seen different things I like that I
resonate with. I've taken little pieces
and along the way said no to like 90% of
what I've seen out there as well. I'd
say the only thing with a lot of this
stuff that's true is that it's going to
keep changing and adapting over time and
that all this stuff is iterative.
Doesn't really matter how you like end
up running your sales team, you're going
to start like listening to feedback from
them and like evolving it. That's good
for us for a few reasons. We go really
big with content. Like we go really big
like I talked to you this morning around
our margins with content. So, I want to
know like as I'm outlaying this content
and we're going bigger with marketing
and I'd like to keep on going bigger and
bigger, starting a second YouTube
channel, doing more cinematic [\h__\h] like
just going big with it, right? I want to
know that like we're collecting off that
at a good rate so I can feel confident
continuing to go bigger on the marketing
end cuz that's just what we want to do.
I think that because we're doing all
this amazing marketing and we're so
generous on that side, if someone's on a
call with us, like by default, they know
what the hell we do. And I think they're
showing up pretty warm to that call. Cuz
I think that the default emotional state
someone's in off of organic content is
curious. Whereas the default emotional
state that someone's in off of ads is
skeptical. So if someone's curious and
then you build confidence, they convert
in a way that is going to have a higher
propensity to pay more upfront. where
someone's skeptical and you get them
over the fence, they're going to say,
"Hey, I'm willing to dip my toe in the
water and you better be legit, but I'll
pay you over 6 months." It's going to be
likely a little bit different, but
through proper training and through
proper content and nurturing and like
proper pre-all sort of content as well,
pre-all videos, pre-all emails, all
that, you know, you can get someone even
from cold ads to like move up that trust
ladder. And through proper training, the
calls can also build people's trust as
well. Put this through your own filter,
obviously, right? This is just our quick
crash course on this, right? We're
talking about managing sales teams and
all this, so I'm kind of giving you just
the nuts and bolts of it. What we
haven't talked a ton about here is again
that vibe and the energy, which I'd
actually say is like again another 50%
of the equation. You know, we're
constantly kind of like talking on the
team about like how do we be of service
to these people? How do we go above and
beyond? Some recent things I've seen
that I've been really proud of our sales
team for is every single guy on my sales
team now has gone and brought on a VA on
their own dime. I've never been on a
team that people have done that before.
So, they're basically taking this like
10% that I'm giving them, giving a
person underneath them a cut and then
using that person to then go and own
their personal WhatsApp and making sure
that any person that's been on a call
then is being followed up with in
WhatsApp. Relationships are being built.
they're helping them out. Sometimes
those processes go on for 3, four months
and then suddenly now someone's in. And
I think we generate around 50 up to 50%
of cash collected in a month from
follow-ups, which is pretty insane. One
thing that I think we always want to
index very high on that I've only more
recently deter, you know, figured out
that it was rare that I thought was
common place is caring. And I think
everyone here has that as well. I think
that's kind of why we all, you know,
gravitate to one another, right? is that
we like generally care about stuff
beyond just this [\h__\h] that we've been
talking about. You know, it's also just
like we want to build a great thing. We
want to enjoy our lives. We want to
actually genuinely serve people. We want
to show up in a way that's like really
beautiful. You know, I often times talk
to my team about like it's almost like
we want to make people feel like they're
coming to like this luxury hotel.
Welcome to my Zoom call. Like it's great
to have you here. How's your day going?
What's been going on with you? You know,
I've seen calls like when we've looked
at them afterwards just picking a random
one like one of my closers and the, you
know, the founder are like crying. It's
like, well, what the hell happened here?
[laughter]
It's like, oh, there's just some
emotional stuff came up and it they
broke up and then the the closer started
sharing. It's like, what the heck is
going on? And it's just this vibe of
like, okay, wow, like we're really just
indexing high on caring, right? And I
think like, you know, we live in this
like trust route. Something like 70% of
Americans don't trust their neighbors.
And so if you can just like pour your
heart into it, foster a team where like
everyone just [\h__\h] cares, um I think
then inevitably people can feel that
level of like care, that emotional
resonance on a given call. And I think
it is possible to build a sales team
like that despite what you've seen out
there, despite like what people teach
you and all that. I think beyond like
closing tactics or really anything that
we've talked about here, if you can find
people that really really care, they're
really like hungry to help others,
hungry to help you as a founder, they're
coachable, they're willing to learn so
that they can show up in amazing way to
serve people, and then day in day out,
they're just trying to get 10% better,
which in 100 days is 13,800 times
better. Like, you're then going to start
building something really special. So,
we'll leave things there. Thanks, guys.
Appreciate you.