If I watched 10 hours of your content,
would I know your quirks, things you're
being challenged with, the things that
you love, your real passions?
You know, I think it's so easy
for folks to get caught up in things
like your content categories, your brand
pillars, and really nailing all your
positioning. And well, sure, these
things can be important. You know, we
all want our brand to be tight.
Inevitably, people just want to get to
know the real you. You know, content is
really just about scaling relationships.
In the same way, when you meet up with a
friend,
you don't want that friend to be
scripted. You want them just to be real
with you.
Well, the same thing goes
with you and your content and the
audience you're building online.
I know when I first got going on
YouTube, I was petrified. What are
people going to think? Am I going to
nail this? Do I really even know what
I'm doing?
And for a bit there, I defaulted to
teleprompting all my stuff, loading up
the perfect words, nailing it word by
word,
because
you know, I wanted to make sure that
everything was just perfect. But what I
lost in the process was just the
humanness, the realness, right? The just
showing up and
you know, making mistakes,
talking off script, you know, being a
little quirky.
And what I learned over time was that
that's why people were really showing
up, not because of some content
categories and perfection, but they
wanted to understand who I really was,
you know, how do I think? How do I
build? What do I hate? What do I love?
So, embrace that imperfection.
Japanese call this wabi-sabi, right? The
beauty in your imperfection. I think
it's what authenticity is really all
about.