When we look at our businesses, right,
often times they really are a reflection
of our nervous systems as a founder. And
I know that if I get caught up too much
in that intense side of things,
what ends up happening is candidly I'm
just an I'm short-fused. My
intensity can turn into a like kind of
overly abrupt and blunt and you know, a
lack of listening and someone that can
be just too aggressive and just hard to
be around. What you end up finding is
yeah, maybe you're moving a lot of
things forwards, um but you're also kind
of moving some things two steps
backwards. You know, with Founder OS, we
are, you know, really pushing the needle
with everything that we're doing. I view
business kind of like a video game and
the video game that we're playing is
trying to build the greatest founder
infrastructure in the world. I want to
allow founders to go build a plugin to
the infrastructure that we've built and
be able to build out world-class
distribution and media companies for
them. AI is going to replace a lot of
things that over the next bit, but I
think the final frontier of it will not
replace is your ability to build your
own distribution, your own media and
control your destiny. I think there's
this amazing window in this kind of
category that we've been leading and I'm
really obsessed, if I'm being honest,
around being
at the forefront of that category.
Really inventing that category, right?
This kind of founder infrastructure
layer.