All right, y'all. How we doing? How we
doing? Whole squad in here. I got a bit
of stuff to go through and then we're
going to keep things grinding. Let's get
into a couple things. What Apple did for
creatives in the '7s, Nike did for
athletes in the8s is what we're doing
for founders in the 20s. Okay.
>> I felt like if we had this in like a
boardroom, we'd be [\h__\h] banging on
the table. You know, Wolf of Wall Street
jumping on the table getting ready to
go.
>> Don't be surprised how quickly the
universe moves once you've decided that
you want better for yourself. every time
I review your guys' calls. So, you know,
why do you want to why do you want to
work with Matt? And everybody's just
like the vibe and the energy.
>> We're at the cusp of something [\h__\h]
massive here.
We will be way more [\h__\h] successful
than we have ever imagined. When
founders are [\h__\h] really really happy
and customers are really stoked the [\h__\h]
up, I can go and [\h__\h] hike mountains
and make [\h__\h] exceptional content and
we can all just have a lot of [\h__\h]
fun around here. And that's a [\h__\h]
truth, baby. Let's keep it going.
>> We're trying to build something for the
next 100 years, guys. And that's how
we're going to go and impact 100 million
people. We will hit our wildest goals.
We inspire other people that are like,
"Fuck, whatever that is, I want that."
All right, y'all. How we doing? How we
doing? Whole squad in here. Do we have
the Bali boys up in this [\h__\h]
>> Yeah, good. Just settling in. Had an
inperson conversation. He's going to
come in 7,800. Um, but I think there's a
chance he's going to come in 29K if we
can do something special for him. I
basically stopped him from going from
these other AI agencies. Sat down with
him. He paid for my meal and just for a
connection here in Bali. So there we are
doing inerson closing.
>> Can't tell what's better, him
paying7,800 or paying for your $3 meal.
Man, that's
enough.
>> I'm feeling pretty good. I got together
with uh Ben and Dan. They took their
time, you know, run me through
everything and just gave me some good
pointers and stuff. So, thank you boys
for uh giving me some good advice.
>> I'm I'm just going to say you better
open up some calendars for us because
Ross is on his like daily grind of just
[\h__\h] killing it. So, Arbor really
motivated me yesterday. I was not
feeling well and he actually reminded me
my name meaning Hamza means strong lion.
So, he helped me with that. He was like,
you know, you can do it this and that.
And it reminded me, oh, you know, I have
to get back and I got the results. So,
yeah,
>> just living the found lifestyle. Came
down to the beach in the south of
England. Got a couple of follow-ups
later today and yeah, excited to close
deals.
>> Past couple of months have been sort of
all work, no play. Makes Jack a very
dull man. You know, just getting back
into the calisthenics inspired by Hamza,
meditating/ praying quite a lot more.
And the dedication outside of that has
what's been able to bring the excellence
as far as consistency here in business.
Let's get into a couple things. I'll
keep this like pretty short and sweet.
Probably 15 minutes long max. Let's get
into this thing. As we all know, right,
one of the I've been doing a lot of
thought into like the dream client of
Founder OS, okay? And I would
characterize them as this intentional
founder, okay? The kind of person like
we were talking about the other day who
wants like freedom, wants to build a
team, understands that their time is
their ultimate currency. They want
adventure, travel, have meaningful
experiences. You know what we are all
about in one word is freedom. Okay? And
we're creating this aspirational brand
almost like what you know Apple did for
creatives in the 70s, Nike did for
athletes in the 80s is what we're doing
for founders in the 20s. Okay. And so
our mission right is to really transform
these founders into legendary brands
through simple systems. Okay. As we all
know, we're kind of pioneering this
movement towards founder
brands, right? FLB. Okay. And
founder-ledd brands are like one part
creator, one part founder. Our purpose
then as a team, okay? It's really
architecting freedom to end founder
prison and help the world's most
ambitious founders. We're not just
talking about growing founder brands to
get a bunch of followers or views and
engagement. And yes, while we can
definitely do that, we're after
something much larger than that. We're
also trying to help these people
monetize what they're building. and
further than that even helping them
actually be able to live like vibrant
amazing lives because they have systems
that allow them to gradually remove
themselves from operations and focus on
the more important things. And so that
leads us to our big promise. Okay, our
big promise as a team is to dazzle
founders through simple systems,
extraordinary support, which is like all
the founder success stuff we do, the 50
plus live sessions we have a month, the
access to our seuite, the founder
retreats, the AI agent and so much more
that we have on the way where founders
can get a real sense of belonging in our
community and then obviously help them
scale things like their brand, their
content, their team, their revenue,
right? Because again, this isn't about
just scaling systems, right? It's about
helping these people live very vibrant,
full, amazing lives, which inevitably I
think when we talk about say the DMs as
an example and say the Instagram
audience, I'm in there all the time. I'm
seeing what people are saying. I see
messages daily around things like, "Oh,
I'm just trying to do what you're doing
in this or I'm just trying to live that
life but in this kind of thing." So,
we're very much like living this. We're
sharing this. We are being this
exemplary role model team around this
way of being and living and operating.
And as we become our fullest selves
individually and as a squad and as a
brand, we inspire other people that are
like, "Fuck, whatever that is, I want
that." That's very rare in our space.
Not all of them, but I'm just saying
like you being here like just kind of
reinforces just going through this. it's
like the energy comes up and so it's so
integral to like that kind of like
everyone being on the same page. So I
just wanted to recognize that. Um and
yeah, hopefully you can be I guess more
present on future coaching calls.
>> Yeah, my promise is that I will be
present on these and I'm not going
anywhere. And also, if I'm not on these,
it's because I'm probably going deep as
[\h__\h] on some exceptional content
creation because I think the biggest
favor I could do to the sales team in
that moment is just jack up the
marketing. You guys can see the
marketing that's going on, right? So,
you can you certainly know things are
happening. It's not like we're chilling.
Just give you guys that context in a
good way. But yeah, I'm not going
anywhere. And I enjoy running these,
especially over the last while. I think
over the last 3 months, we've
collectively found our energy and vibe
as a team. And I don't see these as like
sales meetings as much as I do kind of
more of like a leadership meeting where
we're all holding each other to like a
high standard of leadership together. I
enjoy these a lot and I'm yeah not going
anywhere.
First off, the definition of our
critical function is the one activity
that makes our big promise a reality. So
again, our big promise is to dazzle
founders with amazing systems, support,
and the community. So question for you
guys, few of you guys can try your best
to answer this. The formula is this.
Okay, the critical function helps us
execute on our big promise. It is the
important thing that when we get that
one thing right, we achieve our big
promise of dazzling founders with
systems, community um and support. What
do you think the critical function is of
this business? Daniel, why don't you
give it a shot?
>> Mr. Dazzle founders critical function.
So just operating at that level with
every single like minor detail we we
focus on just having that standard of
going above and beyond.
>> What about Kevin? What's your guess
>> along the lines of what Dan said, but
just I guess you know striving for
excellence and you know always having
the founders best interest at heart and
really just um being there to provide
for all their needs and just really
executing on that. I guess
>> great answer Ben. the uh one activity
providing the knowledge and
accountability
for founders to have the confidence to
execute on making [\h__\h] happen.
>> So all those are awesome answers and
they're all actually super true. When I
zoom out in my like my role I guess on
like the overall company and if I was to
pick the one activity that we do that
supports our critical function it all
comes down to exceptional content
creation. exceptional content creation
on one side feeds things like DMs and
inbound calls for Ross Hamza Abdul
everyone right I'm arbor everyone then
from there inbound calls DMs all that
feed sales which feed cash flows which
feed our ability then to reinvest into
more content and it creates this
flywheel content sets cash content sets
cash and the audience just rips you know
say on the founder success side they
create amazing content in the form of
amazing office hours looms to founders,
exceptional reviews on sites like
Trustpilot. More founders are convinced
when they're inside of Found that our
delivery is exceptional. They tell their
friends about Founder OS. Those friends
get on calls. More people join Founder
OS. We invest more in delivery. We get
more, you know, positive testimonials,
more positive community developments,
more people tell their friends, and that
flywheel just rips. Lastly, as an
example, the exceptional content
creation around things like founder
retreats. We run amazing content at the
events. The events go well. People leave
great testimonials. They tell their
friends. More people go and apply to
Founder OS. They get on calls. We close
those people. More people come to
events. And that flywheel rips.
>> From a front-end perspective. I had a
conversation today and it's almost like
the power of marketing. Like if people
aren't in our world and they just come
across us, the guy was recommended from
a student, it's so much more powerful.
Like even though you I can clearly
diagnose his problems and what needs to
change, it's just like he's not going to
be putting himself out there and so I
put him back to the content and get him
in he's going to subscribe to the
newsletter and nurture him that way. The
guys that are coming in so important
that they are actually in our world
already cuz I think that a big part of
that is just everything that you're
putting out there and them really being
reinforced that messaging over weeks and
months. So that's just uh something that
I picked up on. Definitely having people
in our universe and when in doubt you
get on a call with someone and there's
going to be a follow-up a week later,
you know, send them a relevant YouTube
video or two, right, that feels curated
for them to kind of get them just in
that zone, in that mental space and are
like quadrupling down on YouTube in all
the ways. So there's a lot of good
bangers there that kind of keep people
in the frame.
>> Nice.
>> So in a sense, right, like when you even
just think about us at a higher level,
what is our core mechanism at Founder
OS? a content GPS. This mechanism that
I've built over the last 15 years,
right? Building multiple profitable
companies, helped me grow an audience
around Urba, 14 million, grow an
audience of two two and a bit million
around my personal brand. And it's
helped me grow all of this without
spending a dime on ads. And so people
know us as just like, damn, I want to
create amazing audiences off of organic
content, build my own founder brand.
Founder OS is the place. And so it's
this exceptional content creation. One
thing I want to cover too that
everything in life is a curve. And so
when you think about the customer
journey, it's not linear, okay? It's a
curve. So when someone goes and watches
a YouTube video, the next step is they
probably get on maybe a set call with
Ross or they're in the DMs with Arbor,
with Hamza. Then from there, they're on
a call with one of the closers here,
Ben, Daniel, Kevin. The question is when
they're going through that process, that
content process, right, does it go and
curve upwards or downwards? Our whole
bet and why we exist is because some of
the reasons you guys just said, right,
where every decision, every call we're
on, we're actually elevating the brand,
elevating the vibe. Someone may have
watched two YouTube videos of 24 minutes
total before getting on a call with Ben.
Ben's sales call is an hour long, which
is twice as much content as they had
previously watched getting into that
call. You guys are as important, if not
more important to exceptional content
creation than anything on the content
side because those calls are content,
right? The experiential side of our
content. You've gone and seen a YouTube
video. You've seen an X thread. Now
you're on a call with the actual team
behind this whole thing. Do they exceed
your expectations where you see it
you're on this like exponential curve to
greatness or does it let you down and
you're like, "Oh, the stake is
definitely less than the sizzle and this
just ain't actually that legit."
Exceptional content creation, guys. It's
not just YouTube. It's not just social
media. It is our sales calls. It is the
email follow-ups you send. It is you
delivering on a promise that when you're
on a call, hey, I'm going to send you a
couple videos after this. I want you to
watch them. That is you guys being part
of the content creation aspect of this
business and making sure that that curve
from when someone hears about us to when
they join and beyond is an exponential
growth curve, not some like negative
customer journey. Content, cash,
reinvest in product, mission, people,
systems. This illustrates a flywheel
where it just [\h__\h] rips. And that's
how we're going to go and impact 100
million people is because we've built
this thing from nothing to three million
people in under three years. You can
only imagine as that just keeps ripping.
The curve we're on is not a line. It's
this. And we're only like here. Similar
to kind of what I was just saying, we
all have two aspects to our roles here,
right? There's our support of the
critical function of exceptional content
and then there is also our core job. You
know the critical function, right? So,
we're dazzling founders through
exceptional content creation. So, as an
example, what I just was saying is
sometimes I'm going to have to go deep
on some content [\h__\h] film four YouTube
videos over the next 3 days, kind of
like I'm doing over the next 3 days
here. I'm going to need your guys' help
like protecting and serving while I'm
doing that so that I can do that and you
guys can rock and roll. So on the
success team, right, this is stuff like
they're going to be creating exceptional
content around the experiences, the
testimonials, the office hours. That's
their aspects of the content creation
side. On the creative goes without
saying, they help a lot with design,
visual storytelling, and support, all
the great [\h__\h] we do. Similar on the op
side with Claire, Don, Zacharias, right?
They've got the systems going, the
support going. They're making content in
their own way. I was just talking to
Claire last night around I don't know if
there's another person on the success
team that has a higher school positive
comment per call rate than Zacharias.
That is [\h__\h] content. And that is
protecting our critical function in two
ways. Number one, I mean it's creating
exceptional content just in and of
itself. And two, when founders are
[\h__\h] really really happy and
customers are really stoked the [\h__\h] up,
they don't [\h__\h] ask for refunds. They
don't cause any [\h__\h] They're
[\h__\h] stoked as [\h__\h] and you guys
don't need to worry about it and I don't
need to [\h__\h] worry about it and I can
go and [\h__\h] hike mountains and make
[\h__\h] exceptional content and we can
all just have a lot of [\h__\h] fun
around here. So then there's you guys,
right? We talked a lot already about a
ton of [\h__\h] right? The calls you're on
are content. The email follow-ups you do
are content. The YouTube videos you
recommend to people are helping
distribute our exceptional content. And
then inevitably, right, like hitting
your projections, right? hitting the
things you say you're going to do. It
helps the content operation, right?
Because the content's bringing the
leads, you guys are closing the leads,
and we can just keep ripping here. So,
the big question then when it comes to
your guys' area is this. How does what
I'm doing right now serve exceptional
content creation and our core promise of
dazzling founders through exceptional
support systems and our community. You
guys are such a great exemplary model of
like the energy, the vibe, the care. We
can see it in the revenue channel and
how much we all support each other. We
can see it in the preparation you guys
are bu bringing to these calls. The
point of this was not to point out what
we should be doing or anything like that
cuz I know you guys know what to do.
It's that I think you guys are owed an
understanding of the overall strategy of
the business. And this is the same
strategy I'm going over with everyone.
You guys have as much information as
Dawn, as Claire, as anyone so that we
can all operate as real owners and
leaders in this chapter and we all have
full information on what needs to
happen. No one's pumping out the level
of like highquality output as we
collectively are as a team. And so
really our only competition guys is
ourselves. Founder OS is here to be this
like household name, right? It's about
freedom. It's about intentional living,
right? It's about building simple
systems that work, right? It's about
helping founders achieve the three Ps,
right? Peace, profit, and purpose. We're
trying to build something for the next
hundred years, guys.
>> That was a mic drop, Matt. That's
>> That was content right there.
>> Coming like, "What the [\h__\h] is going on
here?"
No, honestly I'm not though because like
I was telling Ben too like ever since
the beginning my first conversation with
Zacharias then Claire then uh Matt then
Don I I felt that like you guys really
embody everything that you're saying all
your values and your actions and you
know your whole philosophy you guys tr I
felt that right from the beginning if I
felt that way coming into this as an
internal team member you can only
imagine what everybody else on the
external side of it is feeling as well.
>> I feel the same way. I think we're at
the cusp of something [\h__\h] massive
here. And the more that we believe that
and feel it and embody it, the more it's
just true. It'll just it's a
self-perpetuating machine. And we have
the raw talent here. You know, you guys
in terms of like the growth in all
metrics is like insane month over month
over month the last 3 months. Um you
know the highquality content we're
putting out on YouTube is like
unmatched, right? in in terms of also
like how much better it's getting week
by week, you know, quality of the
delivery side and what we're doing
there. The founder retreat we have
coming up in Bali, there's like so much
good [\h__\h] happening and like we're
barely even started. We all are going to
get really rewarded for in a good way
just like becoming better leaders. It's
really just about that. It's like, you
know, any professional athlete, right?
Like you look at any professional
athlete, they're just looking for that
like 0.01% edge in one area or that
little.5% edge in another, right? And
and we're very much the same way here,
right? Just looking for those little
optimizations, those little edges we can
find as a team. And there's enough of us
in this room here, you know, across all
of that, those five.3
daily add up to maybe a 15% better team
every week and a, you know, three times
better team in three months, right?
which is certainly the bet I would make
on this team. Well, let's just end it on
this note. Okay, so why don't we us all
in a good way put out like an intention
on like what exceptional means to us and
it could be in anything. Okay, it more
than anything I'm talking about this
exceptional vision that we're putting
together to as a squad. Okay, so for me
like as just a random example just being
creative with it, it's like exceptional
to me right now means like just a whole
other caliber of YouTube content going
out. the bar becomes like 500,000 views
per video type [\h__\h] twice a week. That's
what exceptional means to me in my area.
It can be fun and and I would almost
maybe challenge us too in a fun way like
where it almost feels out of reach. It's
that big. What's exceptional for me
coming here just the synchronicity in
terms of doing what I'm doing here.
There's always an intention for me to be
writing and creating again. And that's
just really being here has like charged
me up and got me to really face it. And
there's all these little moments like in
the gym today in Body Factory. It was
like this this quote that I saw at the
front. They have these little cards. It
says, "Don't be surprised how quickly
the universe moves once you've decided
that you want better for yourself. Go be
great." And I'm like, "Shit, there's all
all of these things are literally like
slamming me in the face and saying,
"Fucking wake up and listen." just
continuing to push the boundaries of
like what is uncomfortable because
that's literally where all of the growth
is happening.
>> Yeah. What does exceptional mean to me?
You know, you were not exceptional by
having exceptional results for one day.
You're exceptional by having exceptional
results for an exceptional period of
time. And I think that period of time
part is where everybody falls off the
[\h__\h] wagon. Uh and so for me, that's
just a work of discipline. And
discipline for me and work has really
come from discipline outside of life.
And the dedication outside of that has
what's been able to bring the excellence
as far as consistency here in business.
>> Beautiful. Love it.
>> Yeah. I think for me it's just uh
keeping up the momentum uh being
consistent um having like the the the
best possible leads on on the closest
calendars and just being someone the
team can count on. And at the end of the
day when like the leadership and
everyone can say I'm so glad that we
brought this setter among like millions
of setter here like this was the best
decision ever. That's that's my mission
here. So for me it's like what I
yesterday noticed was like to be
exceptional uh I because to get
exceptional results in life in work in
anything I need to be exceptional
myself. And what I mean by this is if
I'm not getting the resource, it means
that I'm not doing exh exceptional work
as well. It means the problem is all in
me. I'm not going to blame the content
or any other thing because I have to be
exceptional out there to give get
exceptional results.
>> Mine's actually very similar to what uh
what Hamza said. I mean, you know, why
why I love sales and what I do here is
because I have a passion for to want
people to be exceptional. I want I have
a passion to want everybody to become
the best version of themselves. But in
order for me in such a short window that
we have, you know, a 45 minute or an
hour sales call, that short amount of
time that we get to spend with them, in
order for me to help that person become
exceptional and the best version of
themselves, I have to be exceptional. I
have to always strive for excellence
within myself
>> internally and truly embody that.
Otherwise, I don't feel like I'm going
to be able to help people.
>> Um, and that's my mission really. So
>> nice.
>> That's what exceptional is to me.
>> Love it.
>> I [\h__\h] love you guys. That this like
this is our competitive edge, guys. It's
like this energy, this vibe, the [\h__\h]
people we are. You know, I know we're
we're quiet and uh respectful on this
Zoom meeting, but I felt like if we had
this in like a boardroom, we'd be
[\h__\h] banging on the table. You know,
Wolf of Wall Street jumping on the
table, getting ready to go. I ain't
[\h__\h] leaving. Stop [\h__\h] leaving.
the energy I feel. I'm going to have to
apologize to my girlfriend for waking
her up at like 6:00 a.m. with these
screams. But this energy, man. Like,
this is what we feel. This is what we
bring. This is what we bring to the
calls. And this is why we do what we do.
This is why people come to us. Almost
every time I review your guys' calls,
the people are like, "So, you know, why
do you want why do you want to work with
Matt?" And everybody's just like, "The
vibe, man, the energy." And that's the
[\h__\h] truth, baby. Let's keep it
going.
>> I love to see that from Zach as well.
[\h__\h] hype, man. Very good, bro.
>> More of that to come, guys. It's been
good. Sorry for going 2 minutes over,
but it was well worth it. Um, let's have
an exceptional end of the week. Um, and
let's just uh start this new chapter.
Season 4, baby. Let's go.
>> Let's go.
>> Here we go. To the Bone. Let's go.
>> Much love y'all. We ain't [\h__\h]
leaving. Byebye.