I make over $100,000 each month for my
newsletter and I'm about to give you the
blueprint put this into practice and
you'll be able to quit your job in 90
days don't focus on growing your social
media following focus on growing your
newsletter this is where the real money
is made don't just put a sign up link in
your bio you need a lead magnet here's
how to make one identify a paino in your
target audience find a solution for them
package it into an actionable piece of
content test different lead magnets
promote it everywhere you can don't wait
too long to monetize your newsletter
this is the biggest mistake you can make
the more you give away value for free
the more people expect it for free keep
your greatest work behind a pay wall it
doesn't matter if you're not ready yet
pre-sell create a waiting list train
your followers to buy