is your phone screen time shockingly
high here are five super simple ways to
hack your attention and decrease your
screen time grayscale mode this mode
instantly makes your phone less
interesting to look at instead of lots
of colors all you'll see is black and
white or Shades of Gray this can
decrease your screen time by an hour a
day do not disturb mode I always work
with my phone and do not disturb mode
because it's impossible to get into Flow
State if your phone is constantly
pinging you with notifications no
screens in the bedroom follow this rule
it's simple and will instantly increase
your mental well-being the bedroom is
for sleeping for reading and for sex
delete entertainment apps scrolling too
much on social media playing phone games
delete any apps you consider fun from
your phone you can engage with social
media during designated hours every day
on your desktop Track Your Screen Time
Peter Ducker once said you can't improve
what you don't measure log your screen
time at the end of every day in a Google
sheet this will tell you if it's
increasing or decreasing