What if I told you that there's one
formula that creators use to guarantee
their first viral post? Number one, pick
one platform and go allin. Too many
people go spread themselves thin by
being everywhere to everyone and they go
mediocre on five platforms versus going
deep and being world class on one. Focus
creates feedback and you can't improve
what you're spreading thin. Step two is
to test relentlessly and let data be
your teacher. I tested out different
buckets of content, frameworks, systems,
behind the scenes, tips, [music] tricks,
and then started doubling down on the
stuff that I saw working and ditching
the stuff that was no longer performing.
This continual cycle of iteration and
following what works will allow you to
improve over time. Number three, detach
from views and obsess [music] over
iteration. I stopped chasing virality
and started focusing on just making 100
pieces of content [music] that I was
proud of. Sure enough, when you just
focus on the process and getting 10%
better with each piece of content,
you're 13,000 [music] times better after
100.