here are three things I do daily that I
never feel guilty about number one doing
social stuff alone Solitude is an
essential pillar to knowing yourself
cultivate it by doing something normally
social alone eat dinner go to the park
or attend a movie you date your partner
why not date yourself number two
journaling writing out your thoughts and
feelings is self therapy it's something
we all need to do if we want more
clarity and less clutter number three
abundance meditation if you want more
you need to be grateful for what you
already have and you need to believe
more is within your grasp sit down calm
your mind affirm what you want