What if writing down 20 bullet points on
a piece of paper could actually change
your life? I've been using this template
for the last 15 years of my life and
it's been enormously helpful in helping
me design [music] the life and business
of my dreams. So, first off, we're going
to go and kind of chart out our vision
here. So, what's the one word for this
month? I'm going to put in [music]
unstoppable. That's what we're going for
here. Now, when I think about the dream
outcome for the month, right, this could
be anything. It could be a revenue goal
you have, a profit goal, could be a
health goal. I'll go and put here 800k
[music]
of revenue, let's just say. Okay, that's
going to give us what we need to go and
invest in some [music] insane stuff we
have coming down the line. And how I
want to feel at the end of the month. So
how I always want to feel is I [music]
want to feel peaceful and calm.