I've interviewed over 134 millionaires
here at five things I've learned number
one relationships are your Runway nobody
builds a successful business alone you
need to cultivate relationships with
other winners and maintain them number
two iron out your values the more clear
you are about what really matters to you
the easier it is to make money and have
an impact number three invest in your
culture your business culture can either
encourage people to do their best work
or to do the bare minimum cultivate a
hardworking culture and it'll pay
dividends number four demonstrate don't
dictate great ERS embody their values
they don't just talk about them become a
living breathing example of your core
values and others will follow number
five provide immense value the only way
to build trust with a massive audience
in today's world is to provide immense
value for free don't hold back spoil
your audience and your customers with
free value and they will buy from you
when the time comes