There's an amazing discovery in
psychology called the domino mindset.
The domino mindset is realizing that
most of your life is not changed by huge
dramatic overhauls. It's changed by one
small habit that quietly knocks over
everything else. It shows up when
instead of trying to fix your whole life
on Monday, you just nail sleep or daily
writing or you just push that one piece
of content. Suddenly your work, your
mood, your self-respect all start to
shift, right? Because you're just
getting that one most important thing
done that kind of shifts everything else
around it. Psychology-wise, it's really
going to lean into behavioral momentum.
Small wins fuel bigger ones. And this
helps you embody the identity of someone
that does what you say you're going to
do. And it also reduces the amount of
choices in a day, right? Cuz fewer
choices, less burnout, more
follow-through. And over time, this
allows you to feel like the kind of
person that actually shows up, does the
one thing, and is making progress in
your