I've published over 3,000 pieces of
content in just the last 4 years. And
here's what nobody tells you. Most of
those ideas failed before I even hit
publish. Not because I didn't work hard,
not because the algorithm was against
me. They failed because I picked [music]
the wrong ideas to begin with. See, most
people think they have an execution
problem and they're asking, you know,
how do I edit better or what time should
I post or should I use this trending
audio? [music] Wrong questions. You
don't have an execution problem. You
have a selection problem. In the [music]
next 12 minutes, I'm going to show you
the exact filtering system that I use to
[music] find ideas that already have
demand built into them before I waste a
single [music] hour creating. By the end
of this video, you'll be able to look at
any idea and know instantly whether it's
going to work or [music] just go and
die. Section one, the real reason most
ideas fail. You can have the perfect
lighting, right? You can have the
perfect [music] thumbnail. You can write
the best caption of your life. And if
the idea [music] itself is weak, none of
it matters. A lot of people have, you
know, a YouTube channel or an Instagram
channel that is underperforming [music]
and they think, you know, they've got to
start shooting better videos. And
they've got to get their lighting
better, their editing better. But
[music] typically, it's right there in
the ideation phase where they have
failed. When I go and inquire with
founders that I work with and ask like,
you know, how much time you guys putting
to ideation? What's your process [music]
there? There's hardly any process. What
they're asking, right, is how do I make
this then perform better? [music]
When they should be asking, is this idea
even worth building in the first place?
And when I look at what they're
creating, the problem is obvious.
They're guessing. [music] They're
building content based on what they
think people want instead of what people
are actually [music] responding to. The
modern internet does not reward
originality in a vacuum. [music] It
rewards ideas that already have demand
signals built into them. When you
understand how to spot demand before you
create, everything [music] changes.
There's one specific filter I use that
eliminates almost 80% of ideas
>> [music]
>> in less than 10 seconds. If you download
the signal versus noise decision tree
and run an idea through it, bring that
[music] outcome onto a Founder OS call
and we'll go and pressure test it with
you to make sure your conclusion is
clear
>> [music]
>> and decide whether that idea deserves a
real system around it or whether it
should just be cut [music] before it
even costs you any time. You go and
check that out via the link below. You
need to understand what a good idea is
actually supposed to do. [music] A good
idea is something that meets an existing
demand using language the audience
already understands. I want to make
stuff that customers want that I'm going
to have a lot of fun creating
>> [music]
>> and that is going to make me money. At
the center point there, right, are the
best ideas for your founder-led brand.
When you have [music] only two of the
three of these, right, you're making
stuff that people want that makes you
money, but you [\h__\h] hate it and you
feel like you're selling your soul.
>> [music]
>> Or you're making stuff that you love and
some people are saying it's cool, but
you're making no money from it and the
issue there is that you can't build a
team around you and eventually it just
makes no business [music] sense. So it's
not just about being different, although
yes, that's important, right? We also
want to be clear. When I look at content
that works, and I mean really [music]
cranks, not just gets a few likes, it
almost always does three things. One,
it's going to simplify complexity,
right? It takes something confusing and
makes it obvious.
>> [music]
>> Two, it promises a concrete outcome, not
inspiration, not motivation, some sort
of result. Three, it uses language that
the audience is already searching for.
Your best copywriting exists in the
minds of your dream customer. Don't
reinvent the wheel. Don't try to sound
clever. Don't use your industry jargon.
Cut all that [\h__\h] What most people
miss is they start just creating content
out of thin air. [music] Your audience,
though, is already telling you what they
want. They're typing it into different
search bars. [music] They're clicking on
certain thumbnails. They're engaging
with specific formats. And if you learn
how to listen to that data, you stop
guessing and start responding to real
demand. But, here's what you need to
understand first. This is not about just
some brainstorming process. This is a
filtering [music]
process, and that changes everything.
This is the actual workflow. I like to
go and start my process with research,
okay? Now, you can use a bunch of
different platforms for this. One of my
favorites is called oneof10.com. So, you
go to this platform and you can go and
enter in any keyword here at the top.
Now, I'm typically getting informed in
terms of the kind of content I should
create by going and analyzing the
different sales calls that we have or
different customer success calls across
my companies, okay? I typically then
will take that and search that in
oneof10.com, and then I make sure that I
have all of the filters set here as
well. So, I'm setting the outlier score,
which essentially makes sure that the
given piece of ideation that it's
basically recommending is at least
[music] 3.5x better than that channel's
average view count, okay? We're
typically looking for videos as well
and ideas here that have gotten over
100,000 views cuz then we know there's a
big enough market for that idea. And
we're looking at stuff that's been
published over the last 6 months because
we want to see ideas that have recently
really caught fire. The cool thing about
one of 10 is it's typically designed
actually for YouTube packaging, but what
I found is it's actually really good
research for any idea on any platform,
okay? So, what you'll see here then is I
can see a bunch of different ideas for
simplify your life that
have different sort of titles, different
thumbnails, different ways of displaying
that information. And, you know, this
supports my data as well that these
how-to formats [music]
really crush it, okay? So, we can see
that it's using numbers like 4 hours.
It's [music] using how-to in the title.
And so, this is certainly now informing
me as to the way I may want to go and
take this concept around simplifying
your life and [music] then make sure
that the title for that, if I was going
to make that say a LinkedIn post or a
YouTube video,
the title is dialed in based on real
data. Here's where most people stop.
They find a viral video and they try to
copy it. And [music] that's not what I'm
talking about doing here, either. We're
looking for patterns inside the idea.
For example, let's say we find five
different creators who all posted a
video about how to build a personal
brand in 30 days. Let's say those videos
are all performing way above that
creator's average video count. That
tells us a few things, right? One,
there's demand for a time-bound promise
around personal branding. Two, the
phrase 30 days creates urgency and
believability. It's not some overnight
and it's not 5 years, either, right?
It's specific and it's a manageable time
frame. Three, the word build implies a
system, right? A process, something
structured, something repeatable. Before
any idea moves forward, my team has to
answer three questions.
>> [music]
>> One, what existing viewer desire does
this idea serve? Two, where is that
demand already showing up on social
media? And three, why is our brand
uniquely positioned to deliver this
right now? And that third one is where I
see most people [\h__\h] up this entire
system. They go and start taking
formats, taking ideas, and then just
verbatim copying them to their niche.
But the thing is, it oftentimes feels
out of whack with that person's actual
brand, their actual authentic voice. As
we talk about all the time on this
channel, right, is that your brand is
everything. Your brand is your most
valuable asset. And so, if we can't
answer all three of these clearly, we're
likely going to kill an idea. And then,
yeah, if there's some piece of content
that I really want to make, you know,
I'm going and I'm snowboarding in Japan
and I want to take people behind the
scenes, and I know this content's
probably not going to do very well or
serve much of a purpose for other
people, but I just want to make it,
well, you know what? I'm just going to
go and do that. Section four, the signal
detection system.
>> [music]
>> All right, so we've sourced an amazing
idea. Now we've validated also that
there's demand that exists around it.
And now we need to go and test it
without wasting time or energy. We
create the smallest, fastest version of
that idea possible. It could be a single
post, a single tweet, a short-form
video, something that ideally takes like
30 minutes [music] to an hour max. This
is one of the biggest mistakes I see
people make. They take an idea and then
they immediately go all in. And then it
flops, right? And now they're
emotionally attached to it. They're
defensive about it. You don't need to do
it like that. When you run a test that's
a low lift, you can remove that
emotional attachment, right? You're just
running an experiment. And if it works,
great. If it doesn't, you learn
something for free. So, what are you
looking for when we test? Well, here are
the signals. [music] Views relative to
average, right? If a post gets two
times, three times, five times our
normal views, that's [music] a signal.
We're also going to look at things like
the engagement rate, right? Are people
commenting? Are they bookmarking it? Can
we see people sharing it with their
friends? This tells us if the idea
resonated. We're going to look at things
on Instagram like explore page
distribution. If a post hits the explore
page or gets recommended to
non-followers, that means [music] that
the algorithm is telling us that the
idea has broad appeal. The ultimate form
of signal that I like to see is [music]
other founders that I respect either
going and messaging me on WhatsApp or
going and sending me a text, right? And
saying, "Man, I love this piece of
content you just put out. I just went
and shared this with my whole company
[music] in Slack." Here's what most
people don't understand. One good idea
can fuel your content for weeks, [music]
maybe months. You just have to know how
to expand on it. And that's exactly what
I'm going to show you here in this next
[music] bit. We've tested the idea and
now we have proof that it works, right?
So, we got to scale it. This
>> [music]
>> is what we call the content waterfall.
The idea that performed well as a
carousel, well, we can go and take that
now, put it into a long-form LinkedIn
post. We can break it into an
ex-long-form article. We can expand it
into a YouTube video, maybe even a
YouTube video series. We could record a
podcast around it. We [music] can send
it to our whole email list in our
newsletter. Just adapt it to different
formats and different levels [music] of
depth. What we can then do, right, is
then go and bring that over to the
content that I'll go and create if I'm
going to go and use this say for an
Instagram carousel. This one here, the
Japanese, you know, concept around
simplifying your life. It says on it,
"Keep it simple." This has a 15.9x
outlier score, meaning that this
specific concept performed 15.9 times
better than that channel's average
video. So, good signal. The conclusion
that we can make here is that using a
time frame, right, as well as, you know,
meeting the promise of how to change
your life is expected in these types of
content. [music] Here you can see that
I've gone and then taken that research,
right, and put it into this X post,
which is how to simplify your life in
just [music] 7 days. So, I saw that
there was the how-to title format, plus
there was the idea of putting some sort
of number in it. And so, I did that to
go and title this graphic that I just
kind of written in a cafe. The post
caught fire, right? One part because of
just the authenticity of my notebook
kind of images, which people seem to
really love. And then combining that
though with obviously the data that I'd
[music] found on one of 10. The reason
why the data matters to me is because,
you know, I got mouths to feed. I got to
keep the lights on, right? And our media
operation and Founder Hustle is an
example, it costs around $90,000 a month
right now. And so, I want to make sure
that I'm creating the kind of content
operation, systems, and ideation behind
it [music] that we can get a 10x ROI on
that marketing expense essentially.
[music] You know, it's worth spending
time on getting that right ideation
system in your company if you're looking
to get outsized returns from that
content operation that you're building.
The other thing to think about here,
too, is that just as easy, really, to
create a [\h__\h] idea as [music] it is a
great one, right? So, you might as well
make a great one by just going that
extra couple steps more to go and do a
little bit of the research required to
just [music] package things right. The
same thing here, right? When I'm
waterfalling different content, sure
enough, I took that post from X, I saw
it do well, I went and worked with my
designer Jan to then go and design a
carousel for Instagram around it. It's
got here's how to simplify your life in
just 6 months. And sure enough, this got
another 200,000 plus views then on
Instagram, over 4.8 K likes. This also
drove us thousands of email sign-ups for
the resource that we gave in the call to
action at the [music] end of it, right?
So, you can go and invest deeply and
pour your energy into one idea and go
deep with it, and then know that that
investment is going to get multiplied by
becoming content on multiple platforms.
This is the magic, right, of really
going and following the data with your
creativity, putting it out in a
low-weight way on one platform. When you
[music] find signal, then go and take
that to other platforms. Here you can
see the stats, right? Over 831,000
views, 84% were non-followers. So, this
really caught flight just outside of my
existing audience on Instagram, which
drove us a ton of followers, as well. If
you don't have the right infrastructure
in place, right? You can drive a bunch
of views, you can have a great offer,
but you're never going to connect the
two. And the core pieces of a
founder-led brand are being able to
create,
>> [music]
>> to nurture, and then to monetize, right?
And when you have those three right,
you've created something insanely
impactful. All right, that's the system.
That's how you win, and I'll see you in
the next one. Go and be sure to check
out this video on how to build a
profitable personal brand in just seven
steps. [music]
I break down every core system you need
to go and scale your personal brand this
year. I'll see you there, and let's
continue to win together.