This is the smartest way to make money
on Instagram in 2026. Most people
[music] are sitting on thousands of
followers but making zero dollars
because they're missing one critical
piece of the puzzle and it's costing
[music] them six figures a year. I went
from 0 to a million Instagram followers
and millions of dollars all from this
one [music] system. So today I want to
show you how I convert 5 to 10,000
potential clients from many chat alone
inside [music] of Instagram and how that
prints revenue while I sleep. Let's get
into it. Part one. [music] Before you
look to profit from Instagram, you need
to understand why your followers aren't
making you any money. So, imagine you
have a baseball team and you only get
one at bat every single month. Well,
probably not going to do that well. And
that's how a lot of people approach
Instagram. You know, they have this
audience that they're building to 5,000
or 10,000 people on Instagram, but every
single one of their posts only shows up
to about 10% of their total audience
because that's how the algorithm works.
That's not even the scariest part of it.
There's something called platform risk.
Platform risk is when you're completely
dependent on another platform for your
entire business. You know, at any moment
your account could be flagged, it could
get banned, who knows what. And poof,
there goes your business. And so, the
key thing here is to mitigate that
platform risk by actually owning that
audience in your email newsletter. So
stop measuring your success by vanity
metrics like followers and engagement
and start measuring it by a metric
that's actually going to move your
business forward. How many emails are
you collecting every week? That is the
metric that matters. The system I'm
about to show you actually is going to
aid you in this transition. The best
part is it doesn't just help you go and
collect those emails. It's also going to
go and help you boost your reach on
Instagram. The double whammy. And many
chat is exactly how you do that. [music]
Part two. why Instagram is the best
opportunity right now. So now you know
you need to own your audience, but
you're wondering, you know, Matt, is
Instagram really the best platform? And
the answer is yes, because of ManyHat. A
lot of people use Instagram messages or
DMs almost like it's a text message. You
know, people check that [music]
With many chat combined there, too, you
don't need to do all the hand-to-hand
combat in the DMs yourself. you can hook
up an enormous amount of [music]
automations and different sequences to
help convert people from attention all
the way through to transaction. So,
let's get into that. Part three, how to
[music] collect thousands of emails per
month. Now, we're going to go over a lot
of details in this video, and I've gone
and put the core details into a playbook
that I'd recommend that you go and
download via the link in the
description. Inside of this 10X
Instagram playbook, I give you all the
core flows that you need to have set up
so that this isn't so scary and it's
much more simple. Now that you
understand that Instagram is the best
platform for this, let me show you an
inside look at the platform that lets me
collect 1,500 emails in just 10 days.
What I have here is a carousel on how to
make your business run itself in 6
months. The core thing that me and the
team are thinking about is making sure
that each slide of the carousel has the
potential to be shared onto someone's
stories. And that sharability factor of
every single slide helps contribute to
the overall viral nature of [music] this
piece of media. Now, here's where the
real magic comes in. Right? As we keep
flipping through this, you see an insane
amount of value that we're providing
people to help them become systemized
founders. [music] And on the last slide
here, this is where the real sauce is.
Says, "In 6 months, this system gave me
a business that runs without me. I can
disappear for a month, come back to a
stronger company. That's [music]
freedom. Want my full systemized founder
blueprint with templates? Comment blue
and I'll send it to you for free." So,
what's going on here is that we're being
insanely generous across the nine slides
of this carousel. [music]
And then inevitably someone's thinking
in their head, "Damn it, I just want to
be able to implement this in my [music]
life and in my business." And that's
exactly what we give them on this final
slide. They can go and comment blue. And
what happens is when they comment, it
triggers the Many Chat automation, which
is now going to go and send them an
entire robust blueprint for [music] free
for getting their email in exchange. And
so, let's get into the math of like how
this all worked, right? Right. When I go
to the insights here, this post got over
512,000 views. And those views were
propelled by the fact that over 900
people went and commented on [music]
this post. And most of those comments
were the word blue. And so, not only is
that going and triggering the many chat
automation, which is helping me go and
collect these emails, but it's also
providing this post with a flood of
engagement that helps [music] drive an
insane amount of reach in between when
someone comments blue and then going and
getting this lead magnet. That is where
all the sauce is. And we're going to go
and show you that right now. There are a
couple possible ways to set this up, but
I'm going to show you the flows and the
automations that I have set up inside of
here. So, [music] if they've never been
through our funnel before, I'm going to
go and make sure that there's a certain
tag that tags them as a new comment
because we want to treat new people in
the flows different than we treat people
that maybe have continuously been
through the different Instagram flows.
These tags just allow us to start making
sure that just the back end of ManyHat
is all clean. The second thing that
happens in this automation is that we
start then assigning a conversation to a
setter. On my team, I have someone named
Arbor who helps manage all of our DMs.
So, I'm in there often times leaving
voice notes and helping people out. But
because of the sheer volume of DMs that
are being opened every single day, I
think it's something like 15 to 20,000
some weeks, um, you know, I need some
help. So, this is really nice, right?
Because you can delegate things to other
people in your personal media company so
that you know, you don't need to manage
all of this stuff over time. The beauty
of this is that we're getting smarter
and smarter and able to make ManyHat
feel like an actual human. So, we can do
this through [music] things like smart
delays. You can make sure that you know
when someone has gone and entered a
certain field, you can go and put a
smart delay in to get that person to not
get the next DM in the flow for as an
example 2 minutes. So, it feels like an
actual human conversation [music] here.
Then you can see, you know, hey founder,
you're looking for the systemized
founder blueprint, right? And so we're
just double-checking that the reason why
they're in our DMs is that they in fact
want that lead magnet. Now, you can also
go and fill out different smart fields,
right? So instead of saying, "Hey,
founder," [music] you could put in, say,
"Hey," and then a tag there, which would
allow people to go and put, you know,
their first name, which would pull it
from their profile so that those DMs
feel much more tailored and personalized
to people versus generic. [music]
So, they're going to click yes to that.
And so, there's a condition here to make
sure, you know, do we have their email
yet? And if not, let's collect it. We
get their email, we're going to go,
awesome, you're all set. Here's the
playbook. and we're going to then go and
give them the playbook that they've
requested. So, they're winning because
they're getting this insane playbook
that me and my team spent 30 hours going
and synthesizing. [music] And we win
longterm because we're collecting all of
these emails from people that we can
continue to market to. All right, I got
some good news for you. This whole many
chat sequence automation is all broken
down into the 10x [music] Instagram
playbook. So, go and get that via the
link in the description. You know, this
is a lot more simple when you have the
step-by-step guide. And so, that's what
we wanted to give you so that you go and
implement this in your team and business
today. So, there's the carousel science,
there's the many chat science, [music]
but there's also a science to these lead
magnets. So, there are kind of two core
formats of lead magnets that we use here
at Founder OS. One is the Google Doc
lead magnet, and then another is the
Google Slide lead magnet. Here's a
Google Doc as an example, and this is
for the systemized founder blueprint,
the one I was just showing you there.
This lead magnet is around 13 pages
long. I'm being generous in giving
people the exact prompts that they
should use for different parts of it.
Um, you know, I'm making sure that I'm
breaking it down week by week what they
should be focused on and I'm even giving
them next steps. Now, [music] you can
see here at both the top and the bottom
of the document, I'm plugging some
information on Founder OS velocity,
which is the core offer that we have
here at Founder [music] OS, helping
founders go and remove themselves from
operations and build a systemized
personal brand. We're then going and
plugging a link in these and it pops up
a few times throughout the lead magnet
which drives people through to [music]
our application and if people are
interested they can go and click apply
now. They go through this then and then
fill out all of their information. They
then become a lead which is piped into
HubSpot. So [music] we'll go and get on
a call with them which is all booked
through a calendarly hookup into this
whole flow. [music] And you can see here
someone can pick a time, go to next, and
then book that call. This is the whole
flow now going from that carousel to
many chat to lead magnet all the way to
booking a call with us. And we do a
similar thing with our Google slide lead
[music] magnets. Inside of this, I have
a Loom video that starts off this lead
magnet. In the Loom video, there's a
book a call with my team button that
appears the entire time through that
Loom video, which at any moment people
can click that and go to that
application funnel. So, it's one part
giving people an insane amount of value,
but it's another part actually going and
pushing them further down the funnel.
Now, moving them from, yes, your rented
audience to an owned audience now that
you have their email, but now moving
them from your owned audience to a
monetized audience where they're
actually going and purchasing your
product or your [music] service. All
right, so we're feeling a bit generous
here. So, if you want these two lead
magnets, you can go and get them both
via the link in the description. And if
you want to go and learn more about what
we got going on over here at Founder OS,
you can go and book a free 15minute
systems audit with my team. We'll go and
dissect your business and find out the
one part of your business that's keeping
you stuck from your next stage of
growth. So, it's a no-brainer. Go and
book that call right now and we'll go
and help you out. The craziest part of
all this, right, is that all of those
comments on a post are racking up both
engagement and then helping boost that
post [music]
in Instagram's algorithm. Here you can
see this. I'm 35. If you're in your 30s
or 40s, read this. This post got over
25,000 [music] likes. And when we look
at the insights behind this post, right,
we can see that it got over 16.3
million organic views without spending a
dime on ads. It reached over 99,000,
right? And in terms of the saves,
[music] 26,000 saves, 25,000 likes,
9,500 shares, and that was all boosted
because it received over 2400 comments.
Now, where are all those comments coming
from? The last slide here says, "Age is
not your enemy, and experiences. You
have the experience, now you get the
systems. Comment [music] 50 and I'll
send you 50 proven frameworks that help
me grow a profitable and sustainable
brand." As you can see here in the
comments, people are going crazy there.
and just messaging 50 all throughout
these comments, right? And sure enough,
what do you think's happening? Well,
Instagram's seeing all of these comments
fire up in those DMs and then it's going
and causing it to rocket ship that post
onto more and more news feeds and
causing this post [music] to spike. And
the cool thing is when this happens, the
majority of the reach of this post is
being seen by nonfollowers. And I think
that this post alone drove me like 7,000
new followers to my account. And [music]
so again, the power of ManyHat isn't
just collecting emails. It's not just
converting people to customers. It's
also the power of it to help take your
reach and follower growth to the next
level as well. So it is the triple
whammy. Part four, what content do you
post to make it work? After running this
system for months, I started tracking
everything. [music] The three formats
that work best are number one, how-tos.
I'm talking about posts like, you know,
how to make a company strategy that
actually works or how to make a plan for
October that you'll actually use, right?
It's [music] these posts that cause
people to learn a lot and then discover
some new framework that you can then
give them for free via the many chat
sequence. [music] The second type of
posts are posts with numbers in it like
nine AI courses that every founder
should go through. Eight [music] traits
of high performers, right? People
inevitably build a lot of curiosity when
reading these posts and then it's a
great parlay [music] to the free thing
you're going to give them inside of the
ManyHat DM sequence. The third type is
storytelling, right? Giving people some
background on your journey, your
mistakes, your failures. Inevitably,
they see all of this, they're captured
[music] by the storytelling, and then
they're thinking, well, yeah, like I
want to avoid those mistakes or I want
to get that system that took [music] you
15 years to learn. and it parlays
perfectly to giving them that in
exchange for a comment and an [music]
email. Here's the data. When I post a
carousel with a how-to hook and then a
CTA in it, I get anywhere between 200
[music] and 700 comments. That said, if
you look at reals, I generally get
between 27 and 57 comments. So, the
difference there is like [music] 10x.
So, for me and for many accounts I'm
seeing currently on Instagram, it's
carousels that are going to really drive
those DM conversations you're after.
[music] And then one pro tip here is
that when you go and you create those
trigger words in ManyHat, I'd recommend
that you make them five letters or less.
[music] Why? Well, we want to make it
easy for someone to go and type the word
so that the more people that are typing
it and submitting [music] it, the more
conversations that are open in ManyHat
and the more emails you collect. [music]
It's simple. If you want to get my
entire system for how I went and set up
all these Instagram flows and the core
data I've seen across my top carousels
ever, you can go and get it via the link
in the description. I've put it all into
a 10X [music] Instagram playbook, which
is all the core learnings I've gone and
shared with you. So, be sure to go get
that right now via the link in the
description. Part five, from 0 to a
million. So, the final question is, how
do you actually build this
infrastructure? Whether you're just
getting started or you're already doing
300K a month, here's what this looks
like at different stages. You know, if
you're getting started from zero, keep
it simple. Just have one post that goes
out with one CTA and have that lead to
one many chat automation sequence. Over
time, you can make things more robust,
but just getting that first one up and
live is a big win. As you scale, your
infrastructure gets more sophisticated.
you're likely looking at your content
and finding the data across your top 10%
of posts and doubling down on those
content [music] formats and topics. Then
when you go and you zoom out, you
probably also are looking at the core
pain points that your customer has. I
know for me it's things like organic
content, personal brands, removing
themselves from operations, right? And
then I'm building core lead magnets for
each of these content pillars. This is
an example of the lead magnet kind of
database for Founder OS. So, safe to say
that we have a lot of lead magnets
because the key thing that we're trying
to do here is constantly be insanely
generous, giving people a ton of value
in different ways that we can serve
them. You know, as an example, we have
the 555 hiring system, which is a core
system that we recommend that founders
use to go and build out their teams and
make sure they're hiring A players, not
a bunch of B players, right? Obviously
with everything growing around AI, more
and more people are coming to me because
they want to go and learn these AI
systems, but they also want my help
going and leveling up their entire team
as well. And so we give people things
like our AI growth playbooks, our
prompts, how to set up claude projects
and chat GBD projects inside of these
different lead magnets. The truth is
that I am totally fine. And I'm actually
more than happy, right, to go and give
all this stuff away for free because
sure enough, as you start wanting to
implement it at a high degree, you
[music] know, the kind of founders that
are doing, you know, 30K, 100K, 300K,
right? They want actual help, not just
getting these systems, but [music]
helping them implement it for them and
their entire team. Because, you know,
one of the core beliefs I have over the
next decade is [music] it's founders
with AI powered teams that are going to
win. That's why infrastructure is
everything. [music]
You know, you go and you create that one
post. It goes and hits up that one
automation into one funnel, gets them on
one sales call and converts them, right?
When you have that infrastructure in
place, you [music] know, you have a
business that is systemized and
scalable. That's leverage. That's scale.
And that's how you build a business that
doesn't require you to be online 24/7.
If you want to get help with setting up
this infrastructure in your business and
you want to actually go and level up
your team so they're all running on a
much more systemized infrastructure,
well, you should go and check out
Founder OS. This is exactly what we help
people with and you can just get on a
simple 15-minute systems audit with my
team. We can learn more about your
business and what's kind of keeping you
stuck from that next stage of growth and
assess if Found [music] is a good fit
for you. So, go and book a call via the
link in the description. If you enjoyed
this video, be sure to like and
subscribe. And if you want to power this
up even more with AI, go and watch this
next video.