your best friends might not be good for
you you've probably heard that you are
the average of The Five People You spend
the most time with but have you actually
documented your friendships and improve
the quality of the people you hang out
with grab a pen and paper write down the
Five People You spend the most time with
every week then ask yourself if those
are people that you'd like to emulate if
not decrease how much time you spend
with them next write down five people
you already know who you would like to
emulate then resolve to be more
intentional with those relationships
you'll be shocked at how quickly you
grow when you spend more time with
people who actually inspire you