This is the actual dashboard running my
17-person, $700,000 month company in
real time. Not me solo, not Slack, not a
spreadsheet, this, okay? And the sad
reality is that behind most businesses
making 30K a month or even a million a
month, it's the founder who is starting
to feel a specific kind of exhaustion
that they just can't explain. The
problem is they're trying to hold the
entire company in their head, and your
head is not a system. What you're going
to see is exactly how I use this real
operating system to go and run my
company, and why founders who run one
are leading their businesses while
everyone else is being run by theirs.
This is my Ops Machine. I've used Claude
Code mixed with Vercel, combining it
with a lot of the data that I store in
HubSpot to go and create this one-stop
dashboard for everything I need to run
my core team. There are three things
that I think every core team needs:
dashboard, an amazing meeting rhythm,
and you need to make sure that your team
has clear objectives and key results.
And so, we're going to get into every
one of those pieces here. So, starting
out with the command center, right? This
is like the cockpit of the company,
right? We're able to see the core
company priorities here, things like
going and recruiting and building a
badass founder success team. So, what I
can do here with all of these goals,
right, is go and see all of our goals
across our week, you know, across the
core leadership team, right? And as we
go and check these off, right, they
gradually go and just kind of show that
progress bar, which is pretty cool. So,
we're able to every single week just
chip away at the core task we need to
get done every single week, then how
that ladders up to our given month and
what we're working towards, right? And
then similarly, how that goes and
ladders up to what we need to get done
in a given quarter. This is the big
thing that I'm, you know, huge on in my
businesses, right, is creating like this
maniacal sense of urgency, right? And
so, if we all have a clear direction,
clear goals for the week, for the month,
for the quarter, we are all rowing at
the same rhythm. This next piece is the
Level 10 Meeting, okay? This comes from
a book called Traction by Gino Wickman.
This book really talks about the
importance of running level 10 meetings
inside of your company. Now, the
structure for the level 10 is a
game-changer. You start off with wins,
right? So, what are people on the team
going and accomplishing? Let's share
those, get the energy going, right? The
more, you know, energized the team is,
you know, the more that that just flows
through the results, momentum, all that
good stuff, right? To me, having fun in
a business isn't about ping-pong tables
and some culture initiatives,
right? To me, fun is winning, right? I
view building a business like a sports
team, and that's why, just like in a
sports game, right? You've got some sort
of scoreboard, well, we've got a
scoreboard inside of our company as
well, showing things like cash
collected, our margin, the FSMs that
have been hired, our close rate, show
rate, all that good stuff, right? So,
that we know across the core business
what we're on track, off track, and what
we may need to get, you know, kind of
grooving on. Why this is important is
that on these leadership meetings each
week, what we're aiming to do is
understand what's off track, because
then we bring that down to something
called the issues and opportunity
section, which I'll get to here in 1
minute, okay? Now,
across the company, I think the core job
of the CEO, right? Is to set the company
goals. Everything inside of FounderUs,
giving founders their founder operating
system, um and really helping, you know,
eliminate the use of like a hundred
different spreadsheets, hundreds of
different Google Docs, different teams
running off of Notion, one person on
Google Workspace, another person on
ClickUp, you know, another person on
HubSpot, and your business just becomes
this like mess, right? And to me, that's
what leads to founder chaos. My theme
this year, and really helping founders,
is helping turn them into architects
versus just the pure operator in their
business. And, you know, things like the
Ops Machine are my, you know, products
that I'm trying to birth and help uh
founders go and implement um in their
businesses. In addition to that, right?
I'm really big on kind of McDonaldizing
our delivery, right? I want, you know,
almost like when you go to McDonald's in
Tokyo or Paris or New York, you're
getting that same kind of product. Well,
that's exactly what we're doing in
Founder OS, just to really systematize
every single part of it, make it
insanely scalable, scaling our team from
five customer success managers to about
12 over the next 4 months. Um so, things
are growing at a good clip. Um I just
need to obviously make sure that as we
grow, those systems get sustained. From
there, you know, it's a lot of like
focusing on retention. At a business of
our size, trying to get to a $2 million
a month, um it's a game of just
retention, retention, and so
um the best way to do that, right, is
just to be product obsessed, deliver an
amazing product for founders, really
embed the infrastructure that we've made
into their businesses, making their
lives easier, getting their team more
aligned, um helping reduce the confusion
inside of their business, and really,
you know, helping founders across all
the different departments, right? And
from there, if we're doing our job,
founders are sticking with us for years
to come. What I want you to take out of
this is less like the details of my
business, although, you know, happy for
you to see it, and be transparent. But,
is this this idea of like imagine your
own business, right? If you had every
core initiative, every company goal, all
listed, and all the subtasks around
there, imagine how much tighter your
business would be. This is what it's all
about, right? It's about knowing the
details, and having every single task
laid out across all core initiatives, so
that nothing slips
between the cracks. That to me builds a
formidable empire. This is what we do.
We just go from top to bottom through
this, making sure that every single
project is on track. If anything's
missing, we talk about it, and we move
it down to the identify, discuss, and
solve section here. You can see that we
can go and move these areas around. You
know, we can move different aspects up
if we think it's a higher priority. And
what this allows us to do is just make
sure that as a leadership team, we're
addressing the biggest issues that may
come up. We're solving those first, and
working our way down this list. You can
imagine this whole meeting, we're doing
it on Zoom. My team's all over the
world, and all these meetings are
recorded on Fathom. From there, we're
able to go and automatically pipe that
Fathom recording into Claude code and
this whole ops machine and this meeting
rhythm is automatically updated. No more
going in, you know, what did we say last
week or what happened 4 weeks ago that
we committed to? No more of that stuff,
right? Make sure that any meeting that
you're on inside of your company, you've
got that recorded, right? And that
that's being fed into Claude, right? So
that you build this kind of company
brain. Now, from there, we've got the
initiatives tab, right? So this is
really measures all the core aspects of
our company, right? We've got our media
platform across YouTube, Instagram,
LinkedIn, X, right? And bunch of
initiatives going on there. Things like,
you know, new styles of infographics,
we're doing more raw, real rant type
content just like this right now on
YouTube and on Instagram. Hope you like
it. With all that, right? Just involves
like different stuff going on across the
team, right? Different things that we
want to keep track of. And this is how
we kind of make sure that, you know, all
the core initiatives are moving forward
in a nice way. We're able to track
progress, see when things are behind,
and basically just make sure that we're
all moving forward in one organized way.
You know, on the front end, right? You
guys see my brand, you know, a lot of
you guys have said, you know, they looks
really tight, we seem to have everything
together, it's really polished. Well,
the way that all happens in the
background, right? We're just running a
seriously tight operation. And too many
founders I see, um you know, that come
to us in Founder West, right? They, you
know, feel like they're just operating
some house of cards, that everything at
any moment could just fall apart. You
know, the same systems that work for you
at a million dollars a year start to
break at five million dollars a year.
And so, that's why this kind of
dashboard, right? A good meeting
structure and clear goals and rhythm
across your team are so imperative. The
cool thing about this as well is that,
you know, in any given week, right? I'm
talking to different advisors of mine
and I'm constantly learning, right? So,
folks like Dan Bolden, you know, Neil
Patel, had a conversation today with
Ryan Klog, and after those
conversations, Claude is going and then
pushing in different recommendations and
action plans that I need to get done.
So, this morning, had a call with Neil
Patel. Now I can see this whole LTV
expansion plan has all been added into
our actual initiatives here, right? So,
things like getting clients on ACH first
payments and having a backup credit card
there. Um something that he's seen work
in the companies he runs, um which he's
been cranking it um for 20 plus years
now. And then some recommendations on
where we can find CSMs, um different
kind of ways of building out our
conversion infrastructure. So, lots of
cool stuff there. When we get to the
team, right? It's also a bit of a team
scorecard, right? Being able to see kind
of scorecards across the team, who are
the active members of the squad, um
which is just a nice place for us just
to have like that one-stop shop uh view
of everyone on the team right now. And
as well as look at things like our
capacity on our team. When you're
building a team, I see it almost like a
sports team, right? And you're building
your own fantasy roster, right? so this
is my fantasy roster. I think building a
business is kind of like, you know, a
video game. Um and this lets me see the
squad that we've got today, right? And
um understand just, you know, where we
can improve, where we're maybe seeing
some gaps, um areas we can automate, you
know, just nice to have that one-stop
view. Any business is only as strong as
its recruitment, okay? And so, about 30%
of my job at least is recruiting. You
know, I was just on an interview before
filming this video. This quick side
note, my favorite interview question to
ask, and I learned this from Elon Musk,
is "Tell me about something that you've
done that is exceptional." Why I think
this is an interesting question, right,
is that you end up hearing responses
anything from stuff that's actually
exceptional like this last guy had built
his organic audience on Instagram to
over 180,000 followers, all the way
through to things that are not all that
exceptional. Um someone I talked to a
few days ago had helped a high school
person um go and win like a little
science experiment. And I just was like,
"All right, like interesting, but not
quite like exceptional in terms of the
level of caliber we're looking to bring
people on, right?" So, good test to try
to try to really understand what people
are capable of, what they've actually
done in their life, and if it's
mind-blowing and truly exceptional,
those are the kind of people we want to
hire. Inside of a recruiting
leaderboard, we're recruiting people
from all over the world, right? We've
got recruiters in Lebanon, Brazil,
Eastern Europe, Latin America, you name
it. If you're interested, by the way, in
joining Founder OS, we're currently
hiring folks like salespeople, customer
success people. You can go and check out
Founder OS and apply at founder
os.com/careers,
okay? And so, inside of this then we're
just constantly going and monitoring our
pipeline, um keeping our eye out for
quality people, um and you know, when we
find great people, bringing them on
board and running them through the
systems that we have for onboarding. I
think what's most important is as you're
building a team, right? Everyone
understands the journey that your
customer goes through, right? Everyone
in your company must be product
obsessed, and they must understand the
strategy. So, here we have the founder
journey, okay? When someone joins
Velocity as an example, which is our
core product here at Founder OS, we go
and build their entire social media
machine for them. Across 75 days,
there's seven calls, and we deliver
around 60 different assets for them,
helping them go and scale up their like
organic content machine, okay? So, it
includes things like an onboarding call
right away. We then do a bit of a brand
deep dive, understanding their brand.
Six days later then we deliver their
brand positioning document, build out
their content GPS, you know, their
content pillars, their different
conversion assets, and then we end up
kind of building out their content
machine, their revenue and monetization
pack, um and then really help them go
and scale out things like workshops,
email sequences, and newsletters, okay?
And everything that we do at Founder OS
is really just reinforcing that journey,
right? The automations we build, the
different products we're launching, we
eat, sleep, breathe, really building a
really delightful, constant process here
that ideally every single email we send,
every asset we deliver for founders is
an aha moment, right? That's the bar
that we have. Um I like to think that
we're trying to build this Apple for
founders, right? Just like Apple when
you open an iPhone has this gorgeous
unboxing experience and you can just
tell every single piece of, you know,
the product that they're showcasing for
you has a degree of intention involved
in it. We want to make our process feel
the same way when we're working with
founders on their social media and
helping them with their their organic
content. We built a free tool called the
Founder Freedom Score. You answer a
short set of questions about where your
time goes, what you control and what
controls you, and then you're going to
get a score, okay? And the score is
going to tell you exactly which part of
your business is trapping you right now,
whether it's your priorities, your
leadership team, your customers, or some
other strategic gap, okay? It takes
about 4 minutes. Link is in the
description, so go do that right now,
then come back because we are about to
go and see is the answer to wherever
your score flags. Now, every business,
right, that's really trying to grow to
levels we're trying to grow to, needs a
flywheel, okay? And for us, again, it
all comes down to building an amazing
product, right, then marketing the
results of that product, showing the
kind of founders that we help, and then
those founders spread the message,
right? There's that belief that, you
know, people don't buy what you sell,
they buy what other people want to buy,
and so by us just doing great work by
founders, uh, we're able to just, yeah,
attract more amazing founders of that
caliber and the machine just keeps on
growing. And so this is kind of a
one-page company strategy, okay? On the
left here you can see
the different media platforms we have.
We then capture that audience inside of
things like our email list, which we've
grown to a quarter million people, all
organically. We drive people through
workshops every single month that then
get people interested in the kind of
things we got going on. We run
cohort-based programs every 3 months, on
the next one being something called Cash
Flow Machine.
And then, you know, I've even got some
software products and I got a book
coming out soon. And then that brings
people then to typically our core offer,
which is Founder OS Velocity, right?
Which I already spoke about, so we'll
move past that. Now, the strategy side
of things, right?
Why I most like this tab is actually
because every single week I aim to talk
to about five different mentors or
advisors, right? So, like I'd mentioned,
I was actually just at lunch with
William Brown. I talked tonight to Ryan
Holiday. This morning was Neil Patel.
I talked yesterday to Dan Bolden. You
know, that's just an average week and
what I typically will do is show those
guys this strategy tab, right? So, that
I'm able to get feedback on how I'm
thinking about things like our value
ladder, how I'm progressing, you know,
on the product side because inevitably,
just to be honest, right? There's a ton
of stuff I do not know, right? I've
built media companies and, you know,
different industries. I've built
education companies before, but
inevitably, like we're all kind of on
this like new frontier here with AI and
how fast things are progressing. And so,
one of the number one ways that I think
that you can really stay ahead is by
finding a tribe, right? A community and
mentors and advisors. And that's what we
do in Founder OS, but I also honestly
live and breathe that myself, right?
having my own tribe of mentors that are
constantly helping me. And so, this just
is this an example of how I'm kind of
currently looking at things. Um, we've
got some insane offers that we're
constantly launching to keep things
fresh and fun. I'm going and just
constantly refining my business by
talking to folks. You know, Paul Graham
says that as you're building a business,
it's important to get outside the
building, right? So, I'm getting
outside, talking to folks, I'm learning.
It's not that I from every one of these
conversations I'm getting like 20
insights that I'm implementing.
Sometimes it's just like a couple
epiphanies or often what I find is it's
like one person says something over here
and then you connect that with what
someone else is saying and you kind of
then come up with some other crazy idea
off that. So,
that's currently, you know, what I'm up
to and how I'm building. Lastly here is
the vision, okay?
My vision with Founder OS, right, is to
build the operating system for founders
who want their business to run without
them. I talk a lot about how, you know,
I see myself as more of an artist than
an entrepreneur, right? And I think that
as you're building, you kind of want to
be this artist who's able to be creative
and then have this autonomous engine
running behind you. Those two things
combined allowed me to make insane
content and basically have my business
all run off a series of automations, all
visible in dashboards with a key meeting
rhythm and a team that's aligned around
the same kind of goals. It's important
to have your vision in one spot. I
learned this from Mark Benioff in his
book Into the Cloud. He always had this
card that he'd show every single person
in his company the mission, the vision,
and their core goals. And so, I think
it's important that you have things
centralized, right? Producing
world-class content, building folks'
social media machine, and then really
just keeping them on board forever
because the product is so damn good,
right? We want to be the Apple of
founder distribution, the standard, the
reference point, the brand every serious
founder is proud to be associated with,
the system they credit with helping them
make a million, 5 million, even 10
million dollars, right? That's what I'm
after. And so, when we look at the kind
of stuff we're building, right? I
mentioned it's all around building your
social media machine, right? And
for me, the genesis of Founder OS, which
OS stands for operating system, it also
stands for open source, right? And the
really origin of Founder OS was giving
away all these systems that I had used
over the previous 18 years of building
companies. Now, these days, I think that
systems have become skills, right? And I
believe that my brain can be poured into
an orchestrator. And so, when folks join
Founder OS, we're giving them
essentially my brain and all the skills
I used to run my autonomous business,
okay? And so, that's what this is all
about inside at Founder OS Velocity. If
you're interested, what happens when you
join is that we do an intake form, learn
every single piece of your business.
You're uploading all your core
documents, things like your brand
positioning, your content, your
platforms, your website, your offer,
your pricing. So, we learn everything
about it. From there, we do a brand deep
dive call, and then we deliver your
brand positioning, right? So, you have
content pillars, your founder narrative.
You really know how to go and own your
own corner of your market. One core
tenant we have internally is always
going the extra mile for founders,
right? And we want to have that like
Four Seasons, like Ritz-Carlton level of
like luxury founder experience in what
we do.
And so, you know, it's giving people
things like their content waterfall, um
and not just getting access to me. What
typically happens is founders are going
to go work directly with me, and then
they go and get access to my team. Folks
like Nick to help their marketing team,
Diego to help people like their video
strategist. Um we have Claire to help
them on the op side. Um really make
ensure that we're building leverage
around the founder, right? So, that um
they truly do get to remove themselves
from operations and have their whole
real leadership team get up-leveled
inside of FounderOS. And so, you know, a
dedicated advisor, their social media
machine, and their entire team getting
trained. If that's interesting to you,
you can go and check out FounderOS
Velocity and go and join via the link in
the description. We'll get on a brief
call, learn what your business is all
about, maybe what's constraining you
right now, and see how we can help. So,
that is how to go and run your ops
machine to scale.
Hope this been helpful. If you're
interested in learning how to build a
business that runs itself, you should go
and check out this next video. I'll see
you over there. Thanks so much for
watching. Be sure to like and subscribe,
and let's win together.