imagine running a $13 million business
while traveling the world no burnout no
12-hour workdays well that's my reality
right now and in this video I'm going to
break down the seven core hires that
I've made over the years to help me get
to over $1 13 million across my
portfolio of online businesses let's get
into it all right so the first hire that
really is transformed my business is the
chief of staff you know the chief of
staff is someone that can really help
you go and manage all of your operations
so that you can work on your business
and not be stuck in your business so
we're going to get into the task the
kpis growth systems cash and results
that this hire is responsible for and
then do the same for each of the
different key hires that you need to
make to get the $13 million a year the
task that the chief of staff is in
charge of they're like the CEO of your
calendar okay so
all scheduling my chief of staff who's
actually my sister Claire behind the
camera is in charge of making sure that
my calendar is all clean all my mornings
are blocked off for 4 hours of deep work
which is my sacred time where I can go
deep and go and work on things that only
I can do and then I like to go and batch
all of my meetings on Tuesdays so from
around 9:00 a.m. till 6:00 p.m. sales
meetings team meetings one to ones team
jams all that stuff all happen in that
block on a Tuesday so that the rest of
my week is relatively free the next
aspect here is all you know kind of
communication so this includes like
internal communication around different
you know events going on different team
updates team meetings initiatives it
also includes external communication so
my chief of staff is managing all of my
emails um any core updates that we need
to send different partners or the
founders that we help at founder OS on
where we're helping Founders scale to $5
million and Beyond using proven systems
for audience brand in Revenue Grove the
next aspect here is also being the
expert sort of project manager and for
us we use a sauna at founder OS as an
example we have our Tech team design
team writers designers the list goes on
and all of these different teams have
different projects going on our
website's being updated we're running a
big Mastermind event in Sedona in a
month here all of these projects need to
be meticulously managed with key owners
dates and subtask so that they get done
on time and the team is held accountable
to hit those key deadlines ASA is the
project management tool that we use for
all of this now the core kpi for this
role I would say there's one company kpi
and then one more kind of soft kpi so
the main company kpi is essentially
getting my time
back and typically what I'm looking for
is it getting at least 20 hours of my
time back per week
the next kpi that really matters for
this role I want to make sure that if
everything's running smoothly the team's
going well we're making good hires we're
managing things like scheduling
communication and auna right I want to
be able to sleep at night okay and
so the reality is you bring on a chief
of staff to be able to lower your stress
levels and this person is largely also
in charge of your well-being you know on
one side of things you could have a
chief of staff that's just scheduling
meetings all over the place you're not
able to get into a rhythm you're not
getting good sleep at night you're not
able to get into a creative flow on the
other side you have someone that is
intentionally scheduling your meetings
is locking down internal communication
is making sure that your life is running
smoothly and that your company is
scaling peacefully and inevitably what
that allows you to do is just feel more
freedom in life now in terms of the
growth areas that they're most in charge
of it depends on the kind of chief of
staff that you're looking high but in my
business I have my chief of staff most
focused on growing the founder
experience and so my chief of staff has
a little bit of a bent towards founder
success customer success and the actual
product itself if you find that your
company needs more attention on Tech you
may find a chief of staff that has that
sort of leaning towards Tech or if you
find that you need to be making more
sales and that's an area that you're
maybe a little weak in you may find a
chief of staff that has a bent towards
sales for me founder experience is at
the heart of everything that we do at
founder OS our vision is to create the
greatest founder experience of the 21st
century and so I want to make sure that
my chief of staff has a bent towards
founder success and so we'll put that
down the next aspect here are systems
when I think about a chief of staff I
think the core thing that really matters
in this role is number one the person
needs to be a down [\h__\h] number
two they need to take extreme ownership
and number three they need to be an
expert project manager so the core thing
here is I have my chief of staff in
charge of all the systems around ass
sauna and essentially making sure that
each project has core systems around it
and is running smoothly essentially
quarterbacking our project management
systems if auna is running smoothly
there's core owners for every single
task that we have going on we have key
due dates being hit the team is being
held accountable all of the projects are
running smoothly being hit on time and
delivering on the core kpis so an
example of this is like I mentioned in a
month we're running a massive experience
in Sedona with 120 legendary Founders
this is this unbelievable Summit of the
biggest Founders and creators in the
world all coming together to trade
inside secrets and help one another
level up their businesses now as you can
imagine that is one massive project we
got to fly our team out there we got to
organize accommodation
we got to actually find the venue we got
to make sure all the programming is
tight around it that all the founders
are taking care of to say it's just some
big project would actually be an
understatement right this thing's
massive the chief of staff is really in
charge of making sure that every single
piece of that experience goes smoothly
so it is executed flawlessly now when it
comes to cash my core metric as the CEO
generally comes down to the numbers the
people and the culture and when it comes
to cash flows you know we're just trying
to make sure that the cash in bank is
growing and hitting the goals that we
have I see too many people get caught up
over Revenue right revenue is cool cash
is obviously a lot cooler and so the key
thing here is making sure that you have
core profit goals in your company right
in my companies we operate every single
company at a 70% plus profit margin and
as such we go and model out you know
where the cash in Bank should be on a
month-to-month basis that's what I'm
focused on amongst other things and on
the results side so well none all that
different than the kpis here right we
want to make sure that we have
accountability across the
team and we also want to make sure again
that there's just a peaceful amount of
scaling going on across the company so I
think it's
peace and a calm
company so this is roughly how I look at
the chief of staff role and so the next
role we're going to move on to is
the social manager I think one of the
most underrated roles in any company I
talked to so many Founders and they're
like oh I can probably just go hire
someone you know an EA overseas they
could just handle all this this is easy
enough truth be told I think being a
social manager is one of the most tricky
and difficult taxing roles in a company
especially these days when every single
company is a media company you should be
creating organic content growing an
audience owning your audience in an
email list and monetizing that audience
via amazing compelling High converting
scroll stopping content so let's get
into it first off the task that the
social manager are most in charge of
right is making sure that all content is
properly scheduled so we're going to put
content
scheduling contrary to popular belief I
don't think that the social manager
should be in charge of creating content
I'm going to show you who I leave to
that a little bit later on in this video
but most importantly they should be in
charge of actually scheduling the
amazing content that your team has
already created now that may sound easy
but the truth is across multiple
platforms if they're doing you know X
LinkedIn YouTube Tik Tok you know maybe
threads and IG they're going to be
driving all these people via
ctas to your newsletter you know that's
no ordinary job and the core thing here
is that if you're doing this correctly
right and you are going in putting out
High converting content across all
platforms driving people to your
newsletter and to your offer you are
going to make a lot of money my social
manager is in charge of bringing in
around $3 million of Revenue every
single year right just based on the core
actions that they're doing at the top of
funnel the kpi for this hire is a lot
different than what most people think
earlier on in my career I used to think
that this person was in charge of social
growth I've changed my mind on this over
the years and you made disagree but I
actually think that this person's most
in charge of just making sure that we
post on
time and with no
airs when you think about a high output
content strategy across X LinkedIn
YouTube Tik Tok threads IG you're going
to have a certain time of day that you
post on each platform at X you may post
at 8:06 a.m. and 2 p.m. on LinkedIn at
8:03 a.m. on IG at noon and at 6:05 p.m.
on YouTube every Sunday at 1 p.m. and so
on this person is basically the CEO of
distribution they are not in charge of
the actual content creation so what does
that mean you can't really go and judge
them totally on just the social growth
because they're not that ones actually
creating the content that's some other
core roles we're going to go over here
in a sec and so if they're not creating
the content how can they be solely
responsible for the social growth maybe
you're just making bad content and
that's the reason why you're not growing
as fast as you want so we want to make
sure that we're actually giving people
kpis that they can actually control so
let's move on to the growth side I think
the growth here that they really control
are your
ctas ctas stand for call to actions and
across each platform when you add them
all up there are around 18 core call to
action areas that you need to go and
make sure you have implemented correctly
across each of the platforms to make
sure they are as profitable as possible
so on link in that's things like your
cover photo Link in BIO featured section
the end of a given post on X that's your
link in BIO your cover photo and at the
end of a given post on Instagram that's
your stories that is in your bio that's
at the end of a given post you can drive
people to your newset drive people do an
offer there are these core points in
every single platform we want to make
sure that we have the CTA set up and
that in every single piece of content we
are driving people to a core call to
action which for the most part should be
your new newsletter my newsletter at
founder is the only newsletter that you
need to grow your personal brand and we
give out one free system every single
Saturday to help you grow your brand and
your business and so for me part of my
organic content funnel ensures that I'm
driving people from my social platforms
via the ctas to my newsletter when you
have that set up correctly you have a
Formula 1 engine in your business and
the social manager is the driver let's
move on to the systems that this
person's most in charge of I want to
make sure that every Friday I'm getting
the core metrics from this person
understanding all of the growth that's
going on across all platforms and also
understanding what are the core pieces
of content that are working that we can
double down on and what are different
Trends they're seeing so that they're
bubbling up different ideas of what we
could go and create next we'll put here
I want to have an ideation system in
place I want to have my metric system in
place any other core insights that
they're seeing out there and so the core
systems that this role is in charge of
are your ideation your insights in your
metrics every Friday you're ideally
getting 30 High converting content ideas
understanding what stuff is working and
what's not working so you can double
down on the 20% of your content that's
doing well and eliminate the trends that
are not performing well and from there
just looking at the metrics to then
double down and keep growing across all
platforms now as far as cash goes right
this person via the call to actions is
going to help you go and hit your
application goals or your marketing
qualified leads goals right so some
people would call that
mqls in my business we call it
applications essentially you can just
think of this as
leads now in terms of results when this
is being done right you're essentially
just growing your overall Revenue
because you've got high quality
applications coming in and you're
hitting your goals and so from here you
know everyone in my
company at found us an example is
focused on getting to that $1 million of
Revenue per month okay and like IID
mentioned this role right now is
currently over the last 12 months driven
over $3 million to my businesses all
right so the next role that we have
going on here is another underrated role
that I think a lot of people they rush
and they screw it up it is the tech
manager this is the person in charge of
making sure that all the pieces of the
are all running smoothly here we go and
first off on the task side you know for
me in my business there's really Three
core platforms this person's taken care
of number one convert kit convertkit is
the newsletter platform that we use to
manage all of my newsletter at founder
OS and it's also a core piece of our
funnel the second aspect is web
flow my entire website runs off webflow
we chose webflow for founder west.com to
make sure that everything was beautiful
it's super flexible it's easy to use my
tech manager manages web flow and all
the Integrations with webflow convert
kit and then the third thing here is
HubSpot HubSpot is the platform that we
use as our CRM to manage all of the
leads that are coming in and then the
pipeline of those leads turning into
customers turning into referers and it's
the way that we use to scale our Revenue
right so HubSpot super core platform the
combination of HubSpot web FL and
convert kit it's not only that the tech
manager is setting these things up but
making sure that each of them are
integrated properly so that we can see
you know what lead is coming from what
page on our site or what email they
visited that caused them to convert to
HubSpot and become a lead and then
convert into customers so what this
allows us to do is over time get a lot
smarter with our content we can start to
see a certain customer came because of
this YouTube video or because of this
newsletter and then we can start to
understand that Journey that they've had
before buying and then double down on
the content that we're seeing work the
next aspect here is the kpi similar to
you know the sales team I actually just
view this person as helping us drive our
Revenue
goals this revenue kpi is important
because I actually have my tech manager
have a bit of a sales bent to them okay
I want to have someone that's helping us
make sure Hub spots running smoothly
they're working really closely with my
sales guys to ensure that they're
enabled they're empowered that all the
little icies of HubSpot are engineered
immaculately so that we're able to go
and hit our monthly Revenue goals at our
company right now this is 1 million per
month at founder at my other companies
we're already doing that the growth side
then is we want to make sure that as we
continue to scale up these different
platforms that everything is running
smoothly without any issues right we
want to have zero downtime on Tech right
anything you know screwing up breaking
we're trying to reduce all that and then
they're just executing the tech road map
inside of a sauna we've gone and
outlined all the core projects we have
going on so maybe we have Pages coming
out for Black Friday Cyber Monday maybe
we're putting out some low ticket offers
you know there's constantly just
different things that we're running
right different experiments and the
speed of your Tech shipping is dictating
largely the speed of your product
velocity right the speed at which you're
able to ship new things we simply go and
outline our entire Tech road map into
different swim Lanes in a sauna this
person is really in charge of making
sure that we are shipping things on time
at a very high quality on terms of the
system side really what I want them
doing is all of the systems in this area
right so in charge of our convert kit
content GPS which is the core system
that we have at founder OS that has
allowed us to scale to over $8 million
of the last year right and convert kit
hooks into our content GPS which again
is the most powerful system I've ever
discovered and we then link that in to
our HubSpot systems so we're able to
track people from convertkit in our
content whoops to HubSpot our CRM and
continue to double down on the content
that we're seeing work best in terms of
cash this Revenue goal right so a
million per month and then on the result
side I want to make sure that we are
pushing the envelope right so that we
are going and charting out an aggressive
Tech road map of different improvements
that we could be making so for me right
now you know I want to make sure that we
have impeccable Black Friday Cyber
Monday I want to make sure that we have
a good book funnel going on as I'm
releasing a book in the very near future
so you're going to want to check that
out and then I want to make sure that
the overall founder OS funnel is working
great if you want to go and check it out
and you even want to join founder you
can go check this out and go and take
this funnel for a spin at founder os.com
slash trining and you can go and even
see how we've set this up and the cool
thing is at founder OS we actually go
and install this content
GPS in your business for you and so if
you're interested in actually going and
having all of this system plus the stuff
I'm about to go over installed in your
business for you you should go check
that out because uh it's my life's work
and we know what we're doing so the next
aspect here in the next role is the
closer all right so the closer is the
rain maker in your business you know
there's a drastic difference between
someone that's able to make that bank
account or someone that just cannot
bring in anything an amazing closer is
going to be able to close at like a 33%
or Beyond close rate too many Founders
make a mistake okay they try to bring on
a closer though before they've even
proven out the script themself you need
to make sure that you've gone and you've
created your own pitch script on how
you're going to run the discovery
process on a given call which is
generally around 20 minutes how you're
going to go and actually do the pitch
process of a call which is another 20
minutes and then how you're going to
actually overcome any objections that
come up which is around 20 minutes to
make up an hour call the big thing here
right is closing begins when objections
begin too many people think that oh just
because they've gone and pitched
something the prospect's instantly going
to say yes that's not how it works right
so you need to make sure you have that
all ironed out you've got that process
ripping you are able to close at ideally
a 30% close rate and Beyond so that when
you go and you bring on a closer they
can simply just follow your proven
process and make you money the task that
The Closer is in charge of they just
need to get on calls and close deals it
ain't rocket science now the third
aspect of this though is I think what
makes an amazing closer and that is
follow-ups
a real Jedi on the closing side has that
insane follow-up game you know
inevitably there are some people that
they don't close on a call the question
is do you follow through now there's a
guy named John on my team a closer
absolute Legend you know just yesterday
I was checking out slack and he had gone
and followed up with someone like 13
times and eventually went and closed
that lead you know that is the mark of
someone that really gives a [\h__\h] right
that doesn't just take not for an answer
that doesn't just let a lead go by the
wayside it's about staying on top of
things right we have a duty as a team to
serve those that need what we do so the
core kpi here right is really just you
know deal is closed you know for me at
founder OS as an example we want to make
sure these people are closing 30 plus
deals per
month when they're doing that they're
helping go and feed the engine of found
which is organic content syst sys the
mentorship that we provide helping
Founders install their organic content
GPS and the list goes on right and so
the more that you're able to go and make
sure you have a great closer the more
cash flow you have in your company right
which is going to go and kind of be the
fuel to you increasing your marketing on
the growth side what you really want to
see from this person is that they're
being a student of the game and they're
contributing to the overall culture of
the sales team I want to have someone
that has like you know high energy and
contributes to an insane
culture I talked a lot about this right
at founder OS we have two main cultural
values number one you must be a down
[\h__\h] and number two you must
take extreme ownership and so what I
want to see from this person is that
they are embodying that right they're
helping Fuel and energize the team you
know we have a slack channel that is
called Revenue inside of foundos and all
of my portfolio companies and anytime a
deal is closed by a closer that then is
fed in automatically to that channel and
then the whole team is chiming in
congratulating now on the system side I
want them going and helping really with
two things okay I want them to invol
evolve our pitch okay and the system
around our pitch what are different
things that are hot buttons that are
really working for the people that we're
selling and how do we lean into that
more what are parts that are not really
resonating and how do we remove those
and also remove those aspects maybe even
of our product a closer is on calls with
maybe 30 people 40 people a week right
so the amount of customer feedback
they're getting is pretty insane so I
like to have a tight Loop between sales
and products sales and customer success
so we can be evolving things at an
insane rate now the next aspect here is
a little bit more on the admin side but
super important is
HubSpot
okay I want to make sure that they are
actively updating their deals inside of
HubSpot and sharing any feedback with my
tech manager on how we can make things
easier for them on the cash side it's
really for me the 30 deals per month
right and the cash flow that that brings
in to founder as an example and same
thing at my other companies like her
bonus points here okay the basic rule on
incentives is you get what you reward
for so if you have a dumb incentive
system you get dumb outcomes Charlie
Munger talks about the fact that humans
are incentive machines well the key
thing is that in any given role in your
company think about what really
motivates these people what fires them
up so for a closer they're probably
motivated
in part by money on the result side here
inevitably what's going on is we've just
got a well oiled Sales
Machine Sales is the lifeblood of your
company when you're managing a closer
you want to really make sure there's
three things in play okay you want to
make sure number one that you have
morning meetings with them every single
day initially so that they're properly
scaling your business number two they
should be sending endof day reports on
how each of their calls went and any
deals they closed and any feedback or
help they need from you and the third
thing is you want to make sure they
clear projections you've gone and
outlined maybe that they're going to
close 30 deals per month so how many of
they projecting that they're going to
close every single week so you're
keeping these tight feedback loops right
you're not letting a team suddenly miss
a deal or a goal over a quarter and then
wondering oh man what happened there
let's do better next quarter no no no no
you need to tighten those feedback loops
so that you're getting at least 10%
better every single week and when you
compound that over a year we're talking
like getting 100 times better across
your company the next role I think is
actually the most important role in your
company and most people would be shocked
it is a role we call the setter a Setter
is someone that's actually going in
setting deals or setting calls for the
closer so the tasks here are simple
right they are setting high quality
calls say your closer can do say six a
day five days a week right you're doing
roughly 30 calls per week right so if
you have your closer closing at 30%
Beyond right they're closing roughly you
know 10 deals a week that are being set
by the setter and there we go we got a
welled machine going here and we are
destined to hit some serious Revenue
goals on the kpi side so getting to
their 30 high quality calls per week we
want to probably give them depending on
how you're generating leads maybe it's a
certain amount of DMS they're sending
okay or it could be calls they're making
or cold emails so whatever is the core
action that is above getting the call
set up you want to make sure that that
quantity is there so as an example let's
just say that cold email is the core
thing and the way that you're going and
driving high quality calls so you may
have your Setter making sure that
they're reaching out to a certain amount
of people via email getting on a certain
amount of setting calls with those
people qualifying them making sure
they're good and then putting that on
The Closer calendar on the growth side
what you want to have happen here is
that this person is really helping you
with all of the different scripts so
number one is I want to make sure that
person's helping me with all the
different scripts that are on the calls
or in the cold emails or the DM scripts
and making sure that those are high
quality the second thing is super
underrated okay and this is I want them
to help come up with content ideas for
me because they are on all of these
calls with people and they're seeing why
are these people interested right
because founder OS we actually don't
even need to have Setters outreaching to
people right because we get inundated
with leads we have more leads that we
can keep up with well we need is a
Setter to sort through all these leads
and go and make sure that we're getting
on the calls with the people that make
the most sense for the community that
we're building at founder OS what I want
to go and have them do is they're going
to be on all these calls they're going
to understand okay what are the core
Trends going on among the founders that
are best suited for founder OS and maybe
things like you know a lot of Founders
are looking to save more time in their
week they're looking to learn delegation
they want to build a high performance
team they want to build their own
personal Media Company they're going to
Bubble Up what do these core problems or
things they're hearing from Founders and
then I'm going to go and create content
with my team around that kind of stuff
which is then going to just attract more
highquality leads that the setter can
then set with the closer on the system
side we want to make sure that
essentially just the call booking system
is nailed making sure that that closer
is getting on calls you can use cly for
this you can use HubSpot for this and
just make sure that all the calls are
booked properly we're just moving people
through a sales pipeline incredibly
smoothly efficiently on the cash side
they're really getting those 30 calls
per week which again they ladder up to
the million dollar month goal that we
have in my business right so 30 calls
per week and that in drives right the 1
million a month on the result side when
it's going correctly you know they're
hitting those 30 calls per week and on a
bigger side right I think that we've
tightly coupled content with sales and
when you do this you have
HCC which is the goal of every business
High converting content the setter is
going in letting you know what is the
content that is really resonating with
Founders the most that are most
qualified for what we do feeding that
back to the content team so that we can
go and scale our content media Empire
around the topics that people care about
the most that's this role the next role
we're going to get into is the writer
all right so the writer is someone
that's going to help you with a ton of
stuff across your media Empire things
like landing pages newsletters
converting emails all the different
pieces that require any sort of words
that convert are done immaculately
impeccably and done in a way that's
going to really convince people to buy
from you the core task here that a
writer is really in charge of are things
like your landing pages giving you a
hand with some of your Social
content and also handling your
newsletter the next aspect on the kpi
side okay so this person because they
actually have their hands on your
content depending on what you're getting
them to do you may want to make them in
charge of a certain open rate right and
clickthrough rate for your
newsletter on the social side depending
on what platform you're having them on
it could be say x you want to maybe have
you know an X follower growth goal you
want to make sure they're actually
driving you lead right or depending on
your business you make all that like
applications those are some kpis as I
see it they're driving people from a
newsletter to applications and driving
people then to actual sales of your
product the next aspect here is the
growth of this right the key thing here
whenever we're building any sort of
content business right is that we don't
want to come across as salesy it's
important that we actually build a brand
and so the growth here I just think is
someone that really is going and help
build brand affinity for founder OS my
goal is that you know what Apple's done
with sort of creativity and the 70s what
Nike did with athletes in the 80s is
what I want to do for Founders in the
2020s we want to be this community this
experience that helps make the founder
Journey Joyful We want to help Founders
and Empower them with the systems the
support and everything that we've
learned over 15 years building multiple
seven figure and eight figure businesses
to help unlock their potential so we
make sure that we have content scheduled
out months in advance which is the key
system that I make this person in charge
of which is the content calendar which
again we manage inside of a sauna and
the next aspect is the content waterfall
system so what we're able to do as a
team me and this writer we are able to
go and create content right that then
maybe starts off as a long form X thread
and then from that X thread becomes a
long form LinkedIn post becomes a
newsletter four weeks later becomes the
concept for a long form YouTube video we
can then break that up into three short
form videos that will go on things like
YouTube shorts Instagram reals and a Tik
Tok so the cool thing is that when we
nail One Core idea that one long form
piece of content can oftentimes become
24 more pieces of content Downstream my
goal with my entire content operation is
to create a Pixar for Founders keeping
things insanely simple and really
focusing on ideas that I wish I had
known four years ago or eight years ago
earlier on in my career we're primarily
making content for Founders that want to
go from being millionaires to
multi-millionaires so on the cash side
because this person is a high converting
content writer the big thing here is
leads and then backing that into the
revenue goal of a mam month so again
these writers right they're not just
people that are just making words up and
just driving followers right it's really
about dollars and making sure the
content that we write is tightly coupled
with sales and so that we are attracting
the right people to Any Given business
making things flow right keeping that
well oiled machine that we're really
after here so on the result side I think
there's two things okay one thing is
just overall growth right you should see
the platforms all growing nicely right
you should feel that your lead flow is
growing and that your newsletter is
growing the next thing is the thing that
actually brings me a lot of Joy okay
okay and I'm going to call that signal
when I'm going and creating any piece of
content it's not seeing that it gets
hundreds of thousands of views or
millions of views the thing that fires
me up the most getting a text from a
really amazing founder that I admire and
having them say you know what I love
that recent piece of content you just
put out Matt that's that piece let's
move on to the next role here the final
one here here we go this one is a role
that I've recently started to really
admire and believe that it's really one
of the most core roles you can have if
you're looking to get the 13 million a
year that role is the video editor your
video editor is your visual Storyteller
the tasks that they should be really
owning in any given week if it's YouTube
you're probably going to go and get them
to do one long form video per week and
maybe one trailer for that video as well
which would go and be like a short form
trailer that may appear on YouTube
shorts IG reals and on Tik Tok if you're
getting video editor for short form
video which is probably a different
video editor uh because you can only so
much output with one um so let's just
say it was IG you may do around four
short form videos per week so the kpi
here is we just want to make sure that
person is hitting the brand identity the
brand guidelines for each video and that
they're hitting the output goal okay so
it's the Brand Plus the output goal all
right I think that just purely giving
this person like a views goal or a
subscriber go growth goal it can be a
little bit shortsighted right you may
find that some of the the content ideas
that you really need to create are not
content ideas that are going to go viral
they're stuff that's more Niche more
specific more tailored to an exact
profile of person so I don't want to
make the video editor in charge of just
growing on the growth side for this I
want to again make sure that they're
really growing the kind of quality of
the videos by say 10% better every week
now I get it right this is a little bit
subjective but you can kind of start to
feel this over time right say you're
making videos for YouTube are the edits
getting better are the hooks getting
better is the scripting getting better
are the animations the Motion Graphics
are they tightening up the edits are you
seeing that the retention curve is
growing from maybe 30% of people
finishing a given video to now 70% are
finishing a given video right quality
can often times be seen by video
retention on the system side we want to
make sure that they're really owning and
helping you with the
workflow so the video workflow works
like this let's talk about YouTube for a
sec you're going and you're filming a
bunch of content right and then you're
uploading that say to a Google Drive and
then you're sending that over to the
video editor to then go and put together
like the actual first draft of the
actual story you want to get that back
in frame frame.io is what I use right to
make sure all of the edits are managed
smoothly and so
frame.io is what we use to make sure
that when the edit comes to me I can
then leave comments on things that I
want improved or made better from there
we then would have the final edit done
okay that's where they're implementing
any of my feedback and comments inside
of frame.io and they're going now and
adding different b-roll different cuts
to kind of like liven up the video and
make it that much more engaging on the
Cat Side the big thing here is that if
the videos are going great we're
probably generating leads from these
platforms right
so that's the thing that you want to go
and help them understand right is you
likely want to have unique tracking
links for each of the platforms that
they're on things like Instagram and
YouTube so that they can monitor each
week themselves and understand how that
video that they put out actually went
and drove high quality leads to the
business so what you probably want to
have is unique UTM links which are
basically tracking links where you can
identify where the leads are coming from
you're going to be able to understand
which platforms are driving you the
highest quality leads by making sure
that you're using uniquely identifiable
links then feeding that into some sort
of dashboard or Google sheet that your
video editor could just monitor every
week or so and just start to see okay
which edits that they did which hooks
they have done have led to the most high
quality leads and are generating your
cash flow goals on the result side I
think when you get this sort of stuff
right you should look back on videos you
did a month ago or two months ago and be
embarrassed ideally that growth rate of
the quality of the Artistry of the
storytelling the edits is growing at
such a great Pace right that 10% every
week that when you look back you're like
damn what were we thinking right that is
a sign of growth so the results here is
that you're just seeing a quality
increase over time I think it's just
that you're making content that you're
proud
of with the right video Eder on board
you really have an amazing partnering
crime that's helping you execute your
Creative Vision on the video side of
things and helping you take your brand
your business your audience to the next
level so those are the core seven roles
I'd recommend that you go and get after
it right away making sure you have these
hires in your business if you need help
that's what I'm here for go be sure to
subscribe to this Channel and I look
forward to seeing you in the next one
right here