This is how I replace 16 content hires
with a single voice memo. So, you know,
a decade ago at Herb, you know, I've
produced over 36,000 pieces of content
over the last, you know, 16 years
building media companies. And way back
in the day, I had like 16 people, you
know, SEO, branded folks, crazy
production teams. My new way at Founder
OS, we just keep it dead simple. It's
me, my CMO, Nick, and a video editor,
right? Same output. I would say way
higher quality, certainly more soulful,
better resonance, way higher converting,
way more cash flow, and it all comes
from a single voice memo. I go and
record my thoughts while I'm on a walk
in nature. I use that voice memo then in
Claude Code to transcribe it. I then go
and take it and format it for things
like carousels, for reals, for YouTube,
and for my newsletter each week. And
then I give it an edit the next day,
polish it up a little bit, and then just
let that puppy fly. Right? I've been
able to cut 40k plus of headcount from
this and have just a lean, mean,
profitable media team. This it's a
beautiful