Now, look. Cool thing is I still have
that icky guy. And what's changed? Well,
I've optimized this consistently now for
about 3 years. And it's trippy because
like I mean
I'm living it. Hiking, mountain biking,
living the dream, coaching founders, you
know, traveling the world, living the
dream, right? Like it's all coming true.
What will you do? I'm going to set my
personal brand on fire. At back here I
said I'd get my Twitter to 100k,
LinkedIn to 100k, email to 50k. Now my
Twitter's at 360k, LinkedIn's at 840k,
email's at 190k. Pretty insane. I said
I'd launch a social entrepreneurship
course. Well, now I run something called
Founder OS. Helping founders achieve
their dreams through proven systems. And
you know, that's what we're all about,
right? But you can see how small I was
starting here, right? I wanted to have a
community product bring me in 500k a
year. Now we do 10x that. You know, I
wanted to have, you know, yeah, two
masterminds a year in nature. We're now
doing that. I want to get Herb to around
autopilot. And now it does that, right?
The books I'm going to read. Again, you
can see I was always just investing in
books and upping my game in personal
development. You want to go and rise in
success, you have to rise as a leader.
And the way to rise as a leader is to
invest in personal development, right?
Personal development is the key to your
success because you need to upgrade
yourself. What I'm going to launch, you
know, all these things, right? You can
just see what I was learning back then.
What I'm going to write, you know,
website copy, all this good stuff.
Business 30-day goals, personal 30-day
goals, what went well, right? I, you
know, upgraded my game. What didn't go
well? I was still, you know, lots of
things didn't improve. What did I learn?
And that's that.