I just got off a call with five founders
in my community, Founder OS, and they
had some problems that were insanely
sticky. And you'll get to see those in a
second. But I went over four core
systems that will help them become
unignorable this year and get over some
of the trickiest problems they're
currently facing in their business. Now,
these are aspects that range from
everything from where AI is going all
the way through to how to go and
leverage systems and people in your
business to stand out this year. Let's
dive in. All right, guys. Well, happy
Tuesday. Hope everyone's doing well. Uh
the format it's pretty simple. Um you
guys have questions on your mind,
whether it's challenges in your
business, constraints, opportunities
that you want some help and insights on.
Anything's fair game. Nothing's offside.
Um and uh we can all just chop it up and
and grow here together. So without
further ado, we can go any direction
with this. Um is there anything on
people's minds that they want to kick it
off with? So prior to joining the
program, I was traditionally run a
marketing agency primarily in the niche
of of dentists convinced me to go down
the consulting path and to instead of uh
doing what we're doing, we teach people
how to do what we're doing. So sort of
give them the insiders scoop into how an
agency works and teach dentists how to
manage and control their own profit. And
this week, well two weeks ago, there was
been some push from the governing body
here in Australia for who look after the
medical industry and they've changed all
of the advertising guidelines. So all of
the things that I know that I've been
using for marketing the last 15 years in
terms of building social proof, all of
those have kind of been now pushed
aside. And so what direction do I now
take the consulting business? Because my
background in marketing has been a lot
of emotive language and you know the
psychology of sales and things like that
and even those sorts of words like even
in ad copy you're not even allowed to
use emojis anymore. Yeah. Inevitably
over the last I think 5 years there's
been a new trend as you know the
internet and online businesses take a
whole new shape and form and that is
compliance. Most people don't even think
about this but the 2000s were like the
invention of the internet. 2010s kind of
like the wild west of things being built
but now things are getting more and more
regulated in the 2020s. You're going to
see compliant marketing becoming more of
a thing. And this is something that I
see a lot of people struggling with. And
so inside this next clip, I share my
current perspective on this and how you
can actually use compliance to become
your new competitive advantage. Like I
actually see this as being a big trend
for a lot of industries over the next
like 20 years. I think we've gone from
like websites and online being a thing
in the 2000s to then like it being the
wild west in the 2010s to now like it's
been out long enough that like consumer
safety and consumer awareness and
legalities and policies and all this are
like more important than ever more and
more like compliance is going to be a
thing in a lot of these different areas
right you see it whether you're talking
about dentists in Australia or you even
see it on like Hormos's recent workshop
for $100 million money models as an
example, like compliance is being done
in all of these different spaces. So, I
think the only thing that is inevitable
in a lot of our spaces is that like
compliance is really important versus
[clears throat] like resisting it, like
finding the opportunity in it. You can
also be sure that I think 97% of people
will just ignore it. And meanwhile, if
you're like a student of the game and
just embrace it, you're kind of already
just from that mindset in like an elite
group of people.
>> Yeah. It kind of positions us as the
authority as well. I was kind of like,
we we know what what's happening and we
know what the rules are. We're going to
help guide you through it.
>> If they get on the phone with another
agency and they're like, we don't we
don't even know what these guidelines
are that you're talking about because
they're just generic and look after so
many different industries.
>> Yeah. And I would be pointing out with
them. I'd say, hey, listen, I just was
looking at things. Um, and I I found
these three issues in your area. Like I
would consider finding a VA, giving the
VA like a few audit areas that they
should look for with every dentist and
then sending customized emails to each
person that point out three areas where
they're offside cuz it's such a burning
thing. It's like if right now you're
offside and the rules and regulations
say that if in a month it's not fixed,
you're find $10,000 a day, like you got
to fix that now. And so they got to get
on a call with you now. It's more of a
burning pain than ever.
>> No, hold on. Yeah. as you're building
every single different professional or
expert out there, it's probably governed
by someone. And it's important that on
any platform you're in or any career
path you take, right, you're obviously
abiding by the rules and regulations
there. You know, you may look to the
left or look to the right at competitors
that are not doing things compliantly,
but don't think that that's the way that
you should go. I think that as founders,
if we want to build something
anti-fragile for the long term, we got
to play by the rules, right? We got to
have integrity and just put stuff out
there that we can feel proud of and that
we can sleep at night knowing that we've
done a great job. When it comes to
compliant marketing as an example, you
know, it's always good to understand the
parameters at which you can work in and
especially if you're helping other
people with their marketing or their
growth, it's imperative that you know
you're an expert on those rules so that
you're not only abiding by them
yourself, but you can also help others
leverage them as well. So I think you
are at a crossroads, right? There's two
ways you go. One is like you use this as
an opportunity. The game has changed.
The rules are different now. It's almost
like a whole new blow blue ocean. I
actually think that m that opportunity
is massive. And this is probably like
almost in a weird way could be like the
best thing to ever happen to you. On the
other side of it, it's like, okay, like
I like to use my tactics. I like to use
emotive language. I like to use before
and afters. That's how I do things. This
niche no longer allows for that. I'm
going to move into a niche that does
allow for it and keep the playbook and
just move it to a different space.
There's a multitude of ways you could
go, but those are like two simplistic
ways. Personally, my dad's a dentist.
The last thing these guys know is
marketing. He just knows teeth. That's
the opportunity. Like, they're not going
to know compliant marketing and how to
adapt this. And they're probably doing
things even better. They're uncompliant
right now. So, that's the opportunity.
It's not even to help them grow. It's
that they're offside currently. So,
like, you have to get them like reduce
the risk they probably currently have
because there's probably a lot of stuff
that's going on now that's no longer
allowed. and then setting them up to
then do the stuff that is allowed in a
in the best way possible. There are
really two kinds of businesses as we
look at over the next decade. This
compliance thing is going to become more
and more of a trend as more of the
internet gets more regulated. There's
more rules and laws and all that and
versus thinking it's something that's
working against you. Future founders
actually see it as the wind in their
sales. An opportunity to create a whole
new blue ocean in your space and a new
area that you can compete on while
everyone else gets left behind.
>> I know what I need to do.
>> Yeah, that's great.
>> Anything on your mind, Dave? Like on a
similar note or related note?
>> Kind of. This is a new chapter of my
journey. My background is e-commerce.
I've been doing that for years now, but
it just it feels so fragile. I want to
be in a business where it doesn't feel
like Amazon could turn me off tomorrow
or I'm I'm like at the risk of just
external factors. So,
>> just to kind of riff on that for a sec,
right? Like I do think that all of us
founders, right, desire this kind of
like antifragile business. We've all
been there, right? Like you, you know,
you start your first business, your
first offer, whatever. It's kind of
slapped together and suddenly you start
like feeling just like the whims of like
customer needs and market shifts and you
know ups and downs and peaks and valleys
and you know suddenly yeah you start to
desire something that's like more
secure. It's more stable, good margins,
peaceful operations, streamlined systems
and like a great team. as you're
thinking and probably we're all thinking
about building like more anti-fragile
businesses. One aspect is obviously like
the people as you're looking to build
leverage as a founder, your team is the
number one thing that you can optimize.
I hear all the time from founders, how
do I hire? How do I fire? How do I
optimize my team? How do I remove myself
from my team? There's so much there,
right? And when you can crack the code
on the different pieces of constructing
a high performance team, you unlock new
levels of being able to really
accomplish the mission you're after with
the business you're creating. And I hear
questions about team all the time. You
know, the power of any company is the
power of the team you create. I've just
been watching this documentary on the
Dallas Cowboys on Netflix and you know,
Jerry Jones is an absolute legend. And
when you think about, you know, any
sports team, if you as a founder are
building a sports team, you'd be like
the owner of that sports team. You're
building your own like fantasy team
roster. And inevitably, you know, you
have your high performers that you want
to be, you know, doubling down on. You
want to make sure that you're investing
in these people. you're understanding,
you know, what else they think they can
contribute to the organization. So that
basically the organization is
frictionless and you're just allowing
those people to rise to the highest
point they can go to in their lives
because your team, your brand, your
company only benefits from those high
performers. On the other side though,
you got the low performers, right? And
often times, you know, we just let these
people kind of stick around. There's a
statistic that around 7 months is the
average amount of time that a CEO allows
a low performer to stay on board before
removing them. 7 months. Yeah, that's a
long time. So, what do you do? Now, I'm
about to share in this next clip, I show
you how to go and actually rank your
team so you can build your fantasy
roster by having people that are above
the red line and below the red line and
then how to handle those folks so that
they don't become a parasite to your
growth. You guys have probably heard
like the adage like the kind of person
that gets you to maybe five million a
year isn't the kind of person that gets
you to 20 million a year or the kind of
person that gets you to 100k a month
maybe isn't the kind of person that gets
you to 500k a month at every stage like
you need to be auditing your team
constantly what people are like
embodying the values what people are
performing what I'll often times do is
like rank my team from just best to
worst around this time of the year
approaching like November December
sometimes what I'll do too depending on
how I'm feeling is put like a red line
in that Google sheet and there's people
below the line and above the line. Below
the line typically if you're building
something right and say you have a 20
person team hopefully there's not more
than like four people max below the red
line. But as you approach like October,
November, December, it's a good chance
to maybe cut everyone below the red line
and start to kind of like replace them
now with the new people that hopefully
are near the top 10% of that document.
So you're just kind of constantly going
and building like an anti-fragile team,
right? Cutting the dead weight and
bringing on the people that are going to
help like propel it forward and the
people that give you peace of mind and
less problems, all that good stuff. You
know, as November is just around the
corner here and you're looking to go and
determine, you know, who are your A
players, B players, and then who's below
that red line. What I went and created
was my team ranking OS. This is how you
can go and rank your team from best to
worst, right? and then make some tough
decisions going into 2026 to make sure
that you're set up for success. So, you
can go that check that out via the link
in the description. Go and rank your
team, determine who's below the red
line, and then you can go watch my other
video on how to fire without being a
dick. So, go enjoy that. The last thing
I'll say on this quick and then Billy
will get to you is like one question I
always ask myself and I will say that
sometimes it's something I need to check
myself on cuz it can borderline on
giving you anxiety. So you have to kind
of thread the needle here and keep it
like a productive worry, not a
destructive worry, which is Charlie
Mer's inversion technique. We live in a
culture where entrepreneurs are
constantly trying to grow, grow, grow,
right? Get to that next revenue
milestone. 10x the business, 5x the
business, all this stuff. But one thing
I don't think that gets talked about
enough is Charlie Munger's inversion
technique, which simply is asking
yourself, how could I fail, right?
Versus always thinking about how
successful you could be. You know, think
about your downside and looking at the
different risk points across your
business, the different ways that you
could fail. Start ranking them from the
ones that are, you know, the most
pressing to the least, and then start to
work through those aspects one by one.
You may do a session where you just
write down all your failure points and
then start to rank your failure points.
So like what's the one that feels like
the most pressing that you could solve?
Like number one is like I don't keep up
with the regulations and I become you
know an extinct marketing agency. So
he's like okay I'm going to be like the
best student of these regulations. I'm
going to get the best compliance lawyer
in Australia around these. I'm gonna
create the best program around it and
the best mentorship around it and the
best brand around it that's like
certified and it's like okay now we've
derisked that failure point now okay
next failure point and then what happens
is you've looked at some of these
failure points you've mitigated or
solved them so what are you left with
hopefully upside because all the areas
that would cause you to your downfall
you've looked after those inevitably if
you can protect yourself against all the
different downside risks in your venture
you give yourself the maximum potential
to just only leave upside left. And so
this technique is something that I often
see founders ignoring. Unfortunately, I
see a lot of people ignoring it to their
own peril. And so I think it's something
that you should be aware of to avoid
disaster. When I'm talking to founders,
one of the things that inevitably comes
up in any conversation is AI. And more
founders are wondering, you know, how do
I defend myself against it? How do I
protect my business against it? There's
this impending doom. they feel like I
like to think of it kind of like this
barbell technique. What you have on one
side is using technology to its maximum
degree. So as an example, if you're
building a community, you may actually
leverage agents to go and deliver part
of the value inside that community.
That's one way of leveraging AI for its
maximum benefit. Now on the other side
of the spectrum, right, you have going
almost the other side which is like
super offline and like anti- AI things
like in-person retreats, doing things
off-rid, you know, an example with
marketing would be like sending
handwritten letters to people in your
community. I think the area that gets
tricky is the middle, which is
everything else. People that are just
doing business the old way. Yeah,
there's a lot of stuff in between those
two extremes that is going to get
replaced. I think there's also three
things to think about that are
essentially irreplaceable as far as I
can see it over the next decade. Well, I
think that there are like three things I
don't see AI competing with on the same
level as humans say over the next like 5
years. Those three things being taste,
authenticity, and creativity. On the
taste side, that's like your own unique
approach to your branding. your brand is
like your way, the way you're trying to
get it to show up. AI can come up with
amazing ideas and ways of doing it, but
taste is like knowing that like, oh,
that's not quite right. It needs to be
not this, but this, right? And so that
taste is always going to be needed. Like
people are like, oh, AI video is going
to take over the world. It's like, have
you seen AI video? Like at least for
this the next bit, like some digital
version of me is going to be speaking
and doing YouTube videos and people are
going to be like, yeah, I love watching
digital, Matt. I don't see that
happening for like a few years to be
dead honest with you. Second is the most
important one which is authenticity.
What will happen is like a lot of AI
generated stuff kind of feels knockoff
like it's not the real thing. So like
what actually makes you you and like
what makes humans human? It's like we
make mistakes, we use ums and a's a
little bit we have that kind of like
wobbby nature, right? Like we're very
imperfect. The last thing there just is
in creativity, right? like the next
Scorsesei film being made 100% by AI, I
don't think it's going to happen. I
think AI can be used to come up with
creative ideas. Don't get me wrong, I
use it all the time. But that said,
human creativity is its own magical
machine. You know, you create something,
you know, by hand, whether it's, you
know, writing a book or, you know,
creating some art or whatever it may be.
It's just got that human touch on it.
And I think more and more people are
going to crave this sort of like
homemade handmade real touch that's
human amidst all this AI soup you're
going to see across social media and
across the world over the next 10 years.
I think that founders that embrace their
authenticity, embrace their taste and
creativity and exploit it to the biggest
degree possible will not be left in this
next wave. In fact, they'll likely
thrive and stand out versus everyone
else. So with AI being a hot topic,
every founder is looking to leverage it
to make sure that they still exist over
the next decade. So what I did is I went
and worked with my team over about 40
hours and we collected all of the best
data, insights, and systems we could
think of so that you could build AI into
a moat. And so you can go and download
this resource via the link in the
description, pass it on to your team and
implement it in your business today. So,
what you're seeing here, right, is a
room full of people all helping one
another the core aspects of building
successful businesses. This room is
packed with founders that are putting in
the work. They're implementing systems
and they're getting the support, the
mentorship, and as you can see, the
direct insights from me to really scale
up what they're building. And so, you
know, if you're looking to go and join
the community, you go check out Founder
OS via the link in the description. Go
and apply. We'd love to chat with you,
understand what you're looking to do.
Hopefully, see you on the inside. Let's
get it.