I get this question all the time. How do
I fire someone without being a dick?
Now, firing can be one of the most
nerve-wracking moments as a founder. And
there's three stages I'm going to go
over in this video that will help you go
and do it in a way that feels authentic.
It's being kind, but it's also
preserving the sanctity of your culture,
your business, and you as the founder.
Think of the firing framework almost
like a stoplight. I'm going to draw this
out for you. So, got three lights here
and we're going to get into all the
details. So, we got yellow, orange, and
red. Okay? And this is our firing
framework. And so, let's start off with
the yellow stage. This stage is where
you have someone that's underperforming.
You're going to give this person a
warning. And the key framework here is
radical cander. You're going to care
deeply for this person, but you're going
to speak directly. We're not sugar
coating [\h__\h] As an example, if you have
someone on your sales team that you've
been asking them to go and complete end
of day and end of week reports and they
haven't been doing it, the next step for
you is to go and sit down with that
person and you're just going to go and
tell them directly, I've been noticing
over the past couple weeks, you haven't
been filling out these reports that the
rest of the team is all completing. Is
there anything getting in your way?
You're going to be looking to see if
that person takes responsibility for it
or on the other side makes excuses.
Assuming they take responsibility for
it, they tell you, "Hey, listen. I'm
sorry. You know, I'm going to change."
But this person's now on notice. They
know that they need to perform in a
certain aspect, fix it, and then move
along. You know, my belief is that as
you're building a company, you get what
you tolerate. If you tolerate mediocre
level performance, well, that's exactly
what you're going to get from the people
you hire. Inherently, there's nothing
terribly wrong at this stage. I can
speak as a founder and as a, you know,
high achiever. I make mistakes all over
the place. I get feedback all the time.
And I think what matters most is that
you're building a culture that allows
people to make mistakes, but also is
ruthless about not allowing people to
make, you know, the same mistake two,
three, four, five times. That leads to
the orange stage. This is where the
performance just continues, right? And
you're just not seeing an improvement.
This is basically your final warning
before firing someone. This is where
you're going and creating a PIP or a
performance improvement plan. You're
going to get into your values and where
they're falling short, their actual
performance, and what you need to see.
And you're probably going to decide on a
specific time frame, generally between 2
to 4 weeks. So, the PIP is pretty
simple. You're going to go and simply
identify across your core values as well
as that person's KPIs where they are
falling short. Don't over complicate it.
It's probably pretty obvious right out
the gate the three areas that this
person's underperforming. Under my
example of the salesperson that's not
sending end of day reports and end of
week reports. Well, at Found, we have a
culture of being writing first and this
person is not embodying that writing
first culture. The second aspect of
Found us is we take extreme ownership
and this person is not running their
aspect of the business like an owner.
Third is that we obsess over quality. If
someone's not going to go and fill this
out, we don't know what's going on and
we're not able to go and deliver the
best quality founder experience
possible. I'm going to go and detail
those all out and also indicate that
this is a core aspect of us even
bringing that person on in the first
place. From there, it's documented. I'm
going to book a meeting quickly and go
over this with someone. Again, speaking
directly, caring deeply, but kind of
letting them know that this is the final
warning. If you're looking to go and get
my template to build your own
performance improvement plan because
you've been going through this video and
you're like, "Oh my gosh, I need to talk
to Tim or Mary." Well, now you can go
and download it via the link in the
description. This is the performance
improvement plan template I've been
using for the last 15 years, building
multiple successful companies, and well,
now it's yours. So, go check this out.
you can go and document that person's
areas for improvement where they're
going and contradicting your values and
give them either two weeks, four weeks,
whatever feels right for you to get
things on track. Now, I generally will
put someone on a 2 week sort of
probation saying, "Hey, I need this to
turn around and I need this to get to
this specific outcome in the next 2
weeks or I think it's best that we just
go separate directions." It's pretty
obvious at this stage things are not
working out. If performance continues
the direction it's going, there's no
seat for them here on the team. I'm not
doing this to be a dick. I'm not doing
this to attack them personally. It's
just important that any business I'm
creating. We obviously have a massive
vision, a big mission. And mediocrity is
not going to be stood for. I see a lot
of founders get tripped up here because
they let people underperform and then
underperform and then underperform. And
what ends up happening is you have a
high performance culture that will
eventually revert to the mean. Meaning
that you look around, no one really
cares. You've got a bunch of people
around you that you really don't
respect. You're definitely building a
culture that no a player is going to
want to be a part of. And so it's
important that as low performers go and
pop up around your culture, that you're
doing everything to promptly address it.
Not just because your mission requires
it, but also because you've got a team
of people that are likely dedicated.
They're invested. They're giving it
their all. And you can imagine if an A
player keeps on seeing a C player around
them who's not showing up the same way
they are, it starts to affect their
performance as well. And that's the last
thing that you want. So, you go over
this performance improvement plan, but
inevitably you have folks that just
continue to underperform. This is where
we get to stage three. This is where you
need to fire someone without being a
dick. It's that tricky conversation, but
the good news is there is a way to fire
someone. First off, you're going to book
some time and it's going to be you plus
one person. This is just good generally
for kind of legal and all that
standards. Now this is not legal advice
but you get it. Next aspect then is just
being direct and simple with it. Okay.
And then lastly you know having empathy
and offering help.
If you can just stick to these three
aspects when you have to fire someone.
It makes it clean, makes it simple and
not so scary. This is just my own
approach after 15 years running
businesses and over the years,
unfortunately, having to fire a good
number of people. I think you want to
keep it simple. You want to be
respectful. You obviously want to have
someone in that meeting with you. So,
for me, typically, it'll be myself and
my chief of staff, Claire, that will go
and schedule a meeting with the given
person and let them go. Now, first off,
I like to just be direct. Couple weeks
ago, we chatted. I went over your
performance. Unfortunately, we haven't
seen a big change there. And we think
it's best that we go separate
directions. That's it. It's that simple.
You don't need to overexlain yourself.
You don't need to get into every little
bit they could have done better. At this
stage, it's done. It's over. So, just
keep it simple and save everyone the
oxygen. Now, the second aspect of this
is saying something like, I really
appreciate what you've put into the
company, you know, and I want to support
you going forward. if I can make this
transition smooth for you, make any
intros to other folks or help you on
your path, you know, just count me in
your corner. You're not here to be a
dick. You're not here to, you know, come
at them in any ways. You're just saying
that in terms of the mission, the vision
that you have, it's just not a good fit,
but you want to help them on to the next
stage in their career. The third aspect
here is just signing off and not
overexlaining any aspect of it. Right?
At this stage, sometimes you're going to
get questions from someone saying, "What
did I do?" or can I have a second
chance, which is probably a fourth
chance at this stage. Or it may just
blow up into some other sort of
conversation. And I'm here just to
reassure you that you don't need to go
all those directions. You can kind of
curtail those kind of conversations by
just simply saying, "We're probably both
going to have different viewpoints with
this and I respect your way of looking
at it." That said, you know, we've
thought long and hard about this and it
just doesn't make sense given the stage
we're at and I just think it's best we
go separate directions. I'm going to
follow up in an email with everything.
We're going to get you offboarded now.
And you know, when the dust settles, if
you want to reach out or let me know how
I can help you, you know, I'm here to
support you. Whether it's with a
reference, an intro, anything. This
isn't personal. There's no hard
feelings. I just got to do what's best
for the team, for the mission, and for
the culture. It's just simple. And I'm
not getting into a long- winded, you
know, affair here. The reality is you
want to have empathy. I think you want
to have empathy for yourself, right?
This is a tricky moment as a founder,
right? It's probably one of your least
favorite moments of building a business.
On the other side, too, the person that
you're letting go, it's a really hard
day for them. It may be the low moment
in their year or maybe for some people
even the low moment in their career. I
think it's about showing up calmly with
empathy, caring deeply, but speaking
directly. Firing is uncomfortable
because we're humans. But as a founder,
firing is a necessary part of your
growth. You need to embrace it. you need
to borderline find it something that's
enjoyable. And so what I find is that if
you dread this, you end up piling up
mediocre players. Whereas, if there's an
aspect of you that enjoys it and knows
how to handle it, you're quick to go and
correct your team along the way so that
you can build an empire with the top
performers without being a dick.