Most people can't speak clearly and
that's why nobody listens to them. I
wasn't born a great communicator. My
ideas were good, but I would overthink
every single word and come across as
awkward or insecure. Becoming a better
speaker changed [music] everything. It's
the unfair advantage that helped me
build my audience to 2.8 million people
and helps me run a portfolio of online
businesses that I can operate from
anywhere in the world. So, today I'll
share the six communication skills that
will make you more articulate than 99%
of people. Skill number one, the
authenticity code. Now, for years, I
tried to sound like other entrepreneurs.
I would see a speech from Gary Vee or
you see something from Tony Robbins or
Jesse Sler, and I would try to embody
their energy in what I do. You know,
what I realized over time is that, you
know, I'm not them. I don't view the
world the same. I don't use the same
language, and we don't even have the
same energy. What I've realized is that
my uniqueness, it's me. You know, when I
go and survey founders that join Founder
OS and ask them, "What is it that caused
you to join?" About 64% of founders tell
me that it's your energy, Matt. It's
your vibe. And so, I'm here to tell you
that your unique energy is what's going
to separate you. You don't need to be
like Alex Heroszi, Ivon Gazi, Tony
Robbins, or Gary Vee. You just need to
get comfortable being you. The reality
is is that you have your own way of
speaking, your own energy, your own
tonality. And it's your own quirks and
vibes that people are going to resonate
with, and that's going to separate you
from everyone else. Now, when you get
talking and when you start to go and
speak around your given space, what
you'll find is that there's common words
or phrases you like to use. For me,
that's things like the content waterfall
system, personal media company, founder
brands, and founder flow. And so, what
are the words that you own? Now, when I
think about some of the most well-known
people online, they all own a core word.
Whether it's James Clear for habits,
Ryan Holidayiday for stoicism, Olli
Abdal for productivity, I own systems.
You know, what word is it that you own
that when people hear that thing, it
should be a trigger for them to go
follow you. You know, your words matter
and owning your own content IP is
everything. You know, you need to go and
discover your own authentic voice.
Here's how to go and find your most
authentic voice in just 4 weeks. Step
one is go and take a YouTube video or
any speech you've done and go and send
it to your five best friends. From
there, step two is go and book a call
with them and have them go and give you
just their unfiltered, brutally honest
advice around what they loved around it
and the things that they would suggest
that you improve. From there, what I'd
recommend is that you just listen and
you're just writing notes. Step three
now is view them as your authentic voice
coaches. Go and incorporate that
feedback into your next presentation,
into your next video you may create. You
know, your authentic voice isn't going
to happen overnight. It's going to come
through iteration. Skill number two, the
simplicity filter. For 6 months building
Founder OS, I didn't know exactly how to
articulate the positioning of the
company. I made it super complex, right?
The more simple things are, the more
easy it is for the word to spread. About
60% of your customers are going to hear
about your business through word of
mouth. And so, you want to make sure
that you articulate your ideas in a way
that is simple. But you're probably
thinking, how do I actually go and make
them simple? Well, first off, think
about communicating in an eighth grade
vocabulary. Get rid of the long complex
words. Keep things short, easy, and
simple. Also, number two, eliminate any
jargon. Right? There's always that
industry speak that you know, maybe your
industry friends know, but outside no
one else knows. And when we think about
going and creating ideas that will
travel, we want to make sure that we're
not just appealing to a core audience of
people inside of your industry, but that
you're able to go and attract a new and
casual audience as well, which is going
to allow, you know, your brand, your
message to come up at a dinner table
audience and for everyone to understand
what it is that you do. When you have a
simple way of communicating your brand,
it doesn't just help you articulate
yourself in person. It also helps you
articulate yourself online. You know,
when I go and I have a bio, let's say on
Instagram or on LinkedIn, what I've
noticed is when that bio is incredibly
simple, for example, helping you build a
profitable audience with organic
content, I see the percentage of people
that go and hit my profile follow me at
a much higher percentage. And so this is
just an example of not just seeing how
clear speaking, you know, in person
helps, but also when you articulate
yourself clear online, it can actually
help people go and follow you and build
the movement you're looking to create.
You know, there's this famous saying, be
clear, not clever. This is what's going
to allow your ideas to travel and
inevitably is just going to make you a
lot more money. Complexity isn't a sign
of intelligence. It's a sign of
insecurity. And if people can't
understand you, they can't trust you,
buy from you, or follow you. All of the
greatest leaders in history had this
amazing ability to just simplify what it
is they do. Because if you can't clearly
articulate yourself in a simple way,
well, you probably don't really know
what you're doing. Skill number three,
master your preoter cortex. Early in my
career, I thought I was a great
communicator because I could just riff.
But my ideas never landed. I was just
rambling with people. You know, I would
go and talk about an idea, have it
barely even formed, not even practice
it, and thought I was awesome just
because I could go and hit it off the
dome. But what I realized is people
weren't resonating with it because I
wasn't actually putting that much time
into preparation. You know, those who
prepare more in training bleed less in
war. You know, meaning that also when
you're going and looking to, you know,
communicate articulately and really have
a message that resonates with people,
you're going to benefit a lot by
actually preparing a lot. You know, when
I go and deliver a workshop to audiences
online, you know, I make sure that I
practice that given workshop about 20
times before I go live. It's [music] in
this preparation that I become much more
comfortable with what I'm about to go
and speak about. [music] And that's what
makes it resonate. It's the fact that
I've put in the work so that when I'm
actually [music] articulating it,
there's a degree to which that person
can tell that I know what I'm doing. If
you want to articulate yourself better
than anyone else out there, you need to
go and put in the work. Again, this is
not just me, right? Steve [music] Jobs
was one of the greatest presentation
speakers of all time. He was famous for
going and drawing up on pen and paper
exactly what he was going to go and
articulate in any of his Apple keynote
speeches. This is what allowed him to
come across so clearly, so simply, and
in a way that really [music] was
breathtaking to so many people in the
world. Here's the truth. If your
thoughts are jumbled in your head, your
words won't resonate when they come out.
When people can't follow you, they can't
trust you. It's why it's more important
than ever with so much noise everywhere
and trust at an all-time low that you're
able to articulate yourself. Here's how
to practice this. First off, before your
next speech or next presentation, first
go and get a pen and paper and go and
write down all of your potential
thoughts that you want to get across.
Then often times what I'll go and do is
take a highlighter [music] and go and
highlight some of the key ideas that I
want to make sure are incorporated into
that presentation. Now, from there, I'll
go and synthesize all of the highlighted
pieces and then go a layer deeper there,
coming up with the specific words,
phrases, [music]
ideas, or thoughts that are going to
help them travel the best. I also make
sure that I'm weaving in my storytelling
as well and have stories for each key
idea so that, you know, they're that
much more powerful. Clarity on paper
becomes confidence in person. Skill
number four, the clarity pyramid. The
complexity trap is where most experts
get stuck. They over complicate things
to sound intelligent, but that
complexity creates confusion, and the
confusion kills trust. Top 1% speakers
do the opposite. They make complex ideas
simple. Think about Steve Jobs at Apple
unveiling the new iPhone. He brought it
down [music] just to three key things.
It was a messaging device, music device,
and communications device. Think about
Jeff Bezos talking about Amazon and
their mission. It was simply just to be
customer obsessed. Or think about Warren
Buffett talking about his shareholder
letters. You know, in his job, he just
determines as saying no to 99% of
things. I get told all the time, "Matt,
you're great at taking complex business
systems and making them sound so
simple." [music] Well, it doesn't happen
naturally. I use something what I call
the clarity pyramid. It goes something
like this. Level one, a simple
statement. It's one sentence that
encapsulates the whole idea. Level two,
three supporting points that prove your
statement. Level three, stories, data,
and examples that make it real. So the
next time you prepare for a meeting or
you're making content, ask yourself,
what's the one thing that I want people
to understand? From there, go and make
sure that that one core idea [music] has
three supporting points and that there's
examples, stories, and data to back it
up. [music] Make it as memorable as
possible. So go and take that one thing
you're looking to get across and go and
now tell the audience a story of how you
first struggled with that thing, how you
then learned the given point and it help
you overcome the struggle and achieve
some big desirable goal. People will not
just resonate with the lesson you're
trying to get across, but see themselves
in the story you're telling, which is
going to make it that much more
relatable and heavy-hitting. Simplicity
isn't dumbing down, it's leveling up.
Skill number five, the story spine. When
I started creating content, I started
blasting people with data and realized
though that it wasn't resonating with
them. One day I was mentoring a founder
named Anetta and she said, "Matt, you
know, I understand these content systems
are important, but can you tell me the
story as to how you discovered them in
the first place?" I started showing
Anetta, you know, how I'd use systems
like my batching system and content GPS
to go and build this amazing audience,
transform my life, and be able to also
travel the world while just working on
content a few hours a month. Finally,
when I delivered this story, I could
tell that something [music] clicked for
Anetta. Finally, it all made sense why
these systems were so important. That's
also when I realized that I had been
delivering these systems and this
content in a way that wasn't quite there
because it was lacking the storytelling.
You know, stories form this amazing
vehicle that allow our ideas to travel.
And for me, if I'm just going to go and
give you a system, well, a system may
get you half the way there, but it's a
whole other way if you're able to
understand how I discovered it in the
first place and the impact it's made in
my life. You know, I found that people
were able to really resonate with my
topics and content [music] that much
more. The truth is, if you don't
structure ideas as stories, people won't
remember them. And if they don't
remember them, you don't exist.
Storytelling is really what connects us
all as humans, right? It's what allows
ideas to travel. And so, as you're
looking to go and make your brand more
of a household name, you're looking to
build a cult following around what you
do, you need to go invest in your
stories. You know, when you have this
whole story infrastructure, you kind of
have the fabric that people can now use
to understand who you are as a human.
Because when people are able to connect
with you on a deep level, they're going
to follow you and follow your brand.
Skill number six, the resonance engine.
I learned this technique from a legend
on my team named Petey. You know, Petey
would go and hammer me for going and,
you know, talking about given subjects
that he thought were too surface level.
But the truth is, when I kept hearing
him talk about this, I didn't understand
what he meant. You know, I thought I was
really serving people on a deep level
and speaking to their core. But little
did I know, I was hardly even scratching
the surface. So, I asked Pety, you know,
why don't you go give it a shot? you
know, go and make a piece of content for
me and let me see what you actually mean
by this. I was shocked. PD had gone and
drawn up an entire YouTube script and
the way it was written, I could clearly
now see what he meant by really getting
in my audience's core thoughts [music]
and head versus the surface level
content I had been putting it out. And
trust me, it changed my life. You know,
here's how I [music] would describe it.
You know, at first I was talking about
systems that would help a founder go and
create content so they can get more of
their time back. You know, yes, this is
what a lot of people love and need, but
it didn't speak to them on a deep
[music] level. What PD had gone and
articulated was something along the
lines of the following. You know, you go
and you're making content day after day,
but you're on a content hamster wheel.
You end the day, you look yourself in
the mirror while you're brushing your
teeth, and you're wondering how much
longer you can go living like this.
You've been going over a year making
content, the leads are slowly trickling
in. But when you go and you look at your
filming schedule and the writing you
need to do the next day, you wonder if
this workload is sustainable. You've
been doing it for a year, but when you
look at the next 10 years, there's no
way you could keep up. You can see here
between the two differences of what I
just brought up. One is, you know, a
surface level understanding of what my
core customer is really going through.
The second is literally articulating the
exact story going on in that person's
subconscious mind. What are they [music]
actually thinking? What's the real
struggle? What's that real story that
they're going through? And how do you go
and speak to that voice in their head?
When you can go and articulate the
problem your dream customer has better
than they do, that's when you know
you've [music] tapped into something
special. And that is when they will go
and genuinely trust you. You know, I
used to think my audience just wanted
systems tips, but now I know that people
want freedom from overwhelm. You know,
they want clarity. When you can [music]
speak to the story in someone's mind,
they're going to understand that you
really get them and you're not just
looking to sell them. And thereby,
[music] they're going to want to become
a core customer of what you're building.
This is the power of resonance. If you
want to go and implement these
communication skills into your business
and life today, go and check out my
confident speaking protocol via the link
in the description. And if you like this
video, don't forget to subscribe.