Not a bad office for the day.
[Applause]
[Music]
>> Brand is more than just content. It must
have substance. And if you're building
your own brand, you need to refine your
brand vision and identity. have a
unified and consistent brand across the
platforms you're on and remove the
things you don't like. I'm going to show
you how I execute this process for my
brand. And if you're building your
personal brand, this is how you do it.
[Music]
Dude, that looks insane. [\h__\h]
Feel like this is the postcard of the
brand.
>> So, when you think about the vision,
what do you see the vision in? I feel
like
the core of it is already there. It's
just like going making more obvious the
things that let's say authenticity,
connectedness, like uh raw organic
stuff. It's like all these elements are
already like the basis, the foundations
of your personal brand and founder OS
just like how to make them stand out a
bit more
>> with all these details that we're we've
been doing, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. more the organic behind the
scenes.
>> It's like more documenting.
>> If we have to remember one thing from
this week, it's like just going back to
the like humanness of everything.
>> It's like connecting with you as a
personal brand, right? So
>> just even almost like in my head
sometimes just like having this rule of
like no scripts
>> like like having concepts but then just
rip it, you know? people just want to
[\h__\h] get to know you. Just like I
don't even watch scripted [\h__\h] I think
it can just be more like organic,
relaxed, zen. Just the exercise of doing
that is like you're even getting closer
to yourself like getting more in tune
and then more inspired and then you can
get more like oh I feel like filming
this video just for the sake of you
where do you see
>> yeah I agree in the near term it's more
the day in the life behind the scenes
organic real
creating that story line act just like
as if so people can be more of a fly on
the wall
>> it's all the creative process behind
everything that's what's going to stick
with founders because you don't even
have to tell it so much. It's like just
showing like the process of it. Founders
are going to be like, "Oh [\h__\h] Okay,
that's how you do it." That's what we
get feedback on all the time, right?
It's like people just love to learn just
from how you think about things. Yeah.
Like it's just, "Oh, this is how you
approach branding. And this is how you
approach the creative process from the
evil being like out.
>> I also think that easy way to connect
with the audience and like founders and
everything is just like asking them more
questions about what they want to see or
what they want to use. Like maybe a part
of it is just more just like like kind
of chilling creative retreat vibes. Then
like we've said it's not like it's oh
it's secondary you got to do all this
stuff. It's like just a few weeks
chilling and traveling around, [\h__\h]
around, documenting [\h__\h] hanging out
like and like evolving lots of areas and
then just [\h__\h] around and just
documenting.
>> I think it just proves a point that
creative process is not to be rushed is
like something create room and space for
to emerge naturally. Yeah, there's a
part of it that's like useful to do
a lot and there's also like a lot of
industries from school that have that
like ah it just happens over pasta pizza
doesn't need to happen you know in dark
brewh
[Music]
All right. So, RIP and Thomas here
looking at this stuff. We need some
consistency. Need to need to make this
more editorial.
>> Yeah. I think it's just a matter of like
going back to like what you were all
about with YouTube at the beginning.
It's like since you're already doing
like the hard work which is like going
to sick places and locations to have the
like this kind of view, we don't need
like all these extra
um yeah, let's say details, right?
Because the picture talks for itself.
>> Yeah. Just simplifying it, making them
more editorialized. Yeah. Letting the
photo do the work. Couple words max that
needed.
>> Not a lot of animation. The only things
like we discuss is keeping it like a
magazine cover and like library right
just scroll through YouTube and so like
consistency and like titles and
aesthetics.
>> Yeah. So it's like create a contrast
between let's say you talk about
entrepreneurship
uh productivity and how to build
business and everything like that but
like if you show like sceneries like
this it just creates a contrast and you
stand out in your own niche. So I think
it's just playing with like the boldness
of the font that we choose and making it
like big enough so it's like when you
see a preview well when you scroll down
it's really eye catcher.
>> Yeah, that one set.
>> Uhhuh. Which color would you prefer? The
founder was green like white or you just
play with it?
>> He did the brand colors. I don't really
see anyone using that. So then that way
we're different and stand out from
everyone else. And the second you see
that on your screen you're like oh one
of these like here all the like keywords
and stuff embodying the essence of the
video as a reminder. It's like people
can scroll through your YouTube channel
and be like already feeling inspired
just because they read that yeah
thumbnail card and they're like oh just
start living the magazine cover.
Exactly. Yeah. It's like these words all
speak to almost like words of the brand
dreaming living. Imagine
>> we don't hear many entrepreneurs or
business owners or that talk about like
slow living and then relaxing and
creativity. I mean it balances it show
it's like organic systems like there's
enough systemization engines mechanisms
all that kind of talk balancing that out
with like nature organic slowness you
know tranquility these sort of things
that just feel more like it's rooted
>> I laid out like a few like mockup
preview what the feed would look like so
that would be like before and we have so
many pictures like this like motion like
blurry it makes it more like fashion
editorial Well, I feel like that could
be like a more consistent
fe.
>> And what I like about some of these
pictures is that you can see like
they're darker. So like the contrast
with the title cards makes it more like
crisp. Yeah, like these.
>> So we keep it consistent with like two
or three words, bold titles. Editorial
cover about it like thumbnails. This
could be a cover of like an outdoor
magazine and obviously like like the
best pictures we we have. must scale
mountains to take them photos.
[Music]
>> So now all we got to do is just talk
about what we don't like at the rant. So
>> easy
rant.
>> Yeah.
>> I think every grain goes through like a
period of like tightening and then it
kind of gets a little bit playful and
then it gets tightened. I feel like
we're in a stage now where we need to
kind of re heighten it out again, you
know, and if we're we are playing with
it, play with it in in a certain
standard, more editorial or like the raw
kind of like unfiltered behind the
scenes sort of look. So that then
translates to things like thumbs I think
on IG kind of like tightening it up
probably looking at like the formats
that have performed the worst over like
the last 90 days
>> and just going okay let's cut cut cut
cut cut cut cut cut cut cut cut cut cut
cut cut cut cut cut cut cut cut cut that
like slims it all down and then okay
let's start playing with
>> these two elements but it all feels like
it's coming
>> like me and you
>> it's either nice design editorial [\h__\h]
or it's like off-the- cuff authentic
[\h__\h]
>> yeah I feel like the engagement is going
to come naturally if we really like what
what we're putting out, let's say off
the cuff or let's say editorial, like
even if like I I've been trying more
rock car sales lately, but it's more
like to showcase more organic vibes and
you're behind the scenes like how you
live your life, right? Even though these
don't get as much engagement as like,
let's say, infographics, carousels, I
feel like it's just reinforces your
personal brand, which is like your
personal account, right? And I just
think that over time those are just like
it's the proper way to like share on
socials.
>> Then it just makes sense that more of
the short form videos just like along
the way of the journey. Yours is like
overly planned out. LinkedIn graphics I
think those have been played out now.
We've done this handdrawing [\h__\h] for
[\h__\h] 2 years. Everything runs its
course. I think it's run its course. So
yeah, it's just like evolving. Yeah.
Naturally. Time to just like upgrade
that [\h__\h] and just play with some new
[\h__\h] We want to make stuff that people
want to save, people want to share with
10 of their friends, people want to
print it, like the kind of stuff that
feels timeless, just overall like less
feel less pro promoy and all that stuff
and just more like, hey, like thought
this would be useful and
>> and try to just I always keep that ratio
like
>> one in 10, you know, like versus like
some brands like they just it's like
50/50 or if anything like ask ask a
little bit of gift. And I think we want
to stay that kind of like insanely
generous.
>> One question to ask yourself is like
would I consume my content, right? And
then you're like or what do I consume
like on a daily basis? What do you
enjoy?
>> I think that's the main one, right? I
think it's hard to be honest with
yourself. But then when you just look at
your own habits, that's the ultimate
test is like what do you actually watch?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Like all the things you're
inspired by, it's like oh hey, we can
there's some elements we can just like
study that and take some elements from
it from this and then
>> Yeah. It's just like tighten up the
brand. Yeah, but uh it's like
fine-tuning. It's like the core is
there. Brand identity. Take that to the
next level. Thumbs feel good. Carousels
were rocking.
>> Oh, good.
>> That all right. Get to it.
[Music]
So the key thing to remember with any
brand, right, is that it's just the sum
total of a bunch of little decisions.
You know, here you can see, you know,
just
a day of just little things, whether
it's, you know, thumbnails, lead magnet
mockups, the way we do carousels, raw
carousels, stories, just a continual
kind of work in progress, right? And the
clear thing is if whether it's your
personal brand or your brand is really
built around values that matter to you.
Truth be told, it doesn't really feel
like work, right? It's just this
continual process of really just
artistry. A forever game of making
something that you're genuinely proud of
that you feel like exemplifies those
values to the maximum degree possible
and is something that you would actually
consume and enjoy and be inspired by um
if you were on the other side of it. I
went and built a 7-day media empire
playbook for free below in the link in
the description. You can go and check
that out. Um, I think it's everything
that I wish I had 15 years ago when I
was getting started building, you know,
my first media business. It'll help you
go and break down getting started right
away. So, you don't have to make all the
same mistakes and go through the pain
and he that I had to go through
candidly. You know, building an amazing
brand is the sum total of just the
details, the little decisions that when
you stack these up at the end of the
day, I think it creates something
beautiful, inspiring, something that
people genuinely enjoy because they can
feel the artistry, the craftsmanship,
the details, the mastery behind it all.
I really just encourage you at the end
of the day, just have fun, right? If
you're going to be doing anything in the
long term, you got to make sure that you
honestly are just having a good time cuz
you're going to be able to stay in the
game. You're going to be able to keep at
it. Put in the daily work. It's going to
stack up over time to create something
that you're genuinely proud of. So,
let's get it. Welcome to the Founder
Freedom Movement. Like and subscribe and
I'll see you in the next one.