Your parents lied to you. School lied to
you. Society lied to you. Everything
you've been told about success, money,
and building a good life is wrong. I'm
about to share 35 brutal truths that
will shatter everything you believe
about getting ahead in life. These
aren't feel-good platitudes. These
aren't motivational quotes. These are
the harsh realities that separate those
who win from those who stay stuck. At
35, I know the truth. The difference
isn't talent, luck, or connections. It's
knowing these 35 brutal truths that most
people will never accept. Warning, this
might destroy your current worldview.
Brutal truth number one, the most
addictive drug is momentum. And most
people are addicts in withdrawal. They
start projects and quit, set goals, then
abandon them, take action, then stop.
Every time you break momentum, you're
starting from zero again. Here's the
math that proves it. 1.01 01 to the 365
equals 37.7. If you improve just 1%
every single day, you'll be 37 times
better in a year. But if you do nothing,
well, 1 to the 365 just equals 1. You
stay exactly the same. Most people can't
handle this brutal truth because it
means every day they're not improving.
They're falling behind. The brutal
truth, consistency beats intensity every
single time. Brutal truth number two,
follow your passion is terrible advice.
Here's a brutal truth that will offend
half the internet. Passion is what you
feel when you're good at something
valuable that the world wants. Most
people have it backwards. They think
passion comes first, then skill, then
money. The real order is skill, then
value, then money, then passion. Stop
waiting for passion to strike. Start
building skills that create value.
Brutal truth number three. Hard work is
overrated. Smart work is everything.
Here's a brutal truth that's going to
trigger the hustle culture crowd. I work
4 hours a day and make more than people
working 80our weeks. The difference? I
work hard on high leverage activities
worth $5,000 per hour. Every morning,
7:00 a.m. to 11:00 a.m. I go into deep
work mode. No phone, no distractions, no
meetings. During these 4 hours, I focus
exclusively on what moves the needle.
The brutal truth, most people work hard
on the wrong things. They're busy being
busy. They confuse motion with progress,
activity with achievement. Hard work
attracts luck though, but only when it's
applied to the right activities. Brutal
truth number four. Your friends and
family will sabotage your success. Not
because they're bad people, because your
success makes them feel insecure about
their choices. When you start building
something big, they'll say, "Be
realistic. Don't get your hopes up.
Maybe you should just have a backup
plan." This isn't support, though. It's
sabotage disguised as concern. The
brutal truth. You'll have to choose
between their comfort and your growth.
Surround yourself with people who
celebrate your wins, not diminish them.
Brutal truth number five. Mistakes are
proof you're taking action. Perfection
is paralysis. Here's a brutal truth that
perfectionists hate. Mistakes are proof
that you're taking action. At 25, I was
paralyzed by perfectionism. I'd spend
months planning instead of weeks
executing. Now I finally know the truth.
Launch at 80% ready. Perfect the final
20% in public. You know, the market
rewards speed over perfection every
single time. The brutal truth, perfect
is the enemy of profitable. Brutal truth
number six. Most business advice is from
people who got lucky once. They had one
success and now they're selling the
formula. But their formula only worked
because of timing, market conditions, or
pure luck. The brutal truth, success
leaves clues, but it also leaves false
clues. I've built multiple 8-f figureure
businesses across different industries
and different time frames. The patterns
that repeat across all of them. Those
are the real principles. Everything else
is just noise. Brutal truth number
seven. Your biggest limitation is your
own standards. You don't get what you
want in life. You get what you tolerate.
If you tolerate mediocre relationships,
well, that's exactly what you're going
to have. If you tolerate lowpaying work,
to get. If you tolerate disrespect,
that's what you're going to receive. I
set my hourly rate at $5,000. Anything
below that gets delegated or eliminated.
This wasn't arrogance. It was standards.
The brutal truth, the quality of your
life is determined by the standards you
refuse to compromise. Brutal truth
number eight. Building multiple income
streams is a myth for beginners.
Everyone preaches, you know, diversify
your income, but they're wrong about the
timing. If you're making less than 100k
annually, you don't need multiple income
streams. You need one stream that
actually works. build one stream to
500K, then add a second, then the third.
I have multiple sevenfigure income
streams now, but I built them
sequentially, not all simultaneously.
The brutal truth, diversification is
protection against ignorance.
Concentration is the path to wealth.
Focus until you succeed, then diversify
to protect what you've built. Brutal
truth number nine. The flywheel effect
separates amateurs from professionals.
Here's a brutal truth about scaling.
Amateurs try to grow linearly.
Professionals build flywheels. Most
people think growth looks like this.
More effort equals more results. That's
amateur thinking though. Professional
thinking is build systems that compound
that effort. My founder flywheel looks
like this. My personal brand growth
feeds my business growth. The business
growth then drives success stories.
Success stories then drive word of
mouth. Word of mouth drives more
customers. More customers drive more
revenue. More revenue then drives better
systems. Better systems drive more
freedom and more freedom then drives
better content. And better content,
well, that fuels my personal brand
growth. Each element feeds the next,
creating exponential growth. The brutal
truth, if you're not building flywheels,
you're building jobs. Brutal truth
number 10. Content is currency and most
people are broke. If you're not creating
content, you're not creating
opportunities. My content waterfall
system looks like this. I create one
pillar piece of content and then
transform that pillar piece into 10
short form tweets, three animated
videos, one talking head video, one
LinkedIn post, one Instagram carousel,
one newsletter, and one YouTube script.
So that one idea becomes 30 pieces of
content. This helped me grow to 950,000
Instagram followers, 354,000 followers
on X, and 840,000 followers on LinkedIn
in just 2 years. The brutal truth in the
attention economy, invisibility equals
irrelevance. Brutal truth number 11.
Find your icky guy or stay miserable
forever. Icky guy is the intersection of
what you love, what you're good at, what
you can be paid for, and what the world
needs. Most people are miserable because
they're working against their nature
instead of with it. When I align my
business with my icky guy, which is, you
know, systems, audience growth, and
founder freedom, everything finally
clicked. The brutal truth, you can't
fake passion long term. Either find work
that energizes you or accept a lifetime
of mediocrity. Brutal truth number 12.
Your social media profile is more
important than your resume. This brutal
truth is going to trigger traditional
thinkers. Your profile is the front door
to your business. On my profiles, for
every thousand visitors I drive, 190
follow me. That's a 19% follower
conversion rate. Industry average is
like 2%. The brutal truth. In the
digital age, your online presence is
your professional reputation. Optimize
it or get left behind. Brutal truth
number 13. Morning pages in your journal
will unlock your genius if you can
handle the truth. Every morning, I write
three long- form pages immediately upon
waking. This practice forces you to
confront your real fears, your hidden
desires, your limiting beliefs, your
true potential. Some of my biggest
business breakthroughs came from morning
pages, not strategy sessions. The brutal
truth. Your breakthrough is hiding
behind your comfort zone. Brutal truth
number 14. Vulnerability is your
competitive advantage. Most founders
hide their failures and then only share
highlights. When I started sharing
vulnerably about my struggles with
things like burnout, overwhelm, and
failure, my audience grew exponentially.
People don't connect with perfection.
No, they connect with authenticity. The
brutal truth. Your wounds can become
your wealth if you are brave enough to
share them. Brutal truth number 15. 10x
goals are easier than 1x goals. It's
easier to raise 10 million than it is 1
million. It's easier to become a
millionaire than to make a h 100,000 per
year. Why? Well, first, there's less
competition at the top. 99% of people
aim for the middle. Second, 10x goals
fundamentally change how you think. You
stop thinking incrementally and start
thinking innovatively. The brut of
truth. Small goals attract small
thinking. Big goals attract breakthrough
thinking. Brut of truth number 16.
Specialization is for insects. The most
successful entrepreneurs aren't
specialists, they're effective
generalists. I've intentionally
developed skills across multiple
domains, then surrounded myself with
specialists. You know, I'm a full stack
founder. This lets me understand every
aspect of my business while delegating
core things to experts. The brutal
truth. In a rapidly changing world,
adaptability beats expertise. Brutal
truth number 17. Your evening routine
determines your success. Most people's
evenings kill their next day's
potential. My evening routine protocol
looks something like this. Wind down
with specific routines. Plan the next
day. Read for personal growth. Get to
bed at a consistent time every single
night. The brutal truth. How you end
today determines how you start tomorrow.
Brutal truth number 18. Experiences
create wealth. possessions consume it.
Here's a brutal truth about money.
Material things depreciate. Experiences
appreciate. Every experience you go on
gives you new perspectives, you know,
better stories, enhanced networks,
expanded creativity. Plus, experiences
make better content than possessions.
You know, the brut of truth is this.
Rich people buy experiences. Poor people
buy things. Brutal truth number 19. Your
network determines your net worth. But
most people network wrong. You know, I
surround myself with people who inspire
me, who challenge me. These connections
have led to amazing partnerships worth
millions. The secret? Give first, give
consistently, and give without expecting
anything in return. Brutal truth number
20. Content ideas are everywhere if you
know where to look. Here's my 5-year
reflection framework. What systems,
templates, and advice do you wish you
had 5 years ago? To the you of 5 years
ago, you're now an expert. Write down
your lessons learned, your mistakes
made, your achievements unlocked, and
your skills developed. This alone will
give you 100 plus content ideas. The
brutal truth, you already have more
valuable content than you realize.
Brutal truth number 21. Words are
weapons. Master them or be defeated by
them. The rhythm of your writing
determines its impact. Vary your
sentence length to create music. Short
sentences, they're punchy, they grab
attention. Then use longer sentences
that flow and expand on your ideas.
creating a rhythm that keeps readers
engaged and wanting more. The brutal
truth. In an attention economy, boring
words equal broke bank accounts. Brutal
truth number 22. Learning without
implementation is just entertainment. I
dedicate time weekly to learning, but
I'm strategic about it. I focus on
skills that I know will compound. Things
like writing, systems thinking,
psychology, technology, and leadership.
The brutal truth, information without
actually applying it is just expensive
entertainment. Brutal truth number 23.
Mindfulness prevents bankruptcy, mental
and financial. Success moves fast. It's,
you know, really easy to lose your
perspective. I practice daily
mindfulness to stay present and prevent
burnout. 10 minutes of meditation is
greater than 10 hours of stress. The
brutal truth. If you don't schedule
breaks, your body will schedule
breakdowns. Brutal truth number 24.
You're not building a brand. You're
building a media company. I've built a
team that turns my personal brand into a
machine that generates opportunities for
me 247. While I sleep, my content is
working night and day. While I travel,
the leads are flowing in. The brutal
truth is in the attention economy, media
companies win and everyone else just
rents attention. Brutal truth number 25.
Your body is your business hardware. If
the hardware fails, the software doesn't
even matter. I prioritize physical
health through consistent exercise,
proper nutrition, quality sleep,
recovery practices because this is the
brutal truth. You can't build a
million-doll business with a minimum
wage body. Brutal truth number 26.
Writing daily is thinking daily. Writing
isn't just about content creation. It's
about clarity of thought. I write daily
to process my ideas, reflect on
experiences, and build an archive of
life lessons. The brutal truth is this.
If you can't write clearly, you can't
think clearly. Brutal truth number 27.
Generosity is a business strategy. I
dedicate a portion of my time and
profits to helping others achieve their
dreams. The more I find that I give, the
more that comes back to me multiplied.
You know, it's not just karma, though.
It's smart business. Generosity creates
loyalty. The brutal truth is this.
Generous people get more opportunities
because they create value first. Brutal
truth number 28. Creativity is your only
sustainable advantage. Everything else
can be copied, automated, or outsourced.
I protect my creative energy by creating
before I'm consuming, capturing ideas
immediately, and limiting negative
inputs in my life. The brutal truth is
this. In a world of infinite
competition, creativity is your only
moat. Brutal truth number 29. 80% of
your results will come from 20% of your
efforts. I regularly audit my activities
in a day to identify the vital few that
drive the most results. Then I double
down on those and eliminate everything
else. The brutal truth is this. Most
work is just waste. Find the 20% that
matters and then ignore the rest. Brutal
truth number 30. Building in public is
your unfair advantage. Sharing my
journey has accelerated my learning
through feedback. It's helped me build
this amazing community of supporters.
It's created opportunities I never
expected. The brutal truth is
transparency is the new competitive
advantage. Brutal truth number 31. Sleep
is non-negotiable despite what hustle
culture tells you. Quality sleep
improves your energy levels, focus and
concentration, decision-making ability,
and emotional regulation. The brutal
truth, you can't hustle your way out of
biology. Brutal truth number 32. Nature
resets your operating system. I take
regular time in nature to decrease
stress, increase creativity, and improve
mental clarity. Some of my biggest
business breakthroughs have come during
walks in nature. Biggest brutal truth
here is your best ideas come when you're
not even trying to have them. Brutal
truth number 33. Rejection is
redirection. Embracing rejection has
decreased my fear of failure. It's
created unexpected opportunities. It's
built resilience. The word no is just
data, not defeat. The brutal truth,
every rejection brings you closer to the
right opportunity. Brutal truth number
34. Ownership changes everything. It may
not be your fault, but it is your
responsibility. When you own the
problem, you then own the solution. The
brutal truth is this. Victims make
excuses. Owners make money. Here's the
final brutal truth. Brutal truth number
35. Focus is your superpower in a
distracted world. For certain periods, I
go into complete focus mode on one key
objective. This focused intensity has
helped me complete projects in weeks
that would take most people months. The
brutal truth. In a world of infinite
distractions, focus is your unfair
advantage. The truth hurts. Big lies
hurt more in the long run. These 35
brutal truths have completely
transformed both my life and business.
They've helped me build what became a
$13.8 million per year portfolio of
online businesses. That's not typical.
You know, most businesses never reach
those numbers, but it shows what's
possible. You I've done all this while
just working 4 hours a day. They've
given me complete freedom over my time,
location, and choices. If you're ready
to stop being a prisoner in your own
business, and start building something
that actually works for you instead of
against you, something that can actually
grow while you sleep, generate revenue
while you're on vacation, and attract
better opportunities without you having
to constantly chase them, then Founder
OS is where you need to be. The link's
down below in the description. And
listen, if you watch this whole video
and you don't at least go check that
out, well, you're basically choosing to
stay stuck. And I know you didn't start
your business to stay stuck, right? So,
hit that subscribe button if you can
handle the truth. And remember, the most
addictive drug is momentum. The most
brutal truth is that most people will
never get their first hit. Don't be most
people. I'll see you in the next one.