Now, this is all part of the content
GPS, which is the best system to build
your personal media company. And this is
exactly what we go and help founders
install inside of Founder OS. And so, we
help people go and build their rented
audience across platforms like X,
LinkedIn, TikTok, Instagram, and
YouTube. Then own that audience in their
newsletter and with phone numbers. And
then go and convert those people to
leads, to their magnetic offer, and then
go and build communities where people
are loving it. They're vibrant. People
are really building movements inside of
Founder OS. And then they're driving
those people to referrals, testimonials,
and recommendations, which then leads to
an upsell mechanism, which drives people
back into the funnel again, gets them to
tell more of their friends, generate
referrals, and it creates this profit
flywheel inside of your business. Let me
show you what that looks like on the
owned audience side of things, okay?
This is your kind of content GPS
mechanism right here, which is where
you're going to convert consistent
content, and then nurture people through
to revenue. So, your owned audience is
built through your call to actions.
You're going to put CTAs in every piece
of content you have. I funnel both to my
newsletter and my main application form
on my website, which is at founder
os.com/apply.
And when you go to that, you'll go and
see that you can go and fill out a brief
application, and if it makes sense and
you qualify, we'll get on a call, either
me or my team speak with you, and then
if it makes sense, get you started with
Founder OS, getting access to me, my
C-suite support, all that good stuff,
and so much more.