Attention is the new distribution. Trust
is the new currency. And content is the
cheapest way to earn both. When you go
and think about building a company, I
want you to remember this one line.
First time founders focus on product.
Second time founders focus on
distribution. Distribution is shifting
right to the [music] founder. People
want to get to know you, your point of
view, and what makes you unique. And so
the advantage of putting content out
there is that that content is like a
salesperson that never sleeps. [music]
It's helping you drive leads. It's
helping you attract top talent. It's
opening up different partnerships and
credibility and also helping you over
time [music] have more pricing power.
Start your content ideation with
actually understanding your dream
customer. And the best way to do this is
number one to listen back to sales call
transcripts and understand what their
core problems are, what their
constraints are, what their dreams are,
and what they're hoping to get your help
with. The second aspect is to literally
[music] survey them, asking them what's
their main goal this year, what's
keeping them up at night, and if they
were to wave a magic wand, what would
they most want your help with? The
answers to these questions contain the
kernels for high converting content
that's going to help you get ahead.