my first million almost broke me and
it's because of one massive mistake I'll
never make again I tried to do
everything myself every sale every
system every task it all ran through me
my time gone my energy drained my growth
was capped here's what I wish I
knew leverage weapons not willpower
delegate hire one person who's a weapon
not a Helper but a builder someone who
can take tasks off your plate and build
systems to make them run better without
you document everything turn your brain
into a Playbook and document different
processes into Google Docs and Al Loom
videos anything repeatable must be
systemized step three focus on less but
better cut the noise build deep systems
and then let them scale this shift
transformed my hustle into Pure Freedom
1 million isn't the goal a calm scalable
business is