You can't stop intrusive thoughts, but
you can neutralize them with the right
environment. I think as humans
oftentimes that we think that we are
designers of our environment, but the
truth is our environment also heavily
influences us. Here's how to install
your external OS. Number one, go and
audit your environment. Go and remove
the things that are causing clutter,
disorganization, or are kind of low
energy. Two is remove one piece of
outdated code. Again, we don't need to
solve everything all at once. Just pick
that one thing right now that it's in
your environment and you feel like it's
some way somehow bringing you down.
Three, add one cue for clarity. That's a
nice vision board where I work. Your
mind performs best when your environment
is fine-tuned and simplified to execute
your true goals. Upgrade your external
OS and your thoughts will