Rick Rubin teaches us that iconic brands
aren't built by guessing the market.
They're built by creating what you love.
Rick Rubin's produced albums from
everyone from Johnny Cash to Kanye West.
It's all with this one principle that
the audience should come last. Now, for
a lot of people, that sounds like
creativity suicide. You know, aren't you
building for an audience? Well, the
answer, sure, they're part of the
equation, but the most important part of
the equation is you. It's your taste,
your intuition, your judgment. And
inevitably when you get too caught up in
what people think, you lose the true
essence of what you're trying to build.
And if you're looking to create an
iconic brand, it's in that essence the
depth, the beauty, and the originality
exist. And so when you're looking to be
creative, you got to block out the
audience and you got to focus on the
craft and the product at