Most founders think their content
problem is a creativity problem, but
it's not. It's an org chart problem. You
filmed your own videos, now you have to
manage the B-roll, manage the analytics,
hire the next person, and before you
know it, you're going and doing the next
one again, and just feel like you're on
this content hamster wheel. Here's what
nobody told you, all right, when you
started to build your personal brand.
The moment it started generating you
cash flows, and you started getting
those people hitting you up going, "I
found you on YouTube, and now I'm going
to work with you." Content stopped being
about self-expression. It starts
becoming a business unit, too. And no
one runs a business unit alone. So, in
this video, I'm going to show you the
exact six-person [music] team behind my
personal brand that has actually made it
a media company. Not for better content,
but to actually build an eight-figure
[music] personal brand. Let's get into
it. Role one, the CEO of video. About 3
years ago, I was doing everything. I was
writing every script, sitting on every
edit review. I was posting, checking,
tweaking. I told myself that this was
commitment, right? This is how you build
a brand. So, here's what Diego actually
owned. Every YouTube video from concept
to publish. So, he's making sure that,
you know, we ideate on great ideas that
are going to drive us real cash flow,
and that those ideas go all the way
through to executing the real vision in
mind. He's helping execute the long-form
strategy. So, topics in which order,
based on the business and what we need
right now, and organizing the whole
content pipeline and content calendar.
And then there's the short-form pipeline
as well, which is extracted from my
long-form content. So, we're never
creating content separately for
platforms like Instagram or X. And then
he's holding extremely high production
standards. You get what you tolerate as
you build content, and we're trying to
build the greatest founder-led brand in
the world. And we don't only have one
YouTube channel anymore. We actually
have two. We just launched a second
channel, which is the raw,
behind-the-scenes, authentic, no edits,
just real cuts. You can actually go and
check that out via the link in the
description. We got a lot we're putting
out there. Every given month now, in
terms of YouTube, I think we're pushing
something like around 78 pieces of
content. Now, here's something most
founders are getting it wrong about
YouTube, okay? YouTube is the only
platform I know of where content
appreciates in value over time. You
know, on Instagram, you make a post and
it's probably dead a few hours later.
LinkedIn, your post may live for a day.
X, it's gone in hours. But YouTube, I
have videos that I put out a year ago
that are still getting around 50 views
per hour. You know, a video I recorded
just here 18 months ago is still driving
founder us applications and real cash
today. Not views, I'm talking cash. And
so, the more someone watches, the more
they know me. And the more they know me,
the more they trust me. The more they
trust me, the more likely they are to
apply. And that's just a beautiful
compounding loop. And it only works if
the content is built with that logic
from the start. Rule two and three,
distribution and attribution. This is
the point where most founders say, "I
need a social media manager." That's a
weak fix for a structural problem. What
you actually need is ownership of
distribution and attribution. Here's a
quick [music] test, okay? Without
opening anything, can you tell me what
percentage of your applications last
month came from YouTube specifically?
>> [music]
>> All right, I'll wait. Which video drove
the most qualified leads in the last 90
days? Is that [music] video still
generating you applications today and
cash your business? If you can't answer
those in 30 seconds, you don't have a
distribution system. You've got some
posting schedule, and that's not going
to get you to where you're really
looking to go with your brand. If you
couldn't answer those questions
immediately, [music] don't ignore that.
There's a free personal brand team
evaluation in the description that will
help you action all the value from this
video. I want you mentally scoring
yourself. Because by the end of this
video, you're going to know exactly
which function you're still owning, and
that's the constraint in your business.
Nick and Anna on my team own two things
[music]
most founders have never built. First is
platform-specific distribution. The
metadata behind a YouTube video, the
links, the tags, the description are
compounding SEO assets that determine
whether this video gets watched 18
months from now or it's just forgotten
in 18 hours. The publishing cadence
across LinkedIn, Instagram, and X
requires a different logic for every
platform. Nick and Anna own that logic.
They're making sure that when we post a
YouTube video, that's then embedded into
a LinkedIn newsletter that Friday.
They're then making sure it's cut into
four different Instagram Reels, Shorts,
as well as TikTok videos so we get the
content waterfall system ripping from
that piece of content. And the thing
[music] is, distribution is not
something you just set it and forget it.
It's something that continues to evolve.
You refine things. And so the second
piece here is attribution. Every single
link, every CTA, every piece of content
that can drive someone towards a
FounderUs application has a UTM tag on
it. We use HubSpot to manage all of
that. So from lead through to
conversion, we can track the performance
of every single piece of content. That
tag tells us the platform, the specific
piece of content, and the date it was
published. And then when someone applies
to FounderUs, I know exactly where they
came from. Not approximately, exactly.
What I'm describing here, right? The
team, the systems, the attribution, the
compounding content machine, this is
exactly what we help founders with
inside of FounderUs Velocity. FounderUs
Velocity is not some course, it's not
just some done-for-you agency. It's a
tight-knit community of founders and
we're helping everyone do serious
revenue, right? We're helping founders
that are doing serious revenue really
scale their founder-led brands. I'm
talking about refining their offer,
coming up with hooks, getting their
content strategy down, linking that
content to emails, emails to lead
magnets, lead magnets to sales calls,
sales call scripts reviewed, all the way
through to building your own profitable
personal media company. Everyone gets
direct access to my C-suite, my CPO, my
COO, my head of media, my head of video.
We offer access to your core team
members as well. We're not here just to
scale you as the founder because we want
to build leverage around you, okay? And
no better way to go and fast-track your
learning and your team's learning than
by getting in the room with other
legends that have been doing this stuff
for decades. This is for established
founders only that are ready to invest
in their personal brand as an asset and
who want to build their infrastructure
around signal and stop being the
bottleneck of their own brand. So, if
that's you, the link is in the
description. It's an application, not
some sales page. We only take people
that are a real fit. All right, now back
to the team. Rule four, visual
authority. All right, there is a disease
spreading through the internet right now
and I need to call this out. Every SaaS
homepage looks identical. Every coach I
see has the same Canva template. They
blur into each other completely. They're
lost in this disease of sameness and
it's costing founders millions. When
your brand doesn't look consistent and
[music] even if it is consistent, it
just looks like the next person, you
have failed. Your audience's brain
characterizes you as just one of many
and [music] one of many never gets
premium pricing. I call myself the chief
detail officer of my company. Every
thumbnail, every motion graphic, every
slide, every piece of typography that
goes out under the Founder U.S. name, I
have a standard for it. And Yan, my
chief designer, is the person who
protects that standard across every
[music] piece of content, every
carousel, every motion graphic, every
slide, every piece of typography that
goes out under the Founder U.S. name,
Yan maintains a standard for it. And
it's not about expensive production
here, right? It's about taste,
consistency, intentionality. You know,
your designer's job is to dress your
brand for battle so it can cut through
the bloodbath of the online competition
for your customer's attention. Here's
where the whole operation gets really
interesting. Design signals before you
speak, but it's the words, the carefully
chosen language in your captions, your
hooks, your video descriptions that make
a viewer feel understood. And feeling
understood is what precedes every single
high-ticket purchase decision. That's
where this next rule becomes a
requirement to win. Rule five,
psychological messaging. I want to tell
you something that took me years to
learn. Founders write about what they
know. Their frameworks, their results,
their experience, their challenges, the
things they've been through, the trials,
the tribulations, and then they wonder
why their content gets views but no
leads. Why people engage but then don't
actually buy their thing. Here's the
answer I think to that, okay? Your
audience doesn't need more information,
okay? They need to feel found, right?
They want to feel like you really
understand them, that you get them.
Rachel's title in my company is social
copywriter, but that doesn't capture
what she actually does. So, Rachel
translates. Her job is to take the
internal dialogue of the person watching
this video, you, the frustrations that
you have, the fears that you're carrying
into every sales conversation with us,
the dream you've stopped saying out loud
because it sounds too big and feels too
large that you'll never be able to
accomplish it, right? The language that
lands in a LinkedIn post makes someone
stop scrolling mid-coffee and think,
"How does this person know exactly
what's in my head?" And that's not some
coincidence, okay? That is a system, and
her raw material isn't creative
inspiration, it's data. [music] It's
survey responses from founders, you
know, voice notes I've sent her, it's
sales call recordings, it's all the data
that we have in our voice of customer
documents. So, she's essentially going
and mining all of that language and then
reflecting it back to people when they
hit our website. And so, the result of
all this, well, it's content that
doesn't just get views, okay? Because
views don't pay the bills, it gets
applications and cash flow from people
who already feel understood before they
ever got on a call with our team. A
viewer who reads a post and thinks, you
know, "This was written for me," arrives
on a sales call already 70% sold.
They're not there for information,
they're there for confirmation on the
next step. And that conversion rate
difference between a qualified prospect
who feels deeply understood and a
generic prospect who is still deciding
lives in the copy. Your copywriting is a
salesperson that never sleeps. It's not
in the pitch, but there is one more
problem. We got five roles, five people
doing genuinely excellent work every
day. Without the sixth role though, all
of that work just resets. Every video
consumed once, every post that performs
for a day, every system that lives in
someone's head because
>> [music]
>> no one is building the infrastructure
that makes it compound. Role six,
systems and leverage. Memo is absolute
legend. He's actually the one behind the
camera right now who I'm filming with.
What Memo actually owns is the
infrastructure that turns the entire
operation from just being some temporary
effort into actual intellectual capital.
Every video that I've ever made is
indexed, okay? And I don't know how he's
cooked this all up, right? But he's made
this whole massive database that
automatically goes and cuts our stuff,
synthesizes it, so we're able to scale
things like the second channel up to
three videos a day and soon to be seven
videos a day. Don't tell him that
though, right? So every framework I've
ever articulated now is retrievable. And
you can start to see how this ties into
other areas of the companies, you know,
Rachel on the social copywriter side is
then able to see those transcripts
because Memo's got the infrastructure in
place. And now I don't need to say
things twice to my team. Rachel can
simply go and look at those transcripts
and then use that for future
copywriting. And so every
high-performing moment from the past two
years of content is now available to the
entire team. It's this content layer
that we can now build on. Memo has also
built a custom AI tool trained on my
existing content and then the target of
our ideal customer that allows him and
the team to then surface and deploy
ideas from the library without me
recreating the thinking from scratch.
That's a big thing, [music] right? Is in
general we think of systems, right? As
stopping founders from having to do the
same thing over and over again. And with
this content database that we've built
and hooked into AI through Memo, you
know, we've been able to make sure that
I'm not just repeating myself over and
over. And the nice thing is then I can
focus on the next piece of systems or
where the future's going or agentic AI.
Content is not a cost, it's intellectual
capital, but only if you build it like
one. Let me zoom [music] out. Six roles,
six people, each one with a specific
function and total accountability to one
outcome. None of them exist to help me
just post content. Every single person
on this team exist to protect and
amplify one thing, the signal, cuz it's
the signal that lead to the attention,
that lead to the IP, that lead to trust,
and ultimately that lead to a profitable
media company. You don't have to go hire
six people tomorrow. That's not the
point of this video. The point is this,
look at the six functions I just walked
you through and ask yourself one
completely honest question. Which one of
these functions is currently owned
entirely by you? Because that is where
your bottleneck exists. And clearing
that bottleneck might be the highest
leverage thing you do this year. Here's
what I would do if I were you. Download
the personal brand team evaluation below
in the description. Score each of the
six functions honestly. Identify your
lowest one and that's your bottleneck.
Then go and book a call with my team and
we can go and review your application
with you. We'll go and look at the
evaluation that you just went and filled
out and then we're going to look at it
together, quantify what that bottleneck
is costing you in time and revenue, and
then map the systems that you need to
fix it. Every founder I know who is
genuinely free, who has the time, the
peace, and the leverage they set out to
build, got there the same way. You've
got to do it systematically. Stop trying
to be the creator behind everything. If
you enjoyed this video, be sure to go
and like and subscribe. Go and download
that evaluation below. Welcome to the
Founder Freedom Movement and go and
watch this next video, which is how I
helped my friend Ali Abdaal go and set
up a similar system for his offer and
monetization. So, go check out that
video and I'll see you in the next one.