Here are some filming notes that I like
to consider, okay? And I'll go and zoom
in on this a little bit. So, loosen the
grip. Don't take it so seriously. You
know, make it an activity of play,
expression, and service rather than
pressure. I adopt a low importance
mentality. I actually learned this from
a book called Reality Transurfing, which
is a behemoth of a book. It's about
1,200 pages long, but one of the key
things is not taking things so
seriously. I also see it as this
movement from trying to perform for
someone, and it's more of just an
expression of myself. I'm just sharing
what I love, sharing the kind of things
that I find useful, and hopefully you
find it useful as well. I also approach
filming as this flow ritual. It's this
chance to really just get into my zone
of brilliance, tap into things that I'm
great at, that people really love from
me, and help just, you know, really give
you guys uh the stuff that I'm finding
useful right now. From there also, like
I detach myself from outcomes. I
honestly don't care how many views this
video gets. I don't care how many
subscribers this goes my channel. I'm
just looking to make content every week,
two videos a week that I'm proud of. And
if I push stuff that I'm proud of, then
honestly, I'm feeling good that week.
So, it's more of an obsession around the
process and the craftsmanship and the
beauty and the value than it is any
outcome.