So, it's funny. I get messages from
people all the time that see sort of
some of the travels that I may be on and
it looks sexy sometimes from the
outside. The reality is is that on the
background there's a bunch of kind of
systems that make all of this run
smoothly. When you go and you start
working and traveling, there are a bunch
of considerations. Wi-Fi, work setup,
routine, where's the gym? Where's the
healthy spots to eat around you? And so
what I've essentially done is in a lot
of the spots that I frequent regularly,
I've almost created like a pack for each
of those spots. So I have a Google map
save list of all the best spots in that
given location. I already have a saved
sort of ideal schedule based on that
location's time zone so that I don't
need to, you know, do some guessing game
around when I should wake up, when I
should take calls, when I where and when
I can have my morning coffee. I've kind
of optimized that day and instead of
just moving on to the next spot and
forgetting about that whole schedule,
I'll actually go and save that somewhere
so that my chief of staff, my sister can
go and just replicate that exact
schedule that was amazing, that was
peaceful, that was inspiring, and just
use that exact schedule when I come back
again. And got these time zone calendar
travel packs for each spot. So, I have
my kind of perfect week every week, no
matter where I