[Applause]
I'm
here
alone in a
jungle in the middle of nowhere in
Columbia I got 8 miles ahead of
me it's time to unpack some demons
[Music]
I've been an entrepreneur for almost
half my life I've been Rich I've been
poor I've loved my life and I've wanted
to end
it entrepreneurship may be this sexy new
career that everyone's going after but
the truth is it's not as sexy as these
Instagram grids would make it out to be
yes I currently operate two business
business that do over a million a month
but it hasn't always been that way I
graduated from college with no idea what
I wanted to do with my life I got a 9
to-5 that completely suffocated my brain
my first business bit maker burnt me out
and along the way I lost myself devic
it's been a lonely journey and I've kept
a lot of lessons challenges and
struggles bottled up these past 15 years
I want to take some time to unpack the
good
the bad the ugly and the Beautiful of
what these past 15 years in business
have taught me and we're going to do it
over the next s miles here in beautiful
Colombia let's
[Music]
go one thing that really drew me to
entrepreneurship was the power of
compounding if you're an entrepreneur
then you likely already understand this
but if you're not let me educate you for
a sec you know entrepreneurship is about
compounding growth whereas if you're in
a 9 to-5 you're on that linear growth
track the equation that helps illustrate
this is 1% better every single day 365
days a year is 37 times better in a year
and this is what you're really after
when you're an entrepreneur and not just
on the money side of things but from a
skill set standpoint as
well early on when I was building
businesses I knew how to sell and I knew
how to reach out to people that was
really about it as I started going and
growing as a Founder I realized that I
needed to have more than just two skills
I need to be a full stack found founder
copyrighting Marketing sales Tech design
you need all these if you really want to
scale up something
big compounding sounds like a obvious
thing now to me but when I was first
starting out I had no idea what I was
doing I was in a 9 to-5 job absolutely
hated my life going from grocery store
to grocery store working for craft
Foods it was the worst I realized that I
needed to actually own equity in a
business so I could see the effects of
compounding and get out of this dead end
9 to-5 and so I started trying anything
that would just allow me to get building
my own thing coding building websites
learning any skill I could and one thing
led to another and I started my first
business bit maker where we trained full
stack software engineers and got them
jobs at tech companies like Shopify meta
and Google the effect of compounding an
entrepreneurship is a lot like investing
you know you put a bit of money in the
stock
market and then you make some money over
time but the key thing is to be patient
you know not to rush it you know I think
people these days struggle with
impatience and they want that quick
money those quick results and the truth
is that's not how it works building an
audience creating content building a
community getting happy customers these
things they compound over time and the
most important thing just like investing
is to just let compounding work its
magic
[Music]
although a lot has changed there are
some parts of Entrepreneurship for me at
least that have stayed the same and one
of those Concepts is deep work deep work
to me is sacred time that you have each
day to focus and work on your most
important task I wake up every day
around 6:00 a.m. slow down get ready and
from 7:00 a.m. till 11:00 a.m. I block
out all distractions it's just me my
computer a notebook with a clear
checklist my headphones and a great
playlist either on brain.fm or listening
to some burning manset whoa from kind of
music brain.fm is essentially a website
you can go to you can go and select
different playlists that go and sync
your brain waves with the music and then
set a timer I'll go and set a timer for
4 hours every morning and my goal is to
work straight through those 4 hours on
generally the 9 things that I set out to
do which I've written down in my
notebook the night before and so I'm
waking up with purpose I know what I
need to get done and I'm just going
through those tasks from 1 through to 9
and then after those 4 hours generally
going taking a break in
nature those 4 hours are something that
have stayed consistent for me the last
15 years building businesses I think
there's nothing more important than
setting aside that time for yourself
daily you know if you can't go and set
aside time where you can focus daily on
what's most important to you then what
you're really after may never come
because time just slips You by and you
never prioritize your most important
things in
[Applause]
life and so the next thing you may be
trying to figure out is well how do I
figure out even what to deep work on you
know you may be so confused so
overwhelmed so lost well the first
things first is doing anything is better
than doing nothing you know the most
addictive drug in the world is momentum
and so give yourself permission just to
work on whatever you think is going to
be that next step
forward just taking action leads to a
feeling of progress leads to you feeling
like you know the winds at your back and
before you know it you know you're
stacking up a bunch of winds how I
figure out what to work on is simply by
looking at my 10year goals and then
working back from there at what I need
to get done over the next 3 years one
year 90 days then the next 30 days and
from there I'm very clear on well what
success looks like and I make sure that
in a given week
my goals lad up to completing those
30-day tasks and so I think the most
important concept for you to understand
at the very least is this the biggest
leverage thing you can do is before you
go to bed make sure that you write down
the nine things that you want to
complete the next
day I think that subconsciously when
you're asleep you start to process those
tasks you start to kind of formulate
solutions to them and most importantly
you wake up
with drive with a sense of purpose and
Clarity to get after it versus just
waking up in a malaise confused and
having no purpose or Clarity in terms of
what you're supposed to get done that
day and so you wake up you have your
nine things they're written down and
boom you're Off to the
[Music]
Races I think there are two kind of
Founders out there the first first
founder you know sees some initial
success then you know hits a bump in the
road and sure enough they don't know how
to get out of it because they're only
you know capable with the skills that
they initially had and feel like they
have no ability to
learn second kind of
founder hits a patch where they're not
sure what to do just like this and sure
enough they learn their way through it
right when I first got started in
business I didn't know all that much in
fact I didn't really know anything I
started picking up how to sell by just
getting out there and giving it a shot
and sure enough I ended up learning a
couple skill sets pretty quickly sales
and reaching out to folks but I quickly
learned that that wasn't enough to get
me by you know marketing is a whole
other beast and you can go and reach out
to people all day but it's a lot better
if you can just have people coming to
you like a magnet and so I started
learning the skill of writing online of
creating videos creating content and
everything changed for me and had I not
had that desire to learn I would have
never you know entered those
uncomfortable paths I would have never
even tried to make content never even
tried to grow an audience or grow my
personal brand
[Applause]
so some of you may be wondering well how
do I go and learn new stuff well first
things first you know learning is not
pretty you know often times it's just
you know picking up a book buying that
course joining a mastermind finding a
mentor or reaching out to a coach just
anything that whoa you know gets you
moving in the right direction so when it
comes to learning over my own career
there have been a few really standout
sources for me one is books you know the
concept of a book is actually kind of
trippy when you think about it you know
you got this ability to go and kind of
follow along a brilliant author and
learn directly from their best lessons
and so one book that really stood out
for me was the almanac of Nal rant nval
rant is founder of angelist prolific
investor in the valley and a legendary
founder and I love how the book dissects
his own philosophy on life business
and you know his approach to just living
a great life and so you know one thing
that really stood out for me from that
book is you know hard choices easy life
easy choices hard life
if it feels hard if it feels difficult
you're probably doing something right on
the other hand you know the easy life of
sitting on the couch or just relying on
the same old skills you've always had
while it feels easy in the short term
you're probably signing yourself up for
a hard life in the long term the second
source for me that's been really
transformative is coaches and ment ship
so years ago from all the stress of
building my first business I burnt
myself out and a doctor told me to go
get a life coach I was like what the
hell a doctor telling me to get a life
coach but sure enough I went and got a
coach his name is Ryan begelman and
Ryan's been one of the most
transformative people in my life he's
taught me how to manage my emotions
he's taught me how to better deal with
stress and how to find more positive
mechanisms for coping with the ups and
downs of Entrepreneurship
[Music]
so learning is good and all but where
the magic really starts is when you
prioritize taking Swift action action
breeds momentum and momentum breeds
results when it comes to taking action
you may be wondering well what do I take
action on I feel like one good mental
model here which was inspired by Peter
teal on this one is think about your
10-year vision and how could you
accomplish that 10-year Vision in 6
months now this caused you to really
take some big swings cuz you don't have
all the time in the world you know you
got to go and really get going
fast another mental model I find very
useful comes from Mel Robbins and it's
called the 5-second rule and so how it
works is this when you know you need to
accomplish something give yourself 5
Seconds to then go and get started on
that thing you know don't let yourself
procrastinate procrastination is the
worst disease of the 21st century and so
if you think of something that you need
to get going on get going immedi
[Music]
immediately you know there's a rule
called Parkinson's law you if you give
yourself a month to do something it's
going to take a month you give yourself
a week it's going to take a week you
give yourself a day well it's just going
to take a day and so I think what you
want to do is you want to shorten those
Loops so that you don't give yourself
all the time in the world to get things
done because you know what you don't
have all the time in the world you know
when you're small and you're getting
going speed is your competitive
advantage and so while all the other
guys are taking forever to get moving
you can win by just moving
[Music]
faster so when I talk about taking Swift
action the key thing here is I don't
mean on just anything the worst thing
you can do is just say yes to a bunch of
distractions and the most important
thing as a Founder is to be Discerning
it's to have good judgment you got to
know what to say hell yes to and then
not be afraid to just say no you know
Warren Buffett one of the richest guys
alive you know basically just gets paid
to sit on his hands and say no to 99% of
things so that the one yes he does say
he can put all his chips on that I
learned this lesson the hard way in life
I had an opportunity you know years ago
where I started working on a business
and for 6 months I was working on that
thing and realized I should have said no
day one you know I got clear on my
criteria and it turns out my criteria
for starting anything you know I need to
control 95% of the business I need to
love the customer I need to love the
problem I need to be able to build that
thing in 3 months or less I need to be
able to build Distribution on it day one
and it's got to have the ability to make
$5 million a year within the first two
years and this particular opportunity
that I found myself working on for six
months I had co-founders and you know
what I've learned over the years [\h__\h]
co-founders this opportunity I just
wasted a bunch of [\h__\h] time you want
to get clear on your criteria you know
what are the opportunities that you're
going to say yes to and what are the
criteria you need to see in any
opportunity if you don't see those
criteria you know say no don't feel like
you need to jump at everything
you know you only have so much time in a
day and so focus focus focus don't think
that you got to say yes to everything no
is often times the most powerful
response but the other side of that
equation obviously is yes you know how
do you know when to actually say yes to
something and the reality is
I like this concept called whole body
yes and it's how I make my decisions now
in my life and it goes something like
this you know when you go and are
considering any given opportunity you
got to kind of feel into your head your
mind your body your heart your soul how
does it feel how does it feel to say yes
to that that next move how does it feel
to say yes to that potential partner how
does it feel to say yes to that business
idea you know if it doesn't feel right
in your mind then don't overthink it
just say no if it doesn't feel right in
your heart trust it say no if it doesn't
feel right in your gut same deal just
say no you know only say yes to things
in life that are a whole body yes that
you feel aligned throughout your whole
body and excited invigorated to move
forward in that direction that's what we
call a hell
yes you know the worst kind of
entrepreneur is the entrepreneur that
says yes to everything you want to go be
Discerning and only say yes to the stuff
that makes
sense made out of the Jungle we're
moving here
but we're not done still three miles to
[Music]
go all right now that you've made a
little more space in your life by saying
no it's time to fill it with the most
important thing your health all right
let me just set that up there we go
nice okay the next lesson I had to learn
the hard way is that healthy Founders
build healthy
businesses when I was building my first
business I smoked daily I drank too
often and succumbed to a bunch of other
vices
and while we ended up having a
successful exit I nearly died along the
way what I learned is that building a
business is a marathon not a Sprint it's
about longevity it's about
sustainability and it's about staying in
the game for the long
term I think that too many Founders burn
themselves out by thinking that they got
to just rush everything you got to take
a step back and
perform a little bit of like the regret
minimization test you know look at
yourself when you're 82 years old and
look back on your life now you know what
are you going to wish you had done and
often times it comes down to things like
this you know getting out into nature
slowing down relaxing enjoying yourself
you know you're going to be successful
the question
is you know what would you do if you
knew you would be successful
you know you'd likely get outside
explore go on that trip take that
vacation now I make an effort every 6
weeks to go on what I call a sold trip
which is essentially just a spontaneous
trip out to a national park just like
this in Columbia you know been to yede
Big Sir Joshua Tree you know somewhere
just to escape turn off my phone unplug
with a good friend
and just go relax you know I think it's
these moments that end up giving you a
lot more clarity in your business and
giving you the ability to actually see
where you want to go you know I find
when you're just rushing all the time
often times you end up working really
hard but going in completely the wrong
direction slow is smooth and smooth is
fast and just slowing down you know
building good systems around your health
you know meditating to feel calm you
know reading to bring Clarity running to
get the heart pumping you know lifting
weights to really challenge yourself and
build resilience you know doing the
things that make you feel full give you
energy make you feel good so you can
bring that energy back to your mission
to your vision and accelerate things
[Music]
one belief I've learned over the years
is that entrepreneurs are
athletes and when you think about the
stress that we're under the
relentlessness that's required to day
after day no matter whether you're
having a good day or a bad day you got
to get after it and just like great
athletes need to train and need coaches
you need to train you need to coach and
you need to prioritize your health when
you're going in you're smoking drinking
watching porn you know just miserable
that's going to translate to your outer
world and your business is going to be a
reflection of how you feel similarly
you're taking care of yourself you feel
full you know you're making things
happen you're running you're You Know
Your vitality is ripping you know you're
hiking you're exploring nature you're
getting outside you're feeling good you
know the business around you is a
reflection of that and it grows while
you may win in the short term by just
grinding your faith off and hustling
overnight I can promise you it's not
worth it in the long term and I speak
from experience unfortunately so that
when you make all the money in the world
you're not just some person that can
hardly walk or is fat as hell you know
you want to be someone that can go and
Hike you know a 10,000ft Peak at 55 with
your family and your kids and look back
Without
Regrets you my belief is that it takes a
community to raise a founder and the
saying that your network is your net
worth is incredibly true and so let's
dive into that one on this next leg of
the
hike here we go all right
[Music]
if you're looking to build you know
multiple seven fig or even eight fig
business you need to build an amazing
Network the way I think about this is
like building a personal Board of
advisers you know think about all the
areas of your business that you need to
be successful in Marketing sales Tech
design who do you have around you that
can really help advise you in all of
those core areas don't think that you
need to do it all
alone now you may be wondering well then
how do I go Network and what does this
mean well generally I think networking's
got a bad rap because a bunch of people
don't know what they're doing and they
just ask ask ask folks and that's the
wrong way to go about it what you want
to be doing is really giving back to
people right if there's someone you want
to reach out to find a way that you can
actually help them you probably have
skills or some knowledge you know and is
there a way that you can first be of
assistance to someone so that you know
you're building some Goodwill and
building a real long-term relationship
versus making something you know super
transactional
you know I know along my journey mentors
you know have been everything my first
business was nearly shut down that's a
whole other story but it was chath you
know the legend that grew Facebook from
a million to a billion users that ended
up helping me out and saving my business
when I needed to get out of a super
sticky situation I met up with chath we
went for a walk
around Ottawa Canada he realized that
the government was looking to shut us
down for some ridiculous reasons and he
beli that our business needed to exist
and sure enough made a couple calls and
that was that we were back in business
in a week you know if that doesn't prove
the importance of your network well then
you know I don't know what
[Music]
will opportunities they don't happen in
isolation
get outside the building meet new people
you never know where any relationship
will go you know I've had some crazy
scenarios you know I reach out to
someone that I think will be a mentor
and then one thing leads to another and
they invest in my company or you know
one minute you're just helping someone
out with their business and helping them
grow and the next thing you know they're
a customer and so
as you're growing you know don't be shy
reach out to folks find a way to connect
with others you know you don't need to
go the Journey of Entrepreneurship alone
you know it's lonely enough as it is so
you don't need to make it any
[Music]
lonelier Steve Jobs Rick Ruben The
Beatles they all understand one thing
taste is the ultimate competitive
Advantage too many Founders these days
are focused on just shipping products or
creating content and what gets lost in
the mix of all this is the art the
love the
intention slowing down and making
something that you're not just proud of
tomorrow but you're going to be proud of
in 20 years in 50 years something that's
going to stand the test of time the
business knowledge that I've gone over
GE it took me 15 years to learn pain
Agony that's a lot of time I've gone and
synthesized all of these lessons into an
easy to implement chart down in the link
in the description that you can go
download right away so you can actually
take action and Implement these in your
life so go get that right
now when I go and look back on my 15
years there's a lot of stuff I put out
there that was candidly just complete
garbage it was rushed and I wasn't doing
it for the right intentions I was trying
to impress others my mom my dad some
friends a girlfriend who knows and I
realized the importance over time of
just doing things for you
you know I see myself as more of an
artist than an entrepreneur and I think
with that it comes down to putting a
piece of your soul into every single
thing you ship so don't just make
content make art don't just ship a
product make art don't just build a
company build a
[Music]
masterpiece now as much as I'm saying to
make a network
there are one form of individual that
you want to watch out for on your
journey I like to call them energy
vampires energy vampires are those folks
that after hanging out with them you
just feel like garbage they make you
feel down they make you feel like you're
stupid you know some way they screw up
your Vibe your Chi your energy so that's
why we call them energy vampires
these folks come in many forms I've had
teammates that are energy vampires
business partners customers and what
I've learned the hard way is the second
you sus one of these folks out cut them
get them out of your life because they
will drain you and they will break you
down know I've spent far too long over
my career with certain people around me
that all they're trying to do is bring
me down trying to discourage me trying
to see me fail ultimately and these
sorts of people you need to cut them
with a Vengeance there's no reason that
on your path you should be surrounding
yourself with people that make you feel
down or not worthy if you're not sure if
you're dealing with an energy vampire
here is the bulletproof energy vampire
test so you go and you hang out with
someone and you're not sure is this
person an energy vampire or not well all
you got to do is you got to leave that
given moment with that person and then
do a bit of an audit on how you feel do
you feel full of energy and feel like
going for a run or you know energized to
go and start building out a new idea or
do you leave that and just want to sit
on a couch feel drained maybe feel
sleepy want to go to bed or feel down
that is is an energy vampire you want to
run and cut that person from your life
as quickly as
possible you now often times it's hard
for us humans to understand opportunity
cost and with each person that we allow
into our lives we're ultimately saying
no to other potential people other
opportunities you know if I have one
teammate that's really bringing the
company down and sucking everyone's
energy you know that person is not just
going to bring me down but they're
sucking the opportunity that the entire
company could be getting after along the
way I could just be making an amazing
higher that could 10x that given area
and make us all feel the momentum that
we're really after and so you know being
intentional not just about Community not
just about your network but also making
sure that you do a bit of an energy
audit of the people around you and if
you're surrounding yourself with people
that are not going to be part of your
life in 5 years are bringing you down
cut
[Music]
them another crucial aspect to your
journey building a successful business
is well what I'm doing right now which
is storytelling you know just being your
authentic self here I am right out in
nature exploring adventuring hiking
doing the things that I love to do and
just sharing you know a couple stories
along the way with all of you
storytelling is really the vehicle by
which you can create a movement many of
you are out there whether it's getting
your first 100K per month or maybe your
first million a month and the crucial
thing is that you're not just building a
community but you're building a movement
of people storytelling is going to help
you sell more it's going to help you
Market your business and it's going to
help you attract top
talent you know at founder
West we're all about helping 100 million
Founders accomplish their dreams through
proven systems and my goal is to
make the founder Journey more joyful I
think that far too many Founders are
lonely
overwhelmed you know and don't have a
lot of community around them and proven
systems to help them scale their
businesses
storytelling is something that I really
overlooked early on in my career the
truth is though it is one of the most
powerful things that you can do you know
storytelling is more than just you know
writing it very much dictates your
strategy you know there are full-time
people within some of your favorite
brands that are just dedicated to
crafting and distributing the story
behind that
[Music]
brand how do you go and actually create
content with amazing stories well first
thing is you want to get clear on your
content categories right what are the
sort of subjects that you want to go and
talk about for me it's things like you
know Freedom audience growth systems
content you know and scaling businesses
now from there you may think about the
different formats by which you want to
tell stories could be things like
howtos guides in-depth
listicles now there's a lot of different
ways one thing I encourage you to do is
move from being a consumer online to a
curator someone that consumes content is
just simply ingesting this stuff all day
and not doing anything with it a curator
is someone that goes and when they see
content that really resonates with them
that hooks their attention they go and
they save that and they use it as
inspiration for their content in the
future and so you want to be going and
probably keeping an apple note on your
phone of all the different content ideas
that you come up with save different
things that catch your attention on
platforms like X LinkedIn Instagram even
on YouTube and then next time when
you're going to go go and create your
next Bank of content you likely want to
go and use these sources of inspiration
that you've gone and found to then draft
your own compelling storytelling you
want to be intentional about your story
and what it may look like is first off
getting clear on your mission from there
what's the origin story of your business
you know what are the emotions that
you're trying to evoke I know for what
I'm trying to do I'm all about evoking a
sense of inspiration of freedom and of
Adventure and
so I'd recommend that you go and you
write down your origin story what are
your missions what's your 10-year vision
and how can you use your story and
things like your onboarding your hiring
your marketing to attract more of your
dream customer
[Music]
[Applause]
every single lesson I shared with you
throughout this video and this hike
wouldn't be possible without systems
when it comes to video content branding
storytelling hiring onboarding all of
these pieces of your business require
systems entrepreneurship is a marathon
and it's not a Sprint
and so to stay in the game long enough
you need to make sure that you have
sustainable systems so you can run a
calm company a company where you don't
have crisises you don't have constant
chaos where you can breathe it's
peaceful it's enjoyable it's sustainable
so to create systems I like to go and
generally just keep it simple right the
best systems are the ones that are
followed and so for all core areas of
your business you want to go and
document you know exactly what are the 7
to 10 steps to go and complete that
given task you're going to go and list
those all out in a Google doc then
typically I'll use Loom to go and record
myself actually performing that task for
around 5 to 10 minutes and then from
there I have the video I have the actual
documentation and now I'll go add this
to a notion Company Wiki
that looks like this all right so this
is a notion Company Wiki inside of this
I keep all of the core systems for
founder OS so that whether you're an
existing teammate that needs to navigate
something that we've created you can
easily go and reference it and find it
quickly inside of the wiki or if you're
a new team member that we've just
onboarded you can easily go and navigate
all the Core Company documents inside of
one home base this is like the
brainchild of founder OS and so in this
I mean we've got everything um but you
know any one of these areas you know you
can see how we script long form and some
of the upcoming Concepts we have you can
see all the different deep work prompts
that I have for using chat gbt to
quickly bang out um different outlines
or landing pages um similarly you can
see every single role in the company all
the job descriptions um you can see you
know how we go and run our sales um
things like our pitch and the exact
script we use so anything founder us
related when we create it it's
systemized and then it's inputed into
this founder us Wiki so it's
referenceable and scalable I simply have
all of the different tasks organized
across the entire Company by department
and thereby people on the team when they
need to reference a certain system they
can go and refer to the Google Doc and
the loom video and it's especially
useful for new team members so when
you're hiring you're able to bring
people up to speed in record time so
that those people can go from newbie to
expert in a matter of 60 days document
your systems across your company to get
true
[Music]
Freedom if you want to work 4 hours a
day build systems if you want to have a
strong company build systems you know if
you want the ability to achieve achieve
real freedom in life build systems if
you want to be able to go and hike
around jungles in Columbia on a
Wednesday and pass the one month test
knowing that when you come back to your
business it's stronger than when you
left it build systems systems equal
[Music]
Freedom this channel is dedicated to
stories and to systems which are two
essential components to every successful
business if you enjoyed this video
you'll love my next video over here
which is how I work 4 hours a day using
proven systems and make over $730,000
per month so if you're looking for more
proven systems to scale your business be
sure to go like And subscribe below and
join the community of Founders globally
achieving Freedom through systems
[Music]