There is an advent of AI going and
transforming underneath our fingertips
here and I think most businesses are
going to die in the next 12 months. You
know, I'm talking to founders that are
doing $30 million plus a year in revenue
that are shaking in their boots because
one person in their garage with a swarm
of AI agents is going and just
completely transforming that business
model. What I'm going to be doing here
is going and mapping out the five core
areas of the stack with my good friend
John and we're going to be diving into
things like awareness, inquiry, sales,
delivery, and then automations and
looking at what the founder stack is
going to look like in 2030. Let's get
into it. How I think about this full
stack Yep. is where is AI eating into
and where should I play? Mhm.
>> So when I think about the most
successful founders, you're constantly
asking yourself what is the highest
point of leverage that I should be doing
that someone else can't do.
>> Right. So let's talk about that cuz
maybe there's like a criteria by which
maybe us both and like founders in
general should be even thinking before
they just dive in on this [\h__\h] So we'll
say criteria.
Um cool. So that one was Go for it. I
would just say like where is my humanity
and taste required? Okay. Everything
else because my thesis and I'm going to
get to here is everything else should be
done by AI. Right.
>> That is essentially where we're getting
to where a year ago people were saying
one person billion dollar businesses,
Yeah. I think we just hit the
technological escape velocity point
where that's going to start happening
and it's about who's going to be
prescient enough to know what part of
the stack for their particular
personality they should be exerting
their taste and then combining that with
like really really methodical moniable
thoughts around, okay, how do I build an
army of AI agents that handle the rest
of this and are thinking on my behalf.
All right. I love this. So let's talk
about taste for a second, right? Cuz
it's kind of a loaded word, right? Like,
oh, you know, be vulnerable or you got
to be more authentic as a creator,
right? And then there's taste. I mean,
when I think about it, I think it's like
your own unique combination of sort of
references, data, your judgment, your
intuition, maybe even like a bit of like
something above that like calls you to
like have just like around the edges
like this is beautiful and good and is,
you know, something that I think others
would love and this is like no bueno.
Yeah. How do you view it? If I were to
try to condense it down to a mental
model as you push me on this, I think I
actually view it through the lens of the
left brain and the right brain. Okay. As
in all of us all of us are on I tell the
team my team all the time, when you
think about the next wave of founders,
many of them will be what I call
successful creator entrepreneurs. Like
our most successful customers here at
Stand are all creator entrepreneurs. And
what I mean by that is if you think
about the spectrum of creative to
entrepreneur, on one side you have an
artist to the nth degree. So let's say
Vincent Van Gogh, right? Who was like an
artist to his own degree and never saw
commercial success while he was alive.
And on the other side on the
entrepreneur side you have someone like
Bezos or Elon who are highly mechanical,
highly rational. But arguably one could
say like maybe they should go to a
little therapy, you know. Point being to
answer your question on taste, I think
there's two forms of taste that I
recognize in myself. One is the right
brain side, so the creative side. And
that's all of us are born as a human
being or a soul that has unique ways
that they want to express themselves. We
all uniquely care about something. It's
like what is our gut? I think that is
the taste in which you present yourself.
That's like actually the outcomes of
brand in many ways. Like when people
think about brand that's actually just
someone exerting their taste in the
world. Mhm. Right? So that's the right
brain side. The left brain side, when I
think about taste, I think it just you
can condense it down to insight. And so
I think the most successful founders are
finding the pinpoint between their
insights in the market. So that's the
very logical brain being like, holy
[\h__\h] I see this market opportunity,
right? I see that people, for example,
want to like we are hitting a world
where the macro environment is leading
to so many people being able to be
entrepreneurs and also needing to be
entrepreneurs given where like society
is heading in terms of corporate
layoffs. Like you and I think have both
recognized that there's a clear market
opportunity and an insight to like, holy
[\h__\h] there's going to be a lot more
entrepreneurs in this next wave. And
then creatively authentically like both
of us are called to some version of
like, this is also sick. And I know
exactly how I want to help people. I
want to help founders specifically in
this way build this thing. And that's
like you expressing your taste and it's
a it's a Venn diagram to intersection
ideally between your logical insights
and then also your creative endeavors
and how you want to express yourself in
this world.
>> And I'm also thinking about this model
too in the sense of like how are agents
in this new like agentic wave going to
change these areas that people will also
be able to understand, okay, well, like
this is where we see sales going or this
is where we see, you know, personal
brands going in the future.
>> Totally. Once you know now the rules of
the game and how you're going to play
it, the first bit here is awareness. And
that's what this channel is all about,
right? Really helping you go and build a
profitable founder-led brand and do it
in a leveraged way with systems, agents,
the right team around you, and the right
thinking around it all. A founder-led
brand has really never been more
valuable, right? We talk about all the
time how distribution is the new moat.
You know, now you can see based on how
things are going, right? You're going to
be able to replicate so many different
things, but the one thing that can't be
replicated, right, is your own taste,
who you are.
>> In this next bit, we go and deep dive
into some of the core insights we think
people need to adopt, the mindset behind
it, and how you should be thinking for
the future. Let's start with like
awareness. So, you know, we're both
into, you know, we see this world where,
you know, founders have an incredible
amount of agency, distribution is the
new moat. It's been the moat for a
while, but now it's become more
important than ever. You have this like
future where a single founder can create
a billion-dollar company. And the big
thing is like, if you're a creator and
you only have, you know, one person in
your audience and I'm a creator and I
have a million people in my audience,
same tool, even if yours is better,
mine's inevitably probably going to be
more successful just from sheer
distribution.
>> Yes, exactly. That quote that, you know,
we all know is like, you know,
first-time founders focus on tech,
second-time founders focus on
distribution. So, this area seems more
important than ever. How are you kind of
looking at it?
>> I think net-net, if we were to
generalize, I 100% agree with you that
distribution is the new differentiation.
I I would that all the time now, cuz if
you think about it, where is AI eating
from? So, if we were to draw, like But
if we were to think about like little AI
bot
here. This is a work of art. Look at the
taste here. Look at this taste. This
guy's just low-key just like this is
like the future Reddit logo almost by
going on here, you know?
This is starting to get to my
visualization, buddies. But if we think
about where AI is starting right now,
where you think of Cursor, you think of
Lovable, we're now compressing like
anyone being able to code with Cloud
Code or any of these tools. And so,
where is AI today? It's this way. And
so, and then we think about what are our
competitive advantages as human beings
for lack of a better term. It's going to
be this way. Yeah, like And so, we're
going to have to meet in the middle at
some point where I'm going to guess, at
least for me as a persona, I'm more of a
the founder personal brand visionary
storyteller persona. I'm likely going to
be better off asking my my AI bot to
think about automations in my business
over time and partner with awesome smart
people who can think about this stuff.
And so, my stack is going to go this way
in terms of very clear automations. And
then at the same time, I'm going to do
this, but I'm going to be really, really
insightful about If I want to scale
actually over time, I'm going to put my
magic here, but then I need to just
steal my magic into a workflow so that I
can also AI-ify this as well and
automation this as well. In this case,
we would talk to AI agents and turn the
workflow there, but before we would just
be telling our team and teaching a team
how to scale. This is just significantly
more efficient. Yeah. Right. And the
ramp-up is is significantly faster. So.
>> I love that thinking. And so, a lot of
people watching this, you know, we've
both built some organic audiences on
YouTube. And just to get more tactical
maybe in this area before you move on,
someone's, you know, growing on YouTube.
They've put out, you know, 50 videos.
They've got around 1,000 subs. The
world's changing. Like how do we maybe
thinking that these folks in their world
may change and some things that they
should be paying attention to in the
future? This is exactly why we launched
Stanley and he's having so much success.
So, for everyone else's context, um
Stanley is our new AI content agent.
Basically, we're turning him into
someone's head of content. And the way
we think about it is we want to unleash
human potential. If you even if you
think about awareness, a lot of this is
basically marketing, right? Marketing
awareness is marketing. Awareness is
like good creative, coming up with cool
creative concepts. But you and I have
been doing this long enough that you
know there's also killer execution
behind it of like, for example, having
competitive insights of knowing like
what is actually doing well in the
market and then how can I repackage
that? Mhm. Or it's like, oh, how do I
actually really analyze my analytics, my
watch time retention to actually improve
my videos over time so my product of
content or awareness actually gets
better over time as well? And so the way
I would really think about this is a
mental model for awareness for anyone
out there who's making content is what
are my special sauces? What am I
disproportionately good at? So that
might be like ideation and scripting.
Like you are just a killer at like
visualizing the coolest video ever or
like you for sure can just like spit
game. Yeah, what is my special sauce?
Um, that's where I'd be over indexing
towards spending my time and then I'd be
thinking about how do I use an AI agent
like Stanley to do everything else. So
like how do I have an agent like edit
for me if like editing blows my brains
out? Like there's like tons of AI tools
out there that you can do whatever or
you can build your own and so in that
process basically it's like, okay, what
are all the things within awareness that
I suck at or that should be automated or
I should have like a logical brain
applied to this and have um, your AI
tools do that and then on the aware and
then you're pairing that with like your
special unique human special sauces.
Yeah. Okay, so awareness alone isn't
going to cut it though, right? You need
to actually go and own your audience,
right? You need to own your distribution
and that happens in the inquiry stage. I
actually think this is the most exciting
part of the whole flow and here's why.
We move on to now like inquiry, right?
When it comes to how I see this is like
just basically we both agree that, you
know, with founder led brands, the big
thing is like you actually own your
distribution, right? You don't need to
rely on Zuck, you don't need to rely on
Musk, you don't have that platform risk
that we all terrified of, you know, you
never know that one day you just get rug
pulled by a platform. The whole
attractive part of actually owning your
distribution is like having an email
list and owning that data. How do we see
that kind of evolving I guess, by 2030
or, you know, we can maybe even just
2028 at this rate? Well, I think this is
where things start to get really
exciting and it goes back to this little
guy here,
which is um
right now, if you imagine the average
stack for inquiry, it's, you know, you
give out a lead magnet, what have you,
maybe have someone join a you know, they
go to your landing page, what have you,
and then they maybe join your email list
or even for people who are doing, let's
say, high-ticket sales, the inquiry is
still like, you know, you reach out to
someone, they get on the phone, all this
kind of stuff. But, if you notice, it's
all like very static. And the thing
about this this little clanker here is
like
this is
Clanker, man. I like the name, too. This
is a good name. I like it.
But, in this specifically, imagine you
have someone who's constantly obsessing
over your landing page, who's constantly
obsessing over your email, right? Right
now, like, you know, you think about,
okay, right now we have to do the mental
cognitive work. Our old mental model was
we had to do the mental cognitive work
to figure out how to optimize this
inquiry stack. How do you optimize your
conversion from awareness into actually
sale? But, now instead with these guys,
like, for example, I could just be like
I could just set up an agent and be
like, this is my landing page. I want
you to constantly obsess over AB
testing. You can just give them the
agent the prompt, "You're in charge of
maximizing this conversion rate." And
then this guy is going to be so smart
and he's going to test, "Okay, well, I
see that you have a traffic of 1,000
people a day. I'm going to send 500 to
this page. I'm going to send another 500
to this page." And then the next day
he's going to take that learning, he's
just going to keep iterating in some
sort of way. And I think this is where
agents get really, really exciting for
people as they think about like the
ultimate like way to optimize their
business. Like, holy [\h__\h] what if I had
1,000 people or 1,000 agents thinking
about how do I optimize my business
across the stack? Yeah. And I think the
inquiry stage, as you were saying
before, is one of the exciting most
exciting places to do that. I also see
it, too, as
it's like right at this stage here, like
you've
captured attention in like a really
saucy way, right? With like smart
packaging and all that. Yeah, similar to
what we're both saying. I think, yeah,
again, this is where it gets super
exciting to me because now you've
actually captured some form of data,
but because now it's like on steroids.
Like just the amount of richness that it
can now
kind of consume based on that data. Like
now maybe it knows, "Okay, Matt Gray's
entered entered in his email here. Okay,
well I've already captured his
Instagram, his LinkedIn, his X, his
YouTube. I've already provided this
report. I've spun up this thing for
him." And like my next interaction,
it's kind of already selling me. Yeah.
And cuz it's just so mind-blowing.
>> Totally. Yeah. Yeah. I think there's
like a crazy amount of This is a new
way. I I think you're very right to say
that this We'll get into these They're
sure really exciting, too. But this is
one of the places that is most ripe for
innovation in a way that like
it's going to be better than anything
anyone's ever done before because you're
just going to have Think about it like
agents autonomously creatively thinking
about how do I upgrade this conversion
flow. It's going to be a lot of a lot of
chaos in that, too, but out of chaos
comes a lot of creativity and therefore
productivity.
>> Yeah, I think this is the opportunity
for like like we're both saying, like
the biggest wow moment I think will
exist here because this is also in like
the most boring [\h__\h] like a thank you
page. Like the what people expect and
then
um you know, what's cap- what you're
capable of now is just that dis-
you know, that that whatever, that
divide or that gap is just so wide. From
thank you pages to insanely optimized,
you know,
landing pages already being built for
you after you just put in an email is
pretty nutty. Yeah. So now you've gone
through inquiry and now it's time to
make the sale. One thing I'm hearing a
lot at this stage is, "Will sales people
even exist in 2030?" You know, it's a
good question. And I certainly think
that bad sales people will become
extinct. Great sales people, I think,
will move beyond just being sales folks
to really thinking of themselves like
entrepreneurs. Everyone needs to think
of themselves as running a business
unit. The world is changing and it's
that entrepreneurial hunger, grit, and
ingenuity that's going to help anyone
compete in 2030 and make sure that
they're really capitalizing on this
opportunity that is under our fingertips
today. Cool. So let's move to sales now.
Are sales people going to exist in 2030?
You know, I've been thinking about this
a lot and I was talking to a buddy this
past week as we were both playing with
our open claw bots and we were like,
"Dude, we're so cooked as a society."
And then I was like, "So,
are we humans just going to exist to
vibe?"
Like I think at least for the next few
years, if you're selling something high
ticket or there's a human decision maker
with a large budget, I think some
version of like us as humans vibing is
still going to be very valuable. That
like now that model completely goes away
one day when like we've all lost agency
as human beings and AI take over
decisions as decision makers in the
buyers, but I do believe that there's
still something to be said of how how
one feels about you, what they think of
you, their perspective on you, whether
they trust you. I think that's very
inherently important. Like that's one of
our core values here at Standish, like
make sure that we're showing up in that
way, but I do believe that sales will
exist in some format, but I think it's
constantly what AI's doing is like if
you think about all the rote activities
under sales, so it's like prospecting,
even sending cold emails to some degree,
we're just basically automating
everything under the stack like before
technology and the internet automated
like writing email like writing letters
to people or doing phone calls into
emails and have you, it's condensing
that stack. So basically what AI's going
to do in the automation is going to do
is going to allow you to further move up
like the human actualization curve of
like, "Okay, what am I what am I what
are the most human parts about me?"
Which is like how do I express myself,
how do I connect with people and I think
that's still very inherently valuable.
Yeah, one thing I've been thinking about
like on the subject of vibe is something
a little bit different. It's like
there's always these
you know, pendulums in terms of like how
the world's thinking about like a given
company. Like years ago, you know, I
think it was like 5 years ago, there was
kind of a moment in society where it was
like, you know, kind of even now, right?
Like screw all these billionaires,
right? Like what the hell are all these
billionaires doing and there's a bit of
that there's a bit of an
anti-entrepreneur
sentiment in society, let's just say,
right? So the pendulum, let's just say
has gone a little bit anti-entrepreneur,
let's say in one world, right? I feel
like this is kind of bringing it back
where the pendulum's got to come back to
a centered place where we're all
entrepreneurs.
>> Yes. And what does that mean? Well, in a
sales department, let's just talk about
that cuz we're on it. It's like we are
all founders and we all are running
business units. And so you're just an
entrepreneur running your prospects and
your business within this. And the ones
that will still exist in 2030 will view
it like that. Like, oh yeah, I've got
my, you know, I got my thousand folks. I
got to run it this way. I yeah, I got to
automate these road activities. I got to
come up with new ways. I'm going to keep
on speaking this thing and automating
more and you got to run it like a
business. I think the ones that will not
survive and will be gone well before
2030 are the ones that are kind of just
like, "It's another day. Where are my
leads, you know? What's going on over
here? Things look a little dry. Like
what what's going on here
John? Like what what's happening? Where
are all the leads?" And it's like, yeah,
that's not going to fly anymore. At
least as a general mindset, you know.
100% it goes back to what we said before
like high agency people are going to
win, right? It's I think about this all
the time with the best hires. You're the
best hires, it's a can versus can't do
attitude. Right. Do you use the fact
that you don't have leads as an excuse
that you're not performing or are you so
[\h__\h] hungry that you want to make it?
That you're like, "Fuck it. I'm then I'm
going to [\h__\h] put things in my own
hands. I'm going to build a bunch of AI
agents or I'm personally going to go out
there and source on LinkedIn if I have
to." Right? So that same attitude is
what's going to lead to someone's
success. And you just now have a
superpower rocket fuel tool to do so.
Yeah, exactly. Yeah, no, I think yeah,
hungry sales people will always win,
right? So sales is your promise, okay?
But delivery is the proof. 90% of
founders that I speak with, this is the
stage that is the hardest part for them.
If you sell someone, but they're not
happy with your product, well, you're in
for a storm of bad reviews. But you nail
this piece like we have at FounderUs and
you end up with 100 plus Trustpilot
reviews on your pages there. And so how
do you go and make sure people are
delighted? Well, first thing I think you
got to think about the people that are
actually doing the work in your company.
Typically, the customer success folks
that you've hired. And so I think
there's a beautiful future here where
every single customer success person on
your team is armed with a few core
agents that can help make things like
onboarding, delivery, about all the done
for you assets you want to produce or
people all easily done working 24/7
executing things at an insanely high
degree. And so, how do you go and
capitalize on this? I think you need to
take a step back because there's a few
key frameworks that we uncover here that
I think will be extremely useful to you.
One thing I think we've kind of been
pointing out here a little bit is just
this idea that things are just getting
smarter. Yes. Right? So, how do you kind
of see that going on your side? I think
this is a really great example of how AI
is going to make delivery so much more
awesome. I think we're all I think we're
about to hit the era of incredible
consumer experiences. What I mean by
that is if you are no longer stressed
about like up times and like coding and
building the actual thing, that allows
us as entrepreneurs or who are
delivering who are thinking about a
product or service to really be
creative. Right? Because if you have an
AI agent already automating and thinking
about how do I improve this product at a
baseline, that then frees up your net
zero sum time and energy and mental
focus to be like, "Okay, what is the
like I already have a solid funnel here
of like how do I make sure that
someone's successful in their first like
30 days on my product? How do I [\h__\h]
push the needle and make this awesome?"
And like this is what the human
creativity allows you like it is now
enabled to do because the stack below it
is now completely run by agents who are
doing the coding, who are doing the
basic product management, who are doing
the project manager, tracking the Jira
tickets, what have you. And then this is
all just like how do I as a human being
show up for other human beings in a way
that they really [\h__\h] with.
>> For a lot of founders, I think this is
the area that causes the most headaches.
Yes. Right? It's easy to market
yourself, right? It's easy to sell some
[\h__\h] then delivering it is just, you
know, that shit's hard sometimes, right?
Like and, you know, customers have, you
know, changing tastes and preferences
and you said one thing but then they
want a different thing. So, how do we
see, you know, on the positive side here
like I'm a customer success person like
how's my life going to get just [\h__\h]
way more amazing in this new era? It's
well it's going to get I think way more
amazing because it's you're going to
really succeed in terms of the
repeatability of quality execution.
So, when you think about delivering a
phenomenal
product at scale, when I mean that like
think about it's easy for a founder to
you know, personally serve one or two
people. Where it really breaks down is
when you start to have a million people
who are different. Right? And like
Santa's starting to hit the scale where
it's like holy [\h__\h] You wouldn't even
guess all the nuances of like all the
17,000 different like edge cases that
things go wrong. And you don't have
enough people with enough like resources
and energy to focus and fix all these
things. Also because fixing something
for one person actually leads to it
breaking for someone else or like not
being optimal for the other person. And
so what AI allows you to do is to like
customize at the edges. And so it really
allows a single person as an example,
like a single person founder to build
something that can serve millions of
people in a way that ends up being
customized for that person. Yeah. And
that is something that we could just
could not have done before. Yeah. I also
think like it's so customized.
I think the mental model that's going to
be most helpful for people here
is so much of our lives we've always had
to be doers. And the people who will
succeed in this new paradigm will be
directors. So, really upgrading your
thought process from I'm a director from
I'm a doer into I'm a director and
decision maker. The more you can do that
with this, that's how you're going to
get more scale. Right? Because you're no
longer spending all of your time like
all your because like people don't
recognize that success at the highest
levels I've learned one of the key
pieces is how you focus your time and
energy. Because focused time and energy
is zero sum. It's like one of the it's
our most limited commodity. And so in
that, if you're spending all of your
time just like being like you know, a
little investment banking intern like I
was back in the day just like cranking,
you're obviously going to do great work
there, but is it the highest value work?
No, it's not. Instead, you're going to
have an AI agent do that stuff and send
your client follow-ups. And then that
allows you to like really make the right
decision and really see the high-level
pattern that you wouldn't see if you
were like stuck in the box. Maybe let's
kind of
land the plane here a bit. Um so, in the
interest of landing it, I think what
people are probably wondering is like,
"Okay, cool. So, I understand a little
bit of the map of a general kind of
customer journey in a given business,
and I see how these different areas, the
kind of four pieces of most businesses,
are going to change dramatically." And
then the kind of mindset um that's going
to help separate you, whether it's like
really seeing distribution as a moat all
the way to seeing yourself as a director
over a doer. And so, when we think about
kind of building this kind of like
agentic future as a founder, what do we
think are some things that you know,
they can take action on like right now?
So, this is the one you've been waiting
for, right? Automations. With so many
things about to get automated, it's
pretty hard to think about what a
founder is even going to do in 2030. And
so, first things first, when we rewind
to today, right? How do we go and even
think about the role of a founder? And
how do you even take action in all this
today? It's one thing to see the future,
and I know half of you are probably
seeing the opportunity of it, and half
of you are freaking terrified. Or maybe
you're a mix of the both. But either
way, there's one thing that we can
control, what we do right here, right
now. And so, I don't want to leave you
here without giving you the seven core
steps that I think you should take right
now. I think one thing, just to kind of
kick us off, is I think that everyone,
similar to what we've done awareness,
inquiry, sale, delivery, just in terms
of the future, I think that everyone
should map this for their business. And
start thinking like you had brought up
on the road activities in all these four
quadrants. Yes. So, let's maybe I don't
know, we can start there, and you rip
the next part.
>> Yeah. Um so, road
activities
per
pillar, let's call it.
Go for it. So, this I think is exactly
the baseline foundation. So, in order to
free yourself up to do net innovative
things, one must first have to have to
get out of the shitty stuff that you
don't like. In the same way that like
when a founder first starts, they're
answering all their emails, at some
point they get an EA who loves doing
that cuz the founder doesn't love doing
that. And so, the 100% the first thing
to do, very tactically, is to map out
your whole business like a supply chain,
like a little workflow diagram, and be
like, "Oh, I [\h__\h] hate that. That
That That's not very good. I I do like
doing that, but I'm it's not very good
at this." And so, those are all the
things that we should be thinking about,
"Okay, how do I deploy automations that
are better than me, right?" Or how do I
at least hire someone who's awesome to
do those things with AI agents? From
there, then you get to evolve to two,
supercharge yourself. What I mean by
that is once you automate all the [\h__\h]
that you don't like, and you have
something in place in your system that's
better than you, then this is where AI
gets really really crazy. Because you
and I now, because we know how to build
and make great content, and this is one
of our superpowers, now like, "Okay, how
do I deploy AI agents underneath me to
be really [\h__\h] sick?" I see you know,
from here it's like, you know, when they
tell you like if a plane crashes, like
put on your safety mask and then go put
on the others. I feel like step three is
now, "Okay, you've used the tech, you've
deployed it as yourself, you've worked
on this map hopefully with your team as
an established founder, and now it's
time for you to supercharge your team."
Yes. And so, when you think about a
team, right, and supercharging it in
this new age, like culturally, just how
do you like get them on board this [\h__\h]
This is so This is actually what I'm
thinking about constantly right now.
I've been telling it internally as AI
fluency. I've basically just been like,
you have to culturally make sure that
your whole organization is thinking
about AI. And the way I position it to
the team is like, "Guys, obviously this
is super important for our business.
Everyone gets the rational piece of
this, but what's like personally really
important to me is that you learn these
skills so you don't get left behind."
And so, we're already planning our first
AI build day, like a little AI hackathon
week. I'm hearing this from like the
best guys, like
>> Yeah, everyone's like doing these like
hackathons or something.
>> to upgrade You got to upgrade your team.
You got to help them scale, right?
Because it like I I feel I like you
write this as a thing, cuz like maybe
out of this, get your team together,
it's a hackathon time. It is You have to
Your job as the founder, the
entrepreneur, is to How I view it is
like, you're all on this path together.
And like, if you're on this path, oh my
god, this is such a bad bad animation.
But you're walking this path, you're the
trailblazer up here.
And in this context, AI agents are the
trailblazing that you have to do. Your
team is so busy doing this [\h__\h] like
you owe it to them to help them get up
here and see the next ledge. And so very
tactically what that means is you got to
learn how to do this stuff. You got to
hack away in my opinion on cloud code,
co-work, what have you or like build
your own open cloud bot so you
understand. You start to see the use
cases and then yes, you translate that
to your team. You're like, "Guys, spend
2 hours with me like doing this." And
you'll have a couple other people on
your team who are already excited about
this. Like very tactically we have a
channel called #AIBuilders that my
teammates started. I didn't start it.
And they just post their super cool
products. Like someone will be like,
"Hey guys, I actually completely built
this dashboard to monitor this thing
with AI." And that culturally you'll see
all of your top employees start to
inspire the other folks. And then you
get everyone in a room and you
fundamentally over a week upgrade how
they think about the world. Yeah. Once
you get them all hackathoning where
like, "Holy [\h__\h] this blew my mind. I
have so much more agency to do cool
things." Yeah, the next part of this
that I think it's like a little bit of a
curveball, but you know, in this idea
that like everyone these days is an
entrepreneur, right?
>> Yes. And so, you know, as entrepreneurs,
right? Like what is one of the things
that like have agency, right? But we're
also heavily incentivized. Yes. Right?
And you think about Charlie Munger, he's
like, you know, "Humans are incentive
machines." Right? So I think like you
have this hackathon and maybe like a few
great things come out of it, right?
Maybe, you know, it's like Google's like
Fridays where they had their own free
time and you see something bubbling up
and it's like the Gmail of your company.
Right? It's like, "Okay, cool. How do
you go and incentivize these people now
off of these like little innovations
they're building within your business?"
Because the reality is too, everyone's
an entrepreneur right now and it is the
day and age where anyone can go and
build a one person billion dollar
business hypothetically, right? So how
do we make sure that as these new things
are being spawned inside of our
companies that people are like, "I'm
[\h__\h] stoked as hell, right?" It's
like, "Wow, the upside potential here is
amazing." I mean, this is where you get
into like boring management topics at
times. I think it's important though,
you know?
>> It's very very important which is it's
all about org structure and
compensation.
Let's say someone comes up with an idea
for the next Gmail. Org structure wise
if you still have them working on the
old project, you have to make the
decision, do I empower this person? Do I
see enough potential in this thing that
I'm actually going to free up their time
to do this thing and give them the
autonomy and direction to do that? You
have to make that decision for your
business based off the context. And
then, like anything else in life,
exactly you said the Charlie Munger
quote, show me the incentive, I'll show
you the outcome. If you're hiring great
people, they're going to be hungry
enough to do this themselves, no matter
what. My personal philosophy behind that
is also they should take a ton ton of
that upside, whether it's equity or or
cash-based compensation. Like yeah, you
got to give them the upside and the
incentive. Yeah, and then I think I just
all along the way, like you had brought
up, right? It's like just cultivating
that director mindset. Yeah. Right? Um I
love that vibe of like, yeah, be a
director over a doer. And whether it's
the director of your little fleet of uh
clunkers
uh clankers, sorry.
This is uh this is pretty crazy future,
damn. Yeah.
Yeah, it's a lot to take in. It is
simultaneously the scariest time, I
think, ever in human society in many
ways cuz of the sheer complexity of the
world and all of the changing chaos, but
also to that the most exciting time.
Yeah. Right? Well, I'm excited.
Appreciate your time here chopping it up
and uh I mean, let's get to work. Dude,
heck yeah.
>> Here we go. Thank you. Thanks, sir.
Boom. And uh like and subscribe to Matt.
He's going to teach you how to build a
great personal brand. Yeah. All right,
so that's the full stack. Awareness,
inquiry, sale, delivery, and
automations. You know, you got to really
understand what's the parts that you
have the best taste and judgment in, the
areas that are your biggest strengths,
and then the areas that you're excited
by. I then recommend that you go through
those seven steps so you can make sure
that you're taking advantage of this
moment cuz truthfully, I don't think
there's ever been a more exciting time
in my 18 years building companies. I
want to go and make sure that on this
channel, we're giving you kind of the
breaking new ways to go and make sense
of this because I think the game is
being rewritten as we speak. And so, be
sure to go and like and subscribe. You
can go and check out this next video in
terms of how I go and organize my whole
business to take advantage of this
movement we're seeing, and I can't wait
to see what you create. Let's win
together.