All right, here are five signs that your
business owns you. Right? You wake up
and you check Slack before your eyes
even adjust to the sunlight.
No bueno. Number two, you can't
disappear for 30 days because
if you leave your business,
everything's just going to collapse.
Number three is that your calendar is
fully booked from 8:00 a.m. on Monday
all the way through to Friday at 5:00
p.m. Right? Where's your time to think,
to scheme, to plot?
You need time just to think as a
founder.
Number four,
your revenues may be going up. Maybe you
just even hit your biggest milestone,
right? You hit $5 million a year.
But your freedom is absolutely destroyed
and that's the real reason why you
probably got into business in the first
place. And then when you think about
your real priorities in life, things
like, you know, your kids soccer game,
well, you can't just be off your phone
because if you're off your phone and not
available, well,
those fires aren't going to be fought.
And so, if you can't leave your business
for a month, right, without,
you know, there being blow-ups
or issues,
well, you've built yourself more of a
founder prison and what you're probably
looking for is founder freedom. So, what
do you got to do? Well, first things
first is I got to get your core team in
a room and map out the 21 core systems,
three in the different seven categories
in your business. Things like your
marketing, sales, finance, ops,
onboarding, delivery, right? And map out
what needs to be in place for this thing
to run more smoothly. From there, assign
a systems owner to each one of those
areas, right? So that not everything
falls on your plate as the founder.