This AI selling hack makes people buy
from you almost every single time. When
you're going and building any business,
you have technically a group of 20% of
your customers that are going to make up
around 80% of your revenue. And so what
you want to go and do is go and pay
attention to the sales calls that you
did to go and get those clients across
the line. go and get the transcript from
Fathom AI which should hook into your
Zoom so that any Zoom call where either
you or a salesperson on your team close
someone you're able to then go and
transcribe all of that. What I'll
typically go and do then is go and copy
and paste that entire Fathom AI
transcript of those top value calls and
go and paste those into a document. This
is a copywriting gold mine. Now what
I'll then do is go and move this over to
Claude. I have a project here called
voice of customer. It has an abundance
of the words of my actual customers and
I can leverage this for different
copies.