These are three types of content you
need to be posting if you're looking to
grow on social media. Number one,
listicles. Number two, how-tos. And
number three, storytelling based
content. Listicles are great just
because they're easily digestible and
they have a clear value ladder that
people can follow. Your how-tos are
going to give people a deeper dive into
how you can actually provide value for
them. These kinds of content are going
to be the ones that probably convert the
highest. On the storytelling side, this
is the kind of content that allows
people to develop a level of emotional
resonance with you. It gives people the
ability to get to know you. where your
failures, your mistakes, challenges,
wins, successes, all that stuff that
allows people to really get to know the
real you. So once you then have these
three types of content, what you want to
be doing is content waterfalling these
into all the platforms to become
omnipresent. Simply [music] taking one
pillar piece of content, say an in-depth
how-to video, and then turning that into
three Instagram reels, three YouTube
shorts, a newsletter in a few weeks, a
podcast, you get it. When you can
maximize each of these formats, [music]
you can double down on making the most
exceptional content in your niche.