I've cut a million dollars of head count
in the last 5 months.
A million bucks.
Simplifying things,
deleting what is unnecessary,
all in the interest
of building, number one, a beautiful
cash flowing portfolio.
Two, just keeping everything insanely
simple.
Because really to me that's like one of
the most important values
in my life. And I've done it by creating
around like 160 different skills, things
for, you know, call grading,
proposals, decks,
you know,
basically everything from sales to
customer success, finance, ops, kind of
building this autonomous engine.
But at the end of the day,
I really just want to be an artist,
right? With a
beautiful systematized like autonomous
engine behind me.
So, I don't need to worry.
You can just have peace. You feel me?