Relaxation
is really a superpower. This is going to
sound backwards, but the most successful
founders I know don't work the hardest,
they work the least. Not because they're
lazy, but because they've discovered
something that most founders never
figure out. Relaxation is power. Now, I
know what you're thinking. You're
probably grinding on your business, you
know, checking Slack messages at 10
p.m., waking up to endless emails and
feeling like every day is just a grind,
and that if you relax, you're being
lazy. But what if I told you that the
founders making millions are working 4
hours a day while you're burning out?
Even if you think you need to hustle to
make it, even if you believe being busy
equals productive, don't worry. I used
to think the same thing. But that's the
real paradox of relaxation. You know, a
weird thing has happened to me over the
years. You know, the more relaxed I've
become, the more successful I've become.
The more calm I've become as a leader,
the more money I've made. I think it's
because, you know, relaxation allows you
to be your ultimate creative genius and
tap into the ultimate creative power
that surrounds you. It's everywhere.
It's abundant. And when you're tense,
you block that. But when you're open,
when you're relaxed, you channel it. You
channel it into everything you're
building in a day. This ability to then
go and channel that energy, right?
Because I'm in this relaxed state, it
allows me to build bigger, better,
crazier things, right? Because I'm
tapped into something special, right?
That creative flow, those juices, that
magic, right? And it is there in all of
us. It's at all of our fingertips. And
the question is, are you relaxed enough
to allow it to just be? Because it's
truly your natural state. But we often
times get so busy, so wrapped up, so
tense, so stressed,
so addicted to things and distracted
that we just block that creative flow
that is at the root of who we are. I
used to think that taking a break
was a sign of laziness.
I used to think taking a weekend off was
a sign that I wasn't serious.
I used to think that, you know, going
and spending time with family and
friends, you know, I had to make up for
that time by grinding harder afterwards.
This general hustle, this grind culture,
it's really getting to us. How many
nights do you find yourself with your
thoughts stirring in your head,
wondering, you know, where your next
lead's going to come from? What's going
to happen with that employee that's
going sour? you know, how you're going
to go and get your business to the next
level given the current challenges
you're currently facing. You know, these
thoughts circling around in your head
constantly. The tension building in your
body, the feeling like if it goes on
another 3 6 9
12 months like this, are you going to be
able to hang on? Here's what no one
tells you about building a business. You
know, the market rewards calm, not
chaos. You know, while everyone else is
just hustling and grinding and rushing,
the real founders are focused on
calmness. The calmness that's required
to build something of quality, the
relaxation that's required to build a
team of legends,
the tranquility that's needed to
magnetize a movement around what you're
building. You can't attract people if
you're stressed the [\h__\h] out. You're
just going to scare them off. When you
have that calm, confident state, that
sort of zen vibe, you attract people
because there's a degree of resonance
there. By the end of this video, you'll
see why the richest founders do things
like take long walks, meditate, journal,
and integrate travel, nature into their
everyday lives.
Because the truth is
success isn't about calmness or
profitability.
Now, the most successful founders
actually realize that it's about both.
And we're going to get into some key
systems that'll show you how to go and
integrate relaxation into your life to
build a more powerful life and business
and ultimately be a more powerful
leader. And for the first 5 years
building businesses from the age of
about 19 to 24, I was all about
grind, grind, grind. I think it's super
important to put in that work, right?
Certainly not discounting the importance
of hard work, getting after it, and you
know, really going for your dreams. I
also think that if you're going to be
doing this for the rest of your life,
you're going to be building things,
crafting things, mastering things,
tinkering, designing, writing, building.
You know, one of the most important
aspects then is longevity. It's making
sure things are sustainable and that
you're going to stay in the game.
Because most businesses I've built,
they've been successful over the long
term. And when I look at that, one of
the most important things to consider is
to be able to stay in the game, to not
allow yourself to suddenly get too burnt
out. You know, start drinking to cope
with it and be able to actually go and
find a level of peace, of calm, of
relaxation,
of adventure, travel, living your
dreams, some degree of balance, whatever
that means to you. You know, as an
example, right now I'm building a
business called Founder OS, and my
mission is to impact 100 million
founders through proven systems to help
them grow their audience, their brands,
but also live amazing lives. I believe
that entrepreneurs shouldn't have to
worship the church of hustle. There's a
different way of building businesses.
Building something around what you love
that contributes to the world in amazing
ways that you love your customer. You're
able to serve them in a beautiful way.
You're able to dive deep into your own
mastery, your own artistry, and over
time build something super special. One
of the most important traits is having
this long-term mindset. But the piece
that doesn't get talked about enough is
the importance of relaxation, of rest.
Now, here's what people get wrong. I
call it the relaxation paradox. People
think that relaxation equals being lazy.
They think that if you're taking it
easy, if you're living in that calm,
relaxed state, that you're too chill and
you're not taking your work serious
enough. But that's not how I see it.
I've learned something that I call
strategic stillness.
Now, we've all had it, right? You've had
a busy day. You've been tense, stressed
out. You decide you're going to go and,
you know, take a quick hot shower. So,
you go get undressed, get in the shower.
The water starts hitting you. You feel
this sense of calm come over your body.
You suddenly, you know, lathering
yourself, doing your thing, and suddenly
a light bulb moment hits you.
you have a major breakthrough and you
weren't even thinking about the thing
you were trying to solve. So
what happened in that moment?
What suddenly changed? You weren't
trying any harder. You weren't
overthinking it. You certainly weren't
stressing it. You were rather relaxed.
That's exactly it. You loosened the
grip. You let yourself slow down. You
let your body
chill out and suddenly like that you get
the exact breakthrough you were looking
for. This is what strategic stillness is
all about. It's about finding that level
of relaxation, not just in a warm shower
here and there, but trying to integrate
it into more and more moments in your
daily life. I know that sounds difficult
because I've struggled with this a lot
myself. Here's a quick strategy for you.
I call it finding your relaxation room.
Now close your eyes, okay? And imagine a
room that's insanely relaxing, like your
dream room in life. For me, it's on, you
know, a nice leather recliner chair in
my cabin in the woods of Big Su,
California.
I'm sitting back. There's a relaxation
that comes over my entire body. I'm
looking out a window, seeing the waves
crash against the coast. As I look
around, I'm living my dream life. I'm
who I want to be. I'm where I want to
be. I'm surrounded by nature, by love,
by community.
I've built everything I ever dreamed of.
And my body feels entirely relaxed from
my head to my toe. This is my relaxation
room. and I come to this imagined room
probably 20 times a day. I use it in
moments where maybe I'm going from a
busy meeting and now I'm going on a date
and I want to make sure that the
franticness maybe of a meeting doesn't
carry over to that date I'm about to go
on. that in between offers a chance to
go to my relaxation room to tap into
that level of calm and tranquility so
that I can reset myself for that next
experience in my life. And this is a way
to then bring presence to that next
experience so that I can be my full
self. I can get lost in the moment. I
can shine. It's important to understand
that if you're going to be your ultimate
creative self, which I think that as
founders, our mission should be to
unlock our full creative potential and
help others do the same. My biggest
strategy for unlocking that full
creative potential. If I was to think of
one thing that's most important, it is 4
hours of relaxed founder flow every
morning. Now, founder flow is that
opportunity to dive deep into your most
important tasks of the day before anyone
else can bug you. It's removing
distractions. It's being able to
completely block out any stressful stuff
and be able to relax, settle in to the
stuff that only you can do. That's why
you were put on Earth. That's the stuff
that's really going to take your
business to the next level, take your
life to the next level. Well, those 4
hours of founder flow are critical. And
when you find yourself relaxing into the
founder flow, that is when you're
unstoppable.
Now, I know, you know, I've used things
like alcohol, other drugs to go and calm
my nerves because I couldn't cope with
the stress or I didn't know how, you
know, didn't treat people great.
I got angry, frustrated. I was an
[\h__\h] at times. Truthfully, I was
treating myself a hundred times worse.
You know, we can talk about all these
external systems and ways to grow
businesses, right? Increase your cash
flow. You know, make sure you have tight
controls, make sure you're hiring,
right? Make sure that you're building
content in the right way, your audience
growth systems, make sure that you're on
every platform in the right way, the
right style, with the right formats. All
these things, sure they matter, but the
most important thing to your business,
your dreams, is you. And when I mean
you, I mean that inner state. Being more
patient, slowing down,
embracing nature,
giving ourselves time to be quiet
can be that medicine, you know, that
mentor
that helps us
develop clarity. develop that
breakthrough thinking that is going to
really help us transform and not just
maybe double our business but 10x it.
You know, when I learned to relax in
businesses that I've built, you know, I
stopped focusing so much on the metrics.
Yeah, cash flow is important, audience
growth is important, you know, profit
per employee, all these things matter,
but
I think the ultimate metric as a founder
is
sleep at night. That feeling that you
have peace of mind, that you can have a
great sleep, sleep your whole eight
hours and not be waking up in the middle
of the night or waking up in the morning
in just a sudden night tear or just
dreading the day to come because that's
no way to live. And so these days when
I'm going and building something, I
focus on that mastery. You may be
saying, "Well, that sounds all good,
Matt, but what is mastery?" To me, I
stop worrying about metrics and I start
thinking about reps. You know, I know
that when I started this YouTube channel
as an example, I wasn't focused on
getting to a million subscribers or 10
million subscribers or millions of
views. It was about making 100red videos
that I'm proud of. And that allowed me
to go and sink in and relax into the
cinematography, the lighting, developing
my own edge, my own voice, becoming
comfortable in front of the camera and
speaking to you guys. That focus on the
craftsmanship makes it more of this
forever journey. I'm going to spend the
rest of my life, you know, mastering my
ability to become a good
cinematographer, become great on camera,
become great at connecting with you,
being vulnerable, giving you guys the
value you deserve, helping the previous
version of myself that needed a hand,
needed some mentorship, and just really
having the backs of founders like
yourself. really making sure that you
guys are taken care of, you feel like
you have a best friend uh that's looking
out for you, and hopefully bit by bit,
I'm able to make your journey a little
more joyful. Even if you think that
relaxation is anti-productive,
even if you think you're already relaxed
enough, no, I want to dive deeper into
this subject and show you why the right
form of relaxation is really the secret
to your success. I want to now show you
how to go and build a profitable comm
business. So, let's break this down a
bit. And if you're looking for my
complete comm business blueprint, you
can go and get it via the link in the
description. I've gone and synthesized
everything I've learned over the last 14
years building multiple calm, profitable
businesses into a free easy playbook
that you can go and check out. over 25
pages of some of the best systems,
tactics that you can go and implement
today to go and transform your life and
business. Now, I'm always going to be
real with you, right? The truth is, you
know, I have stressful days. I'm not
some guy that's, you know, always
relaxed or anything like that, right?
We're all human. You know, life can get
a little hairy. But there are some core
strategies that I've learned to build a
calm, profitable business. And I'm going
to break down my calm founder system for
you. Calm stands for clear your mind,
automate your operations,
limit your focus, and master your
energy. I'm going to go and break each
one of these down in detail so you can
go and implement them today.
Every morning, I spend about 20 minutes
doing what I call mind cleaning. I'll go
and have nothing but my journal in front
of me. I'll go and start off by just
journaling oftentimes between one and
three pages just my founder flow as to
what I'm fueling that day, right? And
this is before I've touched social
media, touch Slack, touch email. It's
just me, my subconscious just letting
out any of the thoughts in my mind.
Often times what comes out um is a lot
of gratitude. Gratitude for you, the
amazing community that we've built
around this channel. Gratitude for
everything around me, my ability to
travel, experience amazing nature like
this. Gratitude for my health, my
family, my friends, the love in my life,
the success, the wealth, the abundance.
And then from there, I'll go and ask
myself, you know, the three things that
I can get done in those four hours of
founder flow that will move the needle
most in my life, helping me get towards
my big 90-day goals, one-year goals,
5year goals, and ultimately where I'm
looking to go over the next 10 years.
This
activity allows me to start my days from
a degree of groundedness.
Feel relaxed knowing I don't need to do
everything. What I need to focus on is
keeping the most important thing the
most important thing.
So the next step to building a calm
profitable business is to automate your
operations. I used to try and do
everything in my business. I thought
that, you know, if you want it done
right, you got to do it yourself.
But this was a fast track to burnout and
being absolutely miserable. It really
comes down to taking a bird's eye view
of your business, zooming out for a sec,
and going, "Okay, what are the seven
core steps that take a customer from
hearing about me to converting to my
business and then telling their
friends?" So these stages may look like
things like you know awareness,
you know, joining your email list,
hopping on a sales call, converting,
onboarding, joining your community, and
then referring their friends. Now, when
you go and you look at each of those
seven stages, what you will find is that
there's often times like three core
parts of that stage. So then 21 pieces
or components in total that make up your
entire business for the most part and
are kind of like the 8020. And if you're
able to automate those 80% of your
operations and make sure that there's a
systems designer or architect other than
you in charge of each one of those
pieces, you're able to then go and
delegate it. Have peace of mind that you
don't need to be in charge of that
aspect anymore. And you can go and focus
on things that are way more important in
life, right? Working on your business,
not in it. Having peace of mind that you
can go and be your ultimate creative
self. Work on the parts of your business
that you love the most, that you lose
track of time doing as we collectively
do this as this systemized empire, this
calm, systemized business. We're able to
go and accomplish things that, you know,
years ago we wouldn't even dreamed
possible. you know, running epic
experiences all over the world, founder
hikes, building an awesome movement
around what we're doing, growing the
audience at 3x every year, creating
content that inspires people. You know,
I have dreams of, you know, bringing
this YouTube channel and getting a
Netflix deal one day. I have dreams of
opening a founder retreat center here in
the Doommites. You know, I have dreams
of releasing a best-selling book every
single year for the next seven years. I
have dreams of you know going to every
country in the world all 195. This is
all possible right because of these
systems right and this calm approach
this relaxed approach and the core to
that is making sure that I'm systemizing
all the pieces around me that could
become distractions and removing myself
from those pieces so that every moment
of my life can be as calm as possible.
Now, this is all good and all, and it's
all good to go and know that you've got
to build your systemized comm empire,
but the next thing that you need to get
right is you need to limit your focus.
So many founders that I meet and so many
founders that I help inside of Founder
OS, they're trying to do everything all
at once. And this is the recipe to
overwhelm. If you really want to build
something, I think you need to follow
the 333 rule. Maximum three projects at
a time. maximum three tasks you're
focused on and maximum three things
you're going to get done each morning.
When you can just really hone in your
focus, you can transform your life.
Focus is your scarcest resource.
Everyone's pulling at it. you know,
social media, the news, your team, and
it is your job to be a warrior with your
focus and protect it at all costs
because your ability to get to where
you're looking to go is the product of
your ability to focus on what is most
important to you. For me, what's most
important is really building an amazing
team, you know, coming up with legendary
product updates and building content
that I'm proud of. If I can just focus
on those three things, those three
projects overall and the few tasks that
come up around those on a daily basis
and just keep checking them off day by
day, amazing things can happen. And you
can see this is also why having a
long-term mindset is so important
because my focus isn't just sprinting
like hell to get everything done in one
day. I know that I'm going to be
building found rest for the rest of my
life. As an example, you know, I'm
living everyday retirement. You know,
the stuff that I work on every day is
stuff that I would do even if I was
retired. And I could retire, but the
truth is, I just genuinely love what I
do. It fires me up. It keeps me
stimulated. And so, I don't need to get
everything done this week. I don't need
to get everything done this month. I
know that over a long enough time span,
I'm going to be insanely successful. And
I think the same is true for you.
So much of building a business is
staying in the game. It's longevity. And
you're going to do your best work if you
limit your focus and have a long-term
mindset with what you're doing. Don't
rush. Slow down. Embrace slowness.
Embrace falling deeply into the task at
hand. Not just rushing onto the next
thing, but going 10 layers deeper.
Because the magic in creation is the
depth. It's not shallowly creating a
bunch of things. It's choosing a couple
things to go insanely deep with. You
know, I'm inspired by people like, you
know, Jurro Dreams of Sushi. You know,
someone that's been, you know, creating
unbelievable sushi, you know, in a
subway station in Japan for like 50
years and still isn't quite been able to
go and make the perfect piece of sushi.
It's this lifelong journey he's on,
right, to make the best sushi roll
possible, right? And you know, for me, I
see it as the same sort of journey. His
journey of making the best pieces of
content possible, inspiring the most
founders possible, of you know, being
able to build a future that helps the
dreamers, the builders, the creators,
because I believe that the future
belongs to founders. It belongs to you.
And my purpose here on Earth is to
enable you to give you the tools, the
systems, the automations, the AI powered
agents, all this cool stuff that we've
got going to help you accomplish your
wildest dreams. That fires me up, you
know, being able to build something that
inspires hundreds of millions of people
just like you. This unbelievable vision
though is only going to happen by just
day by day, piece by piece limiting my
focus and just focusing on three things
at a time. Now you've, you know, really
limited your focus, right? But focus is
nothing if you're feeling drained and
depleted. That's why the last piece of
creating a calm systemized empire is
mastering your energy.
leadership and success. It's a habit of
really taking care of your inner world
because the more in my life that I've
taken care of, you know, my feelings, my
mental and emotional regulation, my
diet, my body, you know, the more I've
taken care of my inner state, the more
my external state has transformed. I've
been able to build, you know, amazing
communities, products, brands, all these
external things that you may see,
they're all a product of me feeling
great internally. For me, it's about
having the right health systems in
place. You know, healthy founders build
healthy systems build healthy
businesses. You know, meditating daily,
taking time to journal. I love to fast
until about noon every day. It's about
getting enough sleep. For me, sobriety
is a really important part of my life,
right? Giving up alcohol and, you know,
sobriety is really a superpower for me.
It's, you know, exercising. It's being
in nature, you know, taking soul trips.
About every six weeks I take a
spontaneous trip to nature somewhere
like this. We're currently here in the
Dolommites in Italy and take time to,
you know, read every day to be creative
to, you know, journal and draw and do
different art projects that eventually,
you know, turn into products. Now, it's
important that you you're taking time to
really master your energy, right?
Because everything that you're after,
right, is a product of your energy,
right? You want to build this thing. And
you want to hire those people. It all
comes down to you feeling relaxed, you
feeling great in your energy because
energy attracts, right? If you're
feeling great, if you're feeling
abundant, wealthy, successful, you're in
love with life, people are going to be
attracted to that, right? And you're not
going to have to chase everything in
your life. Suddenly, it's just going to
find its way in a serendipitous way to
you. Yeah. This is your reminder, right?
Move your body, work out daily, break a
sweat, get into nature, go on a
spontaneous trip, make sure you're
taking care of your inner world. The
better that you feel as a founder, the
better the work you're going to be able
to do in your life, right? That's what
it's all about. That relaxed energy is
critical. It allows your creativity just
to beam through you. It allows you to
really just go and develop that state of
flow with the task. That state of, you
know, everything else kind of is blocked
out. All you're obsessively kind of
focused on is that task at hand. And
you're able to get lost in it. You end
up connecting dots that would not
otherwise been able to be connected. You
end up seeing opportunities that others
wouldn't see. You start to, you know,
tap into other people, other resources
that you have that wouldn't otherwise be
obvious. And you can do this because
you're relaxed, right? You're tapping in
to what I believe is some higher power,
something bigger than yourself. It's
truly magical. And this is how I've
connected all the dots in my business,
right? These sessions have allowed me to
go and build our community to 3 million
plus people worldwide. It's allowed me
to go and move forward our movement of
helping a 100 million founders
accomplish their dreams. It's helped me
build a team of 25 legends behind
Founder OS. It's helped me build Herb to
a company that now runs itself and
remove myself from operations. It's
helped me go and develop insane, you
know, relationships, hire amazing
people. It has been the number one
determinant factor in my success. And it
has to be in a relaxed state. You know,
relaxation is power. Your ability to
build your calm, systemized empire is, I
think, one of the most important and
powerful things you can get done this
year. And so, take time for yourself.
Master your energy, limit your focus,
automate your operations. You know, this
is what you deserve. You deserve
calmness, relaxation.
You deserve a feeling
of tranquility.
So, via the link below in the
description, I've gone and provided you
guys with a bit of a calm founder
blueprint. This is a blueprint that I've
gone and spent about 20 hours of my life
mastering. Um, and me and my team went
and built it out for you. It contains a
lot of the tactics, systems, and overall
playbook for how you can go and
implement more calmness, more relaxation
into your life to build your own calm,
systemized, profitable empire. So,
you're definitely going to want to go
and check that out via the link in the
description. I'm sure it's going to have
a massive impact on your life and
business along the way. If you want to
get more help from me, from my team to
help you go build your own calm business
and implement more of these systems and
tactics into your life, your business,
well, you're definitely going to want to
go and check out Founder OS. It's my
life work, something I've spent the last
four years formally building, the last
15 years of my life architecting. Um,
and I'm sure you'd get a ton out of it
if you've enjoyed this video. And so you
can go and check that out and apply to
Founder OS via the link in the
description. Much love and let's win
together.