here's the real story of how Mr Beast
built an Empire worth more than $500
million his real name is Jimmy Donaldson
and he was born on May 7th 1998 he
uploaded his first YouTube video in
February of 2012 at just 13 years old
after 3 years he' gained 30,000
subscribers he tried college but dropped
out after 2 weeks his first viral video
was in 2017 when he uploaded a 23-hour
video showing himself counting to
100,000 he did other similar videos such
as spinning a fidget spinner for 24
hours and watching in Jake Paul's it's
everyday bro music video for 10 hours
straight and by 2017 his channel reached
1 million subscribers now he's the most
watched YouTuber on the planet as well
as the founder of Mr Beast bger in
febles in his own words dream as big as
you want to and never apologize for it