My best friends know me as an intense
mother [\h__\h] People think I'm just
this Zen CEO guy. And honestly, it's a
bit of a lie. Here's the deal, right?
When you're building a business, things
can get intense, right? At times, they
get a bit chaotic. And the truth is, you
know, my business is no different than
any business out there in terms of this
default state of entropy. You know,
whether it's your business, my business,
you know, things come up. You know,
people quit.
There's still fires that happen, right?
And
I want to just be able to be real with
you, right? That, you know, even me, you
know, at 20 years into entrepreneurship,
you know, I still struggle with this
stuff at times. And I say this to you um
because you know, I don't want to convey
um some person online um that purely all
the time has it like figured out. I
think that all of us entrepreneurs
really are just figuring it out as we
go, right? And there's so many things
that I don't know that I'm still
learning. I was on a call with a mentor,
Neil Patel, this morning talking to Neil
about, you know, our current, you know,
model for the company, how we're getting
the business um to $2 million of cash
collected per month. Um and, you know,
I'm coming to him with a bit of a plan,
but about 50% of that plan, I'll be
honest, right? I really don't know what
I'm doing. I guess I'm just saying all
this because when I look at the people
that I respect most, you know, Steve
Jobs, Jony Ive, Brian Chesky, Elon, you
know, all of us, you know, founders,
we've got flaws. And it it isn't all
smooth sailing. And I think that for me,
when I look at my own life, probably
like many of you, right? I straddle like
many different vibes, many different
sort of personalities almost in a way.
For sure, I can be that Zen guy when
I'm, you know, taking that 3-week break
in the summer to go to the Dolomites or
going snowboarding in Japan for 3 weeks
and just unplugging. But I would
actually say that a lot of my default
state is I'm pretty damn intense, right?
My team would say, "I'm an intense
motherfucker." And I think it's
interesting when I meet different
founders and they get a sense for me in
person, they're like, "Holy [\h__\h] You
know, this guy This guy's really in it.
And he's [\h__\h] passionate." They would
say I'm intense. You know, I was on a
call with a founder, Kyler, um who's
someone inside of Founder OS Edge, uh
which is a, you know, small group of
founders um that I work with directly uh
one-on-one, helping them every single
week to help them scale up their
companies. But, oftentimes what comes up
on these is a lot of like mindset stuff.
You know, even just how to build balance
into business, right? Kyler and I were
talking Kyler's been having some
troubles really, you know, taking breaks
from just the intensity of the work,
having fun, going on adventures, having
a social life. And I resonate with this
because, honestly, that stuff doesn't
come naturally to me, either. I'm an
introvert, reading, you know, working
out on my own, cold bath, sauna, and
deep work. You know, that to me is like
my peace. But, obviously, like, you
know, having a social life and community
and adventures, all this stuff is
important. And you Kyler was asking me,
you know, "How exactly do you fit that
in? How do you think about it?" And for
me, you know, I think there's a few
strategies that I think about. You know,
uh being an intense [\h__\h] right?
How do I kind of build in these moments
um that allow me to find my zen because,
again, truthfully, it's not my default
state. Number one is any location I go
to, I have a list in my phone called,
you know, "Bali peeps" or "Miami peeps"
or "LA peeps", depending on where I am
in the world, which is like my people.
And before I go and land in that given
destination, let's say I'm about to go
and take off to Bali from Miami, I go
and I message all 20 of those people and
I let them know, "Hey, I'm landing.
Would love to do something fun. Do you
guys want to go on a volcano hike, do
some cold bath sauna, go hang out? You
know, whatever. Let's uh let's organize
something." And so, sure enough, then
when I've landed, right, automatically
there's some of these social things
going on. Inherently then, that stuff
gets scheduled and it forces me to kind
of pull myself away from my businesses
because again, you know, I'm an intense
[\h__\h] And so, if I'm not doing
much or I don't have much going on, I
just kind of find myself working,
building because it's just what I love
to do. The next thing that I love to do
is basically every 6 to 8 weeks
scheduling some sort of adventure. Just
yesterday, I scheduled 1 week in Byron
Bay, Australia. Never been before, uh
but we're sending it. Um so, in 6 weeks,
going with a friend,
heading out there, go relax, unplug, do
a bit of a dopamine detox. I find that
there's not only benefit from doing
these kind of soul trips every 6 to 8
weeks for the sake of actually, you
know, pulling yourself away, but the
nice thing, too, is that along the way,
um you get to benefit from the
anticipation of that thing coming up,
right? So, you know, not to mention,
too, it just again forces you to get
away from the intensity of building. And
I think for many of us, intense, crazy
[\h__\h] you know, taking breaks,
right, finding that zen has the same
sort of benefit and you feel the same
sort of way, right? Like initially,
you're like, man, I don't know if I can
afford to take this weekend off, you
know, I don't know if I can afford to go
to this social gathering tonight, you
know, I don't know if I can afford to,
you know, go on that vacation, right?
But then sure enough, you go on it, you
know, you finally have the chance to
down regulate your nervous system, you
know, you realize, damn, you know, I
really needed that and, you know, some
creative sparks start flying, you start
to get that mojo back. Because, you
know, when we look at our businesses,
right, often times, they really are a
reflection um of our nervous systems as
a founder. And I know that if I get
caught up too much in that intense side
of things,
what ends up happening is, um candidly,
I'm just an [\h__\h] I'm short-fused. My
intensity can turn into a like kind of
overly abrupt and blunt and, you know, a
lack of listening and someone that can
be just too aggressive and just hard to
be around. What we end up finding is,
yeah, maybe you're moving a lot of
things forwards, um but you're also kind
of moving some things two steps
backwards, you know, with Founder OS, we
are, you know, really pushing the needle
with everything that we're doing. I view
business kind of like a video game, and
the video game that we're playing is
trying to build um the greatest founder
infrastructure in the world. I want to
allow founders to go build a plug-in to
the infrastructure that we've built and
be able to build out world-class
distribution in media companies for
them. AI is going to replace a lot of
things over the next bit, but I think
the final frontier of it it will not
replace is your ability to build your
own distribution, your own media, and
control your destiny. I think there's
this amazing window in this kind of
category that we've been leading, and
I'm really obsessed, if I'm being
honest, around being
at the forefront of that category,
really inventing that category, right?
This kind of founder infrastructure
layer. And so, with that, right? Because
of that, you know, obsession, because of
the creativity behind it, because of
this mission I feel like we're all on
and that the team is really excited by
and that we all know that we're really
changing the game with. The reality is,
you know, we are getting after it. You
know, my default state is really going
for it, right? Because this is something
we're excited by. Bring founders these
systems. We're excited to serve founders
at the highest level possible. I really
do believe that our, you know, care,
right? Our giving-a-shit inside of the
company is one of our biggest
competitive advantages. While being zen
is nice and all, and you know, maybe my
day start in sort of a zen mode, right?
Maybe listening to this
meditation over here, right? which we
released on YouTube about a year ago.
You know, once
uh once my meditation's over, right? And
I'm up and at it, and we're one, you
know, iced Americano down, you know,
we're going to war here, though. I
realize this is happening
just when, you know, multiple founders
like come up to me, again, they just get
surprised by my intensity, you know, I'm
helping them in their businesses,
they're seeing the pace at which I'm
moving, and, you know, just really
addressing the elephant in the room,
which is like, hey, like, if someone
wants to build a media company, we got
to put some real moves in place here,
right? Like, there's not It's not going
to be easy, right? This is going to be
hard, you got to be committed, um and
they can see a level of like yeah, just
intensity on my side. And I realized
that, you know, while maybe people are
seeing things like the Dolomites or
Bali, and, you know, truthfully, too,
when I'm filming most times, I'm, you
know, just in a bit of a different mode.
I'm sitting down and just talking to you
guys about maybe some systems I'm doing,
or sharing my screen, or cuz and so that
stuff's all true, right? But, what
oftentimes maybe you guys aren't seeing,
right, is just like the
behind-the-scenes at the actual like
pace
um I'm pushing myself and pushing the
team as well. It's that pace you set,
which is kind of the company you build.
Just wanted to basically We just
addressed that, cuz my goal is always to
come across and just be res real as
possible with you guys. Um I want to
paint a real picture, um and, you know,
just had the thought this morning
um that it was worth just uh you know,
letting you guys know about this this
other side of me that you may not see as
much, you know, there's uh there's
obviously a lot of work that goes on
behind the scenes from me, from the
team. Um and that work uh you know,
ain't always easy,
um and it ain't always pretty, and uh it
certainly ain't always zen. And I just
thought it'd be good to be real about
that uh to set the record straight. If
you're someone, you know, following this
channel, you probably follow this for
the idea that we can have it all as
founders, right? We can have a vibrant
life and a vibrant business. We can be
like zen at times and be intense
[\h__\h] We can want to build a
beautiful, calm business, while also
wanting to win our category and get the
[\h__\h] after it. We can, you know, want
to, you know, be able to remove
ourselves in the business for 3 weeks
and come back to a business that's
stronger than when we left. Well, also
when we're in the business and there
with the team wanting to push it, right?
And evolve and dominate. What makes
founders special, right? Is this ability
to kind of straddle two seemingly
disparate worlds, right? And uh you
know, sometimes I think you may see that
one world of the Zen calm systems dude,
right? Um but yeah, do not be mistaken,
right? There is a crazy [\h__\h]
also behind the scenes and I think this
is you know, what I you know, see
founders inside of Founder OS, you know,
getting a taste of, you know, that that
David Goggins side of things that's you
know, pushing the needle, trying to help
folks win,
really helping people
you know, bring a new level of caliber
and expectations to how they operate and
how their team operates. And it's by
setting those high standards for myself
as well that I've been able to be, you
know, successful over the years. And so,
yeah. That's kind of what I But you
know, we just want to be relaxed, you
know, and just drink a little, The Zen
guy is not always
>> Yeah, we're not we're not too Zen, but
we know, we'll have a smoothie here and
there.
>> [snorts]