To everyone who's ever told anyone with
a dream they can't,
this video is for you.
>> Every iconic brand started with a
founder that focused on a key principle
to create something legendary.
>> You're not in it for the money.
>> I don't think anyone at the company's in
it for the money. If today were the last
day of my life, would I want to do what
I am about to do today?
>> Anyone working on a big vision is going
to get called crazy, even if you end up
right. I've studied these principles for
the last 15 years to build a business
and brand that's created more wealth,
influence, and freedom than I ever could
have imagined. In this video, I'm going
to break down the seven core principles
so you can stop playing small and start
building your empire. The first and most
important principle of building an
iconic personal brand,
consistency.
Casey Neistat went and filmed a vlog for
800 days straight. filming, editing,
putting the storytelling together every
single day in the same 24 hours that you
and I have. That is insane levels of
consistency. And here's the math behind
it all. If you go and you put in 100
reps and with each one of those reps,
you get 10% better. By the 100th rep,
how much better do you think you are?
No, not a thousand times better. Not
even 5,000 times better. You're 13,800
times better by that 100th rep. This is
the magic of compounding and this is the
math you sign up for when you're
consistent. I know when I first got
started building my personal brand, I
just focus on creating writing that I
was proud of 1,000 times. Now, you know,
fast forward, I've created a brand that
has over 3 million people around it.
Truthfully, this is not even what I was
after day one. I just wanted to be
ruthlessly consistent every single day
for years. And I knew that at the end of
the day, the score would take care of
itself. And so when you go and you're
building your iconic brand, focus on
decades, not years. Pick a craft that
you genuinely would be excited to do for
the next 10 years and then just stick to
it. Every day do the thing and don't
break the chain.
>> And the three of us decided to start the
company. Frankly, I had no idea how to
do it and nor did they. None of us knew
how to do anything. I think one of my
great advantages is that I have very low
expectations.
>> Jensen Hang was sitting down with some
Stanford students and he said this about
suffering.
>> Most of the Stanford graduates have very
high expectations. People with very high
expectations have very low resilience
and unfortunately resilience matters in
success.
>> In 1995, Nvidia almost went out of
business. Now, fast forward to 2025 and
it was the first $4 trillion company in
the world. It was this level of sticking
with it even when no one believed in the
company. Hell, it was a video game
software company. You know, very few saw
the potential for this to become the
most valuable company in the world. But
Jensen Huang, you know, stuck with it
through thick and thin and even
mortgaging his house. And it was this
level of suffering that led to the
resilience necessary to become this
successful. You know, I've experienced
this in my own life. You know, looking
back over 14 years ago, I was working 80
hours a week in my first business. It
hurt like hell. But it was all this pain
building my first company that forced me
to go and find a better way because I
knew how I was building it wasn't
sustainable. Because in those deepest
challenges in life are the kernel the
genius. And this is the pain and
suffering that's necessary to go and
build your iconic brand.
>> To this day, I use the word the phrase
pain and suffering inside our company
with great glee. Boy, this is going to
cause a lot of pain and suffering. And I
mean that in a happy way because you
want to train, you want to refine the
character of your company.
>> It's currently October 4th, 2015. At the
time I'm recording this video, I have
8,000 subscribers. So, whenever you see
this, compare these numbers to whatever
I have when you watch this.
Mr. Beast is notorious for thinking
insanely long term about any project he
takes. Every single video that Jimmy
puts out, he bets the farm each and
every time. People think he's nuts, a
borderline addicted gambler. But it's
this level of obsession around the
craft, not the results, not the numbers,
not the money, but the craft itself that
separates Jimmy from every other
YouTuber.
>> I think one of my greatest superpowers
is my obsession. And I think some people
would view that as a weakness. But if
you just think about solving problems
three times more than everyone else,
like you're bound to come up with
different solutions.
>> Jimmy had 20 subs in 2012 and 15,000
subs in 2015. These are humble numbers.
You can just imagine how obsessed Mr.
Beast was. That obsession, it didn't
compound linearly. It compounds
exponentially. With each rep, he's
getting 50% better, 20% better, betting
all the chips, going allin every time.
Now, the reality is is that obsession is
contagious. In the world of building
iconic personal brands, every single day
there's thousands of people starting on
the different platforms and a level of
obsession will set you apart. You know,
you can imagine going and choosing to
either build on X, LinkedIn, YouTube or
Instagram. And if you just approach this
as some, you know, side hobby, a thing
you're just going to dabble in, you'll
probably just get lost in the noise.
That said, if you really go and obsess
around a single format on a single
platform and making it the best in the
world, this is how you set yourself
apart. And you don't need to think about
something insane. You know, just a few
years back after being in nature had
thought of, you know, I'm going to go
and start handwriting different images
around concepts that I think will be
helpful for founders. I just started
obsessing around, you know, drawing out
these different concepts and then
sharing them on platforms like LinkedIn.
Sure enough, almost overnight, these
concepts were shared thousands and
thousands of times. In one month, I grew
by over 110,000 followers on LinkedIn.
And not because I was seeking to do
that, but because I was just obsessed
around making these images that I
thought would be really useful. And so,
what's your obsession? What's that thing
that, you know, many people would think
is weird, but that you're really into?
And how do you go to the nth degree to
become the best at it in the world? This
insatiable drive, this obsession around
your craft is what's going to help you
separate your iconic personal brand from
everything else out there.
>> Rick Rubin teaches us that iconic brands
aren't built by guessing the market.
They're built by creating what you love.
Rick Rubin's produced albums from
everyone from Johnny Cash to Kanye West.
It's all with this one principle. The
audience comes last. How can that be?
>> Now, for a lot of people, that sounds
like creativity suicide. You know,
aren't you building for an audience?
Well, the answer, sure, is they're part
of the equation. But the most important
part of the equation is you. It's your
taste, your intuition, your judgment.
And inevitably when you get too caught
up in what people think, you lose the
true essence of what you're trying to
build. And if you're looking to create
an iconic brand, it's in that essence,
the depth that the beauty and the
originality exist. And so when you're
looking to be creative, you got to block
out the audience and you got to focus on
the craft and the product at hand. You
know, I know when I was first starting
to build, you know, my own brand online,
I was obsessed around building this more
soulful approach to entrepreneurship.
And some people told me, you know, Matt,
this stuff's too woo woo or I don't even
think anyone cares about this. But I
ignored every single one of those people
because I knew that this stuff was true
to me. These are the practices that had
helped me separate myself over the
previous decade. And it was stuff that I
didn't see anyone else talking about
online. You know, you don't need to sell
your soul. You don't need to go and burn
out. you can lean into you, your unique
advantage, and separate yourself from
the pack. When you ignore the audience,
you give yourself an ability to sort
through your own weirdness. And often
times, it's in that search that you find
who you truly are. As we all know, one
of the most important parts of any brand
that we come to know and love that's
iconic is that it's authentic, right?
It's truly you. This is what comes from
the weirdness, from that exploration,
and from actually ignoring the end
audience.
>> Well, the audience doesn't know what
they want. The audience only knows
what's come before.
[Music]
Now, you may know Michael Jordan as the
superstar he became and the founder of
what's now a $6 billion brand empire,
but he was cut from his high school
basketball team. Cut. You can imagine
the heartbreak there when he went and
accepted the Hall of Fame award from the
NBA. You know, he went and gave this
speech.
>> If that means I have to do whatever I
have to do, I'm going to win. No matter
how you look at it,
>> Michael Jordan had an insatiable
competitiveness. He used the fuel of
other competitors going and chirping him
or telling him he couldn't do it. And he
took that personally.
>> That's all I needed. That's all I needed
for him to do that. and it it became
personal with me
>> and he didn't take it personally and
just let it go and demotivate him. He
actually used that as fuel to come back
10 times stronger. Now, when you look at
your own career, when I look at mine,
right, there's been so many times where
I've had to go and apply this delusional
self-belief to get over massive
challenges. When I was 21, my first
business was raided by the government. I
had no idea what I was going to do. I
could be fined up to a million dollars
and put in jail for a year. I had enough
delusional self-belief in myself to go,
you know what? I'm going to go and email
3,000 people over 48 hours. And if I let
enough people know about this situation,
something's got to give. After 3 days,
it was trending on Twitter in Canada.
And one week later, we got the only
exemption of its kind to operate a
business like BitMaker.
26 times I've been trusted to take the
game-winning shot and missed.
I've failed over and over and over again
in my life. And that is why I succeed.
[Music]
Jirro Ono has been making sushi in a
subway station for 70 years. And after
all those years of seeking out the best
ingredients and practicing every day of
the week, he tells people that he still
hasn't perfected rice. Now, people could
think this is crazy, but this is the
delusional belief in mastery that
creates iconic brands. You know, most
people think because they've done
something for 3 or 5 years that they
become great. But real mastery comes
from doing things for 20 years, 40
years. And what I think about with all
of this is this idea of everyday
retirement, of focusing on something
that's really in your calling. Often
times in life, you know, the success
that you're looking for doesn't come
from becoming obsessed around the
metrics. It comes from being obsessed
around the practice. When I went and got
started on YouTube, as an example, I
wasn't focused on views, engagement, or
getting to 100,000 subscribers. I was
focused on mastering the craft of
cinematography, of lighting, of sound,
of becoming confident on camera because
Lord knows in those early days I had no
idea what I was doing. It was from this
dedication to the mastery and the love
of just becoming a little bit better
every single time that's allowed me to
go and stand out on this platform. And
so, you know, that mastery, right, is
what's going to separate you from the
rest. Because when a bunch of amateurs
are just going and bragging about the 6
months they've spent doing something,
you're going to build up decades of
experience and still consider yourself a
student of the game.
>> Technology and humanity. What a computer
is to me is it's the most remarkable
tool.
>> Today, Apple is going to reinvent the
phone.
>> When Steve Jobs was shown different
prototypes of the first iPhone from
Joanie IV, it had three buttons on it.
And Steve said it needed to be a lot
more simple. And so they went back to
the drawing board and came back with a
phone with one button on it. And Steve
said, "Still too many buttons." Sure
enough, they went back to the drawing
board and came back with a buttonless
interface. And these were in the days of
Blackberry and, you know, Razer flip
phones. But Steve was obsessed with
simplicity. This didn't just translate
through their products, right? It was in
their ads as well. simply drawing, you
know, different kind of comparisons
between Apple being this new and cool
company and then Microsoft being this
nerdy old school thing that was stale,
right? Just simple comparisons that
people could remember. You know, Steve
was obsessed around simplicity. And
insanely simple is something that's also
benefited me in my own life. At the end
of the day, I find when I'm going into
any week, there are thousands of things
I could get done across the portfolio of
online companies that I run. But each
day, I reflect on what are the three
things I can get done today. Not 30, not
100, three. And then every single day, I
wake up and go from top to bottom
through those core three tasks. And
simplicity isn't just about what you're
saying yes to. It's being comfortable
saying no to 97% of things so you can
say hell yes to the 3% that are actually
going to move the needle forward for
you. Insanely simple focus is also about
honing in the signal and then cutting
out the noise. Steve Jobs was notorious
for ignoring customer feedback, surveys,
and focus groups. He preferred much more
to lean into his own product intuition,
relying on, you know, that quote from
Henry Ford, which is if you'd asked what
people had wanted, they would have said
a faster horse. You know, sometimes when
you just rely on everyone else's
opinion, you get clouded. But when you
listen to that like inner voice that you
have and trust that signal, you're able
to distill things down to one simple
thing. We have a chance if we stay
focused and choose wisely to really
continue to impact people's lives in
some small way for the better. The real
iconic brands go deep, not just wide.
Icons aren't born, they're built. And
with these seven core principles, you
can build your iconic brand today. Now,
if you like this video, be sure to like
and subscribe and go and check out this
video on how you can go and build a
profitable personal