Two massive [\h__\h] light bulb moments.
Massive just happened while you were
talking. This is the hard work that I've
been avoiding.
I got a message from my buddy Blake
yesterday. 28-year-old entrepreneur from
Newport Beach running a $40 million
empire. But the thing is this, there are
some major choke points in his business
that are holding him back from getting
to the next level and just having time
to enjoy his life. What we're really
trying to build here is trying to live a
really [\h__\h] good life. I couldn't
enjoy Hawaii. The whole time I was
there, I was sitting there. I'm like,
"Motherfucker, this is too much." Do not
say that [\h__\h] anymore. Everyone who's
young sucks at this [\h__\h] Burnout is a
[\h__\h] When you find yourself constantly
running on fumes, something is wrong.
You don't seem patient, right, dude?
Just like slow down a bit, right? Like
slow is smooth, smooth is fast. You need
to like systemize this. Sure. And then
it's like, "Yeah, then go get that
[\h__\h] big 100 mil thing." I think
that's 100% right. I told him to come
sit down here in Williamsburg. We're
going to go chop it up, help him on a
whiteboard, understand his overall
business, his objectives, and then help
him get his business to the next level,
and get his time back so we can just
enjoy the journey. Let's get into it.
Basically getting into Yeah. both
business and we can start with like the
three kind of pieces of the portfolio.
Sure. I think we can start with uh let's
call it just Mr. 4 to8. So like my
personal brand has been attached to uh
air the Airbnb coaching business for a
really long time. At its peak, the
Airbnb business was doing like 1.7
million net per month and then at its
trough about quarter million per month.
Right now, it does about 300,000 a
month. I'm trying to make a decision
between do I try and steady state an
education business of Mr. 4 to8 and try
and steady state some of the content
stuff which would maybe and and have it
maybe even increase to like 400 or
500,000 a month like profit while also
trying to make a decision between is Mr.
48 the big thing still? Can I continue
to go bigger and bigger with content? Is
there a lot more profit to be made
there? And if I were to either introduce
a new offer that is the a new B&B offer
or a new complete separate offer, could
it get to a million a month? Could it
get to 1.5 million a month? And is that
the better decision to put my time
between? Right. So, it's and on the
revenue side, you're looking to get that
to ideally if it's steady state, I'd
like to get it to 500,000 a month. If I
was working on it full-time, I'd like to
get it to a million a month profit.
Right now, I'm feeling out of alignment.
Not necessarily because 100% I just
don't believe that Airbnb arbitrage as a
business model works. When I started, it
was Blake, the guy that's starting with
Airbnb, documenting the journey of how
we got here. Now, I've got one of the
biggest Airbnb portfolios in the United
States as a single owner. at the at the
same time if Airbnb is out and they're
just like people are not really feeling
it then I die with the personal brand
dies with the business model making a
decision on the offer side of things do
you pivot out of Airbnb is the pivot
soft more to a higher ticket high area
of expertise I was curious to understand
kind of a couple things which are like
maybe like the criteria you know my
criteria when I'm going and building
anything I think we may have talked
about this on the call the other day is
like I need to be able to get to $5
million of revenue a year within 2
years. Um I need to be able to work from
anywhere doing it. I need to love the
problem. I need to love the customer.
There needs to be like founder product
fit. Like it needs to be something that
like feels right that I'm doing. Um I
need to be in integrity with it. And it
needs to feel like uh something I I feel
really good about that I'm thrilled to,
you know, sell. I need to be able to see
myself doing it ideally for like the
next decade, not just like the next
year. Um I need to be able to build the
thing in 3 months or less. What are some
criteria that you have? My criteria is
as of now, like I have to feel like I
have an edge. Like the edge is something
that puts a somewhat of a clock on me
where it's like maybe I don't have this
edge longer than everybody else, but for
this moment of time, I can push it
farther or harder than somebody else.
So, one of the most important things of
Blake, right, is this idea of time. But
before we go and figure out, well, what
do we need to be removing Blake from? We
first need to understand what does his
dream week look like? If he was able to
just get rid of all obligations he has
right now, right? And imagine he was
even retired and able to work on
anything he wanted. Pick his ideal
morning, his afternoon, his evening.
What would it look like? You know, what
are the things that he wants added to
his schedule? And what are the things
that are really draining his energy that
we need to remove from this next system
I'm about to show him, he's going to get
that clarity necessary so we can figure
out what we need to be going and
supporting Blake with so he can have
that dream week every week, your dream
week. Like say it's 6 months from now,
right? You have a systems in place, you
have a lean team in place, you have a
new offer. Like, how do you want your
week to look like? I think that the A.M.
for me is the most important time of the
day. And if maybe 5 to 6 days a week, if
I had a four minimum 4hour creative time
block where it was solely dedicated to
creative tasks, you know, writing
content, creating content. That's where
I find my most pleasure. Afternoon would
be a great time to be able to spend a
couple hours eating good food, hiking,
gym. PM I don't have much good work that
happens in the PM. So for me, PM would
be, you know, a couple times a week. I
would say two times a week being able to
play soccer or do uh tennis, sunsets, go
to bed. Yeah. Like uh time like a 2 to
three hour wind down. Cool. What What
are the areas now that are currently
kind of like the blockers? I think that
because I have so many energy draining
tasks that I have to do and and and also
like actually quite a bit of
front-loaded work that has to be done
soon in order to get to that point,
right? So, as of now, there's just like
I'm out of alignment with the content.
I'm out of alignment with the offer. I
have this goal of building this other
new business right now while letting
this other one not die and maybe even
grow at the same time. I'm not a good
manager. I can I can tell you what the
dream and vision is, but I can't get you
bought in long term because what I do is
I'll hire you, tell you something once
and then I just end up thinking, "Oh,
you did it wrong the first time. Let me
just do it myself. You're fired." To add
to this whole like big picture of
criteria and things like that, whether
it's for hiring and for me, is like I do
the best when I'm [\h__\h] curious. I
need I need to be curious and so do the
people that I hire because if they're
not curious and it's just a paycheck
then I'm not maybe it's not I'm not good
enough but I haven't done enough
managing people yet to be able to get
them to be so bought in that they push
the needle. Sounds like the big domino
kind of like the main thing that if you
got that right would make everything
else kind of easier or unnecessary would
be first off I mean figuring out this
offer cuz right now it sounds like
you're kind of in this like a bit of a
standstill or like a holding pattern and
then also like a creative side too.
You're like, I'm doing this thing. What
the [\h__\h] am I doing? What am I creating
for this and what am I leading them to?
Where's this going? And then it's
leading to just like, yeah, where just
big questions, right? Transitions in
life can be terrifying. You're on one
opportunity and you know that there's
something bigger there that you could go
and be ripping and getting on to, but
it's scary, you know, and one of the big
references that I have for this is this
idea of being Tarzan in a jungle. But in
this next clip, you're going to see me
going and helping Blake understand how
he can go and effectively remove himself
from the operations of his current
opportunity over the next few months and
then set himself up to go crush it on
this big hairy audacious goal he has
over the next 10 years of his life. So
there is this overarching the angle and
the concept to me is you I'm riding the
train down. I'm seeing the success rate
of everybody across the space not Airbnb
but arbitrage continue to go down. So, I
don't I don't love that cuz I can sell
[\h__\h] on a wall, but like it's still
[\h__\h] I I don't I don't want my personal
brand to die. I want it to be something
that's on the up and up. And I really
want it to
um on the new side of things for it to
embody the next chapter of my life. You
have um all of these different um
business models, right? So, let's just
say, you know, you have the Airbnb
evolution, you have the a new info
product for these people, you have
purchasing Airbnbs for folks, you have a
more service-based offering, let's say.
All of your criteria here basically like
I put it like in a Google sheet. And
then I would just go and rank each of
these things like on a scale of like 1
to 10 of how does each of those
opportunities you're thinking achieve
the the given criteria? Is it scalable?
Right? You're like, okay, it's a 10
scalable product market fit, right? The
next one is like, okay, info. Is that
scalable? Yeah, that's a 10. Okay,
purchasing. Is that scalable? N maybe
not as much. Let's say it's seven.
Doesn't make a deal breaker yet. And
kind of keep going down the list and
going to the next opportunity. Let's say
it's the uh service-based one. It's
like, okay, how's that on scalable?
Decent. Let's say it's an eight. How's
that on the existing audience? Oh, yeah.
It's solid. Are you in alignment with
it? Yeah, you like it. And so now you're
kind of basically formulating for those
opportunities like almost like an
alignment score. Sure. I think that
what's like killing me, the underlying
like gut punch and the two thoughts that
just continue to run through my mind on
creating a new offer is I feel like in
my head the squared version that we were
talking about the new offer is the
business that I want to build the
publishing one that I like feel like I
it's so private can't talk about it like
that's the big thing. It would never be
front-facing. Some of it is like keeping
just money coming in from the Mr. 48
side. And then the other thing is like,
but is like is there a shitload of money
there that I'm passing up or is the big
money over here? Go get this on a
regular offer, done for you, steady
state, pretty hands-free, content still
good. Yeah. Blake's kind of doing this
thing and behind the scenes it's like,
holy [\h__\h] Like you guys have no clue
what I'm building. Yeah. I see it I see
it as two separate things. So, okay. I
see it as like I have this like
ridiculous analogy of like when we're
kind of like transitioning from like one
opportunity to the other. It's like
[\h__\h] like Tarzan swinging on a in
like the jungle is kind of how it feels
like. And you're like on one vine, you
like capture the other one, you know?
You swing back with both of them, then
you like let this one go and then like
swing on to the new one. And so you're
in this stage right now where you kind
of have latched onto this one a bit, but
you're now swinging back. You need to
like systemize this. Sure. Right. Which
is like what we're talking about right
now. And then it's like, yeah, then go
get that [\h__\h] big 100 mil thing. But
from my understanding of talking with
you, it's like we want to first like
this thing, get it steady state, all
that. And that doesn't mean we're saying
no to this. It's actually I view it as
all it's all one part of the journey.
Like you actually are building that
right now. But building that right now
is like taking the cash flows from this,
setting this thing up. It's pumping you
cash that allows you to even maybe
invest bigger in this. Y, right? Cuz
you're like, "Oh [\h__\h] we're just like
to shut this down. I'm saying no to like
potentially 400k profit a month that I
could be investing a quarter of that,
even 100 grand into this new thing to
then blast it off way faster." So
setting this up is like almost a seed
round. It is for or a series A for that
thing. So not they are two separate
things. You're going to do them both,
but there's a sequence of events that
can happen that gets you the most amount
of leverage to do. That's a really good
way to look at it. I think that's 100%
right. I I think that I think it's
because I can't [\h__\h] do everything
that it's easier for me to hit refresh.
So my team here at Founder is around 20
people strong now. But the truth is it
didn't start like that. You know, it
first started with just me, chief
everything officer, trying to do
everything myself. And when I first
started scaling the business, I started
hiring for where the pain was. So, if
there was pain and I didn't want to send
an invoice, I'd hire a finance manager.
If there was pain and I didn't want to
write the landing page copy for
something, I'd hire a copywriter. And
gradually, I started to form this
organization over the past few years.
And so, where Blake's at right now is
that there's no one on his company
that's able to go and help him get his
time back. And so first things first, we
need to model out what does his org
chart look like. We need to be more
intentional about the hires that we need
to support Blake and then help him get
back his time day by day. What's the
team necessary to like make this vision
happen? I think like for me there's been
this shift over the years of again
viewing myself more like an asset
manager and like a smart investor and
less of an entrepreneur. And so trying
to look at it like, okay, like the
people that I surround myself with and
that I bring on my team are an
investment, right? Right. The systems
that I put in place are like an
investment, right? They get stood up,
they get put in place, and then like
they're good and they just cook and most
of them produce a lot of cash. Cuz
here's what you're dealing with right
now, right? Which is why I think it's
good to bring these people on like ASAP.
Is like, do you think it's the first
time you're going to evolve an offer?
Hell no. No. Do you think it's the first
time you're going to build a webinar for
Shelby or the next? Hell no. Do you
think it's the first time that you're
going to go and like listen to the
community, survey them, look at the data
of the survey, go and understand, oh,
what's the [\h__\h] that would really pump
it up and make these people more sto?
Cool. We're going to prioritize based
on, you know, least effort, most impact,
um, and stuff that we can build in 3
months or less. No, this whole process
you're about to undergo is probably what
almost all the offers that you're ever
going to do because you're going to be
this info guy. You're going to have to
do this [\h__\h] every 4 months. But it'd be
nice if next time it's like snap the
finger, you know, implement offer
evolution. Cool. weapons go, they're
like, "Oh, offer evolution. Follow the
SOP." You know the deal. We go to the
community. We survey them. Then we
understand what their biggest problems
are. We rank them from most pain, most
uh least imp uh most impact for them,
least effort for us, most dollar value.
Then we go, we bring back Blake our
report. Blake goes on a [\h__\h] rant on
FaceTime, tells us what the [\h__\h] is up.
He says like, like, like, dislike. Then
we go, we just motor around. We go
implement that [\h__\h] We go and we
implement that. Blake always expects
that we evolve an offer within 3 months.
Cool. Done. Next. Right. And it's like a
little [\h__\h] attack squad that does
this stuff. I wouldn't necessarily say
this exact thing if I didn't believe the
fact that you will be this like info
product mogul in like over the next 5
years. And so if you've like kind of
picked a space and every single thing
you're about to do is still is like in
that space then start to build and
operationalize like all of these things
that are parts of the space. workshops,
webinars, newsletters, social content,
copywriting, hiring, firing, all this
[\h__\h] is like you're going to just keep
doing this for the next 5 10 years of
your life. So, the sooner that you
aren't the only person in your company
that can do all this [\h__\h] the better.
Two
massive [\h__\h] light bulb moments,
massive just happened while you were
talking. Never [\h__\h] made never made
sense to me. Like, I always looked at
SOPs, people that use notion, I'm like,
"You're such a [\h__\h] idiot. Like,
you're using notion all day. Like,
you're not getting anything done. and
you're just doing nothing or SOPs. Yeah,
I'm going to go record this to go find
some Filipino contractor that has no
[\h__\h] clue what they're actually
doing. Go pay us $700 a month. They have
to go send in this video. But actually,
it takes a little bit of taste to know
that you got to change this, that, and
the other. Like, you know, that was how
I looked at SOPs, hiring, firing,
managing. And and I think that too like
one of the things that becomes like like
a little bit less of a ego blow is like
the amount of times that I've told
people I'm just I'm not good at hiring
firing. I was thinking that do not say
that [\h__\h] anymore. I saw when you were
saying that I was like talk. Yeah.
Exactly. And that's a [\h__\h] identity.
Like everyone who's young sucks at this
[\h__\h] right? Like that's not that young
anymore. I'm like almost [\h__\h] 30. Now
you're young. But like every everyone
sucks at that for a bit. Like this is
totally obviously you only learn that
[\h__\h] from experience. I still learn all
the time. I make a bad hire I'd say
every four or five months probably just
from the sheer amount that like you're
working with people, you're trying
things out, you're growing the business,
the person that was good for one stage
isn't good for the next stage. It's
totally natural, you know, like you're
definitely capable of doing this and
you're probably also going to make a
bunch of mistakes like we all do, but
that's actually like that is the process
of hiring. So operations, you know, big
word, everybody needs help with it.
Almost every founder wants to be removed
from it, but hardly anyone has an idea
of who to actually bring on. You know,
building businesses initially, you hear
about these people going and hiring
someone overseas as an executive
assistant. And trust me, I have tried
that. The truth is though, when you're
scaling an empire beyond $10 million,
you need a lot more help than an
executive assistant. And in this case, I
wanted to give Blake the details on a
couple core hires that I think he needs
to make that are exclusively focused on
buying back at least 20 hours of his
time back every single week so he can
build a business he loves and not just
be running himself into the ground,
right? And so when you look at your
team, I mean just to talk about the
major parts of it like because there's a
couple core aspects that have come up.
Obviously isn't the whole team, but I
think just to talk about kind of two
departments at least for a sec. You have
sort of ops and then you have uh
content, let's say. I would consider
hiring like and bring on even two people
in this area. The reason being is that
at least if one person sucks, you have
one person. So you don't end up like
training up and doing this whole
process. You have one person, then they
leave and you're like, "God damn it, I'm
back to square one again." The two
people I like back a napkin is like high
level. Like it sounds like you may need
like a chief of staff type person. And
then I think you just need like
literally a role just called operations.
It's just like someone that is low ego
that's a [\h__\h] beast and it's just
like dude I [\h__\h] love your [\h__\h] Kind
of like that Russian video editor.
Literally that. You just need that in
operations. the, you know, purchasing
part, the alliances, the service based
stuff, depending on what you end up
choosing. It's not just you that ends up
knowing how to do that. These people
know how to do that. So good as an asset
manager again, right? It's everything's
an investment, right? So let's just say
these two people, they cost 20K a month,
240k a year. But if they go and spin up
this offer and help you with a future
offer, let's just say back and napkin,
if I was putting a number on that, the
right people would probably easily make
me like 2 mil a year. Sure. So your ROI
on that is 10x. So it's like it's a
no-brainer investment. I've always
looked at ops and like the chief of
staff, the operations, like things like
that as stuff that you have to go find
somebody in the in a adjacent offer or
space and go tell them hand it off and
be like go do this thing. So I just
thought it was impossible. One thing I
think that you're you've gotten caught
up in is again it comes back to like the
mindset piece. as like annoying and as
cliche as it is, it's like, yeah, you
know, it's the offer. People say it's
the team and all that, but it's like not
clicking. And I think that's what
happens potentially when you're like,
"Yeah, but I don't know how to hire. I'm
not good at this." Or like, "Yeah, like
you end up just creating these block,
you know, blockages and like a lack of
openness to understanding." And even if
you don't understand, just like asking
questions. How would that work? How
could we do this? Who would you hire?
How would you find those people? this,
you'll be good at it because the best
part of this for guys like us is hiring
is a funnel. Hiring is a funnel. It is.
You get a bunch of [\h__\h] leads. You
put an application out there. You sort
through applications to see which ones
look legit. You have them send you a
5-minute Loom video as part of the
interview. Like before you even talk to
them, you just like watch some Loom
videos of people that you think are
legit. A few people really stand out.
You get on a call with them. You go
through your like interview questions
and all that. You then have them
complete a challenge that's like a
challenge that you would actually like
you should give people a challenge of
like remake this offer. Like do it in a
way that hits these criteria I have and
see what people come to you and you're
like holy [\h__\h] that's good. When you're
thinking about getting your time back,
it can become a little bit foggy, right?
Time can have a way of just being stolen
from us daily. The time audit system
that I've created allows you to go
really understand all of the tasks that
you have going by looking at your notes
as well as your calendar and getting way
more intentional about each and every
task that you could automate, eliminate
or delegate. And so I wanted to go and
share this with Blake because I think
that the devil's in the details and when
we go and look at every single task that
he's doing himself, it starts to become
obvious the kind of things that we need
to remove from his plate and then go and
delegate to people like a chief of staff
and an operations person on his team.
One thing that can be useful for you as
you're just even thinking about this on
just a very simplistic basis is like you
may have heard this before. It's like a
time audit system. This can feel really
annoying but the but if you understand
what you're doing then it's like
insanely rewarding. Okay. So, what I
would do is you're going to have like a
Google sheet and I can give you a
template. And what you're going to do is
you're going to have the first column.
You're going to just put down probably
even on a weekly basis, audit your
calendar and your task list. What is
everything you did that week? Like
different meetings you've had, different
tasks you've given people, different
tasks that you've done, everything.
You're trying to mostly pay attention to
the stuff that you're doing. Right.
Right. So, like you made this workshop
deck for Shelby, you made this email
thing, you then made a piece of content,
then you made a carousel for Instagram,
but then you made a story. Keep listing
all the things you're doing. And that's
the first step is just list like all of
the tasks you're working on and the time
commitment as well. You could do that
too, but mostly the tasks like just keep
it simple just so that you don't like
get lost in like so much stuff to do.
So, you have the task. Um then
you have um your energy level and you
don't need to do this every time but
like audit the task at you know on
Friday I'll look at my calendar look at
my task list of all the things I got
done and I add all the tasks here then
look at the and mark down the energy
level right did it give you energy
was it neutral right drain and did it
drain your energy and you just have a
drop down there and the template I'll
give you has this and you're just
marking that down. Y you don't need to
think too much about this. You just put
the [\h__\h] task down, put the energy
levels down. That's like step one. Then
what you're going to have is in the
sheet, you'll see this. You'll have
these like three roles, rows or sorry,
columns. You have like can you automate
this? Can you eliminate it? Or could you
delegate it? Right? So starting to kind
of then go and look at every single task
you put down and maybe after you've done
this for say a month or two weeks even,
doesn't matter. You're then going to
indicate, okay, could you automate this?
Okay, yeah, I could automate this one.
Can I eliminate this? Elimination is the
best cuz there's probably a bunch of
you're doing that you're like, why am I
even doing this [\h__\h] It's like just
eliminate all that stuff. You're going
to look at automating and then that's
like an interesting list and then your
delegation list. From there, you have
these like ops roles you're looking for,
right? These ones. You're going to have
a bunch of tasks on this list that
you're going to mark like delegate,
delegate, delegate, delegate, delegate.
like I shouldn't be doing this [\h__\h]
right? That's all the stuff that should
become part of the job descriptions for
these roles. Um, and so now you've
marked down like all these things,
anything from big tasks to small
[\h__\h] And then you've put like,
okay, um, this is going to be, you know,
chief of staff is going to do that, ops
is going to do this, ops is going to do
this, chief of staff is going to do this
role or this task. You're slowly from
auditing all of your time. What are you
spending it all on? You're seeing all
the [\h__\h] that's draining your energy.
You're seeing the stuff that you're
like, "Okay, I should definitely be
delegating this." And just delegating
all the [\h__\h] that's either like neutral
drains your energy and the stuff that
you need to delegate.
And from that exercise, it doesn't
become this like, well, I'm bringing a
chief of staff and they're going to
manage my calendar and they're going to
manage projects and make SOPs. No, no,
no. Just get them working on the [\h__\h]
that you hate that you need to delegate.
What's starting to become abundantly
clear is this is the hard work that I've
been avoiding. In my head, it's like the
hard work. I just kept like telling
myself every other excuse about hiring
um systems that everybody bloat, nobody
does it lean still, nobody's as good at
copyrighting, how could somebody like
jump in and do operations if they've
never done what I've done in this
industry? Like, it's [\h__\h] stupid.
Mhm. Now that I see it written out, it's
like it's it's good, but it is kind of a
wakeup call that like, [\h__\h] how long
have I been kicking this can down the
road? The feeling of knowing that like
when you do go and take those 3 days off
or you take that week trip with your
girlfriend and then thinking that you
got to come back and there's just a
mountain there waiting for you, it's
like it's dreadful. You can barely even
enjoy the vacation. I couldn't enjoy
Hawaii. The whole time I was there, I
was sitting there. I'm like,
[\h__\h] Like this is too much. I
should be in I should be able to enjoy
this. Burnout is a [\h__\h] the amount of
times that I've just been going with
blinders on and then sure enough hit a
wall. You know, I could know there's
hundreds of times this has happened
quite honestly. Well, it's fine if it
happens, you know, here and there maybe
from time to time. You know, that can be
normal, right? We all just need a break.
But when you find yourself constantly
running on fumes, you know, and you get
that 4-day break and you feel like you
still need more because you keep coming
back to a company that is pure chaos,
something is wrong. You know, I think
all founders at the end of the day want
to run a calm company. You want to run a
business where you can take one month
away from the business and come back to
a team, to a company that is stronger
than when you left. But the truth is
when most founders look at their
businesses, you know, they have a
business that is running them into the
ground. And it's not sustainable because
the most important thing to me, it's
longevity. Now, I'm not looking to just
win over the next 1 2 3 5 years. I want
to win over the next 20 years, 30 years,
and just keep doing things I love for
the long term. I wanted to chop it up
with Blake on this idea of
sustainability and how to stay in the
game, manage his energy, and make sure
he's feeling good for the next decade
because he's got a big vision and I want
to help him get there. I would say
current offer, right, which is let's
call it B&B plus. This is my software
and arbitrage. I have the new potential
offer, which would be the DFY service.
Let's call this 3K and let's call this
35K. But now from a tactical standpoint
as I'm getting all these things in place
and I want to have a better offer here
and maybe increase the price there and
get build this offer, do all this new
stuff and just keep just pushing the
same [\h__\h] and just evolving it as it
pushes. Yeah. I think that with all of
this like it's not going to happen
overnight, right? And so I think it's
like day by day chipping away at this
stuff. Like you have the key thing is to
not try to do too much new stuff in
terms of like new offer this and new
that. Like reduce the surface area of
stuff you got to do to the minimum
amount possible. I I feel like once once
every four months I crack this and I'm
like end up having the best [\h__\h] week
of my life. But I look at all this stuff
I hate to keep take taking your mind.
Okay. I don't need I look at all this
[\h__\h] and then you add in let's call this
girlfriend and then you add in travel
and then you add in lifestyle then you
add in health then you add in new
business ideas and all that [\h__\h] The
problem is like how I look at time is
it's what it feels like to me. It's like
you know we were talking earlier about
all the other things that go into just
like it's not just about courses or any
of this stuff. It's like what we're
really trying to build here is you and I
on on some level trying to live a really
[\h__\h] good life. Build cool [\h__\h] have
fun doing it, do it with cool people,
get to go travel and explore [\h__\h] that
when I look at some of, you know,
startups and types of businesses where
I'm like, "Yeah, okay. Billion dollars
and what? And what? You haven't [\h__\h]
done anything. You're out of shape. Two
divorces. Kids don't [\h__\h] know you.
Big house." And I've been in big houses.
I don't like when I don't know which
when there's too many bedrooms, you
know? So, it's like this time concept of
I think when I get the new biz idea that
there's no time like no none because
it's like this idea is going to flee.
And with B&B Plus, well, there's no time
because I don't have time to create
content cuz there's no time over here.
And it's just this big stress circle
where it almost seems like you're saying
remove like addition by subtraction, but
like on a granular [\h__\h] level. Mhm.
You don't seem patient. No. Right. And
I'm not patient either, but like you can
tell that some of your it's kind of like
really eating at you in your ability to
like do this, right? Because you're like
this now and new thing now and how do I
get this now? [\h__\h] Now I'm like bring
on these people, but what about this new
thing? And when I don't do that new
thing, it's it's going to it's going to
phase away. Um I think like patience
like that's something I've had to learn
like just just literally from just
[\h__\h] like hammering myself like dude
just like slow down a bit, right? Like
slow is smooth, smooth is fast. Number
one. Two is like the opposite of what
you think could be equally as true if
not more true. So say one more time. The
opposite of what you think could be
equally as true if not more true than
what you think. So like as an example,
you think, oh this opportunity is going
to phase out and this that maybe it's a
timeless opportunity. What if AI was so
good in 6 months? Yeah. That it actually
lays it up for you. Like Google was the
17th search engine. It didn't have to be
the first, right? It was like the 17th.
So like it's not necessarily true how
you're viewing as an example that one
new thing maybe that's not and that's
something that's been eating me. Yeah.
And also you've also said in a good way
like I'm kind of have this out in the
ether and like I'll know it when I see
it and right now you haven't seen that
yet. So like just waiting and sitting on
your hands again like a good investor,
right? Like Warren Buffet pays like 98%
of the time he's sitting on his hands,
right? Like being okay with that. like
sit on your hands, reinforce the cash
cow, make the cash cow badass, remove
yourself in the cash cow until something
like calls you like crazy and you're
like, "All right, now I'm ready and I
got the squad to allow that to happen,
which is like real shit." And the other
thing that I think that you're you don't
have people on your team, it sounds like
like purely like these people that their
core metric is your time. Like my
sister's metric is literally allow me to
have 20 hours of creative work per week.
like that thing that you said your whole
morning that you're like I want four
hours every morning. That's her [\h__\h]
job. That's not your [\h__\h] job, right?
Like do not let that get interrupted. So
like no meetings before that. Also like
if people are coming in for [\h__\h]
[\h__\h] figure it out, right? So that
happens every day. I always get that
time. There's never any screwing with
that, right? You don't have people right
now that I think understand even on like
an energy level with you. Yo, I [\h__\h]
need this. Like this business needs
this. My life needs this. You are coming
on board to make this happen, too. I
it's just interesting that you voiced
like that being the priority thing as
like the preface to these hires of like
your [\h__\h] job like I'm going to give
you these tasks to do with the
overarching goal of it's my time that
I'm trying to get back so that
everything moves better. Yeah. Amazing,
dude. Cool. Yeah. In terms of next
steps, I think step number one, time
audit system. You got a big flight like
4 hours. So looking at your calendar,
opening up your notebook, putting all
the tasks down, and then going through
your energy audit, what stuff gives you
energy, what's neutral, what drains your
energy, and then after that, wanting to
mark down what stuff you can automate,
eliminate, delegate, and then I would
start to create V1 of the chief of staff
role as well as the ops role. Um, just
use whatever tool is easiest for you.
All the tools are notes, [\h__\h] Yeah.
Notes, whatever you like. And then
you're going to have those two JDs.
Pretty good. I would then put those, if
you want, into Claude if you like
Claude. and say, "Hey, turn this into a
job description and here's my
business. This is the value prop
formal JD." So now you have a Google doc
for chief of staff, a Google doc for
ops, put that on view everyone access,
send that to me, send it to 40 other
people on, you know, your a player list,
share with your audience of it. Um, and
that's that basically. And then now the
key thing I would just focus is like
step one, this whole time audit system.
Step two, the hiring of these people is
like a big step. And then step three um
is basically then getting into the mix
with them. Ideally, like they end up
working 40, 50 hours a week um and
giving you the ability to then buy back
like 60 70 hours of your week, get some
mental clarity, be able to work on
bigger opportunities, and be able to
just like have some fun and live the
lifestyle you're after. That's a dream.
Time back. All right. Thank you,
brother. Let's get it. Yeah. So, just
wrapping up that session with Blake. You
know, it feels really good to be able to
help founders that are, you know, eight
years earlier in their journey than I am
and be able to share some of the core
learnings that I wish I had when I was
Blake's age. I really feel like when I'm
helping Blake, when I'm helping other
founders, you know, I'm really in my
calling in life, helping them with the
sort of systems that are going to help
unlock their time, help them seize their
potential. I mean, it was cool. You
know, I think Blake is someone that I've
met actually through building an
audience online. And it's cool to cross
paths here in Brooklyn, be able to hang
out, uh, become, you know, deeper
friends. It feels good to know that I've
given Blake someone that, you know, even
after this session, he needs a bit of
help, he can call me. Something comes up
as he's implementing the time a system,
he can just text me. There's something
just really beautiful about being able
to have fellow founders backs as they go
and try to accomplish their big vision.
So, super rewarding. I know Blake got a
10 out of it and excited for the next