Well, first off, this is amazing cuz
what you just gave me, which is a huge
gift. So, thank you. I am really excited
about this. What if I told you that the
biggest bottleneck in your business
isn't your strategy, it's your
subconscious? Today, I'm going to go and
meet up with my mentor and friend
Russell Brunson, and we're going to dive
into how your subconscious can either be
the biggest contributing factor to your
success or it can actually sabotage
their success. These are all the
subconscious feelings, right? If I want
to be a millionaire or a billionaire,
whatever the the next level is for you,
it's like, does a billionaire believe
differently than I believe? We're trying
just a lot of like trial and error
around that, seeing like what sticks.
You got me so excited. We're going to
show how your subconscious can influence
things like your marketing, your
content, your sales, and when you get it
dialed in, it's going to help propel you
to your goals and help you avoid massive
failures that are in front of your face
every single day. I never thought about
the subconscious belief and building it
that direction is fascinating. We're
going to share a lot of different
tactics and systems that I haven't
shared anywhere else. And I also learn a
ton of things that help me go and avoid
sabotaging my own success. So, I can't
wait for you to see this. Let's get into
it. I feel like uncovered something I
think we're both into, but I'm sure in
very very different ways, which is the
power of the subconscious mind and its
influence on different aspects of
business and your personal life on that
talk about bew
um the subconscious side of things,
let's say, mindset side and curious to
dive into some of your kind of like
practices, tactics. what you've seen
really work cuz obviously we got the
sales side which I know is something
that you're super passionate about and
then the content side of things which is
something that we're both really
passionate about from reading over the
years from mentors podcast and just
talking with fellow entrepreneurs I've
come to the realization honestly that
what's going on in your subconscious is
way more important than what even is
consciously happening the idea of not
just programming your subconscious by
thinking or writing certain things but
actually feeling them being the most
important aspect is something that me
and Russell jam on here. Most people
that I know that talk about
subconscious, they start with like the
mindset side. That's what they're
focusing on. And for me, it started the
other way. It started with sales. And
it's actually fascinating if you look at
the history of it, again, I'm a I'm a
book nerd. But if you look back, the
first person that unders like discovered
and started talking about like
unconscious, subconscious, was Freud.
And he was doing it from this whole like
therapy angle. But Freud had a nephew
named Edward Bernay. He was listening to
Freud talk about stuff. This is amazing.
So Bernay came here to America. He
started taking these these concepts that
Freud was trying to do for mindset and
for psychology and for you know therapy
stuff like that. He's like I think I can
use this to like to make money and to
and to change people's thoughts and
perceptions. So he wrote a book called
Propaganda which is an insanely good
book taking Freud stuff but using it for
mass persuasion. How do we persuade
people? How do we move people? The very
first like big project he got was for
the government. And at the time whatever
war it was World War I or something most
people did not want to go to war. They
were fighting against it. So the
government brought him in and said like
use stuff you figured out to get the
whole country on board with going to
war. And so he built these big huge
propaganda campaigns and he went out
there and he persuaded and literally
shifted the entire country to where
everyone was behind the war excited for
the war. And that's kind of the
beginning of him testing out Freud stuff
in mass persuasion psychology and he
kept going going and again that time he
writes this book called propaganda
showing how he's doing it. But then
propaganda becomes this very negative
term and so he goes back he's like we
need to change this. So he renamed
propaganda public relations which became
PR and he was the he was the one who
founded PR. And so I came into the sales
world learning about the subcon like
through that lens of like the same way
that I get somebody if I'm in an
audience and there's you know 5,000
people in the room and I'm trying to get
them to run to the back and buy my thing
like understanding the psychology of
that the same psychology I need to
actually change myself. And so then it's
like turning it inwards. And then for
the last two and a half years of my
life, that's my obsession is like
changing myself, my own mindset through
this same persuasion techniques,
subconscious understanding. So that's
kind of how I connect those things
together. Often times we think we're
being conscious with decisions that
we're making, but the truth is there's
other stories going on in the
background. I've gone and, you know,
become consistent about every single
night listening to a certain meditation.
I love this one from Bob Proctor and
this one from Wayne Dyer. And I also go
and read a one-pager that kind of
creates my dream scene of where I'm
looking to be over the next year. And
when I'm reading that, I'm really
fueling into those emotions. And that
surprisingly sounds like he has a
similar strategy. I think one thing
that'll help this makes sense for people
too is like understand the difference
between conscious and subconscious,
right? The conscious mind speaks in
questions. So a lot of times we're
asking questions over and over and over
again. Whereas the subconscious deals
with stories which is why when you're
doing yourself a night like you're not
like asking yourself questions like
you're painting a vision you're you're
you're painting a picture you're telling
a story for your subconscious mind to
see and to understand right and that's
the thing that a lot of people miss. I'm
consciously deciding like what is the
thing I want to change in my life or or
consciously seeing the thing that is
broken right and then what we try to do
is we try to consciously try to solve
the problem but like you know that
doesn't actually work. I a lot of
entrepreneurs come to my world. They see
like we have an award called the two
comic club awards. They see I want I'm
going to make a two comic. It's like
conscious like I decide I want to win a
two comic club award and they start
going towards it. And it's crazy. Some
people like it's very simple. They just
go and they get it right. And other
people it's like they just can't thing
after thing and they no matter what they
do they can't figure out how to get it.
And it's not a conscious thing. We give
the same training the same frameworks
the same systems everybody but some have
success and some some don't. And the
reason is because of the subconscious
like the story that's told inside their
mind. Right? somebody who grew up in a
family where the family like thought
money was easy to to to get and they
just have this subconscious belief like
the story they told is like oh it's easy
to get money that there's money in
abundance whereas somebody who grew up
in a family maybe where people were like
money is really hard it's very difficult
and they they just have this belief like
this is this belief they have when I
understand that it's like now I have to
I have to figure out how to change that
that subconscious belief and there's a
lot of ways that like what you're
talking about you're deny like you're
telling yourself these stories putting
that pattern into your mind versus the
other one. Yeah. I know you see it all
the time like whether it's like someone
they know they need to make content.
They need to be putting their brand out
there but they're worried what their
team's going to think or what are my
investors going to think and sure enough
they have these stories in their head
that are tripping them up and preventing
them from doing the thing that they
really know I think in their heart of
hearts and like it's part of their
calling in life to get that thing done
but there's just these like stories that
are sort of tripping them up. So the
most beautiful thing about your
subconscious mind is that you can
actually go and influence it. I have a
bunch of strategies that I've used,
things like my board meeting strategy
and Russell's got a bunch of strategies
that he's also used to evolve into a
founder of a multi-billion dollar
company now. So, we chop it up on those
inside systems that we've used. I was
pretty surprised actually to learn a few
of his cuz they're new practices I'm
going to now integrate into my daily
routine. Often times it's that drama
side of things, not the math side of
things that's really tripping people up.
What's like the core thing that you
sometimes find is like this is like a
way to help others or what's something
that's worked in your own life to get
people over that? Let me explain on
sales side cuz it makes it for me it's
easier to explain. It sounds like that's
like where it's all started. Like it was
all it was all there and then it
filtered down to one rip. I'm the worst
ever one-on-one sales person. Like I'm
not good at that. It stresses me out.
But I'm really good at one to many
sales. So the problem with one to many
sales is there's a whole audience of
people and I don't know what their
individual concerns are. You're kind of
just like shotgunning out a whole bunch
of things and hoping for the best,
right? And so when I'm doing a
presentation that I know the goal is to
get somebody to go buy something at the
end of it for them to go buy something I
need them to believe this going to work
for them, right? And then I reverse
engineer like why would they not believe
that? Like what are the stories they
already have in their mind? And so it's
like well one of the case studies I
always share cuz it's like kind of a a
goofy one but easy is like let's say
let's say you're selling someone a
network marketing opportunity, right? As
soon as I said that like I'm sure
everyone listening like you had an
instant like visceral reaction. You're
like I love network marketing. You're
like this is the most evil thing in the
world. or put an idea into your head and
you you instantly subconsciously had a
feeling but they have they have this
story that like if I join network
marketing opportunity I'm going to lose
my friends and my family that's the
subconscious story they have so I got to
think back why do they believe that like
something happened in their life that
caused them to do and again I don't I
don't know each person individually but
as a whole like what probably happened
so usually what happened is that either
they joined a network marketing
opportunity they called their friends
and their family and they got you know
yelled at and they got hung up or they
had somebody that they knew join and the
person kept bugging them so in their
heads no matter how good I am at selling
or persuasion they are never going to
run the back of the room if that's the
belief they have. Even though I'm giving
a a presentation where consciously
speaking, I know that they have a
subconscious belief that will keep them
from ever buying my product. So, I got
to figure out, okay, this is the story
they have, what story do I have that
would trump their story? Cuz if I can
replace their story with my story, then
they will move. If my story will trump
their story, that story will fall away
and then the new story will take over.
And now when I pitch and like this is
like they'll run to the back of the room
if they believe my story. And so that's
that's how we do in sales. And so
mindset's the same thing. I come back
and I'm like, what's the story I
actually have right now? Like I have to
tell myself a better story to rewrite
the false belief. Otherwise, it's not
going anywhere. So your subconscious
doesn't just influence your mindset, but
it can also go and help you with
content. I go over some of my most
favorite tactics here for really helping
you understand what's going on in the
mind of your core consumer. that you can
go and leverage the stories that they're
telling, the dreams they have, and their
biggest fears to then influence the
exact content that you can create that's
going to help them convert. Now, I found
this actually with on the content side.
I see a lot of founders when they're
coming up with like a content strategy,
pull it out of thin air, you know, and
they're like, I don't know where to get
content from. Where do I come up with
these ideas? And one of the core tactics
that I find is most useful to actually
just create content that people either
consciously or subconsciously want is to
just go and create a type form survey as
an example and go and just survey your
existing amazing customers and ask them
a few questions. Know number one, you
know, what's keeping you up at night
right now? Oo, that's a good one. Number
two, if you were to wave a magic wand,
what would you want my help with over
the next year? And number three, what is
your biggest dream right now? And then
taking all of those answers when you've
gone and maybe surveyed say 20 people
and then using that as the backbone to
your content strategy. So, you're
starting to kind of now craft content
that solves those insane problems that
they're keeping them up at night that
they maybe don't even consciously know
that they totally want these things
solved, that you could even solve this,
but can kind of then spin that into a
content strategy that not just attracts
these people, but like really converts
them to your thing because you're
inherently solving those really burning
problems or helping them really see that
dream in a way that if you're doing it
right, they feel like you're almost
reading their mind. Yeah. When I first
started really executing on this, the
coolest thing that happened with the
sales stuff is they're more willing to
buy, but the second off sometimes you
can consciously convince somebody to go
buy something from you, but then them
actually implementing it falls apart.
Those are the ones who refund or they
give up and they don't have success.
Whereas if you do it correct on the
sales side where you re you break those
false beliefs during the sales cycle,
their ability to actually have success
afterwards exponentially goes up because
those false beliefs are no longer
holding them back. And so it's almost
like the better you get at this and the
same thing on the content side. If you
break someone's false beliefs during the
content when they do enter your world
and decide to invest with you or get
coaching or whatever the next step is
inside your funnel, you've already done
the work of rewriting their false
beliefs up front, they're way more
likely to comply and actually get the
things done that you you need to. But
interesting too, there's like that quote
that like people don't buy what you
sell, they buy what others want to buy.
And so it doesn't always need to be be
just you breaking those false beliefs.
If you can find obviously other amazing
success stories from similar people,
whether it's a agency owner just getting
started or that person running their
first SAS business and showing their
success stories. Yeah. They're not just
hearing it from you. They're seeing like
themselves in that other person who also
had those negative beliefs and those
things that were holding them up and go,
shoot, I'm just like that. And look at
the success they've been able to have
from leaning into it. Okay, now I'm
going to subscribe to this train. So
just like every company has its own
intellectual property when it comes to
your customer list or maybe even your
tech, I believe that you also have
content intellectual property. These are
the common phrases that you use that
become almost the monikers of your
brand, the things that people come to
know and love you for. Now I went and
discovered a kind of new strategy that I
formulated with partly my own
subconscious and leveraging chat GBT
which I share with Russell in this next
bit and I'm pretty sure it blew his
mind. I want to run something by you.
Something I've been playing with on this
sort of level recently was inspired by
Mel Robbins. I just kept on thinking Mel
Robbins is such a genius marketer. Like
these like different terms that she's
invented like that or the 5-second rule.
My wife's a huge Mel Robbins fan, so I
hear about it every day. Crushing like
number one on Amazon, number one on
Apple. I'm like, what is going on here?
Basically went and thought like, what is
she doing here? What is happening? And
it hit me that maybe something that's
kind of happening is that she's taking
like all these like psychological
barriers that often times like her
audience has. When I did this with my
own audience, right, I was like, "Go and
chat GBT. Come up with the top 20
limiting beliefs or psychological
barriers rank from top to bottom that
someone in my audience is probably
facing overwhelm. Maybe there's like
imposttor syndrome, fear of others,
let's say, and like a bunch of others."
And I had this thought of like it feels
to some extent that what she's doing is
taking that feeling when it comes up in
someone and then like inserting like a
catchy phrase that's like a trigger
reminder of like oh what someone should
do when they feel that way. So as an
example right for one book you know
she's got one concept let's say let them
right the whole idea that maybe you're
worried about what someone else's thinks
instead of letting your brain go into
that direction say let them think
whatever they think and let me go and
control what I can control. move on. But
that feeling, that trigger that comes up
like 30 times a day, like in different
ways. Oh, I'm going to talk to Russell
today. I hope I'm on my, you know, on my
best today. And it's like, no, at a
certain point, stop praying about this.
Like, let Russell think what he's going
to think and I'm going to do what I do
and let's see where this goes. similar
to her book 5-second rule when you're
procrastinating or when you're putting
off that thing that you should be doing
like using that rule constantly in your
life where again it probably comes up 20
plus times a day and thereby in some
senses like Mel Robbins concepts are
like coming up in your brain like 20 30
times a day and so I started thinking
okay what would it look like to with
each of these like core blockers that my
audience has either consciously or
subconsciously what are like different
phrases that I have or could invent that
help people overcome that. Yeah. So say
for a fear of others and what they're
going to think maybe like the phrase is
like do it uh messy. This whole idea of
like do it messy like launch this like
thing that's kind of Launch a
draft like it's okay like if it's a bit
messy just go for it. coming up with
this basically like a phrase cloud that
all of these phrases then deal with all
of these like subconscious or conscious
like blockers that people get into and
then you have all these phrases you can
test them in like short form content in
tweets in YouTube videos see what
catches fire and then kind of like
double down on that as almost like your
content intellectual property and it was
crazy cuz when I was reading her book it
was interesting the first 15 pages she's
coming up with like so where did I even
come up with this concept I actually put
a short form video out really and I had
shared this cuz my daughter had said it
in the backyard and sure enough this
video caught storm got like 20 million
views in 24 hours and she made a podcast
around it and it was like the number one
Apple podcast around that and she's like
okay now I'm going to write a book
around this. So I'm curious on your side
like yeah what you do around this or how
you're thinking around it any strategies
you you've been a genius with this in
your own way like the concept of like
inventing a funnel as like people were
kind of thinking like I want to you know
drive people from traffic to like a a
website thing to like a product it's
like that's a funnel like how do you
think about that a bit? Well, first off,
this is amazing cuz this left hand
column, these are all the subconscious
feelings, right? When you have a
conscious decision and these are the
things you're feeling, that's what you
got to be aware of. And so, it's like,
why do I have the fear of others? Why do
I have the imposter syndrome? Why do I
have those? Well, you just gave me,
which is a huge gift. So, thank you.
It's just like I never thought about
that lens of what Mel's doing or how to
do in content, but this is what hit me.
I don't know if she's doing this, but it
it felt it felt it feels like I think
you're dead on. She may not even
consciously know that's what she's
doing, but that is I'm really excited
about this. What this is doing is what
we said earlier. This is trumping the
story, right? It's like you do it messy,
you're going to tell a story about that
and next time someone has it, they're
going to default to like fear of others
and that's the story and then it's like
oh wait I can replace it with this story
do it messy and then that gives
encouragement and power cuz you a story
and it's like interesting cuz in the
previous thing we were kind of talking
about like how to then come up with a
content strategy around this. It's like
well you have like maybe a chart of like
20 of these fears or limiting beliefs or
subconscious like barriers people have
like that one thought which in her case
was let them but in this case maybe it's
like again do it messy and it's like how
do you then start to create like a bit
of a content waterfall off of that
basically put it in front of like a
focus group online and like kind of go
and go okay I'm going to make like a a
YouTube video off of this and then I'm
going to go and I'm going to create six
like IG you know reels off six Tik Toks
off that. I'm going to create like a an
email newsletter to just put it in front
of enough people and see if like when
you're in conversations with folks like
are people kind of like oh man like I
was like having this trouble man I was
so worried about what my family was
thinking I was so scared and like
honestly I just came to grips I just got
to do it messy like I love that change
and you're like you're getting DMs
around it now or people are actually
using that language and you're like okay
this is like a sticky idea is
brilliant like I I always create content
based on the hook or the head or
whatever the external thing I never
thought about starting it with the the
subconscious belief and building it that
direction is fascinating. Again, when
I'm speaking from stage, we're
consciously talking to I'm
subconsciously telling stories, right?
First phase I'm doing when I'm creating
a presentation is thinking to what are
the false beliefs somebody has. When I'm
creating content, I'm not doing that.
I'm not starting with like what is it
subconsciously that's holding him back?
Like when you're doing these big events,
this one selling. The thing I didn't
realize for so long is that there's
actually two events going on. There's
like the event that others are seeing,
but then there's also this event that
you're doing underneath all that, which
is like understanding their beliefs, the
beliefs that they need to overcome,
inserting those stories where they just
think it's this awesome thing that you
just kind of put together and it's like
amazing. Like this is quite the show,
but underneath that there's a lot of
belief breaking, belief inserting new
stories. And I think that that's like
the opportunity for both of us. My first
mentor Dan Kennedy, he had an event
called the influential writing workshop
and it was all about writing good sales
copy. What we made all of us do is we
had to go and list out all the false
beliefs that our potential customer has
and then from there we had to write a
story for every single one. And he's
like you need to build like a repository
of stories. He's like most people they
they show up hoping that the story will
appear right. So we made it sit down
there for like hours writing down every
false belief and then figuring out like
a story from our past that would for
every single one that we could tell and
it was like kind of a long brutal
process but I look at the last decade of
my life literally 90% of stories I tell
came from that exercise right I always
look at it from like writing copy doing
a presentation and I've always looked at
content separately which I don't think
is correct so struggle with content
stuff and I think that's probably one of
the core reasons is I just haven't even
thought about the same way I thought
about everything else I definitely
noticed that about you just talking in
person you're like a story bank like
it's impressive. I know I'm learning too
from you like that makes sense. I feel
like that exercise was quite
transformative. It was like it had a ton
of dividends cuz it seems like it's like
created this Yeah. like a repository in
your brain like okay this new person
that did a e-commerce business this
person that had that belief that was
screwed up. This person that thought
that network marketing was ugly or
whatever the heck. And after you do that
the first time then every time you see a
story you're like oh I can use that and
all suen you become more aware of it. So
first it was very much like a written
out thing and over time it becomes more
where you know a lot of more is in your
head but it's just but it opens up your
eyes to all the different ways you
story. So most people you know all of us
we'll go and buy something and I don't
know about you but when I purchase
something I'll go back and go what
exactly happened there that caused me to
convert over the years from having been
on enough sales calls delivered enough
myself trained enough sales teams across
my portfolio of online companies. I
think it's important that you really
prepare for the subconscious script
going on in any sales call. So, we're
going to go and break down how you can
go and plan the different beliefs, the
objections, and the specific stories
that you want to make sure that you're
planting into the subconscious of any
prospect so they're convinced of your
solution, your product, and ready to
buy. When you do your content stuff,
where do you lead initially? Where do
you start? Do you start at the
subconscious belief level or these days?
I am leading into this like um like
subconscious like belief side of it with
like those phrases that I just showed
you. So yeah, me and the team like we
went and took like all the 20 most
popular kind of limiting beliefs people
have and then went and drew up either
new phrases kind of again content IP
that's like unique. It's only owned by
me like people haven't heard anywhere
else so that it's got like a stickiness
factor that can then be associated with
our brand. Yeah, we're trying just a lot
of like trial and error around that
seeing like what sticks. That's like I
think a more like advanced level. I
don't think you need to do that out the
gate. I do think that the thing that
everyone should be doing out the gate is
like the survey of three questions. We
live in a cool day and age where you can
use again type form or whatever you want
to use for that. Google forms doesn't
matter. And then even upload the whole
CSV to chat GBT this analyze this and
just come up with like what are like the
top 20 how-to videos I could create that
would help my the people in my audience.
What are the top 10 lists these people
would enjoy and think about like the
format that you most enjoy for whatever
piece of content or platform you're
making it for and see what ideas you can
get from that. So we took all like 1500
podcast episodes I've done uploaded my
books found all my presentations I've
ever given. And so we took basically
everything I've ever said publicly,
threw it into Jad GBT and manus a couple
different things and then it's been so
cool to be able to like ask it questions
and pull out analyzing patterns like
what are the it's helped me just in the
last couple weeks speed up like pulling
out ideas for all these different type
of things. I'm excited to run through
the lens of the like what are the
phrases or even like based on stories
I'm telling what are the false beliefs
I'm trying to break you know and like
start reverse engineering what we've
been doing over the last two decades and
start figuring those things out. I
always think about this like conscious
mind has got to be a guard for our
subconscious because if we're not
careful like you are allowing these
beliefs to like bypass your conscious
directly into your subconscious and you
can see the results happening on the
back side of it right like we have to
consciously be a protector of like what
we allow in number one but number two
it's like auto suggestions all like
figure out the things we do want like
what are the things we need to believe
the things we got to tell ourselves to
like get our subconscious mind to point
us in the the correct direction right if
I know this is a destination I'm someone
who models right so if I know like
here's people I know who gotten here
what do they believe. Like I got to
figure out what they believe. If I want
to be a millionaire or a billionaire,
whatever the the next level is for you,
it's like what does a millionaire
believe differently than I? What does a
billionaire believe differently than I
believe? What does a founder? What is
whatever the the goal you want, right?
And so we model that and then reverse
engineer. Here's the things they believe
that I struggle with. All right, let's
let's create suggestions to get us to
have the same beliefs that we need to
have to get there. Right. And at your
current level, like is there any content
stuff that you're currently like
noodling on on your own side that you
want to chop it up on? We've been
playing a lot with that recently trying
to figure out like my unique voice. Um I
feel like we've been struggling a little
bit. There's platforms we have like for
me it's like live events or podcasts
where it's like I can speak and connect
to people in a certain way but now and
when the internet got started or social
media got started it was all based on
like we get subscribers we give a
message our subscribers here now but for
most social platforms now it's no longer
subscriber based it's algorithm based
right so it's like a lot of times we're
I'm having to create content in a way
that's not the way I would normally do
it to be able to feed the algorithm and
I struggle with that a debate as old as
our time art versus algorithm so often I
talk to founders and they get so caught
up in the views, the comments, the
likes. And while this stuff is important
as it can give you a general sense of
how a piece of content is performing, it
also can lead you astray. So I guess for
me the question is just understanding
like how do you make it match to make it
work. You know what I mean? Yeah. I
think it's like this like battle that
like every like founder and creator is
going through. It's you know art versus
you know like algorithm. Yeah. when you
weight yourself maybe as like a founder
where inevitably like there's got to be
some like profit on the other side of
this or else you can't afford to have
the whole team around you have to
consider the algorithm but you don't
want to ignore the art when I ask like
60% of people that come and work at
Founder O like what was it that caused
you to want to do this together a lot of
it comes down to like some kind of
comment around like your vibe or energy
and if I just simply go and maybe
optimize for the algorithm I'm like
scripting out word by word I'm like
crafting it exactly the way that I know
that when this video went viral they
said this and I have this thing there
and while you're architecting it like
immaculately maybe for the algorithm,
you're missing like the vibe, the energy
and then suddenly now it's like oh this
is just some scripted BS. Yeah. And I
think we live in a day and age,
especially right now on a lot of these
platforms. We swung so far
algorithmically, I think, is just like a
online creator community more than ever
like just off the cuff behind the
scenes. The authenticity like really is
it drives me crazy as a consumer cuz I
go see like 30 videos of the same
thumbnail, same type, you know, it's
their version, but it's like everyone
doing the same thing, like copying each
other versus again like you said, the
art of here's what I want to teach, what
I want to share. Yeah. So the things
that I think like that are worth like
looking at in terms of the algorithm are
like let's just use the example of a
short form video. It's like you know
like the general like word count you can
go for. So obviously you're not going to
just like go on like maybe a 20-minute
ramble for like a minute video. You know
that you got about 130 words that you
can do. And so like learning to like
package up your ideas into that amount.
I think like the most important thing
obviously is like the hook. On that side
what I've seen successful is like
knowing the hook that you're going to
start with. Like lock yourself in a room
and read these 10 books. they'll change
your life. But then from there, just get
into the 10 books that really changed
your life. It doesn't need to be
scripted from there. What I also found
useful, this is kind of I guess kind of
more of a Steve Jobs thing, right? Is
like the rule of three. Like because you
don't have that much time often times to
get into a given idea, potentially
packaging up your idea when you're
talking about off the cuff into like the
three core things someone needs to know.
Where like art and algorithm I think mix
is like finding like your your brand.
people are going to be able to stop the
scroll more if like you're instantly
recognizable. And where I think a lot of
founders get tripped up because they
think they're optimizing for the
algorithm, but what they're quickly
doing is like they're making a video
that looks just like Hormosy's videos
and they have the same color scheme, the
same font, the same hooks, and suddenly
they just are watered down version of
Horoszi, let's just say, instead of sort
of doubling down on what is your like
color, you know, core color of your
videos, right? What's the core, you
know, font? What's like your unique
B-roll? What's like the sound that you
use? And doesn't just have to be all the
algorithm sounds of what's blowing up.
Like what's the sound of your brand?
Like what do you listen to when you're
wrestling or when you're writing? Like
that becomes like, oh, I'm like in
Russell's world. Where we all get
tripped up sometimes is that the
platforms quickly tell you how many
people like or view your stuff. But
likes and views don't equal cash. Yeah.
and they can be really deceiving because
the things that actually reward views
and likes often times is like beginner
content, viral content, controversial
content, mass appeal content, but often
time mastermind. Yeah, exactly. These
are not even the people often times that
we're trying to really capture and and
talk to. And so you may actually see
when you execute a more balanced like
art approach where it is more unique to
you. you're talking about the things
that matter to that corner of your
audience that you will see your likes
decrease and you will see your views
decrease but you're actually talking to
the right people. It's this like idea of
like you know signal over noise, right?
Noise being like the likes, the views
and all that. What matters a lot more to
me is like I say follow like you and
like a hundred other entrepreneurs on
Instagram that like I respect the hell
of and if I see you comment on something
or my friend Daniel Dalen comment on
something who I like respect a lot who
has good taste like is successful they
know a good idea when they see it that's
10,000 likes. So I'm kind of like trying
trying to get a read on like the signal
of a piece of content versus just like
the views of it or the likes. It's
especially useful for those of us that
aren't just targeting beginners all day
long, right? When you have a more, you
know, sophisticated buyer, inevitably,
you're probably going to do your job
right when you do have less views or
likes, and that's okay. The algorithm
may show you that certain formats work,
but again, if you just copy that format,
not you, but anyone, you end up just
being another one of those. So, can you
be more inventive in a format? It's not
going to get necessarily as many views
or likes, but the right people are going
to see it and like save it, share it
with a friend, like and and be like,
"How do I get in a room where Russell's
doing this?" Which is the exact kind of
person you want potentially. For sure.
That's awesome, man. I love that. Thank
you. Cool. It's really helpful. Well,
listen, it's uh, you know, been great
hanging and a dream come true in many
senses, man. And I appreciate and all
the that you've done to contribute to
the founder community over the years and
you continue to inspire in so many ways
and just really appreciate Yeah. just
all your generosity over the years. It
like means a lot. It's changed my life.
It's changed a lot of other people's
lives and I definitely wouldn't be doing
this and probably a lot of things in my
life right now had it not been for a lot
of the stuff you've shared. So, just
want to say thank you. I appreciate
that, man. Thank you for letting me know
that. Awesome. Finally making this
happen. We've been talking about it for
like a year. We finally made it.
Exactly. No, I appreciate it. Awesome.
Very cool. Thank you, Russell. Thanks.