The worst pricing advice I ever followed
made me more money and made my life
worse. And if you ever raise your price,
landed clients, and then hit the number
and still felt like something was
quietly breaking underneath it all, you
already know exactly what I'm talking
about. More revenue, more stress, more
of you is required in every single deal.
You've hit a plateau you can't see past.
In this video, I'm going to show you the
three layers of what I call the
psychological pricing playbook, the
exact framework I've used with hundreds
of founders to make price feel
inevitable instead of negotiable. By the
end of this video, you'll know precisely
where your pricing is breaking down and
exactly what to fix first. Here's a
belief most founders carry into every
pricing conversation. If I just had more
confidence, if I knew my numbers better,
if I researched what my competitors
charge, pricing would feel easier.
Here's what I've seen. Pricing problems
at scale are almost never about the
price. They're about structural
misalignment. You know, your price is a
signal, okay? And right now, for a lot
of founders, that signal is out of sync
with three things. Your real
constraints, your buyer psychology, and
the risk architecture underneath your
offer. When [music] those three things
are misaligned, it doesn't matter what
number you put on your offer. The
business will find ways to make you feel
it. The founders who never negotiate
price, who never feel like they need to
defend what they charge, they didn't get
there by being more confident. They got
there by designing the right pricing
[music] system. Layer one of the
psychological pricing playbook is
constraint alignment. Once your business
reaches real scale, pricing stops being
a demand problem and it becomes [music]
a constraint problem. When someone pays
you at a certain level, they're buying a
set of expectations about your
attention, right? Your access, your
involvement, and then the quality of
your delivery.
>> [music]
>> And those expectations are directly tied
to what your team can actually honor.
Most founders go and raise their price
without redesigning what's included at
that price. Same delivery model, same
access structure, same calendar, and
just some higher number. And here's what
happens, right? Higher price [music]
clients have higher expectations. They
want more. They ask more questions. They
expect [music] faster responses. And
suddenly, you're working harder for
fewer clients at more money and
wondering why it doesn't feel like
progress. Basically, you know, the
opposite of what you're really trying to
achieve here, okay? So, let me help you
and avoid this. One, what does this
price require from me personally? Two,
what does it require from my team and
delivery? Three is what happens to
client experience when this offer
[music] is full. Those three questions
define your real pricing ceiling. Not
what your competitors charge
>> [music]
>> and not what you think you're worth,
right? Your actual constraints. You can
go and run a perfect constraint audit
yourself. When the price is right,
[music] the offer is real, and the
delivery is solid, and the deal still
stalls, that's not a pricing problem.
That's something entirely [music]
different. And that's layer two. Layer
two is certainty engineering. [music] I
want you to think about the last time a
prospect said, "Let me think about it."
What did you do? If you're [music]
honest, most founders either discount at
that point in time or they add more
value to the offer, or they just start
following up aggressively, okay? Because
the assumption is they're resisting
[music]
the price. But here's what's actually
happening. Buyers don't resist price.
[music]
They resist ambiguity. The human brain
is wired to avoid uncertainty more
aggressively than it seeks upside,
right? [music] That's just basic
neuroscience. Loss aversion, ambiguity
aversion, okay? It's been studied
extensively. So, when a prospect can't
clearly visualize the path from "Yes,
[music] I'm ready to work with you"
through to "Here's the result I'm going
to get", the brain defaults to one
simple answer, "Not yet." I had a call
with a founder in our community, and she
was running a coaching business. Her
offer was strong, and [music] the price
was completely reasonable. And she kept
getting stalled at the close of her
sales calls. [music] The same moment
every time she'd share the price,
there'd be a pause, and then, [music]
you know, "I need to discuss this with
my partner." Three times in a row, okay?
We didn't touch her price, though. We
didn't even touch her offer. We changed
what happened in the 72 hours before the
call. We built what's called a certainty
sequence, a short series of touchpoints
before the sales conversation even
starts that walk the prospect through a
specific sequential picture of what
transformation would look like inside of
her coaching program. By the time she
got on the call, the prospect already
had this mentally rehearsed, you know,
opportunity to understand exactly what
they were getting. They weren't just
evaluating whether to buy, they were
evaluating whether to start now or next
month, right? So, you don't have a
pricing problem. [music] You have a
certainty gap. And you can close that
gap without even touching your price at
all. If you're watching this and
thinking, "Something about my pricing
feels off, but I just [music] can't name
it", I built a short pricing
architecture audit. It's a set of
diagnostic questions mapped to all three
layers of the playbook that shows you
exactly where your pricing system is
[music] breaking right now, okay? It
takes about 10 minutes. It's free, and
it's linked in the description below.
Don't fill it out just yet, though.
Watch this first, then use it to
evaluate your pricing properly. [music]
Now, let's move on to layer three, which
almost nobody
three is risk transfer. I want to ask
you something. Think about your most
difficult client relationship in the
last year, [music] the one where the
team dreaded Monday, the one with
constant check-ins, second-guessing.
Now, ask yourself this. When that person
signed, was it ever explicitly clear who
was responsible for the outcome? In
almost every difficult client
relationship I've ever seen, the answer
to that question is no. Here's the
psychology. Humans don't fear paying
money nearly as much as they fear being
wrong. Here's what I do to intentionally
set up risk transfer. One, what the
client is responsible [music] for,
right? We're talking their inputs, their
execution, their commitment. Two, what
your team is responsible for, the
deliverables, the timelines, and the
standards, okay? And then three is what
shared success looks like, a defined
picture of what done means so that both
sides are measuring the same thing and
seeing success the same way. When those
three things are locked in and clear
before the engagement starts, something
shifts. The client [music] stops being
so anxious. They start feeling confident
and excited. They start managing
progress, right? The relationship seems
cohesive and collaborative. And I want
to show you the contrast. Two founders,
similar offers, similar clients, and
similar price points. [music] Founder A
had no risk architecture. The client
walked away from the sale knowing they'd
paid a lot of money and hoping that the
thing [music] would just work out. They
had no clarity on how it all work and
what success even look like. 60 days
later, constant [snorts] check-ins,
[music]
you know, uncomfortable conversations,
scope creep, and both people being
emotionally exhausted. Now, Founder B
built a three-page onboarding document.
So, when people are joining, they
understand exactly [music] what to
expect. Here's what you do in week one.
Here's what we're building together.
Here's what success looks like at 30
days, 60 days, and 90 days. And here's
what to do if you feel like something's
off. Same price, same offer, completely
different client behavior. Founder B's
clients referred more clients. They
stayed longer, I'm talking more customer
lifetime revenue, and they were
genuinely easy to serve. [music] Not
because Founder B was better at the
work, but because the architecture of
the relationship gave the client's brain
a clear answer to the question, "Am I
making the right decision?" Every week,
the framework answered yes to that
question. And the brain then feels safe.
People were able to relax, and [music]
it ended up being this super fruitful
client relationship. And it's not a
business cost, it's a life cost, which
brings me the most important thing I'm
going to say in this entire video.
Here's what all three layers have in
common. They are not three separate
problems, okay? They are three
expressions of the same thing, whether
you're operating your business or you're
actually architecting it. The operator
will hear things like, "Raise your
prices", and they [music] just raise
their prices. The architect, though,
asks, "What constraints does this price
need to reflect? What certainty does it
need to create? And what risk does it
need to transfer?" The operator just
starts patching systems and throwing
solutions at it. The architect is going
to design an operating system behind
this. And here's the thing. Operators
build businesses that make [music]
money, but architects build businesses
that create freedom. And at some point,
you have to decide which one you're
building. And the thing I want to say to
the founders watching this, right? I
want to say to you, the ones who already
have something real, who are already
doing the work, who are already in it,
you have already done the hard part. The
idea, the proof, the clients, the team,
you've earned all that. If you're still
defending price, still managing client
anxiety, still watching your calendar
get worse as your revenue goes up, you
are paying for that with your time and
with your energy, and you're never going
to get it back. Every year you spend
operating at the wrong level is a year
you didn't spend building the business
that you were really supposed to have.
That's not a business problem, that's
regret in slow motion. And the good
news, the only thing I want you to take
from this video is that it's a design
problem, which [music] means there's a
design solution for it. The pricing
architecture audit is not complicated.
Constraint alignment, price what your
system can actually honor. Certainty
engineering, eliminate ambiguity before
the buyer ever sees the number. And risk
transfer design, make it explicitly
clear who owns what before the ink
[music] is dry. When these three things
work together, pricing stops feeling
like a fight. It starts feeling like a
natural outcome [music] of a
well-designed business. The price
defends itself because the system makes
it inevitable. If this video felt
uncomfortably accurate, good. There's a
next step I want to offer you. Under the
pricing architecture audit linked in the
description below, you can go and
identify the opportunity in your pricing
structure. Then, if you're serious about
doing the work to get the pricing on
track, bring that completed audit to a
call with our team, which you can go and
book for free using the link in the
description below. We'll look at what
you wrote, your revenue level, and your
constraints, and then tell you whether
building this inside Founder OS makes
sense for you. Either way, you're going
to leave with a ton of clarity. So, that
link is below. And if this way of
thinking about business resonates with
you, this channel is where I share
everything I know about becoming the
founder who believes in systems over
hustle, who builds for freedom, not just
revenue, and who wants to operate at
that architect level. Be sure to like
and subscribe, and I'll see you in this
next video on how to go and build your
profitable brand. Much love, and let's
win together.