You do not need every post to go [music]
viral or turn into an influencer to
build a profitable personal brand. In
fact, if you try to do [music] that,
you'll probably just burn out and quit.
What you actually need is two focused
days, a clean system, and the courage to
build it like a founder, not like some
content creator. If your business is
already working and your brand [music]
still depends on you personally showing
up every single day, this blueprint was
built for exactly where you are. In this
video, I'm going to give you the
complete two-day blueprint to build a
profitable [music] personal brand with
out becoming a creator, without shooting
content every day, without learning to
edit videos. Your team will have [music]
a fully operational system to run your
brand every single week without pulling
you into every decision. Let's get into
day one. Day one, part one, the creator
trap. This first session is two hours
and you do it alone. The output of this
two-hour session is not some document,
it's a decision. The decision that you
are done trying to be the creator in
your own brand. Starting today, that
changes. Starting with one honest
question you need to answer to make sure
that this all actually works for you.
Have I been trying to build a personal
brand by becoming a creator? And if so,
what is that cost me? It doesn't get
easier as your business grows, it gets
harder. The more successful you become,
the more your calendar fills up, the
more your team needs you, the more
complex your operation, and the less
available you are to personally produce
content. Then a brand is really
dependent on your output and it starts
to break exactly at the moment it should
be the most powerful. And here's the
diagnostic I want you to really run. If
you personally stop posting for 30 days,
no new content, nothing, would you still
generate leads for your brand? Would
there people still find you, follow you,
and apply to work with you? If the
answer's no, or even I'm not really
sure, your brand is not a system, it's
likely just some content treadmill. The
distinction between creator and founder
is really everything here. Creators
produce content. Most of them make money
just off of ads in that content.
Founders with founder-led brands build
systems that produce content around
their thinking, their IP, their
authority. They have a core business
they're actually driving things to. They
don't need to rely on ads, and they
certainly don't want this to be made so
that it becomes, you know, a bottleneck
where they're at the center of it. So,
the question now is, you know, if you're
not the creator, then who the hell are
you? And what does your brand actually
need to work without you? And that is
what the next session of Day One is
about. Day One part two, the signal
framework. This session is 3 hours, and
you don't do it alone. Bring your chief
of staff and your head of content into
the room with you. That's how you're
going to build real leverage here. Not
to execute necessarily, but so they can
listen, they can challenge you, and they
can push towards specificity when you're
maybe being vague. We need specificity,
we need realness, not a bunch of BS.
Most founders who struggle with personal
branding, they think they, you know,
have some consistency problem, but they
don't. They generally have a signal
problem. Signal is what your brand
communicates before a single word is
read or watched. When your signal is
strong, your audience knows exactly who
this is for, what it solves, and why
you're the one saying it. can make
content decisions without asking you
every single time, and then their people
enter your audience naturally. When your
signal is weak, the audience can't build
a mental model of who you are. And when
they can't build that model, they don't
trust, follow, or buy. It doesn't matter
how hard you work. Effort is not going
to fix this signal problem. Clarity
does. This is where I want you to answer
these three questions out loud in the
room with your team. One, who are you 5
years ahead of? Specifically, not
generally. Two, what do people already
come to you for without being asked? And
three, what are you quietly intolerant
of in your industry? This is going to
start forming kind of your point of
view. It's going to form an enemy of
your brand, almost like how Steve Jobs'
enemy was Bill Gates back in the day. We
want you to stand for something. We want
that energy, that vibe, that
personality, versus getting stuck in a
sea of sameness. If you answered all
three clearly and specifically in under
60 seconds, your brand has some signal.
But if you're hesitating, if you're
giving a bunch of vague BS, well, that's
probably your brand's biggest problem
now. Not your posting schedule, not your
content quality or consistency, it's
that hesitation as to who you are and
what you really stand for. So, here's
how this is going to run in practice.
Buckle up. The first 30 minutes, the
founder answers all three questions
independently in writing. No filtering,
no editing. And your head of content can
write them out as well as your chief of
staff as well. So, we're bringing our
own independent thinking to this one.
The second 60 minutes, you and the rest
of the team present and go through every
answer together. Every vague response
gets challenged until it gets specific
and you start to have these lightbulb
moments. Final 90 minutes now, we're
going to use those refined answers and
then I'll go and draft, iterate, and
then we're going to stress test that
positioning statement until it's
something that feels clear and that we
can say without thinking. That statement
is the foundation and day one is only
halfway done. You also now need the
architecture and this is where the
rubber hits the road. The intellectual
territory you're going to own
permanently that makes your brand
irreplaceable and that allows you to
actually own your audience because this
is about building your own media company
that you own. You don't need to rely on
Zucker Moss, this is yours. But, this
stage is key. Now, quickly here, there's
a free 10-minute founder brand stress
test link below. Once you finish this
video, you can use it to measure if
you've built a system or just some other
obligation. Day one, part three,
authority architecture and content IP.
The third session of day one is 3 hours,
okay? So, here we go. People know me for
building operating systems to help
founders build organic content. They
also know me for building personal media
companies with social managers, social
writers, and video editors. And people
come to me for these things. Founders
resonate with this idea that, you know,
I'm all about freedom, helping folks
control the four Ws in life, work where
they want, when they want, on what they
want, with whoever they want. This
content IP creates
>> [music]
>> the authority that I have in the space.
And so, what I want to help you with is
do the same for you. Your authority
pillars are the three intellectual
territories that your brand is going to
claim, not content categories, not
hashtags. Every piece of content should
touch at least one of these pillars.
What you're going to do now is take your
answers from the signal framework. They
already contain your pillars. For my
brand, my three pillars are founder
systems, founder freedom, and founder
led brands. Every video, every
newsletter, every post, it all connects
to those three. My team knows this and
they don't need to ask me about what
kind of content we should be creating.
Now, the most powerful thing in this
session, okay, is creating your content
IP. And IP here stands for intellectual
property. Content IP is your branded
language, your named frameworks, your
proprietary systems that make your ideas
recognizable, repeatable, and impossible
to copy without attribution. Look at
what I've built over time, things like
the content waterfall system that turns
one piece of pillar content into 24
other pieces of content across all
platforms, or the content GPS, which is
the most powerful system I've ever
created for going and building a
profitable personal media company and
driving people from awareness through to
transaction, or the founder led brand,
which is this future where every founder
is one part founder, one part creator,
and that intersection is where founders
are going and becoming recognized
online, building trust at scale, and
converting people to their cash flowing
company. Here's how this session is
going to run. First 60 minutes, you're
going to identify your authority pillars
using the positioning statement and the
signal framework answers as your filter.
Then the second 60 minutes, you're going
to audit your existing thinking. What
are the things that you find yourself
saying repeatedly, whether it's with
friends or with customers? What language
do you find you're using that others
don't? And this is why it's useful to
have people that you know in the room
with you because they may say, "Oh Matt,
you always talk about personal brand
being a moat." Or you always talk about
the content waterfall and it's like,
"Shit, we should formalize that more."
What processes have you built that
deserve a name? So, the final 60 minutes
here is we want to name at least five
pieces of content IP. You need to give
them a name and make sure it's unique. I
didn't call the content waterfall, you
know, a content strategy because that's
generic. Everyone has a content
strategy. The content waterfall system
is a way of repurposing one piece of
pillar content on YouTube, Substack
newsletter, X article, and making that
into 24 other piece of content and it
has its own unique name online that's
attributed back to me. So, write them
down. This is content IP excavation
here. So, day one is done. Great work.
And now you think differently about your
brand and you did it just in 8 hours.
So, there we go. But before we get into
day two, I need you to know that
everything I just walked you through are
the exact systems we install for
founders inside a Founder OS. Founder OS
is really an operating system and a
community of high-growth founders who
are already running real cash-flowing
profitable businesses, but really want
to then scale a profitable personal
media company around what they've built.
Getting the right team in place, the
right structure, the right workflows,
and the operating system that I've used
over the last 18 years to build multiple
profitable companies and a portfolio
that does over $15 million a year.
Here's exactly what it is. You're
getting access to my most powerful
plug-and-play simple systems for
content, monetization, growing your
team, hiring, delegating. You're going
to get live coaching sessions with me,
live coaching sessions with my C-suite.
You get a monthly strategy call directly
with me and you get a private community
of serious founders building at your
level, moving super fast, building the
same way. This is not some course you
just buy and forget. This is an
operating system for you, but also your
core team members as well. We're going
to level them up on these calls as well.
If that sounds like something that
you're interested in, you should go and
check it out via the link in the
description. Keep in mind, we don't
accept everyone. We got to have culture
fit. This is about building something
too that's fun and, you know, really
building a community that's going to
build cool together for the next
decade. Day two, part one, the media
company identity shift. Day two opens up
with the most important 2 hours of this
entire blueprint. This is the only
session where the full team is in the
room. Everyone who will touch your
brand. I have watched brilliant founders
become slaves to their own personal
brands, shooting videos at midnight,
filling up their entire content
calendar, making sure that their own
content is then repurposed for every
platform, lying awake stressed about
posting consistently when their business
needs strategic thinking. You know, if
you're falling asleep at night wondering
what the next piece of content you're
going to post is, you've already failed.
This is a structure problem, and
structure problems have structural
solutions. Every serious company right
now is a media company. Red Bull,
Disney, media companies. The brands that
are winning are the ones distributing
their brand consistently and building
audiences they own and then converting
those owned audiences then into revenue.
If you already know you need a personal
brand, the only question is whether you
build it as a creator or as a CEO. All
right, so you just spent day one making
that choice, okay? So, here's day two.
It's a two-hour session, and here's
exactly how it's going to run. The first
60 minutes, you're going to walk the
full team through your authority map. We
want everyone to get on board with it.
Have them ask questions. Have them
stress test it a bit. Every person is
going to confirm that the positioning
statement, the three pillars, and at
least three pieces of content IP, you
know, are proper and then the document
feels kind of battle-tested. That's
going to be kind of the quality bar for
that session. The second 60 minutes, you
and the team write the brand's operating
principles together. Who makes what
decisions? What requires your input and
what doesn't? How does a content idea
even get evaluated against your
authority map? These operating
principles get logged in a Google Doc
for the team to reference in the future.
This is how you run a proper team, clear
owners of clear aspects, not just a
bunch of chaos. Now, the question is how
does content actually get made and then
distributed every week without you being
in every step? And that's what comes
next. This is where the whole system
starts to click. Day two, part two, the
content engine. Four hours, your head of
content and your head of distribution
are really going to own this session.
You technically don't even need to be in
the room. And that's intentional because
we want to start removing you from more
of this. If you're sitting in every
session of day two, you know, you've not
made that identity shift. We want to
start trusting the team, trusting the
authority map, and letting these people
build without you. That is leverage. The
system they are now installing is the
content waterfall system. This is the
actual system my team runs every week.
And that simply means that we're going
to take a high-performing long-form
piece of content, could be a YouTube
video, could be a newsletter, and we're
going to turn it into probably 20 plus
pieces of content across all of my other
social media profiles. As this cycle
repeats week after week, the content
library grows. Ideas that perform well
get revisited and deepened. Old content
IP gets introduced to new audiences. The
brand's intellectual territory expands
and expands and also deepens. So, people
now are telling their friends and their
friends' friends. I know the goal of my
piece of content that I put out is that
I want every single piece of content I
put out there for a founder to go and
share that with 20 people in their
company Slack. Consistently occupying
the same intellectual territory online
is going to make your brand a household
name and help people associate you with
the content IP you're putting out. Now
you've built the engine. The content is
flowing. Now there is just one question
left to answer. How does this actually
all make money? Well, it's an important
one and the answer is almost never what
people expect. Day two, part three,
monetization team and inevitability.
Monetization is not about just sales and
it's not a sales problem. For a
founder-led brand, monetization is
generally a trust problem. The
question's not, "How do I get people to
buy?" The question is, "How do we build
trust clearly enough that the people
feel it and would almost, you know, be
irrational and crazy not to work with
us?" Revenue from a personal brand is
not generated by pitching. It's
generated by becoming so clear, so
consistent, so genuinely useful that the
people self-select in your world. By the
time they reach out, apply, or click a
link, the selling is already done. The
brand has done the work. It's persuaded
people to open their wallets before
they've even hopped on that sales call.
Every piece of content you publish, it
either adds trust or it subtracts trust.
I've had founders reach out to work with
me inside of Founder as after just
watching a few hours of my content. They
come in knowing exactly what they want.
They come in already aligned with our
philosophy. This is, you know, very
little selling because the brand's
already done the selling. This is what I
want for you. Now, this does not mean
you're passive about monetization. I'm
not saying to not make money. Obviously,
we're making money here. We're just
trying to not come across as salesy
online, and we're trying to think
long-term about nurturing valuable
relationships, and most importantly, an
amazing brand that you're proud of. The
kind of brand that you could show your
family or friends and really be stoked
to show them versus kind of embarrassed.
Monetization moments are not just CTAs.
They're really contextual opportunities
to go and provide value to the audience
that you're serving, and then point them
towards a logical next step. Your tech
and your system person's going to really
own implementing this infrastructure
that makes the monetization moments
work. The newsletter platform, the lead
capture, the CRM, the application
pipeline, the automations that move
someone from a social follower to an
email subscriber, to a qualified
applicant, to an opportunity, to a
closed deal, and then onboarding them to
your customer success and delivery
function in your company. I'll be real.
I don't think this is glamorous work,
but there's some legends that love this
I always hire people and direct
them towards the pain in the business. I
add people when the absence of that role
is clearly costing me more than the
higher would. It's all about ROI, return
on investment, and viewing yourself as
the investor behind this, not just the
entrepreneur. Making sure that every
single bet you make is a smart use of
your capital. Ensuring that if you pay a
social manager 8K, they're generating
50K per month back to your business. And
it's understanding that math that's all
the difference between building a
profitable personal media company or
something you got to shut down in 2
months. And this is exactly what we help
founders with inside of Founder OS,
making sure that you're building
something that's strong, that's
sustainable, and that's enduring for the
next decade. If you want some help doing
this all correctly with the systems,
support, and access to me and my team
that can help you and help you level up
your team, well, go and check it out via
the link in the description. The brands
that burn founders out are not built by
people with bad intentions, they're
built by founders who never got the
architecture right, who tried to do the
whole thing themselves. And that's what
we're trying to prevent you from in this
video. You become the creator when you
should have just been the CEO. You don't
have to do this the hard way. You've
watched how this system works. The only
question is whether you're going to
actually go and use it now. And [music]
it's the action that makes all the
difference. And since I want you to
actually use this, I'm giving you a
founder-led brand stress test. I'll show
you exactly where your personal brand is
structurally exposed, your signals are
wrong, your architecture's dialed, where
your engine's at, and how your
monetization's functioning. We're not
talking about just content quality, your
posting frequency, or structure. No,
this is the real stuff you need to build
a powerful media company. Go download
it, and please fill it out honestly. And
if you discover that your brand is still
founder-dependent, book a call with my
team, and we can help you identify the
structural bottleneck in your system,
and then really help you go and build
the solution. It's not about posting
more, it's about building something that
frees you because you built your
business to have a life. Build your
brand the same way. It's not about a
better strategy, it's about building a
better life, a more powerful personal
brand, and being able to do it for the
next 100 years. The best founders build
systems-based
businesses. You were already that
person. Now you have the blueprint to
prove it, and let's go take action. If
you enjoyed this video, you'd love this
next video where I break down the exact
content systems I use to create
high-converting content. So, go and
check that one out. Thanks so much for
watching. Be sure to like and subscribe.
Welcome to the Founder Freedom Movement,
and let's win together.