The biggest lie in personal branding is
[music] that it's about having the right
look, the perfect brand, the
cinematography, the color grade. The
real answer is something that people
never actually focus [music] on. I've
gone from zero to millions of followers,
and in this video, I want to break down
the six psychological shifts that
actually matter if you want to build a
real brand. By the way, I put together a
free evaluation that helps you go and
find the bottom neck to building this
kind of brand, right? And you can go and
download it and learn about all of these
six elements that I'm about to go and
dive into after watching this full
video. So, let's get into it. Part one,
who you need to become. If you want
people to follow you, to actually care
about what you're building, you first
need to answer a question most creators
never even ask themselves. Who are you?
Not your job title, not your niche, not
your content pillars. Who are you,
really? I know that when I've opened up
in my journey around having a government
raid my first business, then exiting
that for a life-changing sum, struggling
with addiction, but then rising into
that and building a systematized
cash-flowing business, then starting
Founder OS. It's this journey, right?
That's what you need to go and do, too,
because you want to attract the right
kind of people, the ones who buy, the
ones who refer, and the ones who stay.
And it comes down to three elements.
Element one, your values and conviction.
It took me an entire decade running
three businesses to fully understand my
own core values. I went through
partnerships that didn't work. I hired
people that felt off. I closed deals
that looked great on paper and then
completely drained me. And it wasn't
until I went through all of that, the
wins, the failures, the uncomfortable
exits, that everything finally clicked.
Now, when I was building Founder OS, I
learned about something that Marc
Benioff had done when he had started
Salesforce. He made every single person
on his team carry a note card with the
company's mission, vision, and values on
it. And that hit me hard, right?
Because, you know, after building a
couple companies, we had values that I
think the team was, you know, living,
but they could have really been living
it at a whole other degree. People
joined, they brought their own energy,
and over time the company shaped itself
around really whoever showed up. But
there should be those underlying kind of
codes of the culture, the values, that
never change and dictate how you
operate. And so, when I built Founder
OS, I created this one-pager. Who we
are, what we stand for, and what we'll
never tolerate. And what it really means
to be on this team. That one-pager
changed everything. You know, new team
members would join and they immediately
understood who we are and what I value.
Two of my values that changed everything
for me personally. The first is bring
solutions, not problems. That single
value, right, of bring solutions, not
problems, right, changes how the entire
team operates and communicates. We
stopped tolerating complaint culture. We
started attracting solution-first
people. And that value alone, right, has
been an insane hiring filter, a culture
signal, and a brand statement. Now, the
second is insanely simple. If you can't
explain it simply, then don't ship it.
If a piece of content is confusing,
[\h__\h] cut it. If an offer is hard to
explain, just remove it or rebuild it,
right? Those two values alone shape how
I hire, how I build, and how I create
everything. But here's what most
creators and founders do instead. They
see someone succeeding. They absorb that
person's values, copy their voice, echo
their messaging, and just become this
copycat. The perfect example of this is,
you know, someone I love, okay? The
artist and legend Goks. Goks's
creativity seeps out through every frame
he produces and has grown his personal
brand by finding his edge, not someone
else's, which has built him an insane
audience and cult following. He didn't
study what was working and then
replicate it. He obsessed over his own
creative voice until the world couldn't
ignore it. Here's what I want you to do
right now. Write down three things that
genuinely matter to you. Not what sounds
good on a website, not what you think
sounds impressive, what you actually
care about. The things you already
filter your decisions through, even if
you've never named them. Then sharpen
them. Make them edgy. Make them binary.
You know, I'm not saying be simple, I'm
saying be insanely simple. That clarity
is what attracts the right people and is
going to repel the wrong ones. That's
not exclusion, that's precision. And
precision is what builds a brand that
lasts. Element two, becoming a niche.
Values are your foundation, but a
foundation isn't a brand yet. Element
two is the thing that separates brands
that fade from brands that dominate. Not
a lot of people really remember this,
okay, but Instagram actually started as
a little company/project
called Burbn. It was cluttered, it was
this location-based app. People hated
it. Kevin Systrom, one of the founders
of Instagram, they noticed something.
Their users kept coming back for the
photo filters. So, instead of trying to
fix everything else, they just made a
critical decision. They stripped down
the product to one thing [music] and
started a new thing called Instagram,
and it was around photo filters.
Instagram didn't just find a winning
feature, they found their identity. They
stopped trying to be everything all at
once and committed to being one thing.
And that's what made them impossible to
ignore. It's not going to happen
overnight, okay? So, you got to be
patient. You got to have that long-term
thinking. Every failure is just data
telling you where your intersection
isn't. Keep going, keep listening, and
eventually the pattern becomes obvious.
And when it clicks, that's not just a
brand, that's something no company
pivot, no market shift, and no algorithm
can take away [music] from you. Element
three, authenticity and vulnerability.
Finding your niche is the smart part.
Element three is the hard part. It's the
reason most personal brands feel hollow
even when they're doing everything else
right. Gary V didn't start as some
polished keynote speaker that you see
today, right? He started by documenting
himself grinding in his family's liquor
store, talking openly about his
insecurities, his impatience, the things
he was seeing over the coming 15 years,
and [music] his fear of irrelevance. He
didn't wait until he had made it to
start sharing. He just let people watch
him build this messy brand. The
vulnerability wasn't a weakness, right?
It was proof of a process that he's
real, he's legit. He's just trying
things and putting it out there, just
like the rest of us. And here's the
thing most people get wrong about
vulnerability in personal branding.
Failures and adversity, right, they're
not liabilities. Your mistakes, the
messiness, the, you know, imperfections
along the way, right? Those are actually
assets. They signal depth. They signal
growth. They signal that you're human,
okay? And if you only share polished
wins, people may respect you, right? But
if you share the real journey, the
doubts, the pivots, the internal
battles, people are going to actually be
able to relate to you. And in personal
branding, relatability compounds faster
than perfection ever will. [music]
Sometimes that can be, you know, a
consideration. What's most important is
you, [music] right? Your story, how you
show up, and the fact that you might
stutter here or there, or you may not
know what to say perfectly, right? All
of that just makes you human. People
don't want to see the perfect version of
you. They want to just get to know
[music] you. Ask five to 10 people who
you know really well two questions. What
do I do better than most people, and
what do I care about more deeply than
others? You're going to see patterns
emerge, okay? Traits and strengths that
you probably even overlooked. That's
your authenticity signal. Build your
content and your voice around that, not
some polished persona you think people
want to see. Because the brands that
last, they're not manufactured, they're
not perfect. They're built on truth. And
as founders, we have an advantage here.
We're [music] in the trenches. We're
building. We're actually doing the hard
[\h__\h] That humanness is the thing
[music] that's going to make people
actually care. That's the foundation.
But there's a second half to this that
most creators and founders never even
think about. It's the difference between
people scrolling past you and people
stopping everything to listen. Part two,
how you make people feel. Think about
the creators you can't stop watching,
right? It's not their editing, it's not
their niche, it's something you can
learn to do on purpose. It's how you
make your audience feel. Element four,
trust and credibility. There's a reason
some creators can say the simplest thing
and people hang on every word. And it
has nothing to do with what you're
actually saying. Think about Jeff Bezos.
No matter what question he was asked, a
failed experiment, a stock dip, a bold
acquisition, he always brought it back
to the same thing, customer obsession.
Because sometimes there's things that
change in the world, but then there's
things that stay the same forever. And
customer obsession is one of those
things. Things like long-term thinking,
systems. To outsiders, it almost sounded
repetitive, but to investors, employees,
and customers, it built unshakable
trust. They knew exactly what he stood
for, and they knew it wasn't going to
change based on what was trending that
week. They kind of find a way of saying
one core message like a thousand
different ways. You know, my credibility
didn't start the day I launched a
personal brand, right? It started like
15 years earlier. Before I ever started
posting content, I was doing the reps,
helping people get real results, no
cameras, no audience, just work. I had
successful exits. I've had failures. I
built successful audiences of 14
million, and that's not even 1% of it.
When I finally decided to go and then
build a personal brand, [music] I didn't
invent some new identity, right? I went
back and just audited my own track
record. Just started going and telling
these stories, the wins, the outcomes,
the case studies, right? Just sharing
what actually had gone down those years
of building. The frameworks that
actually had worked for me, I figured
would also go and work for you guys in
the real world. And that's the
difference, right? I wasn't creating
credibility. I was just documenting it
and sharing my experience. Trust doesn't
come from novelty, right? It comes from
evidence. When you build your brand
around proven experience, around
something you've tested, refined, and
then lived, your words are going to
actually carry weight because
credibility isn't created when you hit
publish. It's created long before anyone
watching. Here's what I want you to go
and do. Go pick a hill that you will die
on. The idea, the perspective, the
philosophy that defines you. Then say it
a thousand different ways through your
content, your decisions, your product,
your messaging until people associate
you with it automatically. And back it
up. Audit what you actually know, what
you've tested, what you've proven works.
Audit the stories of the people that
you've helped. Go and look at the case
studies of the folks that you've served
with your product or service. All of
that is content gold. Stop chasing new
tactics or viral formats. Just lean into
what you already know is true, and then
just amplify it. When you do that,
right? Your audience won't just hear
you, they're going to believe you. And
that trust becomes the foundation for
every relationship, every opportunity,
and every deal you want to make. Element
five, aspiration and status.
>> [music]
>> Credibility gets people to trust you,
but the issue is that people trust a ton
of different creators. And so,
aspiration and status is what makes you
the one that can't be replaced. I'm not
looking for you to go and show your
Lambo. I'm not looking for you to go and
have a briefcase of cash. That [\h__\h] is
[\h__\h] gross, okay? Think about Elon
Musk, right? And his plan to go to Mars.
On paper, it sounds insane. A single
person trying to go to space. What the
heck? Like, how's this ever going to
happen, right? Billions of dollars at
risk, deadlines missed, rockets
exploding, critics lining up to say,
"You're never going to make this work."
But here's the thing, right? He still
hasn't made it to Mars, but it almost
doesn't matter because the audacity of
that vision is what draws the right
people to [music] him. He committed
relentlessly to this vision. He wasn't
just building rockets, he was building
belief. He's building a movement. He's
building this following of folks that
all want to get to this ambitious
vision. Even if it takes a lifetime,
they're down. He was showing people a
future that they wanted to be a part of,
even if it's impossible. That's the
power of aspiration. People want to
invest their attention, their time, and
their energy in people who are chasing
something bigger than themselves, right?
We all want to be part of something that
matters, right? We want to do work that
matters. We want to accomplish our
potential, and we want to be a part of
something that is bigger than us. And
so, the vision itself can become the
brand, and that's what makes millions of
people want to follow Elon. When I think
about the aspiration of my own brand, I
want to do what Apple did for creatives
in the '70s, what Nike did for athletes
in the '80s, but for founders in the
2020s. Now, for the final element, and
the one that's going to go and make
everything else stick. Element six,
connection and resonance. So, standing
out gets you noticed, but connection and
resonance is what makes people stay.
Now, when I think about resonance,
right? It's not just saying something to
say it, it's saying it because it's a
whole body yes, right? It's something
that's aligned with your mind, your
heart, and your soul. The kind of thing
that's deeply true to you. And when you
talk about stuff like that, right? When
I talk about the ability to be able to
walk and disappear from your business
for 30 days and come back to a business
that's even better, stronger, more
profitable, the peace of mind that comes
with that, right? You can maybe feel how
passionate I am about living that myself
and being able to unlock that for
thousands of other founders. That That
passion, right? That emotion behind it.
You can tell it's aligned, right? And
there's resonance there. It's the one
thing you can absolutely not shortcut
when you're building your brand. I'm
obsessed with Eric Grangqvist, a Swedish
YouTuber who spends weeks building
traditional off-grid log cabins entirely
by hand. Think about this for a second.
No flashy effects, no trending
challenges, no clickbait [\h__\h]
right? Just one guy, a pile of logs, and
a dream of creating something that's
real. Why would anyone want to watch
that? And yet, millions do. Cuz here's
the thing, too, right? There's like 8
billion people in the world. And so,
there's enough room on the internet for
your own little corner of it. It's not
the spectacle that's going to keep
people hooked, right? It's the
connection. His audience sees that
process, that aspirational sense of
living, the joy of creating, the
struggle that he's going through, and
the satisfaction of seeing it all paying
off over time, right? That's why people
stick around for years. Here's the thing
most people get wrong. They treat their
audience like numbers, metrics, likes,
engagements, subscribers. [\h__\h] all that
[\h__\h] That is completely the wrong
approach. I call that outcome thinking.
On the other side, you have process
thinking, okay? And that's when you go
and you're building your brand for just
the sheer joy of the process. When you
just focus more on the process, the
outcome actually comes faster, and you
have so much more fun along the way.
When who you are collides with how you
make people feel, something shifts
entirely. You stop being just another
creator, and you become someone people
trust. Talk to your audience, ask them
real questions, let what excites you be
the thing that guides you in everything
that you create. Do that, and you won't
just build a personal brand, you're
going to build an amazing legacy.
>> [music]
>> I'm giving you a free 10-minute
diagnostic that walks you through all
six of these elements and forces you to
identify the single psychological
constraint capping your brand.
>> [music]
>> And when you go and complete it, I want
you to go and figure out from there the
real issue you're having. Could be your
values, positioning, credibility,
aspiration, or connection, and what that
constraint is really costing you. So,
you can go and download that below, fill
it out honestly, and
go and take that, and you can go and
book a call with my team, and we'll go
and help you go and figure out how to
build a founder-led brand that
compounds. We'll help you go and
pressure test your bottleneck, and then
map out the systems that are going to
help you solve it structurally. [music]
If you found this valuable, subscribe. I
put out content every week on exactly
how to build a founder-led brand that
scales. [music] And if this video landed
for you, you'll love this one on the
psychology of building a brand that
everyone [music] loves. Let's win
together, and I'll see you in the next
one.