it's not just about what you do but what
you don't do create a list of anti-
goals for everything you want to achieve
write an anti-g goal that must be avoid
it at all costs want to make more money
make it your anti-g goal to avoid
burning out want better health make an
anti-g goal not to create a regimen that
takes over your life want to master
something make an anti-g goal of not to
take on more than one thing at a time
the anti- goal is the thing you're not
willing to sacrifice in pursuit of
success it's the boundary you put up
with your goals or your business it'll
protect you from burnout and it'll make
your success way more sustainable over
the long term