Now, as you can see, we have all of this
all in here, right? We've got our title
research, we've got thumbnail research,
we've got intro research, we've got our
script writing research all in here.
It's like 40 plus videos including my
popular videos all ripping ready to go.
What I'm going to now go do is work some
magic on this. We are going to go and
put this in here, and this is an AI
chat. So, you saw that in seconds, I can
go and embed an AI chat into Poppy. In
here, you can go and click on any tool
you want to use inside of it, but I'm
going to use Claude 4 Sonnet. I've gone
and used that voice to go and now prompt
it, and it's been fed all of my most
popular YouTube videos, and so we'll
give that a second. While we're waiting
there, we can go and create this text
field here. Now, it's gone and it's
taken my entire voice here, and it's
created a complete framework out of it.
Based on analysis of your most popular
YouTube videos, here's a comprehensive
system to capture and replicate your
unique voice and intellectual property.
So, our core brand identity and mission,
you know, I help 100 million founders
accomplish their dreams through proven
systems, the core value prop, systems
first approach everything, organic
content over paid ads, founder freedom
through automation, build businesses
that serve you, not imprison you. It
knows all my four pillars of leverage,
the AED system to automate, eliminate,
and delegate, the four W's framework,
you know, working where you want, when
you want, and what you want, with who
you want, my content systems like my
content waterfall system, content GPS,
content idea machine. It knows all of my
audience growth systems, the founder
flywheel, and then my signature phrases
that I use frequently like proven
systems, rented versus owned audience,
the zone of genius, systems designers
craft their own. I mean, this is insane,
right? So, we can go create a new text
file and go and copy that all in. So,
this becomes our new framework now for
my voice.