a commitment consists of three parts one
the action this is the thing you're
committing to doing or not doing without
clear actionables no commitment exists
number two the timeline this is the
amount of time that you're committing to
take or not take the specific action it
could be 3 months 6 months a year or a
lifetime without a clear timeline no
commitment exists number three the
execution this is the process of doing
what you set out to do whether you feel
like it or not a commitment only truly
exists if we stick with the specific
action for the allotted amount of time
get better at making and fulfilling your
commitments and you'll live a far
happier and healthier life