Authority isn't claimed, it's
engineered. If you want people to keep
coming back to you for answers, this is
how you create authority. When you think
about authority, right, there's really a
flywheel from your content to
credibility to proof to demand to
opportunities [music] and then right
back to more content. As you put
compounding content out there, right,
more people start to see you show
[music] up and they become indoctrinated
to your way of thinking and you start to
build a movement online. As you then
start to serve these people, you build
more proof through things like [music]
case studies, recommendations, and
reviews on public platforms. And that
just generates more demand. All of these
people generating word of mouth around
your brand starts to create
opportunities, opportunities [music] for
you to go and maybe get invited to
things like speaking events or jumping
on podcasts. And then that just creates
a flood of more proof. And this creates
[music] a flywheel in your business. And
so what do you need to do? Well, go and
map out your content strategy for the
year. Make sure that you have the core
team necessary to start building your
own media company versus it all relying
on your pure effort.