my own experience, it's hard sometimes
to discern these things. Is it actually
something that's accelerating your
vision and going to get you the cash you
need and be this proof point of what
you're building and and be that or is it
a distraction constantly like trying to
figure out like is this thing helping me
or is this thing like hurting me? You
know, how do you decide based on
experience? One of that is like the
criteria of like a hell yes or a no.
Does this feel like it's like a definite
hell yes and it's like, oh yeah, like
this is definitely going to help us.
This moves us forward. Like this is in
line with what we're doing. or does it
like feel somewhat murky and it's like
the money's good but [\h__\h] I can't
totally see how it accelerates it and
like we're serving filmmakers we're not
serving like the core thing is not this
thing this is a different thing.