most people make a decision but they
still have their plan B and their plan C
and their Plan D but the entire point of
making a commitment is to do it when
it's not easy and to see it through to
the end regardless of your feelings the
etymology of decide comes from Latin and
it means to cut off to remove all other
paths your plan B is one of the worst
things you can do for your plan a you'll
figure it out if things don't go as
plann but backup plans are often just
because we're subconsciously planning
and preparing to quit when it gets too
hard or scary it's better go all in on
something and figure it out later if it
doesn't work