All right, here we go. This is how to go
and reach your potential as an
entrepreneur. So, first off, you're an
entrepreneur. You're not a creator,
right? So,
go and craft an offer, right? And make
sure that you're going and selling that
offer via your personal brand, right?
That founder energy is what makes you
different. So, lean into it, right? You
are the ultimate competitive advantage
in your business. Your founder energy is
what's going to attract amazing talent,
amazing customers, and help you go and
build a badass business, right? Re-
realize too that you are your biggest
asset, right? So, make sure that you're
taking care of yourself, right? Taking
care of your health. I think that
inevitably what you're trying to do is
escape founder prison, right? Remove the
chaos and be more the architect, the
designer of your business and your
success. You should be able to pass the
one-month test. Be able to leave your
business for 1 month and come back to a
business that's stronger than when you
left, okay? And the way to do this then
is to build systems, right? Look at your
business across onboarding, inquiry,
sales, marketing, ops, finance, and
think about the three core systems
across each of those areas that,
you know, are key to make sure that
the thing is scalable, it's
systematized. And remember too that a
small, mighty team is a lot better than
some bloated infrastructure. So,
keep it simple, my friends.