I think every successful founder out
there at times has come across as a bad
person. You know,
being a great CEO, it's not a popularity
contest, right? You got to be the one to
terminate someone when it's just not
working out. You have to be that one
person in the room often times that
disagrees with a certain direction
because you just know in your heart of
hearts it is not the way to go.
And I think this is one of the toughest
parts about being a CEO about being a
founder is it can be a lonely journey
because sometimes inside you question
like am I even a good person? Right?
You're making decisions where
sometimes you got to hurt people's
feelings or you got to make a difficult
call that you know it's going to be
tough on your team.
And you're sometimes alone in those
things. This is why I think it's so
important as a founder to have a
personal board of advisors, right?
Ideally four or five people around you
that can support you in different areas
whether it be operations, growth, sales,
marketing, finance so that that burden
doesn't all fall on your shoulders. So
that in those moments when you're
questioning yourself, you know, am I
even doing the right thing?
Am I a good person?
You have these voices of reason, right?
People that can help sort of you come
back to your own true north, right? The
things that you know about yourself,
about your business, what you value
and can feel solid in the direction
you're going.