The problem with chatbt is it's only as
good as your prompt. And so when you
think about going and creating a killer
prompt for chatbt, you want to make sure
that you do a few things. Number one,
you must make sure that you flush out
the prompt as detailed as possible,
indicating the bar that you're setting
for it, going and giving it inspiration.
And so, you know, if I'm saying, you
know, I [music] want ChatBT to go and
help me 10x the profit of my business,
I'm going to say, you know, I want you
to advise me like, you know, Ray Deio,
Jeff Bezos, [music] Steve Jobs, and the
best entrepreneurs that have ever
existed. I want to go and think in
systems. I want it to identify a
constraint. And then I want it to go and
use the org chart I've attached to go
and help me go and delegate core tasks
[music] to my team so that I'm building
leverage around me versus having to do
all this stuff myself. [music] The other
aspect too is that your prompt is only
as good as the files that you feed the
given project as well. The more that you
have your business systemized, [music]
the more powerful you can upload those
files to the project and then the more
context Chat GBT has to give [music] you
results that are contextual to your
unique Possess.