Being authentic on social media isn't
enough anymore. You need to be
antifragile. Now, you're probably
wondering what the heck is antifragile.
It's a term from NASM Talib that really
stands for actually benefiting when
times are volatile. And times couldn't
be even more volatile than right now.
Sora just launched. Now, we have AI slop
anywhere. And what's getting not talked
about enough amidst all of this is the
debate of slop versus soul. [music] You
know, slop is all that stuff that's
being put out that's regurgitated from
chat GBT, copied and pasted from Claude,
put online on Tik Tok. And the reality
is is that amidst all of this, you have
an opportunity to create content that is
actually true to yourself. Because
[music]
amidst all the noise, I think that
handmade real human content is actually
going to be more valuable than