Social media just changed forever. And
if you don't understand what's
happening, you're going to get left
behind. I built a following of over 14
million people by studying this stuff
over [music] the last 15 years. And what
I'm seeing right now is one of the
biggest platform shifts that's [music]
ever existed. It's a complete rewiring
of how attention works and how influence
is built. So, in this video, I'm going
to break down the six social media
shifts that you need to know and how to
position yourself for success in this
new era. Shift number one, antifragile
authenticity. Now, you're probably
wondering, what the heck is antifragile?
Well, it's a term from NASA Talib that
[music] really stands for actually
benefiting when times are volatile. And
times couldn't be even more volatile
than right now. Sora just launched. Now
we have AI slop anywhere. And what's
getting not talked about enough amidst
all of this is the debate of slop versus
soul. You have an opportunity to create
content that is actually true to
yourself. Because amidst all the noise,
I think that handmade real human content
is actually going to be more valuable
than ever. You know, there's this
Japanese [music] concept called
wobbishabi. And what it stands for is
the beauty and imperfection. And one of
the biggest issues with AI is that in a
way it's too perfect, [music] right?
There's no chips on its armor, right?
It's all too polished. And there's
something to be said for just showing up
as you are, right? You've made mistakes.
share those. You know, you're going
through different challenges. Share
those unique stories [music] because
it's that uniqueness that AI will never
be able to replicate. We're going
through this massive shift in
entrepreneurship right now where every
entrepreneur is becoming a creator and
every company is becoming a media
company. And so, the best way to go and
make your business antifragile [music]
is to make sure that you're building
organic content that is sending through
hot leads to your business. You know,
more than anything, people follow people
than they follow brands. Right? If you
go and you scroll [music] your
Instagram, your LinkedIn, your ex,
you're going to see that you follow way
more people than you do companies. And
so, the opportunity right now is to be
antifragile by building your [music]
authentic founder-led brand, putting
yourself out there, being the face of
what you're building, so you can go and
gravitate people [music] to what it is
that you do and create this loyal cult
following. Shift number two, own your
audience. If you don't have a way to
convert your audience into real dollars,
you're basically just renting eyeballs
from Zuck and Musk. The reality is is
that the platforms that you're on are
generally just middlemen. The real value
when you're building a business is your
actual email list, right? Those are
emails of potential customers that you
own. Not Zach, not Musk, you. And the
truth is that most people forget that
all these social media platforms have
platform risk. Meaning that at any given
moment something could change on the
platform and all of a sudden you're
screwed. I've seen this across so many
industries, right? One minute someone
has a flourishing Instagram page and
then suddenly something changes and all
of a sudden it's shut down. This is
platform risk at its worst. And the best
way to go and defend yourself against
this risk is to actually own your
audience by creating something like an
email list or a newsletter, right? It
doesn't matter what platform you use,
whether it's Substack, you know, it's
ConvertKit, HubSpot, the tech doesn't
matter. If you don't have an email list
over the next 10 years, you will die.
So, you're not going to make real money
from AdSense or advertising dollars. No,
the real way to go and think about this
is to actually own your audience and
then convert people from email
subscribers to then loyal customers of
your product or service. And so, here we
have, you know, really the operating
system that I recommend that founders go
and implement in their businesses. Okay?
And this is all about going and
converting people from your actual
personal media company all the way
through to loyal customers. And as you
can see here, it doesn't matter what
platform I'm building on, whether it's
X, LinkedIn, Tik Tok, Instagram, or
YouTube. The key thing here is to drive
people via engaging CTAs to my owned
audience. Now, I use HubSpot for my
entire email list. It allows us to go
and have all of our customers inside of
there. we can see, you know, which
people are buying which things, what
email lists they're a part of, and get
the right people into the right thing.
And so what you want to have is engaging
call to actions across all of your
different content on different
platforms. On Instagram, that could look
like different links inside your
stories. It could look like a end of
carousel CTA that drives people to many
chat where you get their email. On
platforms like X, it could be at the end
of a thread in your link in bio. On
LinkedIn, it's at the end of a long form
post. On Tik Tok, your link in bio. And
in YouTube, you can go and put links in
your description that drive people then
to your newsletter signup page where
you're then able to go and capture that
email. But the people that take real
ownership over their future and create
this anti-fragile future are the ones
that realize that, you know, I don't
control how many views I get from the
algorithms. But what I can control is
the amount of my audience that I convert
to an email list. Because when you send
out an email, right, 100% of your
subscribers get that email. Whereas,
when you put a piece of content onto
social media, you're lucky if only like
10% of your audience actually sees it.
When it comes to the actual content
inside of a newsletter, there are a lot
of different ways to go about it. Now,
there are really two core ways I like to
think about the content. You have the
more curator approach or the systems
approach. So, the curator approach is
made famous by folks like James Clear in
his 321 email or Tim Ferrris in his five
bullet Friday. Essentially, what you're
doing here is rounding up some key
little tips, tricks that people can go
and learn about and then sending them on
to different links. Okay. The other side
is the more deep systems approach. And
this is what I do inside of the Founder
West newsletter that I send out every
single Saturday. It's the only
newsletter you need to scale your
personal brand. And how I do it is that
I start off with a story of what I've
currently experienced that week and then
give away a valuable free system that
can help folks go and scale their own
personal brand. These are more deep
dives, giving away free systems,
templates, GPT prompts. Monetizing
attention isn't about going viral. It's
about building conversion infrastructure
that allows you to actually go and
monetize the eyeballs that you have. So
move past this obsession over virality
and focus on the infrastructure. If you
want this entire funnel, want to go and
implement it in your business today, you
should go check it out via the link in
the description. Shift number three, the
content GPS system. If you don't master
distribution across platforms, you're
going to be left in the dust. That's why
winners will have a content GPS system.
So the content waterfall system is how I
go and take one piece of content and
turn it into 20 other strategic pieces
of content. And so the key thing is you
want to make sure you get the maximum
amount of bang for your buck by actually
making sure that that one YouTube video
becomes things like multiple LinkedIn
posts, carousels for LinkedIn. It
becomes Instagram posts, things like
Instagram reels, YouTube shorts, and Tik
Tok videos. So what I'm going to go
break down is one of the original videos
on my channel. This was all about my
story and how I got started. And so, as
you can see here, I was able to go and
take some of the core aspects of this
video and go and synthesize it in a
number of different exposts. Each one of
these getting around 200,000 views. In
this case, one of them got over 1.9
million. So, it's crazy because the cut
down version of that long- form video
actually got more views than the video
itself. Now, over here on LinkedIn, same
deal. You can see that I'm breaking down
my story for that platform as well. And
the post got over a million views as
well. And as we go to Instagram, I took
it and put it into different carousels
that I thought would be valuable. And
these also went and blew [music] up. And
so what ends up happening is when you go
and you distribute this, right, you're
just doing [music] smart repurposing of
your content, allowing the distributed
content often times to get more views
combined than the actual original video
itself. thereby again maximizing your
output while minimizing the amount of
energy you have to put into creation.
Now in addition to that you can see here
on Instagram what we typically do is
we'll [music] go and take the general
concept and turn it into an eight slide
carousel and the last slide there will
drive people to go and DM me where they
get into a many chat funnel and become
part of our email list. And so all of
this infrastructure, right, allows me to
go and stay on top of things, right, and
not just build some media company that's
based on views, but is really based on
systems and conversion, which allows me
to build a valuable media property that
feeds my business, it feeds my
lifestyle, and makes this sustainable
long term. Shift number four, your taste
is what cuts through the noise. Now,
when it comes to taste, right, it's
really that feeling, [music] that
emotion, that general sense that you
evoke amongst the viewer of your
content. And while a lot of people just
ship a bunch of garbage, right? You have
the opportunity to go and really elevate
the quality of everything you put out
there, right? Make art, not content.
Don't just ship stuff that is kind of
50% the way there. Go and actually go
the distance, go the extra mile to make
stuff that people develop some sort of
emotional resonance with. Okay? And so,
you know, when I go and think about
where I'm trying to go with founder OS,
right, for me, it's [music] almost
creating this super aspirational founder
brand. What Apple did for creatives in
the '7s, what Nike's done for athletes
in the 80s is what we're trying to do
for [music] founders in the 2020s. One
way that you can go and think about
creating your own tastes brand is to
come and create [music] your brand
principles. And so, one of my brand
principles is obsessive craftsmanship.
[music]
and showing the amount of detail that
goes into developing a team of A
players, creating org charts that create
a seamless operation within your company
and how to actually go and delegate to
people so you can go and elevate
yourself within your company. You know,
it's having that aesthetic artist touch.
[music] I think that too much of content
is just getting lost in this soup of
sameness. [music] everyone's doing the
same thing as everyone else and you have
an opportunity to actually go and make
things different [music] because there
are two things to think about, right?
Are you trying to go and create signal
or noise? You know, noise is that kind
of content that just goes viral but that
no one's talking about a week from now.
[music] Taste is all about signal,
right? And signal is when you create
something that stands the test of time.
And so when you're actually looking to
go and implement better taste inside of
your own brand, the key thing here is
that the best creators are the best
curators. [music] And you got to make
sure that you're actually curating your
content by being insanely intentional.
You know, [music] stop scrolling and
start using that time to actually save
content that you see that you really
enjoy into different collections on
Instagram or into different exbookmarks,
LinkedIn saves, Pinterest boards,
[music]
into my mind. It doesn't matter the tool
you use. The key is that you stop
consuming and you [music] start
curating. This is often times the first
step to then getting the inspiration you
need to create your brand. You know, I
think that every brand should start as a
Pinterest board. [music] Here's the
Pinterest board that really defines the
energy that we have here at Founder OS.
You can [music] see that it's filled of
adventure, freedom, deep systems and
frameworks, all the while having
inspiring, sharp, quick copy that's
bold, that really evokes emotion, and
that encourages you to just go do the
damn thing. It's this Pinterest board
that really inspired the beauty across
the entire Founder OS brand. And [music]
I think that if you don't have a mood
board for your brand, well, this is your
cue. Probably time to go get after it.
Shift number five, brand identity.
You're not just building a brand, you're
building who you are in the mind of
others. Let me get into a bit of the
identity behind my own personal brand.
So, first off, the core feeling that
we're looking to evoke in people is this
feeling of freedom, right? I'm [music]
all about going and achieving time
freedom, location freedom, and financial
freedom. And it's the systems that I
often times share that have helped me
get there over the last 15 years.
[music] And so, for me, it's this kind
of Zen CEO vibe, right? being able to
travel the world, live a life by design,
go and help founders that I genuinely
love to help. On the aspirational side,
over the next decade, we have massive
ambitions with this founder freedom
movement. You know, we're looking to go
and buy a retreat center and the
Doommites, this [music] epic place
nested in Lagardenna, which is all going
to go and host amazing founders from all
over the world, allow them to snowboard
together in the winter and do some
downhill mountain biking and epic hiking
through crazy refugeios all through the
mountain range in the summer. You know,
I want to go and bring this YouTube
channel and eventually get our own
Anthony Bourdain parts unknown meets
entrepreneurship vibe onto Netflix and
bring this from subscribers to
streaming. [music]
And then over the next 7 years, I'm
looking to publish seven best-selling
books. And my hope here is to really
push the envelope and [music] really
achieve my mission of really unlocking
my full creative potential and along the
way inspiring you to do the same. You
know, the difference between me and most
people out there is that, you know, I
actually use these systems [music]
daily. You know, I'm actually in the
trenches building And I've helped
10,000 other plus founders go and build
their businesses. And so, what I like to
do is just, you know, be this role model
for people on my channel going and
building different systems. And as I
discover new breakthroughs, I go and
share them with you here for free. For
me, one of the big things that I think
encapsulates our brand is being insanely
simple and insanely generous. Whether
it's via different decks we create,
systems we have, or the things that you
can even go and find in the description
of this video. And so, [music] you want
to go and take a look at, you know, what
is your brand stand for? What is the
hill that you're willing to die on? The
thing that, you know, you think that you
were put on this earth to do? And why
not just go and bet on that? And so, I'd
encourage you to go do that thing. Go
build that thing that scares you, right?
And it's quite possibly that that's the
exact thing that's going to help go and
inspire a movement around what you're
building. Shift number six is get
offline to grow online. The most
underestimated leverage of all is
actually just stepping away. Peace
offline is presence online. There are a
couple core systems that I have in my
life that ensure that I get some offline
time that really just goes and fuels my
online presence. Now, one of those is
called the soul [music] trip. Every six
weeks, I take a spontaneous trip with a
group of friends, going somewhere epic,
and crossing something off of my bucket
list. It's these trips that give me the
inspiration, the creativity that I need
to go and fuel this amazing creative
brand that we have here at Founder OS
and around my personal brand. Nature is
the greatest [music] mentor. Another
system that I have is something that I
learned from Julia Cameron and it's
called an artist date. you know, taking
those couple moments in a week to go and
just do something a little bit different
to kind of feed the inner child in you.
It could be going to a pottery class,
doing [music] a painting class, maybe
it's, you know, going and doing a bit of
a nature walk without your phone. Rick
Rubin in his book, The Creative Act,
goes and relates a lot of core aspects
of creativity to nature, you know,
whether it's the different flow you feel
when you're in a creative flow to that
of like a river and the water flowing
down it, [music] you know, or it's often
times, you know, the stillness that you
have when you've released something that
you really feel proud about and you
[music] can just sit there feel proud.
Very much how like a tree feels rooted,
right? The reality is is that when you
get outside, you get offline, you get
into nature, you're able to allow
yourself to get inspired by things that
are not online, right? The issue is if
you're always online, what ends up
happening is you follow five creators,
you're looking at 10 Instagram accounts,
there's another million people looking
at those things. And so [music] the
stuff that's inspiring you to create is
the same stuff that's inspiring a
million other people's to create it. And
it just contributes to this sea of sness
[music] online. Meanwhile, there's those
people that escape to Joshua Tree, go
for a hike in Sequoia, go and escape to
Yusede, go on a road trip for five days
with friends [music] and get inspired by
different things. You know, if you're
looking to go and build your own founder
brand, become more anti-fragile for the
next 10 years, you should go and check
out Founder OS via the link in
description. Thanks for watching this
video, you can go and check out this
video and don't forget to hit like
[music] and subscribe. My job.