If you want to sell without sounding
salesy, here's what you need to do.
Where most people go and screw this up
is that they go and have some sort of
call to action that just jolts people
out of the story. The thing that you
really want to focus on is making sure
that the call to action is tightly
coupled with the story itself. A good
CTA is inevitable. It's a natural next
step. The story opens up a loop and then
the lead magnet closes it. An example is
if I told you about being stuck at 22
working 13-hour days and then said, "If
this feels like what you're going
through, go and grab this guide [music]
so you can systematically remove
yourself from operations." You see,
that's connected, right? Not random.
Where I see a lot of people screw up is
they think that they're just done at
telling the story. The good news here is
that as they go and download that lead
magnet as an example, you're going to go
and you'll be able to collect that
email. And as you probably know from
watching this channel, email is the most
powerful way you can sell to people. In
any business, it's typically your email
list that is your most valuable asset.
So, if you want the email, make sure
that you have lead magnets that are
tightly coupled to your story. This is
how you create stories that convert.