All right. In every company, you've got
stragglers
versus Avengers, right? B players versus
the A players.
Straggler is that person
that's just coasting, you know, leaching
off the rest of the company.
A players are the ones leading the way,
innovating, that all-in mentality,
always pushing the needle.
So,
shout out to all those A players.
You're really
moving the needle, making [\h__\h] happen.
You know you have an A player
when you have someone you can rely on,
someone
that's got your back,
someone that's always willing to go the
distance,
the extra mile, and genuinely just
cares, right? Cuz care is the ultimate
competitive advantage. So, to you
stragglers, get out of here.
All right?
And to the Avengers,
salute you.