Most people have no idea how Elon Musk
actually thinks. [music] They see the
chaos, the headlines, the personality,
but they never see the operating
mechanisms underneath it all. Mechanisms
that allow him to do [music] things that
most normal founders couldn't even
survive, let alone execute at a global
scale. Today, I'm going to reveal the
five operating mechanisms that Elon Musk
deploys [music] across every company he
operates. And most importantly, the
versions of these mechanisms that you
can use [music] without it destroying
your life, your team, or your sanity. If
you've ever wondered how one human
builds rockets, [music] cars, AI labs,
and brain interfaces all while melting
down on Twitter, well, here's the real
[music] answer. Before we dive in, I've
got something for you. It's called the
algorithm deletion exercise, and you can
go and find it via the first link
[music] in the description. I've gone
and synthesized every one of the five
steps that we go over here in this
video, so you can go and apply it to
your team, your funnel, your business,
[music] your life to go and radically
simplify things just like Elon does. So,
go and get that. be a link in the
description and follow along. Mechanism
one, maniacal sense of urgency. Urgency
isn't about working faster. It's about
compressing the feedback loop between
problem discovery and solution
generation. After reading the Elon Musk
book by Walter Isacson, it struck
[music] me that one of the core
operating principles that Elon has
across every one of his companies is
[music] that they operate with a
maniacal sense of urgency. Now, let me
give you an example here. Let's rewind
to 27 2018. Tesla. It's in the Fremont
factory. [music] We called this era of
Elon production hell. Now, he was going
and pushing to get the factory [music]
to get to 5,000 cars per month of
output. And they were running into some
serious problems. No one really had the
clear answer. And so, [music] what did
he do? Well, he operated with a maniacal
sense of urgency. And the number one way
that he knew to kind of go and compress
that feedback [music] loop was to fly
directly to where the bottleneck was and
go and camp out until the problem was
fixed. Now, where most founders or CEOs
[music] would get a manager to tell the
manager to tell the manager to then get
the problem solved, [music] Elon went
directly to the source. You know, he
went and camped out on the literal
factory [music] floor. Bloomberg
reported that he was sleeping under his
desk for a month until this problem was
fixed, working directly with the
individual engineer on the [music]
factory floor that was in charge of this
specific bottleneck. Sure enough, it was
fixed. [music] And this story really
illustrates the power of really
attacking a bottleneck with everything
you've got [music] and really operating
with this maniacal sense of urgency. I
think too often as founders, we let
things slide. [music] You know, we take
timelines as, you know, that'll take a
few months or this may take a couple
weeks and we [music] just accept that as
maybe the way it's got to be. But with
Elon, you can see time and time again,
he doesn't accept [music] the timelines
he's given. He's constantly going and
seeing how he can compress time.
Traditional companies go from problem to
[music] meeting to a committee to then
finally deciding and then testing over 3
weeks and then after those tests are
[music] done probably just coming back
to another series of meetings and other
committees. Elon shows that he [music]
does anything but that with Elon it's
let's talk about the problem. Let's
decide. Let's test it. And that whole
process may just last 3 hours. [music]
So what we're seeing here is like a 100x
compression cycle, right? and you
multiply that over the next hundred
[music] or a thousand decisions, you're
literally moving thousands of times
faster than anyone else in your niche.
So, here's what I [music] want you to
do. I want you to take one project, one
decision you've been sitting on and
compress its timeline by 80%. [music]
So, to be clear here, I'm not asking you
to go and sleep under your office desk,
right? [music] But what I am asking you
to do is to challenge yourself as to how
can you have more decision [music]
velocity. Often times as high
performers, we want to wait until we
have all of the data to [music] make a
decision. Often times what's required is
to make decisions with just 80% of the
data that you have and take pride in
just making [music] the call. Because
where one person may take 2 weeks to
make one decision, you could make 100
decisions in [music] 2 weeks. Yeah,
you're going to make some mistakes, but
at least overall net you're moving a lot
faster [music] and compressing
timelines. Keep in mind that most
decisions are two-way doors. you know,
you make the wrong decision, no worries.
Just iterate [music] and pivot, right?
It's not the end of the world. And it's
also not worth sitting on for weeks.
Learn to start making decisions [music]
with an incomplete set of data. Look at
the areas where you can start going and
attacking the [music] bottleneck.
Typically, there's one core area that's
holding up the entire assembly line of
your company. [music]
Identify the owner of that area and
deeply understand what is really the
problem [music] here. Once you
understand the root cause of that
problem, go and attack it with full
force and the urgency of Elon. So now
let's move on to the algorithm that Elon
uses to [music] strip away everything
unnecessary. Mechanism two, the
algorithm. Elon Musk has an algorithm
that he applies to [music] everything,
whether it's brain interfaces, rockets,
or cars, or even his own org chart. It's
ruthless, it's simple, and it's the
[music] reason that SpaceX can build
rockets for a fraction of NASA's cost.
Here's how it works. What I'm about to
share with you is something that
probably can save you thousands of
hours. So, there [music] was a period
early on in Tesla where Elon was
obsessed with automation. This went well
for a little bit, but then they started
[music] running into some production
problems. And what Elon realized is that
he jumped to automate things way too
fast. And he ended up sending out an
email to all the staff saying that he
had screwed up this decision. And sure
enough, one day he came into the Tesla
factory with a bottle of orange spray
paint and started spray painting every
single robot on the floor that they'd
have to go and remove. This painful
process taught Elon the importance of
deleting and simplifying before you
automate. And so sure enough, as he
started going and building SpaceX, he
was able to go and take these lessons to
improve the rocket process to produce
rockets that were far cheaper [music]
than NASA's. Now, the story of Elon
actually building rockets goes back to
early 2000s of him actually going and
flying to the Soviet Union to go and
look at purchasing rockets from the
Russians. You know, as they went and
started quoting him on different prices,
he started realizing, you [music] know,
why does it cost this much? You know,
why are we even doing this? And this is
what then caused him to start building
his own rockets at SpaceX. Now along the
way there's been a constant push inside
[music] of these companies for you know
different features different
requirements different things added to
things and before you know Elon [music]
goes and adds anything he goes why do we
even need this and who is even
suggesting [music] this he can go and
look at any part across any rocket any
car [music] and go down to who actually
suggested this requirement so that
everyone is accountable for what they're
[music] adding. That way, the default in
the company is not just to add things
and think that you can just get away
[music] with it, you know, and every
single piece of what they're building.
They're always trying to go and delete
first, simplify things, and then get
things down to the bare necessities.
Because truthfully, you can't just have
a bunch of [\h__\h] slapped onto [music] a
rocket and think you're going to get
that thing into orbit. The algorithm is
Elon's operating system. It helps him
think through every problem, and it's
deceptively [music] simple. Let me break
down all five steps because this will
change how you build. Step one, question
every requirement. Now, the key thing
that Elon shows here is that he asks who
is suggesting this requirement and then
making sure that he understands the root
reason as to why they are adding this
given thing because he knows that every
single thing you add just adds [music]
more complexity later. Step two, delete
parts of the process. We all know,
right, there's no sense hiring someone
for a role that you don't even need in
the first place. There's no sense
automating a task that you shouldn't
even be doing in the first place.
>> [music]
>> You know, I know in my own career, I've
learned this the hard way. When I was
25, building Herb, I went on a hiring
spree, hiring a bunch of roles that
later on I learned I didn't even need
these folks. And then I had to make the
tough decision of letting a bunch of
folks go because [music] I had chosen to
scale up a department that really wasn't
even required for us to go and achieve
the vision we wanted. You know, really
making sure that you delete before
[music] you automate is super key. Step
three, simplify what remains. you know,
[music] whether it's Elon or it's Steve
Jobs and his insanely simple values,
whether it's simplifying brain
interfaces, [music] it's making sure
that Tesla and the parts are as simple
as possible so they're not
overengineering things. The core [music]
thing here is that simplicity is key.
Step four then is to accelerate [music]
cycle time. Elon Concy asked himself,
how fast can we test this? When you're
going and building something, right,
again, it's that learning agility that
will set you apart. [music] Where your
competitor maybe takes six months to
ship something and then another six
months to iterate, if you're able to go
and compress those cycle [music] times
to days, right, you can imagine how much
further you'll be than the competitor in
a year or even 5 years. [music] Speed is
your competitive advantage, especially
as a small company. Step five is to
automate last. only move to automation
when you've first gone and you've
deleted things. You've got core owners
of the pieces that have been added.
You've simplified things as much as
possible. Then and only then are you
ready to automate. And here's why this
matters so much. Most companies are
drowning in inherited complexity.
Inherited complexity is the silent
[music] killer. It's essentially all
those processes, tasks, and people that
you just inherit and a lot of people
just accept as the [music] way things
are. And that's dangerous. We've all
been there, right? you go and you ask
someone on your team, you know, why are
we doing it this way? And [music] they
say, oh, well, that's how I was brought
on and that's what I was trained on or,
you know, this is how we've always done
it. And that sort of mentality is a
[music] disease. Delete that [\h__\h]
Simplify things and question every
requirement. [music] So, here's your
exercise. Pick one area of your
business. Could be your content
workflow, your funnel, your team,
[music] and then run the algorithm
through it. If you haven't downloaded
the algorithm deletion exercise yet, go
and [music] do that. I've literally
synthesized a checklist and exercise
that you can take to go and run Elon's
algorithm through core aspects of your
company and implement [music] this today
to radically simplify your business and
your life. Now, let's talk about who
Elon lets inside his company because
this is where things get a little bit
controversial. If you can't name the
human behind a feature behind something
that's been added to your company, well,
you've just added a bunch of [\h__\h]
right? And you should delete that stuff
fast. The action item for you is to make
sure that people are actually putting
their name behind things. They're
willing to die on the mountain of the
thing that they're telling you that you
should go and do. You know, the last
thing you want is a bunch of passive
people, a bunch of idea guys going and
just adding more [\h__\h] to your company
and before you know it, you're sitting
on just a mountain of complexity. And
the key thing is to question things and
make people take extreme ownership over
the things that they're telling you they
want to add to your business. Mechanism
three, build unreasonable teams. Elon
doesn't just hire for culture fit. He
hires for aligned maniacs that are
obsessed around getting to the mission.
And this serves as the filter by which
he hires every single person on his
team. November 2022, Elon just bought
Twitter. He sends an email to the entire
team. And it's one of the most
controversial moves I've ever seen. So,
he sends out an email to the entire
company called Fork in the Road.
basically saying that on a go forward
basis they were going to operate in a
hardcore mode that the company would
have to be completely transformed
because the old way of doing things
basically wasn't going to cut it
anymore. He [music] gave them a link in
that email to click it and then
subscribe to this new form of culture or
just opt in to receiving a severance.
This is just an example of the kind of
culture that Elon Musk is focused on
creating. And by no means am I saying
that you need to have some ultra
hardcore company culture. Each culture
is different just like the personalities
of humans. But the real thing that's
important is that you have a culture
that is aligned, right? And that you
don't have detractors. The core thing
that Elon's obsessed with is that he
wants these maniacs. He wants these
people that want to be hardcore. Now,
I'm not saying you should copy that
email, but there's a deeper principle
going on here around align maniacs. You
either get people to subscribe to your
culture or you remove [music] them.
Because the reality is building a
company is [\h__\h] hard. And building a
company with a bunch of people with
their own agendas is [music] even
harder. If you're building a company, be
clear on what are your values. You know,
what are those uniting principles that
determine the kind of people that you
want on the ship and the people that
you're going to say no to? And make sure
that every single person on your team
embodies that. [music] Be intentional
about that culture setting and make sure
everyone is on board. To be clear, this
isn't about abuse, although many people
would say otherwise. What he's really
looking for here is people that are
missionobsessed, [music]
you know, and I can understand it,
right? The guy is trying to send people
to Mars. [music] And this level of, you
know, a mission, this level of
complexity in terms of what they're
trying to do requires [music]
a different kind of human and a
different kind of culture. What he needs
is people that [music] are obsessed with
getting there because anything less than
that ain't going to cut it. And here's
the uncomfortable truth that most
founders don't want to hear. Great
companies are built by unreasonable
people doing unreasonable things.
Reasonable people optimize for
consensus. Unreasonable people optimize
for [music] breakthroughs. And you can't
have both. Steve Jobs was unreasonable
with his design details. Elon Musk is
unreasonable in his deletion of things.
Bezos was unreasonable with the level at
which he was [music] obsessed around
customers. Success leaves clues. Easy
with a lot of these guys to be a [music]
spectator, right? to look at what
they're doing and think, you know,
that's abuse or that's crazy or I would
never do that. And that's probably the
truth. You would never do that, right?
[music] Which is why you're at where
you're at and these guys are at where
they're at because they defy all odds.
Mechanism number four, iterate at the
speed of thought. SpaceX treats every
single launch like a data pipeline. They
optimize for learning velocity, not
perfection. So, they're able to get more
done in six months than others get done
in five years. [music] You know, a big
difference when Elon was building SpaceX
versus NASA was this idea that at
SpaceX, they allowed rockets [music] to
fail. You know, up until this point,
NASA had constantly said that we do not
allow rockets to blow up. You know,
after the 80s when the Challenger blew
up and there was, you know, I [music]
think six astronauts all killed on
board, they were super aggressive with
just no [music] rockets blowing up. But
with Elon, his whole principle was we
want to learn fast, right? if that means
along the way we blow up some [music]
rockets. That's just part of the price
to make humans a multilanetary species.
And from changing this single [music]
rule, it allowed the overall culture to
iterate a ton faster because they didn't
have to worry that, hey, if a rocket
blows up, everything's [music] over.
Instead, it's that's just kind of the
cost of this insane mission that we have
ahead of us. April 20th, 2023, the
biggest rocket launch in human history.
Starship is 400 ft tall. [music] It's
launch day. 3 minutes into going and
launching this rocket, it blows up. A
massive fireball. [music]
And that's not it. The media is
instantly reporting this as a disaster,
a massive failure. But what does Elon
do? 3 minutes [music] later, he goes and
tweets out, "Congrats SpaceX team on a
successful test [music] launch. We'll
learn from this and we'll go and launch
in the next 3 months." Now, this is just
the mindset of Elon at work, [music]
right? Iterate at the speed of thought.
You blew up a rocket. Good. You're going
to learn from where the mistake [music]
was. You're going to iterate and you're
going to improve for next time. Most
companies would have shut down for 2
years to investigate. Elon went and
launched his next rocket 7 months later.
[music] This is the power of going and
iterating fast. Iteration beats
perfectionism every single [music] time.
NASA's approach is to spend 5 years
planning and over 20 billion of cost for
about [music] 10 iterative cycles.
Elon's approach is spend $3 million with
SpaceX, go and compress time into just a
couple years, and spend a fraction of
the price, [music] only $3 billion. Who
wins? Well, SpaceX. And the core thing
here is that they're not [music] afraid
to fail because every failure is a data
point. Every data point is intelligence.
[music]
And every piece of intelligence goes and
is driven back into iteration, which
allows you to go and iterate on the
product 10 times faster than competitors
like Nassau. When you optimize for
perfection, you're optimizing for
comfort. When you optimize for
iteration, you're optimizing for truth.
So, the lesson here is to shift [music]
messy, right? Get things out there,
learn fast, and iterate. My thinking was
always, I'm just shipping a product to
learn the product that I'm supposed to
[music] build. It's from this level of
just learning, iterating, and not being
scared to fail that I've been able to go
and outpace the competitors in my space
because I'm [music] just focused on
learning. Mechanism five, engineer for
scale beyond yourself. Elon doesn't run
six companies. He designs operating
systems with amazing people in it. And
he's playing long-term games with the
lieutenants structured inside of these
businesses. People love to point out how
Elon runs six companies all at once.
It's Tesla, SpaceX, the Boring Company,
Neurolink, but the truth is in each of
these companies, he has lieutenants,
right? The kind of people that he wants
to play long-term games with, right? An
example of this is inside of SpaceX. He
has someone named Gwen Shotwell in place
who he's [music] worked with since 2003.
We're talking 23 years of history with
someone. [music] She started off as an
engineer is now COO of the company and
is his lieutenant there that he can
trust with all of the core decisions so
he can focus on the stuff he loves to do
more of the engineering and design side
of it. Now you can imagine [music] right
23 years of history with someone right
these days you know people are lucky
that if you're working with them for 8
months right people are so transitory
and they're hiring someone that they
think can last 6 months and then they're
gone and you see that there's these
revolving doors of talent [music] in so
many companies but imagine you know
working with people and the average
duration being like 10 15 years imagine
the chemistry that goes on on a team
like that imagine the level of just
almost a mindmeld across a team and
make, you know, decisions [music] almost
instantaneously with the whole
enterprise and team in mind. There's an
illusion that Elon's just running all of
this. Now, [music] yes, he's super
involved, but here's the pattern you
need to understand. Great founders don't
centralize power. They distribute
effectively to other weapons on their
team. So, how does Elon actually
allocate his time across these six
companies? He uses a strategy called
5minute time blocking. So, this sounds
insane, right? But Elon schedules his
entire days in 5minute blocks. Monday,
Tuesday is for SpaceX for things like
rocket reviews. Wednesday, Thursday is
for Tesla, their production and design
reviews. [music] And then Friday is for
all the rest of his companies. He is
ruthless with his calendar. And it's
from this ruthless approach to how he's
allocating his time that he's able to
squeeze [music] so much out of just one
hour, likely getting more done in 1 hour
than most people get done in [music] one
week. Now, I'm not saying you need to go
and allocate your day in 5 minute time
blocks. What [music] I am saying is you
need to know what only you can do and
then delegate everything else. So here's
what happens next. Step one is to go and
download the algorithm [music] deletion
exercise in the link in the description.
From there you're going to go and
analyze your company, see the [music]
parts you need to delete, automate, and
simplify. And then go to step two, which
is to hop on a call with my team. We'd
love to learn the system that's [music]
currently keeping you stuck and help you
go and scale to the next level. Here's
the hard truth. If your business needs
you to operate, you don't have a
business. You have a job. And at some
point, you need to decide, are you
building a company or are you building a
prison? And look, if you're sitting here
thinking, you know, Matt, I get it. I
need systems. I need help, but I don't
know where to start. Well, this is
exactly why I built Founder OS. We help
founders that are established doing 30k
to 500k a month go and install the right
infrastructure in their company go and
make sure they have the right operating
system amongst their team [music] and
help them source amazing talent so that
over time they can remove themselves
from more of the operations work on the
business not in it and have a business
that runs itself. If this is interesting
to you want to work with me onetoone and
directly with my seuite should go check
out founder west [music] via link in the
description. If you like this video, you
would love this next video on what I
learned from Steve Jobs. Go and check
that out. Be sure to like and subscribe
and let's win together.