The highest performing CEOs I know work
fewer hours than you and they're getting
10 times more done. Now, I know that
sounds backwards. You've probably been
told that the harder you grind, the
further you get. [music] That more hours
equals more output. That the founder who
answers Slack at midnight [music] is the
founder who wins. But, that's all wrong
and I'm going to prove it to you right
now. I built [music] three companies
from the ground up. I've coached
thousands of founders, people doing
anywhere from $50,000 a month
>> [music]
>> to $3 million a month. And for years I
was right there with you, right? 14-hour
days, feeling productive, but getting
almost nothing done that actually
mattered. What I figured out and what
I'm going to share with you today are
five habits that helped me stop being
the bottleneck and take back my time and
focus on work I actually love doing,
stuff that [music] fires me up. By the
end of this video, you're going to have
a completely different relationship with
your calendar, a new way of thinking
about your team, and a system that top
CEOs use to do less and scale faster
because of it. And I put together a
quick CEO [music] time leverage audit
you can use to apply in your own
business after watching this video to
locate where you may be the bottleneck.
Let's [music] get into it. Habit one,
time multipliers. Here's the thing that
nobody tells you about hiring.
>> [music]
>> Most founders hire as a panic button.
They get overwhelmed, they bring someone
on, and they feel better for about two
weeks. [music] And then they realize
that they've created more overhead, more
culture risk, and honestly just more
management work than before. I call this
the founder prison
>> [music]
>> and freedom requires a completely
different way of thinking about your
team. It was about 14 years ago into
building my first company where I
remember sitting at my desk on a Sunday
>> [music]
>> and feeling completely underwater. I had
a team, I had revenue coming in. By
every outside measure, things were going
well. But, I was more stressed out
[music] than ever in my life. More in
the weeds, more reactive, and I couldn't
[music] figure out why. And then it hit
me. I had been hiring to relieve
pressure instead of hiring to create
leverage. [music]
I'd bring someone on whenever I felt
like I was drowning and instead of
getting lighter, I just felt like I got
more to manage, more context [music] to
share, more questions to answer, more
culture to protect. The moment I started
really focusing on hiring for ROI,
everything changed. So, [music] every
founder I've coached who makes this
shift says the same thing. It's like
someone lifts a weight off their
shoulders that they didn't even know
that they were carrying. The business
[music] feels lighter, the decisions
feel cleaner, and for the first time you
start to feel like the owner of your
business instead of some employee
[music]
inside of it. That's a shift and here's
how you can actually make it. Every
person you bring on to your team should
[music] hit one specific number. If they
don't hit it, you're not ready to hire.
And that number again is return on
investment. [music]
And so, to make this concrete, you know,
you really need to focus on well, what
is that one thing they need to hit? Say
you go and you bring on a social media
manager at $5,000 a month. They save you
30 hours a week in content creation and
distribution, that's 120 hours a month
returned [music] back to you. Now, think
about what your time is actually worth
as a CEO. Even if your effective hourly
rate is $2,000 an hour, the revenue
potential from those 120 [music]
reclaimed hours is significant. We're
talking $240,000.
And so, when you stack [music]
enough high ROI hires together and pair
them then with the right systems, that's
when things really start to compound.
[music]
I have a founder who I've been helping
for the last 3 years and he's automated
95% of his business by building the
right team and applying this delegation
framework properly. [music]
Now, he spends entire summers with his
family, not checking Slack at dinner,
[music] not stepping out for meetings. I
mean, like actually present. Here's the
deeper layer though. That math only
holds up if you hire the right person.
One A player is worth 20 B players. A
players are going to return leverage, B
players just accumulate debt. Before
your next hire, run the delegation math.
Trust me,
>> [music]
>> you will save yourself so much time and
headaches. Time saved per month
multiplied by your hourly rate. Subtract
the annual hire cost. If the ROI isn't
at least 5x, restructure that role or
just hold off entirely. And once you're
ready to hire, rank your candidates
based [music] on ROI. Make the highest
ROI hires first. You know, most founders
can properly recruit, onboard, and
integrate about two people per month
without damaging their culture. But,
here's the thing. The best founders
don't stop at hiring. That's where habit
two comes in and this one genuinely
changed how I think about team building.
Habit two, automation first. Before you
hire the next person to solve a problem,
there's a question you have to ask.
>> [music]
>> Can this be automated? I was talking to
Oren Hoffman a few years ago and he
completely rewired how I think about
teams when he said something that
stopped me cold and that I haven't been
able to shake out of my mind since. He
said, "Matt, hiring is a mark of
failure."
>> [music]
>> I was like, "Failure? Really? I thought,
you know, hiring meant you were growing
and, you know, it's great that you're
adding to your team." His point was
this, [music] right? If you're creating
a new role, it means you failed to
automate it first. You know, we're at an
extraordinary inflection [music] point
right now. AI tools can handle
engineering tasks, content production,
customer service workflows, research,
scheduling, distribution, and virtually
every piece of grunt work in your
business.
>> [music]
>> Using Claude alone has helped me produce
content and frameworks that would have
taken an agency [music] weeks to
generate. No, the tools are there today.
Most founders just haven't reorganized
their thinking around [music] them yet.
What Elon Musk does better than almost
any other operator is his four-step
algorithm for building companies
>> [music]
>> and I think every founder should have
this in their head. Step one, you're
going to find the limiting constraint in
the operation. Step two is to eliminate
everything unnecessary around [music]
it. Step three is to simplify what
remains down to its most essential form.
Step four is to automate what you can.
Only after all four steps would you ever
go and consider making that next new
hire. If your team's default answer to
every problem is, "We should go and hire
someone," there's a cultural sign that
they aren't pushing hard enough on
simplicity, automation first, and taking
extreme ownership over problems. Run
through four questions, [music] okay, in
this exact order to help go and level up
your company. One, what exactly needs to
happen here? Two, [music] does it all
actually need to happen at all? Three,
can AI or a system or automation handle
[music] it? Four, can an existing team
member then absorb it? Only after
working through all four should a hire
even be on the table. And build this
expectation [music] inside your team.
Can we automate this always comes before
should we hire for this. Now, even with
the right team and the right systems,
there's one thing you still have to
perfect and this is where most founders
lose. Habit three, founder flow. Why do
some founders accomplish more in two
hours than others do in an entire week?
It comes down to this one habit and it
took me way too long to figure out. 17
years back, I had a pattern that was
slowly destroying my momentum. I'd wake
up, I'd check my phone, look at social
media, fire off some responses, jump on
a morning call. By the time I had three
minutes to actually think, I was already
drained and my mind was scattered. I'd
look at my task list at 7:00 p.m. and
practically nothing had moved at all.
I'd tell myself I'd handle it that
night, but then, you know, 8:00 p.m.
rolls around and you're just absolutely
cooked. And before I know it, it's 9:00
p.m. and the same [music] critical tasks
are just sitting there untouched. I know
you, right? A lot of founders are living
this right now and just calling it a
busy season. But, it's not a busy
season. It's a trap. And financially,
[music]
this is the smartest thing you can
figure out as a founder. Every day you
spend entirely in reactive mode is a day
you didn't build the thing that
compounds. It's a day you didn't write
the framework, you didn't go and rejig
your offer, didn't create the amazing
exceptional content that would have
worked for you while you slept. The cost
is invisible in the moment, but it
stacks up enormously over time. I read
the book Deep Work, maybe you have too,
by Cal Newport. And Newport's argument
is that the most valuable economic
output in today's world comes almost
from distraction-free
cognitively intense [music] work. I call
this founder flow. For a CEO, founder
flow is worth thousands of dollars an
[music] hour. The Slack replies, the
quick questions, the just two seconds of
your time, those requests, that's $5 an
hour work. And most founders are putting
in 12 hours on $5 stuff and then
wondering why the high-leverage stuff
never gets done. Here's what founder
flow actually looks like in practice. I
used my founder flow to write a full
21-day email course and build out an AI
course curriculum and I did it just in
two days. That's work that would take
most teams weeks. That's the difference.
Two days versus two weeks. And the only
variable was protected, uninterrupted
creative time. Block four hours in your
calendar tomorrow morning. Not
afternoon, not whenever it's convenient,
morning. First thing. If you have a
family, school runs, a team pinging you
before 9:00 a.m., well, just go and wake
up a little earlier. Trust [music] me,
it's one of the things, just try it out
for 60 days. Regarding your morning is
just the beginning. The founders who
really break through, they go one layer
deeper. And that's habit [music] four.
And look, if your business brings in six
to seven figures a month or more right
now and the reactive days, the stolen
mornings, the feeling that your calendar
runs you [music] instead of the other
way around and if that hits close to
home, I built something specifically for
that. [music] It's called Founder OS
Velocity, and I want to be clear about
what it is. It's not some course, it's
not a done-for-you agency, it's the
[music] exact operating infrastructure I
use to run a portfolio of high-margin
cash-flowing companies. I've opened it
up to just a small group of serious
founders. Here's what you actually get.
You get weekly strategy sessions
directly with me, access to my full
C-suite, the operators who help me run
everything behind the scenes at my
personal media company, AI tools built
on my systems that execute for you
around the clock, a vetted talent bench
so you can make the right hires fast
without the guesswork, and a tight-knit
community of founders building the same
way that you want to build. If that
sounds like what you need right now, you
can go and apply via the link in the
description. We only take founders who
are a genuine fit, so if you're ready to
stop being the bottleneck, then go and
apply, and someone on my team will get
back to you within just a few hours.
Okay, have it for. This one is about the
single most dangerous word in a
founder's vocabulary. Habit four, the
not-to-do list. This next habit will
feel wrong at first. Saying no to a good
opportunity, I get it, it can feel
terrible. But saying yes to a bad one,
that pain is physical,
>> [music]
>> and that loss is real. As a founder, you
already know you need to train your eyes
for a good opportunity, but what most
founders forget is that you also need to
train your eye for the bad ones. It
makes sense, right? But every
opportunity looks like it could be the
one. All the time, right? You can find
things that all sound [music] useful,
right? I've gone to events though, you
spend six to eight hours in a room with
genuinely interesting people, and then
you just come home and think, I should
have just worked and stayed in, [music]
because I knew what I needed to get
done. The problem is never a lack of new
ideas, it was a lack of executing the
ones that you [music] already have. Gary
Keller put it this way, "What's the one
thing you could do such that by doing
it, everything else becomes easier or
unnecessary?" So here's your action
step. Write down everything on your
plate right now. Every single item, then
ask yourself, [music]
"What is the 4% of this list that's
going to drive me 64% of the actual
impact?" Clear out the rest, set your
default answer to no, and protect
[music] the few things that actually
matter. And if you genuinely don't know
what your highest leverage activity is
yet, well, congratulations, you just
[music] found your first high-leverage
activity to focus on, figuring that out.
So far, everything we've covered has
been about doing less of the wrong
things. This last habit though is going
to flip it. [music] It's about doing
more of the one thing that only you can
do. Habit five, design your ikigai.
Every founder eventually looks up and
realizes they built a business that owns
them instead of the other way around.
The ones who took back control did one
specific thing [music] differently.
About eight years ago, if I'd looked at
a breakdown of my week, most of it was
going towards things that [music] other
people on my team could have done better
than me. Tech builds, funnel setups,
automations, operations. I was busy,
genuinely busy, but on the wrong things.
[music] The moment I finally sat down
and asked, "What are the things that
will actually move the needle?"
everything [music] changed, and I
started to restructure my entire
business. For me, those things are
building communities, [music] you know,
growing distribution through organic
content, designing frameworks that
simplify how founders operate, [music]
and writing. This is my zone of
brilliance. Everything outside [music]
of that, it needs to be delegated,
automated, or eliminated. [music] And
there's a Japanese concept called ikigai
that maps this out exactly. There's four
core [music] questions. What do you
love? What are you genuinely exceptional
at? What does the world need? And what
can you be paid for? The intersection of
those four areas is your ikigai, [music]
or as I call it, your zone of
brilliance. I want you to understand
this. The goal isn't to own a niche, the
goal is to become the niche. Now think
about someone like Tim Ferriss. He
[music] didn't build a brand like as a
productivity expert, he built a brand
around his own curiosity and his
obsessions, right? And he's built an
amazing 20-year [music] career openly
sharing whatever genuinely just
fascinates him, even when it [music]
didn't fit into some category. My own
epiphany came when I started thinking
about myself this similar way, and more
as an investor. [music] I had actually
discovered Carl Icahn in this
documentary Icahn on HBO. Carl Icahn,
this famous investor, at the time owned
about 12% of Apple. He didn't go and
operate inside [music] of his companies,
right? He manages them as this asset
manager. And the moment I started seeing
myself as more of this asset manager, a
portfolio manager, my businesses [music]
and my mindset changed. Look at every
founder who left a real mark. Jobs had
product obsession. [music]
Buffett has capital allocation. Tim
Ferriss has the deconstruction of
mastery. And when you become the niche,
your business stops defining [music]
you, you start defining your business.
Work becomes this creative expression,
growth becomes [music] your life, and
that's what makes it sustainable, that's
what makes it fun. So here's what I want
you to do right now. Write down the
things you do where you lose track of
time, even amid all the daily fires.
Then write down the activities that
genuinely move the needle in your
business. The overlap between those two
lists, that's where your work should
live.
>> [music]
>> Anything outside of that zone, delegate
it, automate it, or eliminate it.
Protect that intersection obsessively.
[music]
I think that this exercise is the
highest returning asset you can build.
Here's the truth. Most founders are
stuck on a treadmill, working harder,
hiring more, and burning out faster,
wondering why the effort isn't showing
up in the numbers. These [music] five
habits are how the top 1% get off that
treadmill entirely. None of this is
complicated, but all of it requires a
decision. [music] If you're serious
about this, don't just watch this video
and move on. Download the CEO Time
Leverage Audit below. It will help you
go and filter your entire week into CEO
work, transferable work, [music] and
un-leveraged work. You'll calculate
exactly how many hours you're
misallocating, and quantify what's
costing [music] you annually. So once
you complete that, go and book a call
with my team. We're going to look at
your CEO gap, identify the structural
constraint, [music]
and show you what it would look like to
redesign your role so you're operating
as a true CEO. You have one shot at
this, one life, one calendar, one
version of the business you're building.
Don't waste it being the bottleneck in
your own story. And if you want to see
how I designed the most beautiful
business ever that follows all of these
rules, watch this next video. [music]
Thanks so much for watching. Welcome to
the Founder Freedom Movement. Be sure to
like and subscribe, and I'll see you in
the next one.