You're wasting 90% of your potential
every month because you're distracted on
way too many things. This is your sign
to go and delete the stuff that is not
your core focus. So, go and get a pen
and paper and go and write down the
three things that are going to have the
most impact in your business. Then go
and write down the seven core metrics
that should be part of your founder
scorecard. I'm talking about the seven
metrics that determine that you're being
successful in those three key areas.
Then I want you to go and think about
the relationships around there that are
serving you and then the people that are
maybe just being energy vampires and
that are sucking the life out of you.
Could be that bad hire that you've
allowed in your company too long that
this is your sign to just cut ties,
right? From there,
stop running the creator playbook, okay?
When you're going and building content
online, you only need one offer,
one audience to go and get the $5
million a year, right? So, keep it
simple, y'all, okay? The last thing here
is as I've gone and scaled my businesses
from $3 million to $5 million to $10
million to $15 million, I'm always
surprised at how much success is a game
of deletion, right? Deleting
distractions, deleting things that are
no longer serving you, and just focusing
on the core thing, right? Focus is the
scarcest resource as a founder. So,
delete your way to the thing that's
going to drive you the most profits and
peace of mind.