What a beautiful time to be alive,
y'all. Why tools beat lead magnets. So
first off, a lot of you guys have lead
magnets and there's these basic PDFs and
[\h__\h] right? And while that's cool and
all, the next stage here are tools.
Reason why tools are cool, they get used
daily and also they lead to this next
aspect, which allows you to grade your
leads, qualify them, and then make sure
that they're interactive. So you're
collecting maximum amounts of data and
then getting these folks warm and
closing them, right? And so
the beautiful thing about a tool is that
it can go and direct the right people to
the right next step. So they're more
interactive and dynamic and smart and
intelligent versus just some static PDF.
And so this is really the future and if
you're looking to go and get started
with tools, think about whether you want
to create some sort of quiz or score or
calculator.
Maybe you got another idea, right? And
you can use tools like Cloud Code,
Lovable to go and spin these things up
super easily, publish them to things
like Vercel or your Webflow website, and
just get experimenting with them, right?
If you've not ever built a tool before,
just go and pick something that'd be
exciting to you, keep it kind of small,
concise, maybe just have like seven
questions that people go and fill out.
Thereby, it's both a tool, but it's also
sort of a qualification layer for you
and can move people quicker down your
funnel and do it in a way that's
memorable for them and useful to you and
overall a win-win. So
tools over lead magnets, folks.