Most people don't struggle with content
because their ideas are bad. They
struggle because their ideas are
invisible. You can have something
genuinely valuable, a great insight, a
strong message, a smart product, and
still feel like nobody cares. Not
because it's wrong, but because it never
gets chosen. That's the real game today.
Attention happens before quality. On
YouTube, that moment is crystal clear.
If nobody clicks, the video doesn't
matter yet. That's why I don't start by
filming or scripting. I start by
designing the packaging, the title, and
the thumbnail. In this video, I'll show
you the exact system we use before we
create anything, including why we
generate hundreds of titles and hundreds
of thumbnails for one idea and how that
step quietly drives most of our
performance. Before we go deeper,
there's a short idea to click exercise
linked below this video that I want you
to come back to once you're done. It
forces you to pressure test one of your
ideas the same way that we do internally
at my company before we create anything.
Now, let's get into it. Let's begin this
process by zooming out a little bit and
actually then going internal into the
business, okay? Because that's kind of
where it all starts. What we have at
Founder OS, right, is we have YouTube
specific ideas and then we've also got
marketing ideas that we're taking from
conversations that we've actually had
with different founders. We're not just
making content here for content's sake.
content's job is to solve the problems
of our dream current [music] customers
and then go and attract more people just
like them. From all of these calls, I'm
going and jotting down notes as to the
key things that I'm seeing people
needing our help with. And I'm putting
all of those ideas down into this Google
sheet. As you can see here, this is
quite a bit of ideas. We're talking like
hundreds, if not thousands by now.
Enough of that. Let's get into the
marketing idea side of things. So, this
is where I'm going and me and the team
are also looking at different outlier
ideas we're seeing out there. Whether
it's stuff that we've put out on
different platforms or it's stuff that
we've noticed on different platforms and
we're jotting down those ideas from the
reference videos that we're seeing. Now,
packaging is title and thumbnail. Your
title is going to establish some
curiosity and your thumbnail then is
going to raise that intrigue and open up
a curiosity gap that people need to
click to fulfill. Your title and
thumbnail make up 80% of the importance
of a high-erforming YouTube video. And
if you're finding that YouTube video
after YouTube video is not hitting the
mark for you, the highest leverage
aspect of your YouTube creation process
is [music] your ideation and
pre-production stage. Because shitty
ideas are going to lead to shitty
performance, no matter how good your
lighting is or how good your camera is.
On the other side of things,
unbelievable ideas, even with a shitty
iPhone camera, will perform [music]
insanely well if the idea is that
[\h__\h] good. So ideas win. [music] Now,
when you have these good ideas, this is
where we want to make sure that we go
into research and validation mode.
YouTube videos, right? We essentially
want to go and combine datadriven titles
and thumbnails that we have seen work
out there. Now, we're not copying this
stuff, but we're just using it as a form
of inspiration essentially for how we're
going to go and structure that idea to
earn that click. Those tools are one of
10 YouTube itself. And then I'm also
going to look at some internal
documentation and systems that we have
at Founder OS and make sure that
anything we do is in line and true to
our actual content strategy. So, let's
jump to one of 10. I think this is one
of the most advanced tools out there for
going and discovering the best packaging
and outlier research. I'm going to give
you an inner glimpse as to how we think
about it. First off, when you land on
one of 10, you're going to go and see
just a bunch of thumbnails. Now, there's
a score you're going to see next, okay,
to each of the different titles within
one of 10. That outlier score
essentially is a number that indicates
how much better performing that given
video was versus that channel's average
video. And so if something got a 24x
outlier, it means that that video
performed 24 times better than that
channel's average video. So you've got
one of 10 giving you outliers. Now, and
the other thing you can also go and do,
search for say some keywords that you
want to go and appear against. For me,
it may be things like personal branding.
I may see certain people that come up
for that search on a consistent basis
and people that I think are doing a
really good job. Now, keep in mind,
right, with one of 10 or any tool,
you're just using this as inspiration.
Data is just one part of the equation. I
think the thing that's going to separate
you though more than anything is your
own creativity, your judgment, and your
taste. And so, as you get going on one
of 10, one of the key things you need to
get right is the filtering. When you're
going in filtering, you can go and add
different levers here so that I think
you can tool this up the best way
possible. What I like to do is make sure
that I'm searching things that have at
least a 3x outlier score. I want to find
ideas that have over 95,000 views. I
don't care about the channel size, but I
typically [music]
am looking at videos that get over 5
minutes, okay, in video duration and
that have been released over the last 6
months cuz inevitably the trends in
YouTube are changing all the time. And
so I want to find the most recent
[music] research from videos that are
performing really well in the last 6
months. The reason why I'm looking at
videos that get at least 95,000 views is
because I want to try and find a way to
take an idea that I know my core
customer is looking for and package it
in a way where hopefully it can get at
least 100,000 views on my channel. And
so from here, what we're doing now is
then setting these filters into motion,
right? So I can go and search personal
brand as an example, apply those
filters, and all of a sudden my
experience inside of one of 10 is
completely transformed. And so in here,
you can actually see, there you go, a
couple ideas from me. Um, these were a
couple videos that blew up over the past
couple years. Now, the thing I like to
do here, right, is start then saving and
bookmarking ideas that inspire me. It
may be something about the word they
used in their title. It may be the way
they structured and designed their
thumbnail. It could be something as
small as just a word like charisma or
premium that just catches my attention
and I'm like, damn, you know what? I
want to try that out maybe for some
ideas I have coming down the pipeline.
Level two here too is that you can do
some channel tracking inside of one of
10. When it comes to channel tracking,
you can go and find creators that you
really like on the platform. And I'd
encourage you too to go and look outside
of your niche. It's all good to be
inspired by people in your niche, but I
think it's way cooler to go and find
inspiration from totally different
spaces and then bring those references
into your space. From there, what I can
do is start bundling these into creators
that I think are on the rise, you know,
people that I think are doing specific
things, right, that I want to double
down on. I'll go and save these and
bucket them into one folder. I can also
go and try to find aesthetic creators,
you know, shout out Life of Rizza and,
you know, a lot of other legends like
that that are making videos that I think
are insanely tasteful and then
leveraging thumbnails as well. And so,
another overlooked tactic is just to use
YouTube. One thing I actually love to do
on the platform is go and save different
playlists for things like titles,
thumbnails, and editing inspiration.
Moving from just a consumer of YouTube
to a curator and begin to save videos
that really inspire you across the
platform because you can use those as
references for how you may want to go
and package your next idea. And so
inside of this, right, I can go into any
given one of these categories, whether
it's podcast or, you know, goals, film
making, you know, design, and I can go
and find different [music]
ideas, right? Different titles,
different thumbs that inspire me and
save those for later. Now, we've got one
of 10, we've got YouTube going. Now,
let's get into one of the most critical
parts here. And this is actually making
it sure that it's married with your
brand and having that internal filter so
that you're not just allowing any idea
through. And so, first off, we want to
ask ourselves, can we position this
video effectively with what we're
actually selling? When you think about
it, you're trying to be better than 99%
of people on YouTube. And so what do you
think you need to do in order to be at
that caliber? You need to do what 99% of
people are unwilling to do or unaware
that even exists. And so what I'm
showing you here is the level of depth
and detail that's going to create the
results you're really after. And so over
here too, and this is something that my
team was like, are we sure we want to
show this? But said, [\h__\h] it. Let's just
give them it. This is some data that
shows our past video performance as it
pertains to the cash collected from
those videos. So, we're analyzing videos
based on the different editors that did
it, the categories, the formats because
the data tells a story. And so, we're
looking at the cash collection for video
as well as the number of applications to
found us each video drove and then using
that to understand which category should
we be doubling down on. What we now want
to do is move on to conceptualization.
Right? So, what we're doing here now is
actually allowing the rubber to hit the
road. We've got all these ideas. We've
now done our research. Now it's time to
actually design some [\h__\h] Let's get
into the first step here. Okay. So, here
you can see um you know where we get all
of our research and ideation. And now
we're going to go group them into
different thumbnails. All of that
research, right? We've got like our
panel thumbnails up here. We've got our
more sort of, you know, solo screen sort
of thumbs with a bit of text on them.
And then we also have some that are more
sort of talking head with some sort of
graph behind. Those are three different
styles. And what we're then going to
want to do is create a bunch of
variations that are on brand for my
brand around the research that we've now
done. We also have a bank of text on
screen. And this shows the variability
of the different kind of text that we've
seen perform well. Now, what we go and
do, right, is take all of these
reference titles and we'll go and create
in some cases like 50 60 titles off of
that. I know this sounds manic, okay?
And it is the truth is though that at
the end of the day a lot of success is
just volume. The other way that we think
about this too internally right is like
for a given video the filming of it may
take 3 hours you know the B-roll behind
it may take another hour the editing of
it may take 6 7 8 hours right so in any
video you may end up spending about 15
hours on actually going from ideiation
to final distribution of it. So, it's
worth spending an extra 30 minutes on
the packaging because again, that's the
highest leverage piece of the whole
puzzle. We've now got our short list.
We'll pick about six titles that we like
the most and we'll rank those 1 through
six and those will be the ones that
we'll get going on when we release the
video. So, on the thumbnail side, right,
same sort of thing. We've got different
thumbnail research. We've got the text
on screen research. And we've got an
entire database of different files and
photos and all of that to work with as
well. All right. So now what we're going
to go and do is create like 50 to 100
thumbnail concepts based on the
references in the research, right? By
combining those validated outliers with
the unique angles that we think we can
bring to the video. Here you can see an
exact example. Okay. And what we did
over here, right, is take each of the
different thumbnail styles that we had
validated, panels, solo, talking head,
you name it. And then now we're going to
go and generate a bunch of different
variations of each of those styles
because this is useful as we start using
YouTube Studio's inherent AB testing
functionality. When we start to go and
put the video out there, what's useful
is to then, you know, you put a bunch of
completely different concepts live into
YouTube. you see which one works and
then you have all of these different
variations of that thumbnail that you
can then test as well. Again, this is
all a game of details. You can now see
the amount of work that goes into this.
It's a lot of it. Again, a key thing
here is to generate different concepts.
So, you can see this video about how to
go and build a plan for 2026. We have,
you know, an overhead shot of me writing
a 2026 plan. We have a panel thumbnail
of different shots of me throughout the
year. We're just playing with different
styles because we want to give YouTube
different variations so that the
platform can signal to us which of these
hundreds of thumbnails are actually
going to work. And the question then
comes next is experimentation, right? So
this is all around the strategic pairing
of titles and thumbnails. So first off,
the way to think about any given YouTube
video is that YouTube's going to put
that out to a small set of your
audience. If it performs really well
there, they put it to a bigger set of
your audience and it keeps on kind of
competing in a larger and larger pool of
people. So, how do we figure out right
if we're attacking each of those? Well,
it's through experimentation. And so,
what we're going to go and do is put all
of these thumbnails now into the title
and thumbnail test inside of YouTube
Studio. Let's go and start over here. We
have our initial thumbnail test, which
essentially is going to test the best
title with three distinct thumbnail
variations. As you can see, right, for
some videos, it could be that you're
just testing the smallest variable over
here for a video that I made called how
to build a plan for 2026 you'll actually
use. This video had gotten around
100,000 views, and that we started to
see that the views per hour started to
taper off a bit, right? So, the velocity
of its growth started to slow down. So,
we figured we'd run another test. In
this case, we just were changing up some
minor words in the thumbnail and ran a
couple title tests and sure enough, a
new winner emerged on the thumbnail. We
noticed that stop wasting your year was
better text and the title of don't set a
goal for 2026 until you watch this
outperformed the original title by
around a spread about 22%. That's what
we're running with now today. Out the
gate was about couple days in this video
looked like it was going nowhere. But we
worked on the packaging. We worked on
the title and suddenly things started
going up into the right. The same thing
here, right, for this video that we made
on disciplined on how to force yourself
to be consistent. Essentially this video
for about 22 days, right, was going
nowhere. It just looked like another
average video on our channel. But we
started working on the thumb, added some
new language to it, and made it this
panel sort of thumbnail format. And sure
enough, it hit a chord. and suddenly the
video once we switched it to how to get
addicted went and started taking off.
There are a couple other things here if
you want to get even more granular. Now,
YouTube really gives you some different
performance indicators, okay? And those
performance indicators include things
like your top 10 ranking. Okay? This is
really a bit of a makeorb breakak metric
really. Essentially, what it shows you
is over your past 10 YouTube videos that
you've published, what's your ranking
amongst those of every new video that
you make. The goal obviously is that it
is a one of 10, meaning it is the best
performer of your last 10 uploads. If
it's a 1 to 10 or 2, we typically just
leave that video, right? Let it ride.
You have a horse right out the gate that
is winning that race. On the other side
of things, you may find that you put out
a video and it's a dog, right? It's at a
9 to 10, 10 to 10. Well, those are the
kind of videos that you're probably
going to want to start aggressively
title and thumbnailing testing to kind
of revive them. It's actually possible
to increase the click-through rate and
performance of a video after it's been
published and looks like [\h__\h] This is
what videos that perform really well
look like, right? the click-through rate
either stays the same or climbs over
time. And so here you can see one video
that got about a 7.2%
click-through rate and boom, got over a
100,000 views within the first month.
You're really looking for that
click-through rate to either be a flat
line or somehow go up over time. Easier
said than done, but with this level of
thoroughess in your packaging process,
it's entirely possible. Basically, if
you're not catering too much to just
your core audience, but you're also
showing up for those casual and new
viewers, that's how you're going to make
sure that line flatlines or increases
over time. Okay? Now, what you don't
want it to look like is like this one
over here, right? Where the
click-through rate is decreasing over
time because when that happens,
YouTube's going to stop surfacing it to
more casual and new viewers, and sure
enough, it starts to die. But this
happens all the time to us still, right?
I've been doing this for a long time.
And while there's a whole science behind
YouTube, this stuff is tricky. You're
not going to win it every time. But by
now, having known these variables, you
can gradually get better and better.
Here's what I want you to take from
this. Stop treating packaging as an
afterthought. Start treating it as the
foundation. Before you create, before
you film, before you launch, ask
yourself, how will this idea earn
attention? Then build from there.
Because in the end, great work doesn't
speak for itself. You have to make
people listen. And the click is where
that starts. If this changes how you
think about attention, the next move
isn't to make more content. It's to
pressure test your ideas before you
create them. Download the idea to click
exercise below. Fill it out for one idea
you're about to go and work on. And if
you want, book a call with my team to
walk through it. That's where we decide
whether the idea is worth scaling or
worth killing. And if you want access to
the other 180 systems that power my
profitable personal brand, then apply to
Founder OS using the link in the
description below to join a community of
serious high-erforming founders
unlocking growth through leverage, not
hustle. I'll see you in the next one.