this is a well-documented phenomenon
where an individual experiences an
exponential amount of personal growth
shortly after a traumatic experience why
it's for the same reason that a lot of
the highest quality people you know
actually had terrible childhoods
traumatic experiences can forge us and
help us become more resilient and more
powerful the good news is you can expose
yourself to trauma intentionally by
doing hard things and reap the same
benefits with exercise meditation cold
bath and just doing hard things we all
need pain if we're going to grow and
sometimes it's got to be self-inflicted