This is the exact content strategy that
makes them beg to buy.
First things first, make art, not
content. Whenever I got started on any
platform, say YouTube or newsletter, I
just focused on making 100 pieces of
content that I was proud of, right?
Focusing on the process, not some
outcome of getting to 100,000
subscribers or a million views. The next
one is
position yourself so sharply a stranger
gets you in 5 seconds. You know, people
know I stand for founder freedom,
controlling the four Ws in life, working
where you want, when you want, on what
you want, with whoever you want, and
that I'm known for helping founders with
systems for organic content and building
their social media machine. So, what is
your positioning, right? The next thing
is stack 11 touch points across four
different contexts, right? What you're
looking to do before any sales call,
right, is make sure
that people see an abundance of your
content leading up to it, so they're
pre-suaded and pre-sold, right? And
they're already coming with their wallet
open because they trust you. Trust is
the ultimate currency. From there, you
want two-piston content, right? You want
the type that goes and attracts people
top of funnel, that more growth content,
and then your deeper expertise content
that then goes and converts them.
Along the way, remember to just be
insanely generous, right? Give people
your heart, your soul, right? The more
generous you are, the more they're going
to go and share it and trust you to then
buy from you. Let's go.