your excuses suck here's proof John
Morrow was born paralyzed has had
hundreds of broken bones and pneumonia
16 times he's traveled the world and
built multiple million doll online
businesses using a lip operated Mouse
Nick muuji was born without limbs now
he's a world-renowned motivational
speaker Cornell Rison was born with a
deformed leg with no forearms but has
become a YouTube Star for his incredible
drumming while he was dying from lung
cancer Paul keni wrote his best-selling
book when breath becomes air and has
impacted millions of people because of
it Stephen Hawking was cursed with ALS
and yet made massive contributions to
science the list goes on stop making
excuses and take action