Your mental spiral can be stopped with
just one domino. Before I learned this
trick, you know, I'd find [music] myself
in these crazy spirals. I wouldn't even
take the time to step back for a second
and ask myself, what's that one domino
that if I just did that one thing, it
would make everything else in my life
easier or unnecessary. This breaks the
loop because of something called the
zing effect. Essentially, [music] just
doing one thing, one that just moves you
forward ever so slightly can oftenimes
set up a chain reaction that helps you
start building the momentum, getting
your confidence, and getting [music] out
of whatever's leading you to those
negative thoughts. So, here's how to go
and find your one big domino. Go and
write down the answers to these
questions [music] that come into your
mind. What thought is taking up most of
my mental space right now? What actions
would make this thought lose its power?
If I only had 10 minutes, what would I
do first? The one domino is your ticket
out of analysis paralysis and into
action.