Here's the thing that nobody tells you
about hiring. Most founders hire as a
panic button. [music] They get
overwhelmed, they bring someone on, and
they feel better for about 2 weeks.
[music] And then they realize that
they've created more overhead, more
culture risk, and honestly just more
management work than before.
>> [music]
>> I call this the founder prison. And
freedom requires a completely different
way of thinking about [music] your team.
I'd bring someone on whenever I felt
like I was drowning, and instead of
getting lighter, I just [music] felt
like I got more to manage. More context
to share, more questions to answer,
[music]
more culture to protect. The moment I
started really focusing on hiring for
ROI, everything changed. [music] So,
every founder I've coached who makes
this shift says the same thing. It's
like someone [music] lifts a weight off
their shoulders that they didn't even
know that they were carrying. The
business feels lighter, the decisions
feel cleaner, and for the first time you
start [music] to feel like the owner of
your business instead of some employee
inside of it. That's the shift, and
here's how you can actually make it.
[music] Every person you bring onto your
team should hit one specific number. If
they don't hit it, you're not ready to
hire. And that number again is return on
investment. I have a founder who I've
been helping for the last 3 [music]
years, and he's automated 95% of his
business by building the right team and
applying this delegation [music]
framework properly. Now, he spends
entire summers with his family, not
checking Slack at dinner, not stepping
out for meetings.
>> [music]
>> I mean like actually present.