You ever notice this pattern? You know,
you've made a a video or maybe a post
that you want to go and put out on
social media and right before you're
about to go and post the thing, you're
like, "Oh, no.
Is it good enough? Should I do this?"
You know, I think it's that muscle
that is worth
playing with.
Right? Just shipping that thing even
when you feel a little bit embarrassed.
I think it's
like any great thing in life. Right?
Oftentimes we're our own worst critic.
And in order to start going and building
your brand, building a personal brand,
building a product, right? You have to
be okay with shipping things when
they're a little bit embarrassing.
I know for me
the last two words that I oftentimes
think
right before I go and ship something
that I'm nervous about is [\h__\h] it.
Right? [\h__\h] it. Just put it out there.
What do you got to lose?
So
I find that by gradually just then
shipping these things irrespective of
that voice in my head
I'm able to build my shipping muscle and
get more comfortable shipping things
messy.
Give it a shot.