One of the biggest superpowers I think
you can have in life is being
underestimated. Everyone told me I was
crazy when I packed up my bags for
Toronto after selling my first company.
It took a one-way flight to Indonesia.
I don't know, man. I think it's going to
come in rip.
We'll try to tell this story on the way
down.
Again, one of the biggest superpowers is
being underestimated. You know, most
people tell you even filming at the top
of Mount Pitch and the Dolommites is
[\h__\h] crazy, especially when you know
it's calling for thunderstorms. But no,
he said, "Why not?" Every single
business I've ever started has always
been in an industry where I had no idea
what I was doing. My first business,
Bitmaker, starting a technology school
at 21, I had no idea. Hell, I wasn't
even that good at coding myself. My
second business, I had never started
anything in a regulated industry in my
life. People told me I was crazy. My
family was worried about me. Friends
thought I was losing my mind. But sure
enough, we did just fine. Third
business, Founder OS. People told me
that my expectations were too big. You
know, the idea of helping 100 million
founders is crazy.
But sure enough, we're here to prove
them wrong.
Being underestimated,
it's not a disadvantage,
it's one hell of an advantage. There's a
three reasons why I believe this to be
true. Number one is
people are going to doubt you. Doubt is
fuel for founders. I love the old clips
of Michael Jordan before big games.
Someone goes and says something to him,
you know, it just really pisses him off.
>> If you're going to high-five, talk
trash. Now I had a bone to pick with
you. You know, I'm supposed to kill this
guy. That's all I needed. It became
personal with me.
>> And that was all the fuel he needed to
go and absolutely spank that other team.
Similarly, when you think about getting
into a space you've maybe never been in
it, people tell you, you know what, you
don't have a clue what you're doing, you
should give up now. You know, you can
use that doubt as fuel to prove those
people wrong to show them what you're
made of. This is the fuel that I needed
when I started my first business,
BitMaker. People telling me there was no
way I could start a technology school
and train full stack software engineers
in 9 weeks, get them jobs at companies
like Shopify, Facebook, Google. You were
like, "No way. It's impossible." Or when
I was raising capital for Herb and I had
gotten over 287 nos, people told me just
to pack it in. It's over. But amidst all
of that underestimation,
I proved all those [\h__\h] wrong.
And that is a sweet, sweet taste,
proving the doubters that you can pull
it off. And the second piece of why
being underestimated is one hell of an
advantage is because when you're
underestimated, people's actual
expectations of you are low. That allows
you to get into a space you never been
in before and people don't see you as
competition. So, they'll tell you all
their secrets. You can go and talk to
competitors, ask them how they're doing
things because they don't think much
about you. They'll tell you the mistakes
they made early on and the things that
you should avoid. It gives you the
ability to just move in silence. You
know, basically accumulate secrets
across the industry because no one
actually thinks you're going to be able
to pull it off. You know, Peter Teal
talks about how the best founders build
monopolies based on secrets that only
they know. And when you're
underestimated, you know, you can go and
accumulate a ton of data from, you know,
people that have been in the space for a
long, long time. And then you can learn
from those people and you can hear the
things that they say, you know what, we
tried this but it didn't work. Or this
thing, we gave it 20 shots but it's
never worked in this industry. Now, I've
heard these things time and time again.
That's why I think one of the biggest
advantages again when you're building is
to be completely fresh, to be a rookie.
You know, I think experience often times
is overrated because with experience,
people think old school. You know, they
think the same old way. And at some
point, you know, that can actually be
something that just harms you because
you can't see around corners. You can't
think outside the box. You're too stuck
in the old way of thinking. You know,
there's actually a psychological
principle behind this called the Dunning
Krueger effect. Overconfidence
can actually screw you because it causes
you to miss key facts. When you're being
underestimated, don't worry about it.
Stick to your course. All that matters
is your own self-image of how you view
yourself. Don't worry about how others
view you. Don't cave to their way of
thinking. The thing that separates
entrepreneurs from 99% of people out
there is an unwavering confidence,
trust, meddal, and your own ability to
pull off crazy [\h__\h] You know, your
ability to persevere when other people
would have given up a hell of a long
time ago. The most legendary experiences
of my life have always happened from
just being doubted. That's why I think
the third thing to keep in mind is that
when you're underestimated, you get to
strike from the shadows. Steve Jobs was
famous for coming out of nowhere and
dropping products that absolutely
transformed the way, you know, humanity
used tools. things like the iPhone or
iPod, iMac. People underestimated Apple
at times. They thought they were a done
deal, headed for bankruptcy. But Steve
knew that, well, he was being
underestimated. You know, he had some
superpowers in the background that would
allow him to strike out of nowhere. Once
you discover one simple fact, and that
is everything around you that you call
life was made up by people that were no
smarter than you, you can change it. You
can influence it. You can build your own
things that other people can use. That's
maybe the most important thing.
>> And the benefit here is that people are
underestimating you so much that when
you go and you drop something that's
legendary, you just completely transform
people's thinking. They go from doubters
to fans in a split second. you know, as
I, you know, go and continue to build,
you know, Founder OS, I'm helping
founders all the time get over these
limiting beliefs, this feeling like no
one around them believes in what they're
doing. You know, everyone's going to
tell you crazy until finally you're an
overnight success. I think it's having
that ability to just have faith. You
know why you got into what you're doing.
You have good reason for believing in
yourself no matter what people tell you.
Now, for some of you,
you need a couple more tools to help
you. I get it. Being underestimated can
be scary at times. I've gone and spent
the morning here while waking up with a
ice americano here in the Doommites
to go and prepare a little
underestimation playbook for you. 47
systems you can go and get via the link
in the description to go and help you
overcome the doubters, the haters, the
people that would rather see you fail.
This channel is a channel for people
that are about adventuring, doing the
impossible, working from anywhere,
building their dreams despite what
people say. Now, we believe in freedom,
the true freedom, the ability to control
the four W's in life. work where we
want, when we want, on what we want,
with whoever we want. We believe in
serving a community of people that we
love, you know, working with people that
we admire. Oh. Oh.
And persevering.
Oh, despite how many times you get
knocked down,
want to thank you for being a part of
the founder Freedom Movement. This has
been one hell of a journey, as you
probably can tell. and I'll see you guys
in the next one. Like and subscribe.
Get that underestimation playbook and
let's get it.