you're not lazy your goals just suck
here's a three-part system to set goals
that make you jump out of bed in the
morning make deadlines meaningful reward
yourself once you've completed a task or
set a penalty for not finishing before
the deadline optimize for making your
motivation greater than your discomfort
put your heart in it if you don't care
about a project your heart won't be in
it optimize your goal setting towards
serving others and the motivation will
naturally flow set yourself up for
Success create a plan for execution when
will you finish how are you going to
carry it out how long do you you need
then block off work in your calendar
create a space for flow no phone no TV
no unnecessary tabs set task that can be
completed in no more than 4 hours of
deep work a day