If you want to get ahead of 99% of
people, it really comes down to removing
friction. Your life doesn't need more
motivation. It needs less freaking
friction. Make the right thing the easy
thing. Lay out your clothes, prep the
food, delete the apps, remove all
distractions. The more frictionless your
life, the more obvious it becomes to
just do what you're supposed to do. You
don't want to be just relying on your
willpower. You want to be relying on
systems. [music] As James Clear famously
said, you don't rise to the level of
goals, you fall to the level of your
systems. Right? And so if something
matters, build a system around it. If it
doesn't, make it annoying as hell to