the measuring stick I use for every
business I create is What's called the
one month test ask yourself this if I
take a one month break will I come back
to my business stronger than before if
the answer is no then you need to learn
the art of creating systems here are
four steps to mastering this step one
create a Google doc outline to clear
one-ear goal then reverse engineer that
Vision into 90day goals write up the
list of steps you need to achieve the
goal who's going to do the work and how
they're going to do it step two record a
loom create a 5-minute loom video
covering the pass from top to bottom
explain what needs to be done how it
needs to be done and where to go for
inspiration when they get stuck step
three set a weekly meeting meet with the
systems owner ensure you're on the same
page and check the system is working as
planned step four refine the system make
changes to the Google Doc when necessary
Implement feedback and keep on refining
until you leave your business for a
month and know it will keep running
without you