If you want to make a million dollars,
don't focus on the money. Focus on the
value. Here's how to build a $1 million
predictable revenue engine. Own your
niche. Identify a gap that you can help
people cross. Serve a community. Make it
your goal to be the category champion.
Create a funnel. Publish content your
audience is craving. Transition readers
to your newsletter and have exclusive
content just for them. Hold their hand
as you help them cross the gap. Pitch
your offer. Don't get hung up making
sales right out the gate. Don't be
afraid to ask for feedback. Refine your
offer. Try again. Building a $1 million
business is about mastery of your niche,
connection with your customers, and
delivering value. Focus on that and the
money will come.