These are the seven sentences that I
believe in that became Founder OS, my
third business. So,
first things first, I think that
founders deserve calm, and I think that
for too long we've been sold this lie
that hustle and grinding is going to get
us to our eventual goals. So, in really,
I think it's about enjoying the process
of building something that you genuinely
love. Secondly, is that distribution is
the only moat that AI cannot touch. I
believe that your personal brand, your
founder energy, is your greatest asset,
right? And by creating content in a
social media machine around you, you
create a compounding engine that you
own, and you have the ability to control
your destiny. From there, I think it's
about being a reducer over a producer,
right? Deleting things so you get down
to the essential stuff you need to do in
your business, and have a peaceful, calm
empire. Also, soul beats slop any day. I
think people are getting tired of all
this AI-generated BS online, and I think
more important than ever, it's important
to have resonance, right? Talking about
the stuff that fires you up, and sharing
who you really are. Don't worry about
perfection, right? Worry about just
sharing your soul, and developing your
own tribe online. From there,
it comes down to your architecture, so
that in all this content you're
creating, you're able to go and monetize
it because you have an email list, an
offer, and the right connectors to make
it all work. So, hopefully that helps.
My subject