All right, we out.
Artist retreat.
There's a simple way you can make your
first million dollars with content, but
almost no one talks about it.
Most people treat content like it's a
lottery ticket, but I treat it like a
system. A system that runs a $13 million
portfolio of online companies. So, in
this video, I'm going to share the
million-dollar content engine that I've
done three separate times across three
separate businesses in three separate
industries so you can learn the inside
hacks that I see no one talking about
and apply it to your business today.
Let's get into it. The first thing you
need to know is why you're making
content in the first place. And no, you
know, making more money is not going to
be enough to cut it. 6 years ago, I was
watching a documentary on Carl Icon, the
famous investor who at the time, I
think, owned around 10% of Apple. You
know, Carl Icon's this legendary
investor and he has something called
Icon Enterprises. And it inspired me to
start thinking of myself similar to Carl
Icon does as this company that's in
front of me and I'm just supporting that
logo. Instead, I started viewing myself
as this asset manager that had a number
of different portfolio companies and
investments underneath me that I would
be growing for the next 50 to 100 years.
So, this created a beautiful founder
flywheel. Essentially, the more I grew
my personal brand, the more I was able
to grow my portfolio of businesses,
drive more word of mouth, drive more
cash flows that I would be able to
further reinvest into the audience
growth and putting out exceptional
content. You know, these days I see the
most critical function across my
businesses is me putting out
unbelievable organic content, right?
What do you think the world really needs
to hear from you and how does that tie
in with your businesses? Cuz at the
intersection there lives your zone of
brilliance. This is kind of your
competitive edge that you know you're
going to talk about these things. It's
going to create an enormous amount of
abundance around you and it's the kind
of stuff that you could see yourself
really being curious about for the next
decade or two of your life versus
finding yourself talking about stuff
online that you really don't give much
of a [\h__\h] about. And so to go and help
you with this exercise, I've gone and
created a 48 hour content ignition plan.
It's got all these questions and a bunch
of exercises to help you go and narrow
in on your competitive edge. The second
thing I needed to do, you know,
something that's made me a million
dollars across three different media
companies. And, [music] you know, it's
one thing that's going to save you a ton
of time. So, after making a million
dollars from content at BitMaker, making
my first million dollars of content at
Herb, and making my first million
dollars from content at Founder OS,
[music] you know what I've learned is
one core thing, iteration. And so it's
from putting out over 36,000
pieces of content that I've been able to
refine exactly the successful kind of
traits [music] that exist in content
that spreads versus the kind of content
that no one gives a [\h__\h] about. Even
with all that experience, [music] I'll
be honest, it was a bit tricky at first,
right? You know what I've learned is
when you're getting going on any
platform, you know, you got to be
patient, right? You got to have that
long-term mindset because things aren't
just going to blow up overnight. [music]
Really the success across the last 16
years building all these profitable
media companies has really come from you
know making every piece of content 10%
better than the last. [music] Right?
It's this mindset of constantly
iterating that's allowed me to get to
where I am today. You know I don't want
you to be intimidated by any of the
things I've shared here. Right? Because
the reality is it's just this mindset
that will get you to where you're
looking to go. You know let's just say
I'm on level 63 of this whole content
game. Right? And you're on level two or
level 10. The real game of getting from
where you are to where you're looking to
go is just [music] this mindset of being
10% better every single day. Not getting
intimidated by the people that you see
out there that maybe have it more
figured out than you. Because truth is,
they're also still figuring it out. You
know, it doesn't matter what level
you're at, what industry you're in, what
business model you have, right? When you
have that mindset of iteration and is
obsessing around the process, [music]
right? Success is inevitable. So don't
just chase a million. Chase mastery,
chase [music] excellence, you know,
chase building a cult following, chase
alignment, chase building something
[music] where when you go and you
attract a movement of people around you,
you are excited to go and serve these
people because they're not just
customers, right? These are friends,
right? These are people that you
genuinely get fired [music] up to serve.
I think when you've created that, you've
created the real success in life.
[music] So ask yourself, what needs to
exist that doesn't already exist? What's
that message out there that the world
needs to hear that you were meant to
share? But once I was running all these
experiments with my content, I needed to
understand the difference between signal
[music] and noise. 4 years ago, you
know, I was building on X. But
initially, you know, there was no
traction. You know, I was in this long
tale of just putting in the effort, you
know, going and mastering content
creation around my personal brand and
just being patient. But I I won't I
won't lie to you. You know, at some
points you're just wondering, you know,
is this really a good idea? Is this
going to lead anywhere? Well, just
around [music] when those thoughts
started creeping into my own mind, you
know, I put out a long- form thread on
X. And [music] sure enough, a mentor at
the time named Justin, who had been
helping me craft some amazing,
compelling copy and mastery around
writing for Twitter, um, sure enough, he
retweeted this given [music] thread and
it caught fire and generated over a
million views in 24 [music] hours. You
know, there was an outpouring of people
that really resonated with my story,
resonated with the fact that I was
openly sharing some of the struggles I
had had building businesses for the
previous decade. I finally felt, you
know, a glimpse of light at the end of
the tunnel, right? I just kind of went
back to work the next day, [music]
right? And just kept chipping away day
by day, sharing more stories, more
blueprints, more systems. But [music] at
the same token, I was constantly every
week looking at, you know, what was my
best 10% of content? what were the
patterns amongst it and [music] then
similarly looking at the bottom 10% of
my content the stuff that people weren't
really fired up high and just cutting
that from my content strategy [music]
you know this was the same thing that I
had used to build herb to 14 million
people and now I was just applying those
same principles to my [music] own
personal brand pay attention to the
meaningful signal right those DMs that
you get the text messages and double
down on what people are saying that they
love [music] you know it's all good to
get viral posts but what I'd much rather
is get an inbound own text [music] from
an entrepreneur that I really respect.
That's going to mean a hell of a lot
more to me than a million views. Now,
I've given you a bunch of ideas for
different experiments you can run to
keep this all fun inside of the 48 hour
content ignition playbook. So, go and
check that out. Download it in the link
in the description and start going
through that to, you know, really
develop a level of joy around your
content. Now, let's talk about how all
of this content started turning into
monetization. So there I was putting all
of this content out on X and people
started to resonate with it. I was
getting messages and DMs all the time
from people saying, you know, can you go
and help me systemize my content
operations? Matt, can you help me go and
build a personal media company? Matt,
you know, can you help me with a time
audit to get 20 hours of my week back
just like you have? And I started to
realize that there was a massive
opportunity for me to go and serve these
founders. You know, I'd been working at
Herb full-time, building up that
business, and I had gotten it into
autopilot, had a bunch of time free, and
figured I'd start to get a group of
founders together and help them with
some of the systems that really had
unlocked, you know, tons of time
abundance in my own life. And so, you
know, fast forward to today, right? It
was really those early kernels of those
mini experiments of the content I was
putting out that helped me form and
shape what Founder OS is today. And so I
get asked by founders all the time, you
know, Matt, you know, I'm looking to
iterate on the product, but it doesn't
feel ready yet. Should I even be putting
content out there yet? And my answer is
hell yes, you should. You know, it's
often times that content journey that's
actually sort of the early parts of your
product development. You know, I learned
a ton around, you know, the feedback I
was even getting around some of the
threads I was putting out there and
tweets that helped me shape even what
soulful entrepreneur was supposed to be
in those first early iterations. [music]
I knew to double down more on the
systems because of the content I was
putting [music] out there, right? So
often times, you know, your content
actually is the early seed of your
product. And so I'd think it's never too
early to start putting your content out
there and it's never too early to start
building an enormous amount of leverage
around you by building an organic
audience. I've realized too over the
years that people don't buy just your
product. They buy your conviction.
[music] They buy the alignment that you
have with what you're putting out there.
You know, I think you can tell, right?
I'm insanely passionate about systems,
right? I'm insanely passionate about
helping you go and design your dream
life. We do this all day, every day. I
eat, sleep, breathe, helping founders
get more joy out of their own founder
experience and do it through proven
systems. And so this is stuff that I
would do even if I wasn't being paid a
dime, right? We just genuinely enjoy
this [\h__\h] And so that's what you want
to find, too. Because I think when you
nail this, right, people can feel it.
Here's what you need to do. Go and pay
attention to the people that are most
engaged with what you're putting out
there. Look at the DMs, the people with
longer comments, the people that are
texting you after, and start to ask
them, you [music] know, what's the piece
of content that has most resonated with
you so far, and you know, what's your
biggest challenge right now? And what's
the biggest thing I could help you with?
You know, it's this [music] sort of
feedback that you get from those, you
know, super fans of you that will give
you a general direction as to where you
should go with your content and it will
likely also inform where you need to go
with your brand and your products.
[music] So, you know, go and listen to
these folks and then double down on
their feedback. So, after this, [music]
I ran into a problem. You know, the
offer was scaling like crazy. Founders
[music] were interested more than ever
in Founder OS and we were doing an
amazing job. And I realized that, you
know, my personal brand, if I wanted to
scale it, I had to build a [music]
personal media company. And I needed to
go and actually view myself as more the
CEO of this Matt Gray and Founder OS
media company versus just some rinky
dink personal [music] brand. There's
this beautiful sort of flywheel that
exists inside of Founder OS. The more
that I learn, the more I level up, the
more I push my own taste and creativity,
the more I attract this amazing audience
of high growth founders that are also
looking to leverage organic content and
build an infrastructure around them so
that they can take advantage of the
power of personal brands and content.
[music] And this is the exact sort of
stuff that we're helping founders with.
really capturing the opportunity that
exists when you build a systemized
[music]
founder brand. And honestly, helping
founders with a lot of the sticky
situations that come up along the
[music] way because the truth is
building these sort of brands isn't all
rainbows, unicorns, and butterflies,
right? [\h__\h] comes up. The reality is is
that, you know, the different platforms
change. You know, you're having to build
a team and there's different
complications that come up just like
with any business, right? This [\h__\h]
ain't easy, right? But with the right
systems, the right support and the right
mentorship, you know, setting up this
kind of organic content engine is really
possible. You know, it takes a bit of
hard work, but once it's set up, you
know, it's something that I think can
allow you to become a real category
winner uh and separate yourself from
everyone else in your space. And so, as
Founders has evolved, right, it's
evolved from just, you know, helping
people grow their brand to helping
founders grow a systemized founder brand
and a media company around themselves.
And so what I continue to learn is that
the more that I level up my own
portfolio of profitable companies and
the media divisions of all these
companies, the more it attracts more and
more founders that also want to go and
build [music] this sort of
infrastructure around them. And so, you
know, I think this is, you know, my
message to you as well, right? The more
that you really stretch yourself, right?
you iterate, you get out of your comfort
zone and you make your offer, your
audience, your content 10% better every
single day, you know, the more that
you're able to not only compete at a
really high level, but to attract bigger
and better customers, you know, and
build a really vibrant community around
what you're building. But even with the
best offers, I would have never been
able to make millions from each of the
media companies I've started without
systems in place. You know, the truth is
that you got to have the right systems
in place, right? But when you're looking
to go and build a profitable media
company, you need the right systems for
hiring people, for onboarding people,
for content, for the audience growth on
each platform, and for actually
distributing that content at a really
high degree. And then the analytics
behind it all so that you learn from the
best content, the worst, and are able to
iterate. Here's the deal. When you're
going and scaling out your content, the
only thing that is [music] certain is
that things will change. And so that
systems designer is responsible for
keeping that system updated and also
making sure you know that they're
holding the rest of the team accountable
for operating at a certain level. Now
the last thing I'm going to share with
you here is to learn content. You know
after many years building businesses you
know I don't really have an interest in
anymore building some billion-dollar
company. I want to build an amazingly
vibrant business, an amazing community
around it and just enjoy my life. Now, I
didn't realize this at the time, but all
of these weird and disperate experiences
that I had over the last 15 years
building businesses all seemed to make
sense gradually when I started to see
what people were resonating with in my
content. You know, they were resonating
with the fact that I burned myself out
in my first business, BitMaker. They
were resonating with the fact that while
I had built this amazing audience of 14
million people around Herb, you know, I
still felt like I was unneededly kind of
hiding behind the scenes and needed to
put myself out there more to feel, you
know, like I was being my ultimate
creative self. And so, in some weird
way, you know, I was able to start
connecting the dots looking backwards
and seeing how all this experience that
I had gotten over those previous 14
years was almost the perfect ingredient
to put out the kind of content I was now
sharing with the world. If you want an
exercise to go and help take action on
all the stuff we've talked about here to
get your content operation ripping, be
sure to go check out the content
ignition playbook via the link in the
description. And if you want to go and
build your own cult following and dive
into more branding psychology, [music]
go and check out this next video. Thanks
so much for watching. Be sure to like
and subscribe [music] and welcome to the
founder freedom movement.