There is one decision that you make
every day that will determine whether
you're successful or not. And that
decision is whether you're going to take
that next meeting. [music] Too many
people leave all of their time in a day
for meetings. But the reality is is if
all you're doing all day is meetings,
you have no time for maker time. The key
thing is first off, schedule all of your
meetings on just one day of the week.
The second thing is you got to have a
rule for this. No agenda, no meeting.
So, if people aren't organized ahead of
time, letting you know exactly what it
is they want to cover, then [music]
scrap that meeting. The third thing is
all hour-long meetings should be reduced
just to 30 minutes and give yourself
three or four days of the week to get
the real stuff done that's going to help
you move forward towards your goals.