You don't need to be creative to come up
with creative ideas. You just need this
one trick. Picasso said, "Good artists
copy, great artists steal. The best
creators are the best curators. Taste is
your ultimate competitive advantage."
You know, I think of platforms like
Pinterest, Instagram collections, my
mind, LinkedIn saves, Twitter bookmarks.
These are the best places to go and save
your inspiration and then use them to go
and remix your own content. Once you've
gone and created a pillar piece of
content that's inspired from all of
these saves you have, you can then go
and leverage the content GPS to turn
that one pillar piece of content into 26
other pieces of content. Things like
three YouTube shorts, three Instagram
reels, three Tik Tok videos, a
newsletter a week later, four LinkedIn
posts, 10 tweets. This is the future of
founderled brands.