Values are your foundation, but a
foundation isn't a brand yet. Not a lot
of people really remember this, okay?
But Instagram actually started as a
little company \slash} project called
Bourbon. It was cluttered. It was this
location-based app. People hated it.
Kevin Systrom, one of the founders of
Instagram, they noticed something. Their
users kept coming back for the photo
filters. So, instead of trying to fix
everything else, they just made a
critical decision. They stripped down
the product to one thing and started a
new thing called Instagram, and it was
around photo filters. They didn't try to
compete in social networking broadly.
They didn't just become another
Facebook. They became the place for
beautifully filtered mobile photos, and
the market swarmed around them. They
stopped trying to be everything all at
once and committed to being one thing,
and that's what made them impossible to
ignore. It's not going to happen
overnight, okay? So, you got to be
patient. You got to have that long-term
thinking. Every failure is just data
telling you where your intersection
isn't. Keep going. Keep listening, and
eventually the pattern becomes obvious.
And when it clicks, that's not just a
brand. That's something no company
pivot, no market shift, and no algorithm
can take away from you.