You don't need to post the polished you.
Just post
the real you.
I think we're in this season of content
right now that I call
the three Rs, triple Rs, okay? Raw,
real, rant.
And what it's all about
is that I think
more and more people when they see
content show up on their feed, they're
wondering, you know, was this AI
generated? Is this even who this person
is?
And one of the best ways to go and
conquer this is simply just to go and
grab your iPhone,
pick up your iPhone, and just give
people a raw stream of consciousness
around a specific topic.
You don't need to be super polished.
You know, 5 years ago
I was using an FX3 for all my videos,
$2,000 camera, slapping in a beautiful
color grade on everything, intentionally
editing every piece, and I still love
that stuff, right? And I think it's got
a time and a place, so you know, I'm not
ditching that entirely.
These days though, it's more about just
picking up an iPhone or just pen and
paper and just putting that stream of
consciousness out there to the world.
Cuz people more than ever just want to
get to know who you really are.
And so
raw, real, rant.
This is a season we're in. Embrace it.