But the brutal truth about building a
personal brand is that most founders
spend all of their time on the layers
that don't actually matter. They obsess
over strategy, they obsess over color
grades and sound and a bunch of stuff
that ends up just [music] being some
distraction. And then they wonder why
their brand sounds and looks just like
everyone else's. None of that is the
moat. The moat is the layers [music]
underneath it. The five things that AI
literally can't copy. I'm going to show
you exactly how I embed all five of
those layers into the content that I
make. Let's get into it. All right,
layer number one is the aesthetic DNA. I
think a lot of content, it's about
beauty, right? I like to think of it
like making art, not just content. And I
think that the best creators out there
are oftentimes the best curators. And
so, here is my Pinterest. You can see um
a bunch of different stuff that I am
using to inspire my content. The thing
that I love most about Pinterest is that
um once you get a board going, um you
can simply go to this more ideas area,
um and it just it just it's endless. Um
so, as you can see, I've been getting a
little bit into uh some Kanye tweets.
You can see here, this Ye tweet, "You
have the best ideas. Other people's
opinions are usually more distractive
than informative. Follow your own
vision, base your actions on love, do
things you love, and if you don't
absolutely love something, stop doing it
as soon as you can." Couldn't have said
it better myself. And so, what I'll
oftentimes do then is go and utilize
that in things like, you know, my
newsletter. And so, um here you can see
a bunch of newsletters I've been writing
um the last week. Um and um I'm going
and embedding
um different elements of my Pinterest
boards into these because those are
things that are inspiring me. Here you
can see in this
uh newsletter here, "Less more
trees." I went and embedded um a couple
of my different Pinterest pins inside of
this, right? Things like entrepreneur's
mind, athlete's body, artist's soul. And
that Ye tweet um that I just showed you.
Um so, I'm using uh you know, a little
bit of uh inspiration from this.
Sometimes just uh directly replicate
these and kind of just copy paste them
into uh my newsletter, obviously giving
credit to the artist. But, I also use
this um to go and inspire me for things
like the graphic design that we put out
there. So, when I think about creating
Founder OS, um part of the inspiration
is like Rick Rubin meets Patagonia
uh meets some sort of kind of Japanese
ask design. Give me that kind of
nostalgic nature vibe. I honestly could
go and probably just scroll Pinterest
all day. It's just something about it is
just so aesthetically
relaxing. It feels like I'm giving my
brain a massage. Probably a little bit
weird, but welcome to how my brain
works. I also use it for things like
motion graphics. So, we use different
motion across some of our videos. Um and
here I'm just saving different sort of
shapes that inspire me. We um also make
a lot of carousels on Instagram. You
know, we're going and using not just
words, but images as well to portray
different concepts. So, in this case,
how to build a personal brand in just 7
days, you know, I'm using a lot of the
inspiration that I find on Pinterest to
go and generate things like these sorts
of carousels. You can see across my
brand, um I think what people love is
that there's a level of aesthetics. Um
and often times a lot of those um
inspirations come from Pinterest and
just me looking at creative stuff all
day. You know, I've been really thinking
a lot about the tension of being an
entrepreneur, right? This balance of
being this like zen vibe, but also
wanting to push the needle. And I like
to look at old um Ogilvy ads, old
Porsche ads, different things that
inspire me. Just cool like freedom vibes
and ways of um using copy that I think
is really compelling, right? Inevitably,
you've heard me say, right? Copywriting
is a salesperson that never sleeps. And
I think it's really important to take a
lot of pride in the words you put on
paper, right? Words are powerful. Um
just like design is powerful. I am
constantly curating words, titles,
headlines, ads,
um that I think are really helpful, and
then that gets translated into my
content. Oftentimes, I think founders,
when they're creating content, they miss
the opportunity in powerful copy, in
powerful aesthetics. And it's something
that um I've leaned into from day one
building every brand I've built. Just a
few of the many ways um that I go and
curate um that aesthetic DNA. And if you
want to find out how strong your brand
actually is right now, what's working
and what's missing and where the gaps
are, I built a free brand scorecard for
you, and it's in the link in the
description below. Takes about 5
minutes, and by the end you're going to
have a customized brand score. It's
going to show you where you can improve
your content strategy and strengthen
your personal brand. Aesthetics are what
they see. This next layer is what they
don't. And so, let's get into layer two,
the idea DNA. My favorite tool,
honestly, for ideation,
by far, is good old Apple Notes. And so,
in here, um I have basically just a
running list of ideas that I'm fired up
by. When I'm going and basically
thinking of ideas, I find that the
number one idea that I come up with are
really the ones that from a spark of
inspiration that I get, right? And
oftentimes, my next inclination is just
to take out my phone and go and jot down
a note inside of this with like what was
the idea. These days, I'm really
thinking about trying to shorten that
span from going from idea to publish
because I think when you create
something in that moment, when you feel
really excited, that excitement gets
translated beyond the screen to you as
the viewer. And that's what I think
creates real resonance online. I think
that's what people are really yearning
for is they want to feel like they're
hanging out with a friend that they can
feel the energy that that person has and
they feel like they're kind of creating
this like rich one-to-one relationship
with someone online. I've been using
this like interesting reflection
template um to go and create my weekly
reflections each week. Often times uh
Cloud Code knows me better than most of
my friends these days. This is an
example of this like weekly reflection
template. It's inspired by Bill
Campbell. He was the coach to people
like Jeff Bezos, Eric Schmidt, the
Google founders, Steve Jobs. He really
encouraged these guys to go and do a
weekly reflection. And so what I've done
is then created this um template where
I'm able to go and review my company,
review my goals, um get real about what
did I accomplish, um what did I avoid,
what did I learn, uh my one domino for
the week, um and the ways that I'm
really proud of how I showed up. I
thought this should be really cool to
share with folks. And so um I actually
then one morning uh when I was at my
favorite cafe here in Bali called Saint
Ali. Um I see a lot of you guys coming
up to me there. So shout out y'all. Um I
created a little uh video of me actually
running through um this system. I
essentially just went and recorded
myself going through
that
system. So this is my weekly reflection.
I just completed it inside of my iPad. I
had put all my notes there and I
figured, "Oh, why don't I go and show
people how this thing works." That's
sort of how I think about the idea layer
um in DNA of my content when I'm putting
it out there. All right, the third layer
here is your voice DNA, right? What is
that thing that makes you unique? You
know, I've been thinking a lot about
really the album only I can make. Um and
this is some stuff I've been cooking up
and really thinking about how do I kind
of have this unique voice out there
online, right? And how do I just have my
own authentic, real voice out there just
to attract the tribe that I'm really
after. As I think about the album only I
can make, I feel like it's like this
energy of like Steam Jobs meets Rick
Rubin meets like an Anthony Bourdain, a
founder who builds at the intersection
of artistry and infrastructure, content
so distinctly personal that no one else
can replicate it, a marketing and sales
engine that runs on resonance, not
persuasion. Um, you know, when I really
have gotten kind of grooving on my own
voice, I like to go and think about the
kind of content that I've made that I'm
most proud of. And some of those were
things like the secret to building a
business without losing yourself or,
um, you know, this video here, um, where
I was going and just recording my kind
of raw thoughts
while in the Italian Dolomites. It's not
just that video, right? It's also this
video that I made while in Lofoten,
Norway, inspired to go and share, uh, my
personal board meeting, which is one of
the most powerful systems I've ever
invented. I've used it every single
month for the last decade to go and
document, uh, my personal and business
goals for the next month, um, as well as
go and reflect each month on what went
well, what didn't go well, and what did
I learn. And this rhythm of having this
personal board meeting with myself has
allowed me to continually kind of
improve. And it's also cool thing for me
to be able to go back and reflect on
years later and see kind of how far I've
come. From this reflection, right? I'm
able to see like the parts where I'm
like most excited by my voice. And from
all of this, right? What I like to
oftentimes do is also just like, you
know, make sure that I am documenting
some of the core ideas that I have, um,
that I think most effectively capture my
voice. For me, it's things like I'm an
entrepreneur, I'm an artist who built an
autonomous engine, this idea that most
founders run down the street fully
dressed and wonder why nobody is
looking, and the importance of trying to
be being really
You know, sales is easy, marketing is
easy, the product is the only hard
thing. The product is leverage,
everything else is labor. And so, I see
like the core aspects of my voice and
the things that make it distinct,
non-obvious, and novel are things like
personal stories like Bitmaker, uh my
first business being raided by the
government, um the things that I've
learned um going and having a comeback
from being addicted to a bunch of stuff,
um and um the idea of also um just
really disconnecting um and being in
nature to go and get uh you know, the
most raw versions of myself out there. I
like to bridge the tension of building
publicly. So, with my voice, like I want
to make sure that yes, I'm giving you
guys like proven systems, but at the
same token, just talking about my lived
reality, right? Like the struggles I go
through, the mistakes I'm making, this
idea of the tension between like slowing
down, but also building something
valuable. From there, really just going
and then kind of getting clear on um
what it's all about. So, this is the
kind of stuff that I'm thinking about um
when I'm going and also sharing what I'm
sharing online. I'm kind of filtering it
through like this criteria of like what
I'm really looking to create, right? For
me, a beautiful bootstrap business is
what I'm after, right? We're talking a
70% margin, team I love, nervous systems
relaxed, mind-blowing products, simple
and fun, I love the customer, it's easy
to deliver on, I have distribution
product fit, it's unique to me, it's
involved in my edge, I'm building with a
lean team of like 10 people, and it has
the ability to get to $10 profit a year.
Right? So, these are the kind of things
that I think about when I'm building.
You know, by the way, this is the kind
of stuff that we're helping founders
build inside of Founder OS. And so, if
you want to work directly with me, my
C-suite, um you want us hands-on helping
you build your social media machine, um
and you understand the power of building
your own profitable personal brand,
well, you should go and check that out
and apply via the link below. I talk to
founders all the time, right? And I
understand how hard it is sometimes to
open up in content. You know, oftentimes
the camera gets started and you get
claimed up, right? Like you start to
feel like you got to put on some act,
right? You got to act like someone else.
And I'm here to tell you that the best
content strategy you'll ever make is the
one where you're just more most true to
yourself. If you're going to do anything
in life, right? Just do it just being
the real you. The videos I'm most proud
of, I think, are videos like, you know,
this video over here, right? Um I just
filmed this the other day in Bali,
right? And it's just me getting real
about um the tension of building, right?
This idea that one part of me is this
like Zen CEO, but this other part of me
is this like maniac that wants to push
the envelope in life. And that I think a
lot of founders resonate with the fact
that like we have these kind of two
personalities inside of us. This video
only had like 2,000 views, right? But
like I've said, I don't think it's about
views online. I think it's about
resonance, right? And creating stuff
that's true to you. And what I notice is
that the data supports that views don't
equal cash. Oftentimes I find when I'm
just being my most real self, that is
the most profitable content strategy.
This video number three, you'd be richer
if you relaxed, is that video that I
just shared that I was in the Dolomites,
right? Made over $55,000 to the company.
Or this video of me helping out my buddy
Blake. It was just me whiteboard
session, me and him chopping it up.
Generated over 29K to the company. And
so, you know,
just being yourself is your most
profitable content strategy. The next
layer is layer four, your structural
DNA. This is the real layer here where
we're identifying like the fundamental
structures of content, right? They're
going to make it work. One tool I love
to use is Poppy AI. With Poppy AI, I'm
essentially able to go and take, you
know, my Instagram as an example, and
I'm able to go and then kind of go to
the different reels, and I can go into
Poppy AI, okay? And I can go and
basically copy all of these different
pieces of content into here, okay? And
so, I'll copy a bunch of those Instagram
Reels into this board. I can take some
of my talking head videos, some of my
best edits.
Um you know, I'm really proud of the
content we've made here. So, I'm taking
some of my best content, I'm pasting it
just by copying the link into Poppy AI.
Um and what I can then go and do is
create this kind of group around that
content. It's able to then go and take
all of that data, and I can go and
create a chat window um that's hooked up
to things like Claude or ChatGPT,
depending on what LLM you like most. And
then we're able to go and use that and
start to dissect the framework behind my
best Reels ever. And I can understand
the structure that made these videos so
successful. And so, we can see here that
there's like Loom AI documentation,
there's authentic communication, I'm
owning my words, there's this idea of
systems over hard work. I'm using simple
communication in them. Um I also am
going and dissecting different tools.
And so, people want the details is the
core thing I've noticed, right? It's
always been this journey when I'm
building content. I'm getting into the
details of the what and the how I do
things specifically. The patterns in
terms of the structure that I've seen in
these is that I get into things like
numbers, right? How I'm doing my
financial management, my bookkeeping,
different roles in my company. I talk
about the people, things like hiring,
KPIs, onboarding, meeting rhythms. And I
talk about things like the culture,
right? The values that I have, the
approach that we take to the aesthetics,
the copywriting rhythms. I get into the
depth, right? Which is what people want
from me. They want the deep systems. And
again, this isn't AI-generated stuff,
right? This is my actual voice, my
actual content. I'm just using Poppy AI
um as an amazing source of research and
inspiration. Here we can see it's
enabled to come up with like endless
structures for me to then use, right?
And come up with different example hooks
that I can get inspired by. Um, and this
will then just give me more ideas on
ways that I can tap more into my proven
structures and ideas on reels and make
more videos like that. Um, so a great
way of basically using Poppy AI as like
your AI um, short-form video researcher.
Now, Poppy is actually the brand partner
of this video. I've been using them for
the last couple years. If you're
interested in checking them out, you go
and check them out via the link in the
description, get $25 off. So, go check
that out. All right, layer five is my
vulnerability DNA. These days, um, my
best content comes uh, from walks that I
go on and I essentially go and have a
survey, um, that I call my authenticity
survey with a bunch of questions in it.
This is like a 100-page document. I go
for a walk, I turn my voice memo app on
on my phone, and I have the Google Doc
open to these questions and I simply go
and
talk and yap basically through a bunch
of different concepts, um, that I found
interesting. And so, here you can see me
just going and talking about, you know,
the church of hustle is dead, right? So,
I was on a walk and I was just talking
like something has happened
entrepreneurship. As founders, we dream
of freedom, impact, and taking care of
those around us, but we've been
brainwashed to believe in a false
trade-off. So, that's exactly what I
then use for things like, um, newsletter
editions that I have and I'm writing.
And so, um, here you can see, um, a
bunch of newsletters I wrote while in
the mountains of Bali. What I've now
learned is that, you know, it's really
important to build things that, um,
really fill up your cup, right? That you
feel like, um, you know, embody your
soul, right? And so, um, I was
reflecting on a hike and talking about
this into a voice memo and then that
becomes a newsletter, um, that I may
send to founders, um, this Saturday.
This combination of, you know, for me
these days using voice memos while on
hikes allows me to get the most like raw
thoughts out of my brain um while I'm
hiking whether in the mountains of the
Dolomites um or in the Balinese hills um
and then I can use those like raw
unfiltered thoughts to go and create uh
my best content. After helping over
17,000 founders with their personal
brand, the truth is that most personal
brands die because the founder builds
them on the wrong layer. The five layers
that I just showed you in this video are
the ones that really compound and the
ones that I think that AI can't rip off.
And so, if you want me and my team to
get hands-on with your brand and build
you the architecture that protects your
voice, helps you build a badass content
strategy, well, probably go and apply to
FounderUs using the link below in the
description. We go and help you build a
powerful, predictable,
revenue-generating social media machine
in just the next 60 days. And if you
want to go and take your brand-building
journey to the next level, well, go and
check out this banger video where I dive
deep into this psychology of building a
brand that everyone loves. So, go and
check out that video. Thanks for
watching. Be sure to like and subscribe,
and let's win together.