If you want to die with no regrets,
there are three things you need to do.
Number one, burn the boats behind you.
When I got sober seven years ago, I
deleted my dealer's number and I doubled
down on writing, journaling every single
day, three pages, and then sharing those
insights and learnings online. Sure
enough, it grew an audience of over
150,000 people and completely
transformed my life. And it all came
from leaving that world behind me and
burning the boats. Number two, do the
work that nobody sees. I've read
hundreds of books over my career. Listen
to podcasts, constantly leveling up,
making sure I'm taking care of my
health, meditating, working out, getting
cardio in, all these good habits that
stack up. The success you're after is an
inside game. Level up, learn, grow.
Number three, stop being a coward about
what you really want. Most founders
build sophisticated distractions. I know
because I did this. My first business,
Bitmaker, sold it for a life-changing
exit, but still hated my life. You have
the ability to go and control your
destiny. You need to go and lean in.
There is no secret to changing your life
overnight. The truth is, it just takes
some work.