Most people think that creativity is
about freedom. No rules, [music] no
structure, just inspiration. That belief
is why most creators burn out and why
most business owners feel stuck between
building a business and a life they
actually enjoy. Sam is an absolute
legend. He has the creative part on lock
and now it's a matter of merging that
goat level creativity [music] with some
solid business systems so he can have
the best of both worlds. And so what
we're going to do here is give him the
systems necessary, the offer necessary
so he can go and take things to the next
level. He wants to be able to travel,
have amazing adventures, skydive, you
name it. And now it's just a matter of
having that business that runs itself so
that he can live the most epic life
possible. Let's dive in. [music] It's
December 2025. I know you've got some
big ambitions and some like realignment
you're looking to do
>> in 2026. I just curious like on a more
human level like what's going on in in
your world these days.
>> 2025 has been lots of ups and downs, a
lot of downs for sure. And it's kind of
made me rethink. It's kind of made me
step back and just want to rethink not
just my business, but personal life,
everything, you know? So, I've I've been
in this like introspective
time off period where I've just kind of
been reassessing everything. So, when
you hit me up and you're like, "Let's do
a session." I was like, "Actually, that
feels really in alignment for where I'm
at in life right now." When I look back
on the past couple years and how I've
been living my life, I think that
there's been a lot of beautiful moments
and success in business and in personal
life as well, but I think there's
definitely room to refine things, feel
more seamless moving forwards. I think I
think really a lot of it's in like
business related. Cool. So, why don't we
start with a bit one thing I find useful
is like as I've scaled as a founder
really viewing myself as more of like an
investor than an entrepreneur. And I
think when you look at like the most
successful investors out there, one
thing they're really big on is having
like their own criteria by which they
say yes to things and more importantly
how they say no to [\h__\h] and then we can
kind of use that as like our north star
as we start to kind of like go down and
maybe draw up different offers or draw
up the business or whatever we want to
go with it.
>> I mean, I definitely want to create my
life around play. I think play is a big
one. I think my ideal life is where the
dayto-day feels like I'm at summer camp.
>> [laughter]
>> I don't I don't want to feel like I'm in
a cubicle. Enjoy the people that I'm
doing business with. So the team that I
have, you know, with me on the journey.
I think any new business endeavors that
I'm taking on, I would definitely want
it to be scalable.
>> Okay.
>> That's I think that that's definitely
very important.
>> Yep.
>> Tell me a little bit about like Yeah.
when it comes to just like moving into
2026, looking to recalibrate things,
looking to align things around this and
I'm sure a lot of other things you got
on your mind. What's kind of the real
challenge for you right now?
>> Like the main business that I've been
focusing on since 2021 has been Cold
Your Creative, my online school and
community.
>> Mhm.
>> That has done pretty well for me for the
first 3 years. It slowed down for sure
and that's I think that that's just a
result of me putting less attention
towards it. And the reason I've been
putting less attention towards it is
because I've been focused on other
things specifically my uh the software
that I've been working on dm with in
2026. I the vision or my plan was to put
more attention towards Colder Creative
the first quarter, first two quarters of
2026 to kind of bring it more life, get
more activity going in there and like
just rethink the uh the marketing in
order to get more people in the
community, help more people and, you
know, make more money.
>> Cool. And then on the DM side, what's
your kind of thinking there right now
with it?
>> DM's been a long like in in the works
for a long time. I think like I've been
really wanting to just get an MVP out,
>> test the waters, but we're kind of at a
point where we're just like creating a
final product. And I'm really proud of
what I've created, but I don't really
know what's going to come out come out
of it from a financial standpoint. It's
really been more just like a big
learning experience and solving a
problem that myself and many other
creators have.
>> Cool. When we think about the pricing of
these, like which what offers exist for
these things?
>> So, Colder Creative right now, I believe
the all access is 1,500. Can you just um
let me know what does that mean exactly?
>> It's uh access to everything. So all the
lessons you get access to like the
community which we do yearly contests.
Every year we do a big contest called
the Myer contest. And honestly it's
changed people's lives like massively.
Like every creator that's won that
contest has gotten a lot of big
opportunities come their way. They also
get to go on a trip with me. They build
a a relationship with me and the KC
team.
>> Okay. And so it's 1.5K. Is it an annual
thing?
>> No, just onetime payment. one time like
forever.
>> Yeah. [music]
>> And they get access to the meds forever.
>> Yeah. We want to do uh we want to launch
it as a premium product. So it's free
for everyone. Um and then once you want
to upgrade to the premium features, then
you have to pay pay a subscription.
Sorry, let's add let's add um production
company. I I you know, the production
company, a lot of it is just like me
working on
>> videos, brand deals for clients. Um but
I also work with other creators. I
haven't put as much time into growing
the production company just because I
don't know if that's actually what I
want to be doing right now. But I know
that there's there's that avenue there.
You know, it feels like the focus that
we can really chop it up on is like this
piece
>> cuz it feels like you're about to lock
in Q1 and Q2 is this. We know that this
could hit all these things if we just
engineer it correctly.
>> So, let me show you with like this
business model at least like some ways
to think about it. And then it's going
to be completely irrelevant.
And we can just kind of start to see if
there's a certain model or evs
to what they're doing. They generally
have say like an entrylevel offer,
right? It could go anywhere from say 99
bucks to say $499.
It's like the low ticket thing. Then
you'll have like your typical kind of
like high ticket which is typically um
when people are speaking about that it's
like 2K all the way up to say 10K and
then the last piece is like more of like
a super high ticket. Okay. And that's
generally just basically 11K plus. Let's
just say 11K to like 100K just to keep
it simple. Okay. As an example, as I was
building Founder OS, you know, we really
started in this like high ticket range
with something that was $2,000. Started
selling that gradually increased the
price to 3K to 4K like every few months
as just like demand picked up. We kept
on increasing it. I've helped thousands
of founders and I hear this all the time
that the offer stack framework is one of
the most useful things they received
from me. And so I wanted to go and give
it to you. You can get it for free via
the link in the description. go and map
out your core offer, your entry- level
offer, and any super high ticket offers
you may be thinking about so you can get
clarity on your overall stack and then
take massive action today. Let's just
get into the pieces. So, the parts of
like these offers to keep it super easy.
There's always sort of community is one
component. There's like the actual
systems. There's access to me. There's
support from my team. And then there's
typically like there can be an in-person
aspect as it scales. So there's a lot of
you that are looking to go and build
different sorts of offers. And when you
think about building an offer that has,
you know, education and community as
part of it, I like to go and think about
the different variables that are
included in an offer like this or what I
call the components of a high ticket
offer. As you're structuring these,
right, let's just talk about like high
ticket for a second. Typically like
it'll have some element of like an
online community. could be things like
circle, school, mighty networks,
WhatsApp, Telegram, pick your thing.
That's like one component you have to
play with. The next part is systems or
you know even the material you were
talking about that you have. You have
all this material that these people can
go through inside of Colder Creative and
go and like learn I think all your LUTs
and things like and all the editing
tactics that you use. Access is like if
people were to get like access to you.
>> What kind of access do you give in your
>> Yeah. No, glad you brought up. So
typically in this range you're never
giving onetoone calls. The access that I
give as an example is inside of our high
ticket which is now like a $7,800 offer.
People get access to me on a group call
once a month. I have like as an example,
just to give you different examples, I
have a $36,000 offer, right, that people
are in for a year and they get access to
me once per week and then we have 50
live sessions with my team in a month.
My belief is sometimes as you're
building these businesses, people want
to get to you. But then there's also
like you could open source maybe other
experts that you have because people
would love to meet like your sound guy,
your travel planner person, your color
grader. They can maybe get access under
this hypothetical example to you once a
month, however much you want to do it.
And again, that's a group call. So it's
not you're not doing oneto ones, but
then they could hypothetically also get
access to some like other trusted
individuals that are part of like your
crew or people you respect or however
you want to do that. And then so that's
kind of the support piece too, right?
It's like support from other folks that
you know and then in person. Now, you
don't have to do all of these. These are
just like the parts you have to play
with. I think that like as an example,
this like product like I would have
expected it to be at least like 3 and
1/2K,
>> you know? It's just like 3x more to the
bottom line every sale.
>> And you're now just having to sell like
I don't know backing up like 20 of them
a month to get up to where you're
looking to go versus having to sell like
60 of them a month.
>> Yeah. we wanted to switch it over to a a
subscription model, but with me like
I've always been resistant to that
because I like my freedom and I feel
like setting up a subscription model
creates more expectancy from the
community. You know, they like if
they're paying 3K a year, then I think
that the expectation rises much more.
Like to me it felt a lot more freeing to
just put out content like once and then
you know evergreen show show my whole
system in every software onetime payment
and then I kind of just update and do
whatever I want in this in in the
community when I want I feel like I tend
to kind of try to avoid like added
pressure to my life and
>> and just a couple things just to jam
with you right first off yeah you would
grandfather in all the old people which
is great so then like when you're
selling it as this awesome community of
creatives yeah there's a community of
creatives
>> like you have this awesome pool of
people that you've built up over the
last years that are already jamming,
feeling good, all that. This also like
technically from my standpoint isn't
like a subscription. Initially, you're
just selling like, okay, 12 months
>> for 1 and a2k, 3 and 1 halfk, whatever.
Like, it's just that
>> and whatever you know you're going to do
this year, you're just kind of listing
that as like this is what I can commit
to this year, which is kind of already,
I'm sure, how you think about it, you
know, like you know, generally I'm sure
what you're going to commit to
>> in 2026 or colder. I'm sure it's a
little bit amorphous, but generally you
kind of
>> Yeah. I mean right now it's doing the my
year contest which is something we do
every January at the start of the year
in person kind of vibe right
>> it's just a contest where people can
submit a video where they tell the story
of their year so it would be of the 2025
year
>> we choose winners they win different
prizes the main prize has always been a
trip with me
>> so as you're looking at this stuff so
far like does any kind of questions come
up
>> I'm confident I can you know get get it
to kind of speed up Q1 Q2 of 2026 once I
just start to put more energy towards it
and once I start to put out more of my
own content, which is the plan. So, I
feel good about that. I'm super down to
try a higher ticket price. And and I get
what you're saying. I think the reality
is is like I do think the value that I'm
providing is worth more than 1.5K. I'm
on that same boat. It's just always been
like this difficult decision because I
want to help my community and and
support them and make it more
accessible. A couple ways to think about
this is to draw something out, right?
Sometimes when I think about [music]
structuring these, right? Let's just say
you have your low ticket, you have your
high, and then your super, right? So,
here for you, let's just say this was 3K
>> all access. Yeah. Okay.
>> Yeah. Let's just let's just for Rebecca
and stuff, this isn't real.
>> Yeah.
>> They're going to get the contest.
They're going to get the community.
Personally, if I were you, I would do
their purchasing under this model. Mhm.
>> Do you have any ability to look at how
many people go through the actual
curriculum by any chance?
>> Yeah. Yeah. It's surprising how a lot of
people don't
>> for sure.
>> And that's that's ubiquitous across
every product, right? People buy [\h__\h]
and they're not even mostly joining for
that. Like the number one thing will be
this. The number two thing is this. And
I think in your case, yeah, the number
three is contest. And then the fourth is
like
>> the course.
>> Okay. Cool. No. Yeah. Just double
checking what you call it. I say this to
show you number one like this doesn't
matter that that much.
>> Yeah. Like update like we put our brands
behind these things. So it matters in
terms of like we want to be in integrity
and quality and elevated design. You
want to make sure it matches the colder
brand and all that good stuff, right?
But if people are signing up like from
the data I know, yeah, that's like great
and awesome. Can there be any access to
Sam
>> in any way? Yeah.
>> Right. Keep in mind too like as you're
bringing up like oh the competition all
this. I don't think there's any [\h__\h]
competition if I'm being honest cuz the
kind of people that would come through
for something like this. It's like I
want to hang with Sam and learn from
Sam. The kind of people that would
follow Sam, which is like a highly
created group of fellow like elite
creators that are really looking to
stretch themselves and travel the world
and be adventurous but super [\h__\h]
creative and all that good stuff. Like
it's a certain kind of psychographic
that you attract that whoever the next
person is is not going to attract that
exact person and like they're only this
is the only community where they get
access to you. Mhm.
>> How many people are in it right now?
Back a napkin.
>> Uh over 4,000.
>> Wa [\h__\h] Okay, that's amazing.
>> That's like going to be a huge selling
point then for these people is like the
way that I see it is like say you're to
do a low ticket thing. Let's just say
it's a $500 thing just to name a number.
>> Yeah.
>> What I would typically do is just take a
piece of this course and just that is
the low ticket like appetizer.
>> Yeah.
>> So once you've completed this, you've
completed this.
>> It's not new work.
>> Yeah.
>> It's like Yeah. I mean, you just have to
put up a landing page or and there's a
don't purchase tag here, but we're not
talking anything insane here. Typically,
when you do this, what you would do is
you'd give away the thing. And then in a
couple of the emails afterwards, as well
as within this curriculum, I would have
a quick video from you that's more just
like off the cuff. It doesn't need to be
a like a crazy professional video. Just
more like a, hey, by the way, I've got
this thing. If you enjoyed this, you
should maybe come check this out.
>> Yeah.
>> Like here's even this discount. Like you
can apply the $799 if you want to this.
Okay.
>> So, it's only 24,400. And then this, if
you ever were to do something like this,
let's just say you had a just to name a
number, a 30K thing. This would just be
they would get access to all of this
stuff. Typically, all you do is there's
just added access and potentially again
the things that people typically do is
like some sort of event or experience or
whatever.
>> Mhm.
>> So, as an example, you could be like
maybe you only have five spots in this
and just these people on a quarterly
basis get like their own call. There's
just five of them.
>> Yeah. The main reason I just wanted to
show you this is because I didn't know
this when I was getting going. And it's
kind of like once you have the high
ticket thing dialed in, this is a joke.
And if you wanted to do something like
this, it's just [music] these two
variables.
>> Mhm. I guess where my mind is going when
you're when you're telling me all this
is so sometimes I'm just like I don't
even feel like I'm like educated on
what's like what's what are the newest
things happening in the industry this
and that. Like cuz it's it's not
actually sometimes what most interests
me, you know? like
that and DM
>> just to go off that perspect
and that would keep on buying or
whatever again they're coming for
[music] you like who you actually are.
When you think about going and winning a
category and being the best of the best
in your space, it doesn't come from
going and trying to fix your weaknesses.
It typically comes from leaning into
your strengths. When I look at Sam, one
of his most unfair advantages is the
fact it's [\h__\h] Sam Cer. This guy's
been putting in the work, traveling the
world, worked with everyone from the
Chain Smokers to, you know, epic trips
around Jordan, drone flying, you name
it, right? And millions of creatives
respect this guy. You know, he's [music]
the goat. His unfair advantage as he
goes and builds this offer is to just
get out there, right? And serve these
people. Whether it's once a month, once
a quarter, these people just want to get
to know Sam. You know, when I think
about Founder OS as an example, one of
the biggest unfair advantages that we
have there is the fact that I've been
building tasteful media companies for
the last 20 years. And so oftentimes
people just want to get in front of
[music] me, have proximity to me, be
able to message me whenever they want,
be able to get on calls with me where
I'm chopping it up on the team, the
systems, the aesthetics, and the overall
approach we take to building, you know,
amazing, beautiful, systemized [music]
personal brands. You know, when you're
going and building your offer, it's
important to go and figure out what are
your unfair advantages and go and
maximize those to the greatest extent
possible. We're going to dive into that
here in this next clip. Let's talk about
like the platforms when you think about
scaling it up. Like which platforms are
you looking to kind of get going and
kind of keep on ripping to kind of drive
people to Colder Creative? Like what do
we have in play?
>> The Colder Creative Instagram account
and then my own Instagram account.
>> Okay. in terms of like frequency like
how do you see that [music] in terms of
what's what you can commit to for these
things what are the kinds of content
you're putting out there
>> with KC carousels informative carousels
>> two times per week carousel right
>> or just like any kind of post
>> okay cool two [music] two times per week
and then on your own IG
>> once every month or two months
>> let's just do one time a month just to
keep it simple
>> let's just uh like kind of keep us
honest about like numbers just to
explain how I'm looking at this right
now. Here you do eight posts a a month.
Here you do one, right? So we're talking
about nine times a month are your
current like amount of bullets you're
firing. Let's just say to get to let's
just say back in Akin we were showing
some numbers earlier like let's just say
we we're trying [music] to get seven
members to the community a month, right?
>> So each piece [music] needs to be able
to drive eight people. Let's just say
let's get over to your different CTAs.
How are you driving people from the
content? What do you drive them to?
>> Our website.
>> And so you have, you know, the landing
page for Colder Creative that they're
driven to.
>> Yeah, it's I guess the landing page for
Colder Creative in general or just
directly to the Da Vinci Resolve page.
>> Cool. So it's either Colder Creative or
Da Vinci. Cool. Like this is like the
direct CTA option, right? where your
maybe a given carousel is talking about
like all these like 10 new updates that
people need to know about in 2026 for Da
Vinci and then like hey by the way like
if you want to go and get my updated Da
Vinci pack go and get it here.
>> Mhm.
>> I think the second thing to consider,
right, is like driving these people to a
free lead magnet, right? What people
could do is comment say like to say it
was Da Vinci as an example. They're
given then like some free sort of
resource in exchange for their email,
right? This would all be run through
[music] many chat and now we're
capturing a [\h__\h] ton of emails, [music]
right? And then nurturing people in the
email and driving them over time to
either or both of these, right? We don't
need to just take our one shot in the
post just going right to that. Now we
can capture their email and then market
to them over the next year or two until
like they eventually whether they buy
now or the Black Friday deal or whatever
whenever they convert.
>> Yeah.
>> So I think what you want to do is like
homework is just like look at these
both. It looks like this is maybe a main
thing right now.
>> Try and just understand what that looks
like. Like what are the conversion
rates? So you'd it'd be good to know for
piece of content you're doing. How many
do we anticipate convert when we do
this? And have we tried this method,
right? And if we haven't, let's maybe
try this like for even 30% of the post,
like three times a month, just to see
what happens.
>> Yeah. Providing free value, capturing
emails.
>> Yeah. Providing free value in exchange
for an email and then nurturing them in
an email. [music]
>> Yeah.
>> The key thing on the email side as you
get that going is typically what I'll
have is a 5day free like educational
email course. Like over 5 days, you
could go and educate people as an
example like how you live your dream
life. So now they're even learning like
who the hell you are, how you view the
world, your mission, the kind of people
you help, maybe a bit of the community.
And then typically there'd be like a
4-day, what I call like a FOMO series
where this is all automated, by the way.
So it's just like nine emails over 9
days people get. And then on these four
days, they're all learning about Colder
Creative. [music] And every person that
signs up to the list, you know, by the
end of 9 days, they know what you're
about. They know your mission. They know
the kind of people that you serve. They
know what Colder Creative is about. They
know about the community. They know
about the support there. They know about
the updates you just made on the Da
Vinci Resolve side there and like how
it's like now evolving too to be this
like build your dream life type thing.
And so like every [\h__\h] person that
you signed up knows all of that within
like 10 days of joining. You're now
looking at just what's the conversion
rate of people from how many people sign
up from a given post and by the end of
those like 9 days even how many people
do we convert? I would imagine that it's
like 5 to 10x [clears throat] higher
than this method at least. [music]
>> Yeah. and is worth looking at because
then I think in terms of like a lower
frequency approach, it could just like
really make sense and surpass the goals
that you have and just be like a
beautiful sustainable way of doing it.
And then the email side, I think like I
don't know whether it was like between
one to four times a month having just
like some sort of newsletter that goes
out to people and again I think someone
on your team could make that. Yeah.
>> I don't I think it's just like a general
update on like what's going on in the
community. Like the community I'm sure
it's pretty active I assume. Decent.
[music]
>> Decent. Yeah.
>> Cool. people who I share like cool [\h__\h]
every now and then on it like so it's
like even just like little roundups of
like what stuff's randomly interesting
to you what products are you doing where
are you in the world what's going on in
the community what are they sharing was
there a cool post that week that you
want to share like just simple [\h__\h] and
then people are like oh [\h__\h] what's this
it's like it's from the community it's
like oh I'm going to go and join it you
just have this like steady trickle of
people that are just getting these
emails one other thing that you can like
I think is a low hanging fruit for you
to consider whether you want to call it
workshop master class jam session
whatever once you get Casey like all
updated, right? And you're feeling good
about it. You're like, "All right, I'm
ready to turn on the dial." Like Q1,
you've locked in. Q2, you're ready to go
big with it or whenever.
>> Yeah.
>> Is having just like a free live event
that you do for like an hour and a half.
>> Yeah.
>> Super chill. Doesn't need to be some
like insane sales thing. It's just
people come in, you tell them a bit
about what you've been up to, where
you've been going. People are going to
be like really excited to like hang out
for a sec. Chop it up on like a few
things that like you've maybe been
learning over the last bit that you
thought would be values to them. And
then chop it up. do a bit of Q&A and at
the end let them know, hey, we've got
Casey all updated now.
>> I'm just going to give you guys a bit of
background on what we've been working on
and then give people on that say 25%
off.
>> Mhm.
>> We've done that one time. I've done a
live or like a workshop once it was like
open to the public and and it converted
well.
>> Yeah. So, typically do really well.
>> Yeah. in terms of like the like kind of
like focus of like next steps. First
thing I would look at is like the
pricing side of things, it's always like
the lowest hanging fruit way to kind of
get to what you're looking to do. Second
would be to like just like update
the positioning. [music]
Third, update the actual offer
specifically like you have that Da Vinci
part you said you're updating. And then
fourth, just making sure that the CTAs
[music]
are dialed in around the content. And
then fifth, considering like [music] the
workshop side, that to me feels like the
8020 of like getting to where you're
looking to go.
>> Cool. Yeah. I mean, these are all things
I'm excited to to do in 2026.
>> Cool. We can leave it there. And uh
yeah, along the way, too, obviously just
a WhatsApp message away. So, here to
support you and uh yeah, appreciate you
making time for this.
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. Thank you.
>> Cool.
>> This has been awesome.
>> Thanks, dude. Appreciate it.
>> Appreciate you.
>> All righty. So, if you enjoyed this
session with Sam, you would love this
next one with my good friend Alex Icon.
He's the founder of FiveMinute Journal.
We chop it up deeply on his
infrastructure and how we can go and
monetize his content. So, go and check
out that video. I'll see you in the next
one. Be sure to like and subscribe and
welcome to the Founder Freedom Movement.