it's easier to raise $10 million than it
is to raise $1 million it's easier to
become a millionaire than it is to make
$100,000 per year 10x goals are easier
than 2x goals I've seen this called the
Paradox of ambition and there are a few
reasons for it first there's less
competition at the top 99% of people are
convinced they'll never be able to
achieve something great so everyone aims
for the middle ground this means there's
more competition to become a millionaire
than there is to make a 100 million a
year but even more importantly 10x
schools fundamentally change how you
think because now you're not just
thinking about how to improve
incrementally but how to innovate break
through existing constraints and explore
entirely new ways to achieve success so
don't aim for the middle ground aim
higher dream bigger and your goals will
actually be easier to achieve