Most people don't realize that they're
trapped by this one thought pattern and
it's costing them peace and abundance.
I'll be happy when when I hit 100K per
month, when I have the team, when I have
an exit, when I grow my audience to a
million followers. It's this thinking
that sometime in the future you'll
finally be happy. The truth is it exists
now. And I lived like that for 7 years.
I built my business, hit 500k
milestones, built the team to 30 people,
had a successful exit, and still felt
miserable. You don't need to swing so
big. You don't need to constantly be
chasing some future thing. You just need
to reorient how you're approaching
business in your life and get clear on
where you're actually trying to go, not
what societyy's telling you you should
do. Because often times it's a lot more
simple than you