here are Five Laws of the universe that
are surprisingly accurate Murphy's Law
anything that can go wrong will go wrong
so plan and prepare for it hope for the
best but expect the worst kidin law when
you write down a problem clearly then
the matter is half solved 50% of the
challenge of solving problems is clearly
defining the problem Gilbert's law it's
always your responsibility to find the
best way to achieve the desired result
take responsibility for outcomes and
you'll lead a far more successful life
Wilson's law prioritize knowledge and
learning and money will continue to flow
the easiest way to make money is to be a
constant learner keep reading and always
having a skill you're trying to develop
Falin law when there is no need to make
a decision don't make a decision the
most successful people make good
decisions but they also ignore things
that don't need their attention right
now don't make decisions that don't need
to be made