If you want people to actually listen to
you, don't make this mistake. The truth
is, if you don't structure ideas as
stories, people won't remember them. And
if they don't remember them, you don't
exist. Storytelling is really what
connects us all as humans. It's what
allows ideas to travel. As you're
looking to go and make your brand more
of a household name, you're looking to
build a cult following around what you
do, you need to go invest in your
stories. You know, when you have this
whole story infrastructure, you kind of
have the fabric that people can now use
to understand who you are as a human.
Because when people are able to connect
with you on a deep level, they're going
to follow you and follow your