This system writes me YouTube scripts
that generate millions of views and
hundreds of thousands of dollars. So,
here's how it works. Inside of Poppy, I
have my YouTube goat script writing
board, which has everything that I need
to go and create an insane script in
minutes. So, what I do is I go and feed
this board all of the best title
research, thumbnail research, script
writing research from legends across
YouTube like Colin and Samir, Patty
Galloway, Mr. Beast, and April and
Alter, and then put all of these pieces
together. So, what it's being able to do
then is go and take the best research
out there, go and use my authentic
voice, as well as go and analyze the
patterns of my best performing videos to
go and synthesize all of that research
and give me a concept that is virtually
guaranteed to hit. I know that the
biggest YouTube channels out there have
an AI researcher or a content researcher
on their team, but with Poppy AI, I can
have a lean, mean team and make banger
videos twice per