If you want to make money online, you
shouldn't go viral. Here's what I
noticed. The content that consistently
drove revenue, systems breakdowns,
operations workflows, and delegation
frameworks. The boring stuff. This
content, [music] it's not necessarily
sexy, and it wasn't going to win any
creative awards, but people kept telling
me, "I shared this with my whole team in
Slack." That's when I realized, views
don't equal cash. Value equals cash.
Here's what most people miss. Virality
is just noise, right? It's dopamine.
You're not building a business, you're
building an addiction to notifications.
Chasing millions of views attracts
beginners [music] with no money.
Targeting a specific affluent audience
with high-value content results in fewer
views, but significantly more cash. The
content that makes money is about
solving real problems, not getting
applause. Before I post anything, I ask
myself one question. Would someone pay
$10,000 for this information? If the
answer is no, it's entertainment, not
growth. So, before you post anything, I
want you to ask yourself the same thing.
Focus on high-value content, systems,
operations, frameworks, [music] the
stuff that actually helps people build
and scale.