there's this concept called Mogi that I
learned from a mentor Jesse
ller Jesse's a legend for those that
don't know him and the concept of
misogi is this idea of
doing one really really hard
challenge every
year to test your grit your
might your metal
so that's what we're doing today we're
going on a trail for mountain
biking in the Italian Alps the
dolomites for 87 km
today may not sound like much to many
people and maybe it's not but for
me it's something so it's I think a good
nine or so hours of mountain
biking treacherous Terrain
seven
gondolas through an epic
trail my intention
today is to be a
[Music]
kid i' had written
down a few months ago a list of stuff
that I just really L doing in life and
when was the last time I did
it and mountain biking was one thing on
that list randomly and I didn't even
know I'd be going mountain biking here
and I that
and so today you know it's just this
opportunity to live it up you know
really really live and I think we're
doing all right so far this is the view
about to get a
coffee
going let's
[Music]
go all right we we are off
showered
repaired I
think meeting up with my
guide this is going to be a
[Music]
rip we live in the craziest time ever to
be
alive you know personal brands
or like a gold rush it's never been easy
to go and start an online business you
can work from anywhere crazy
Technologies like starlink give you the
ability to just send it into nature and
to build a business from
anywhere not to mention just the
abundance of resources at our fingertips
tips the ability
to learn anything instantly on a thing
like
YouTube
and to learn from literally anyone right
back in the day you'd have to go to like
a university
or find a mentor in some distant
village now you can just search anyone's
name and go and learn from Top people in
whatever field
at the click of a
button yet so few people actually take
advantage of this and that's really the
opportunity for all of us the
Achievers the dreamers the builders the
creators is to keep pushing
ourselves I I don't think I'm the
smartest person out
there I don't think I'm the most
creative or talented
but one thing I do
have is an insatiable
curiosity I'm always learning always
improving always getting 5% better every
single
day and
that is what makes me different and
that's What Makes You Different too so
keep pushing yourself
[Music]
[Applause]
all right so it's on adventure until you
flip over your handlebars so we just
went down this pitch and turns out this
bike's brakes ain't working so the only
option was to press the front brake and
flip over the handle bars so we got a
little little little something something
there that's okay though you can see
that it it's on a ride out that a little
bruise and how are we doing here you're
taking that thing down we go down this
guy's a maniac your bike you can take my
bike okay one fall down let's see uh if
we can make it through the rest of this
thing uh safe all right so we uh got to
get this bike repaired so where where
are we again Rea yeah one
up eating a massive ass steak here
because you know why not when you're
life gives you lemons you know you make
lemonade
so
wow
yeah local
cow all right bike repaired in an hour
and a half and then back on this
mountain being ain't done
that we're back breakes seem to be good
time to uh maybe bang up another
shoulder let's go and do this damn thing
finish this
Trail all
right so what really could have just
been a massive setback you know leg
scraped up shoulder a little
juicy actually ended up just being the
most profound lesson and just
Community we're at lunch having our
local
steak and
Maria the waitress
there starts calling out people in the
community who could help these guys you
know they're stuck here in arba we got
to get them back to
gardana calling around one mechanic
can't do it no worries calls up another
bike shop sure enough third time was the
charm and we got this
puppy all fixed up so here we are
finishing off this epic epic day like
epic such a good
journey we're going to go
hard but just the amazing reminder of
just in life you know whether you're a
Founder you're building a
startup you know it really does take a
community to build a founder
you know this whole term like self-made
millionaire is just a Croc of who's
self-made you're telling me your mom
didn't do anything for you your father
didn't help you out you you didn't have
a you know Community Helping any friends
that taught you lessons a mentor a coach
yeah this whole self-made thing is a
pile of BS you know it takes a community
to raise a
founder and
so it also takes a community to make
sure Matt gets down a mountain okay this
has been quite the project
so
[Music]
onwards all right I'm calling my shots
here I am
starting a Founder Retreat Center in the
dolomites after being here
for 3 weeks I've fallen in love this
place
is insane
inane absolutely gorgeous super kind
people that you know just just got that
Vibe and I've always dreamed of creating
a retreat center for Founders that's
almost like esselin uh you know helping
people achieve their full creative
potential you know connect with other
like-minded people work on cool projects
together Escape into
nature and explore connect you know fall
in love with just life and so I'm
calling my shot we are starting a
Founder Retreat Center in the next 3
years in the doit this is going to
happen
this it's happening it's happening
[Music]
folks about 50% of the way through
this epic adventure in
sonda and the Italian do M
this now wonder the hardest
things I
think as you you know get
older is to remember to
become
young I don't know about you guys but
sometimes you know things can just get
so damn
serious so damn serious you're managing
people okrs you know performance reviews
all this
BS you you know when you think about
managing a team or you know showing up
for your family or showing up from a
girlfriend or a loved one or
whatever sometimes it's just about not
taking yourself so damn
seriously to or just enjoy life be a
kid laugh Adventure
smile have some damn fun for once you
know think this is your reminder to be
silly makes some damn mistakes be an
idiot be
stupid you know do something that just
doesn't need to make
sense we can be so calculated so
analytical and we lose ourselves and
that kid in US is forgotten about and
the longer you
forget about that kid inside you
sometimes the harder it gets to tap into
it and I think it's that kid that's
responsible
for the art you're going to create it's
the kid that's responsible for the
adventure the fun the
beauty the
creativity you can't forget about that
kid inside
you I think
it's actually the zest of
life I've been guilty
of even to recently just kind of you
forget how to have fun sometimes the way
that you know you can you know like
really going for it losing
yourself losing yourself to find
yourself kind of
[Music]
thing well that's a wrap this has been a
lot of fun two main learnings from doing
my misogi number one stay young and
number two have fun Life is Beautiful
when you just remember to be a kid be
creative and enjoy the moment you're
going to want to go check out this next
video which is going to show you how I
took my businesses from nothing to over
$1 13.8 million in Revenue per year I'll
see you in the next one we're off to
zermat let's go