All right, this is my favorite
interview question.
What is something you've done in the
last 3 years
that is exceptional?
You get a range of responses when you
ask this question.
Anyone,
you know, a straggler's going to answer
this
and say,
you know,
I'm really proud of myself
for, you know, leaving my hometown for a
month
and getting away.
Eh.
Not not exceptional. Not exceptional.
You know, an A player, an Avenger, is
going to answer something like that and
say,
you know,
I was working in a business and the CEO
went away for a month for some health
issues, and so I carried that load, and
I actually ran the business for the
month. Um, renewed five clients, held
down the fort, and it really proved to
myself that, you know, I'm really
capable of so much more than I ever
thought, and this was a really crucible
point in my life, um, and something I've
taken with me ever since. So,
how do you answer that?