I use AI to get what I want almost every
single time. [music] Here's how. I want
to go and actually give you one of my
biggest learnings from Charlie Munger,
which is the fact that humans are
incentive machines. So, first off, you
likely want to have an org chart for
your company. This is what my org chart
looks like right now. What I go and do
is put it into a Google sheet. Now, what
you can do is actually go and get this
sheet, then go and get Cache to go and
fill this out for you. What I'm going to
go and ask you to do is go, I need you
to go and create a Excel document that
has each function in my company, every
single owner of that given function,
their core goal, and then the one core
incentive that we're going to put in
place when they achieve that goal by the
end of Q1. So essentially just what
you're doing is trying to just aim every
single person in your company at a core
goal that helps move your mission
forward and ensure they're incentivized
and aligned with the company's success.
Yes.