Clarifying your thoughts on paper is one
of the easiest ways to become more
articulate. Here's how to practice this.
First off, before your next speech or
next presentation, first go and get a
pen and paper and go and write down all
of your potential thoughts that you want
to get across. Then, often times, what
I'll go and do is take a highlighter and
go and highlight some of the key ideas
that I want to make sure are
incorporated into that presentation.
Now, from there, I'll go and synthesize
all of the highlighted pieces and then
go a layer deeper there, coming up with
the specific words, phrases, ideas, or
thoughts that are going to help them
travel the best. I also make sure that
I'm weaving in my storytelling as well
and have stories for each key idea so
that they're that much more powerful.
Clarity on paper becomes confidence in