I think it's important to understand
that nothing worth doing in life is ever
going to be easy these days people get
so caught up in creating a unicorn you
know hitting a billion dollars hitting a
quar billion
doll I'd much rather optimize for time
in
nature time to
unplug quality time spent with family
and friends and to live a long and
fruitful life full of purpose meaning
love peace Serenity if this sounds
interesting to you I want to cover the
few core aspects which is getting clear
on your dream going and building a
founder-led brand and then making sure
all along the way you are building your
systemized Empire we're going to dissect
all the pieces of these aspects while in
enjoying the
serenity of the Italian
dolomites there are many of you watching
this and you have a dream maybe a
business
idea that you want to get started or you
are
starting and you're hitting different
roadblocks
I think it's important to understand
that nothing worth doing in life is ever
going to be
easy I learned this starting my first
business bitmaker we trained over 3,000
software Engineers over the course of a
few years and the business was sold to
General Assembly it was my first real
success in my entrepreneurship
career that said all along the way I
dealt with mental health issues using
different
substances and it really taught me just
the grit
necessary to build your
dreams I can tell
you that you can build a business that
doesn't solely
rely on just
grit I like to call it a Zen
business you a Zen business is where you
have systems in place to scale your
business so it runs on
autopilot you have an amazing team that
you can trust that every single member
on your team you know that they are
there to do their life's
work it's a business where you're
optimizing it
for peace of
mind for sleep at night not to be the
richest person in the
graveyard these days people get so
caught up in creating a unicorn you know
hitting a billion dollars hitting a qu
billion
dollars I'd much rather optimize for
time in
nature time to
unplug quality time spent with
family and
friends and to live a long and fruitful
life full of purpose meaning love peace
Serenity
all you know a life like
this if this sounds interesting to you I
want to cover the few core aspects which
is getting clear on your
dream going and building a Founder Le
brand and then making sure all along the
way you are building your systemized
Empire we're going to dissect all the
pieces of these aspects in this video
together while enjoying the serenity of
the Italian dolomites
[Music]
Dan's out here you all not a bad View
all right so first things first here
you've got to have a clear
dream you got to have a
dream you know without a
dream where's the fun in life you
know having a dream is one of the most
important things
I think any human can
have for me I wake up every day excited
to help Founders unlock their full
creative
potential and give them the systems that
would make their lives so much easier
than the life I had to live building
multiple companies of the last 15 years
but doing it with a lot of pain and
Agony that could have been
avoided so you might be asking
cool I want a clear dream but I'm having
troubles coming up with it well let's
dive into a bit of how to create a Clear
Vision and dream for
yourself first off grab a pen and paper
go to the link in the description below
and I'm giving you my free vision board
template so that you can go and in just
two pages go and jot down your notes and
follow along here so I'd recommend going
and getting that right away you may even
want to rewatch this video and together
we're going to go and craft your vision
in a matter of minutes okay first things
you want to do is you want to get clear
on your values what are the things that
you know you really value in life that
determine what you'll say yes to and no
to the next thing is what is your 10year
vision your three-year Vision one year
and what are your 90-day goals you want
to be specific measurable attainable
realistic and time bound
now you have this all mapped out you've
written it up the point here too is to
come back and revisit it every single
month it's not enough just to make your
vision one time and forget about it it's
something that you should be coming back
to monthly weekly even daily like I
showed you I do right so that you're
constantly seeing how the little things
you're doing daily are lading up to this
big ambitious dream that you have
[Music]
what a [\h__\h]
dream you told me [\h__\h] 10 years ago
I'd be ripping it in the [\h__\h]
Alps in Italy on a mountain bike for a
Sony
fx3 I tell you you're [\h__\h]
high but here we are
[Music]
as I reflect on my entrepreneurial
career
I really reflect on the
importance of
systems and how much they've really
transformed my
life my peace of
mind and my ability to sleep at
night you know the way I see it there
are really two
kinds of
entrepreneurs type
one and type two
type one is running a business that's
running them into the
ground everything is
chaos there's constant
emergencies your ability to sleep at
night is
ruined you sacrifice your health your
family and your
friends for you know
success but when you actually look at
all the buckets of your life that make
up what success really
is many of your most important buckets
like family friends Faith
fun are nearly
empty so are you truly
successful no I wouldn't say
so type
two
founders run a systemized
Empire they
control their Destiny they've built
systems for all the mundane tasks so
that they can
automate eliminate the unessential and
delegate coreas to weapons on their team
people with high integrity high
energy and high work ethic and they
don't compromise on any of those three
things in any hires they make Founders
that are running a systemized Empire
achieve true Freedom the freedom to walk
away from their business for a month and
come back to a business that's actually
stronger than when they left
it that's what I like to call the one
month test and that should be the goal
of every
founder now early in my career when I
was building
bitmaker I was a type one
founder I felt the pain the agony the
depression the
overwhelm
of the weight of my company on my
shoulders and having no idea though how
to delegate it or how to systemize
it it broke
me but I'm grateful I'm grateful for
that pain because it taught me the
importance of systems it taught me The
Importance of Being a well-rounded
founder that there's more to life than
just building a successful business
that's the Baseline for people like
us we must strive to have much bigger
Ambitions than that have abundance in
all areas of our
life I let the business get to me so
much that in 2015 I had a panic attack
and that was the final straw calling my
dad crying really not knowing what was
going on and needing
help one thing led to do another I ended
up getting some brain scans done it
turned out that on top of the substances
I was using I also had some frontal low
brain damage from some concussions IID
received playing hockey growing up and I
needed to take better care of
myself that concussion doctor then
referred me to getting a coach which led
me to meeting my current coach that I've
been working with for 5 years now Ryan
begelman and together you know we've
really transformed my life I've gone
from someone that could not control his
emotions couldn't find
peace struggled to manage people strugg
struggle to manage myself to someone now
that while I'm still on this journey
right and by no means am I even close to
perfect I have many bad days bad moments
um and each day gives me tons of lessons
to grow upon I've come a long way though
since those days I've been sober for 5
years years I have Rich relationships in
my life I run an autonomous Empire now
with herb I spent according to my EA
last month cuz she tracks it 37 minutes
on that business last month and it
continues to grow at 127% year-over-year
at founder OS me and the team are doing
our life's work keeping things insanely
simple insanely
systemized and having an insane amount
of fun to be quite
Frank I've come a long way from those
type one
days and systems have been the key and
the bridge to getting me to type two and
running that systemized
Empire there are a couple systems that I
want to share with you here and I'm
going to give them both to you away via
the link in the description one is going
to help you with your time and your
energy and the other is going to help
you with the systemized Empire piece of
things the first one is your time audit
system what I want you to go do is go to
the link in the description and go and
get that for free this is a system that
oftentimes people pay me upwards of
$10,000 a day to go and help them and
their team with but I want to give it
away to you for free the time audit
system is essentially you going and
auditing your entire calendar and all of
your to-dos over the last 2 months
you're going to go and list all the
things you've been working on in the
rows from there you're going to go and
mark down does that task give you energy
does it drain your energy or is it
neutral if a
task drains your energy we likely want
to either eliminate it or delegate it if
it gives you energy and it's something
only you can do maybe it's something
that you continue to do so then what
you're going to do is go down the list
of tasks youve just marked down in the
rows and indicate whether you're going
to automate eliminate or delegate each
of those tasks from there you're going
to go create a Google doc system which
is a seven-step process by which you're
going to document exactly how you do
that task so someone can go and do it
90% as well as you and then you're going
to go and film yourself doing a loom
video actually performing the task to
the best of your ability so that someone
on your team can take that off your
plate give you that peace of
mind that Serenity that ability to sleep
at night knowing someone else is taking
care of that task for
you this time audit system should be
able to take 50% of the work off your
plate so you can focus on your zone of
Genius get back your time and be able to
spend more time on what truly matters in
life as well
family friends faith and
fun let's move on now to helping you
create the systemized Empire piece of
things one of the most powerful things
you can do in your company is set up a
company
Wiki I use notion for my company Wiki
and in the link in the description I
give away my exact Company Wiki template
for free with an instructional on how to
use it
so what you're going to do is think
about every Department in your company
right sales marketing Finance HR
operations and what you want to do is
create those categories inside of the
notion Company Wiki this Wiki
essentially becomes like the brainchild
or the operating system for your company
it's a knowledge base so that when
you're on boarding a new employee they
can go and refer to all the core
documents across your company all the
core systems in inside of the notion
Company
Wiki similarly if you're talking to
someone else in a different area of your
company say I'm in sales and I'm talking
to marketing they need something from me
I probably have all the core Sops and
systems inside of the wiki and I can
just refer them to that so they don't
need to go hunt for it waste time it's
going to make your company much more
efficient allow you to scale faster and
build a calm company that can scale
without you which is the
goal so
what you're going to do with the notion
Company Wiki is now that you've done
your time audit system you're making all
these systems and so is everyone else in
your company because each person in your
company should be a systems designer in
owning core systems in their given area
they are then going to go and take the
core systems in their area upload those
to the notion Company Wiki so this
becomes a robust knowledge base for
every single piece of your company so
you can scale smoothly peacefully and
just just have some fun so systemize
your Empire now you'll thank me
later not a bad view though right am I
right or no maybe yeah yeah maybe
right in your back no away you can go
almost anywhere today on a sky
train take a Sky Train