I used to feel overwhelmed every day
trying to do too much try to be
everywhere try to be everything to
everyone and then I realized something
life wasn't supposed to be this
complicated the truth I was choosing
complexity it took me 6 months to
radically simplify my life now I live
with more clarity focus and peace than I
ever thought possible and I want to show
you exactly how I did
[Music]
it because what if I told you that the
more that you add to your life the more
you lose yourself but the more that you
focus on what truly matters the more
that Simplicity becomes a gateway to
Freedom
I used to try to be minimal with
everything you know getting rid of stuff
cutting out distractions stripping
things down you know just throwing
things out just to get as minimal as
possible but the thing is minimalism
isn't the answer Simplicity is
Simplicity is getting things down to the
most essential pieces doing less but
better it's really focusing on what
matters to you what what you're going to
look back in your life and be proud of
and anything that's distracting that's
causing clutter just getting rid of
[Music]
it I realized some of the simplest
people in history found joy in
Traditions tea ceremonies simple diets
Timeless fashion not to make a statement
but because it was part of their
identity why because old traditions
represent Mastery over distraction
they've stood the test of time and they
offer an anchor in a world that's filled
with noise these small rituals allow you
to focus on what's important for example
for me it was cutting out all these
insane ingredients of my food it was
making my diet clean focusing on just
the essentials I had no idea all the
junk I was putting into my system and
the Havoc it was having all my hormones
my energy and my overall feeling around
life so tip number one is the 8020 rule
I came across this sort of way of life
from this book called essentialism by
Greg
mcon the 820 rule is all about focusing
on what really matters in
life so I started cutting out the 80%
that didn't serve me meetings that went
nowhere gone relationships that drain me
distanced habits that didn't add value
see you 20% of clients would drive 80%
of my revenue and 20% of my habits are
going to lead to aboute 80% of my health
so ask yourself what's the 20% in your
life that's driving Real Results what
can you let go of that's adding nothing
but
noise tip two curate your
environment your environment dictates
your success and I'm not talking about
cleaning your desk I'm talking about the
mental environment the people you
surround yourself with the media you
consume the apps on your phone I
Stripped Away all the Clutter both
physically and mentally my phone no
longer has a million notifications my
workspace is designed for flow and I
keep my circle of influence small but
powerful your environment shapes your
behavior so if you're feeling scattered
look around what's cluttering your space
in your mind
tip three is the not to-do list you know
people get so caught up in the to-dos
each day I think the real magic comes in
a list of things that you should not be
doing the not to-do list for me that
includes things like not checking email
in the morning not going on an Instagram
at night installing a brick for my phone
which basically blocks all social media
apps on my mobile device once I got
clear on what I shouldn't be doing I had
space to focus on what actually mattered
and that's when everything changed
all right I'm a lot better at showing
you than telling you so here are five
insanely simple systems that you can
Implement today get your pen and paper
out let's dive in number one here is
establishing rules rules and discipline
equal freedom and so here are some rules
that I've gone and established for
myself so that I can go and have an
insanely simple day every single day so
no morning meetings Okay up until 12:00
p.m. every day I give myself time so I
can schedule 3 hours of deep work 1 hour
of deep work beats 10 hours of shallow
work and so you want to make sure that
you're getting this sacred time every
day in the morning the second aspect
here is a daily workout getting the
blood pumping getting that daily
exercise so that you can go and burn off
steam and be the peak founder that you
deserve to be the next aspect here is no
meetings after 5:00 p.m. it's important
that you're able to wind down before you
go to bed cuz truth is sleep is the
ultimate productivity hack the next
aspect here is batching your core
meetings so if you find that you have
you know a sales meeting or sales calls
make sure that you batch those all back
to back to back so you can focus get in
that mode and then be able to get into
creative mode and batch those sort of
tasks batching tasks leads to maximum
efficiency the next aspect here that is
really important is I like to have an
abundance hour every single morning this
is reserved for really upgrading my
mindset I love to listen to an abundance
medic meditation from bra Proctor every
single morning absolute Legend 23
minutes turn that on at around 5:30 a.m.
and my day is soaring this is an example
of what my calendar looks like so I
actually make sure that I block off my
calendar so it accurately depicts the
rules and the goals that I have for my
dream week you know I wake up I'm
getting that deep work in I'm making
sure I'm eating healthy I'm getting
ample time to walk get into nature and
making sure I have time to also enjoy a
beautiful sunset every evening number
two here is having a Clear Vision
Without A Vision you will perish and so
this is a way of looking at your vision
right what is your one-year vision and
then what are your 90 go day goals to
make that Vision happen when you're
making your goals you want to make
generally three to five goals for a year
and for your 90 days and make sure
they're specific measurable attainable
realistic and time bound now here's an
example of what my one year in '9 goals
might look like I want to grow an at
audience on X in LinkedIn to over 3
million people I want to grow the found
roest newsletter to over 500,000 people
I want to build the founder Community to
10,000 high growth Founders that are
dedicated to achieving true freedom in
their life time Freedom location freedom
and Financial Freedom further to that my
goal is to install the founder
os+ content engine through our content
GPS which is the most powerful system
I've ever discovered in 14 years
building multiple seven figure and eight
figureure businesses and so I'm going
and installing this system inside of
Founders businesses so that they can go
and unlock the same growth and revenue
that I've been able to unlock across my
portfolio of online businesses and so my
90-day plan just ladders up and
basically reverse Engineers the success
of that annual plan and so I'm going to
have an audience on X and Linkedin of
over 2 million people an email list of
over 200,000 people Legends just like
you the founder Community membership
will be at over 2,000 and I'm going to
go and make sure that we've installed
the content GPS in over 2,000 high
growth Founders businesses this is the
plan and it's Bulletproof the next
aspect here number three is writing down
your five goals for tomorrow at the end
of each day right the Super Bowl is one
in the preseason and so you need to make
sure that you're waking up every day
with clear goals in mind you know
exactly what you're looking to get done
so you're not waking up in the morning
and confused so at the end of each day
right make your priorities for the next
day so for me as an example tomorrow I
know that I'm going to go create my book
outline which is dropping real soon I'm
going to send set 10 short form video
Concepts to my team I'm going to make
sure I have a storyboard for one of my
YouTube videos done install three
content GPS systems for three high
growth Founders and I'm going to train a
new team member that I recently bought
brought on board that I'm super excited
uh to level up and you know then be able
to delegate much it has to so four all
comes down to health over everything
healthy Founders build healthy
businesses and so if you're looking to
go and level up this year this should be
your priority so this is an example of
what my health protocol looks like in
any given day in morning afternoon and
dinner I have clear goals in mind that I
know when I go and in Implement these
kind of Keystone habits it virtually
guarantees that I have an unbelievable
day and that I'm Feeling Good Feeling
energized and ready to attack and seize
every single day so in the morning
getting my collagen H2O a little bit of
Honey journaling a little bit of coffee
for breakfast drinking some magnesium so
I say cool calm and collected throughout
the day in the afternoon then having a
nice steak and rice I don't know about
you but that's probably my favorite meal
and then getting into the Sun going for
a walk getting that sun on my body on my
skin getting that beautiful old vitamin
D and last ly having a nice light dinner
before bed and then being able to wind
down so I'm getting at least 7 to 8
hours of sleep cuz great sleep helps you
build great systems and great systems
help you build a great business number
five little bit different than maybe
most of you guys are doing but I love to
make sure I have some core affirmations
that I remind myself of every single day
these become like my motto my internal
mindset OS so my affirmations include
things like I am optimistic I recognize
that less is more I am present in loving
I cultivate belonging and acceptance and
I embrace the present moment with open
arms well those are my five insanely
simple systems that you can go and
Implement today let's go here's the
thing Simplicity isn't about doing less
it's about doing better it's about
making room for what matters cutting
away what doesen and finding Clarity in
the chaos