Most creators are about to become
obsolete. Not because AI will replace
them, but because other creators using
AI the right way will make them
irrelevant. I'm Matt Gray and I spent
the last 6 months perfecting an AI
system that creates YouTube scripts
better than 90% of human writers.
Scripts that have generated millions of
views and hundreds of thousands in
revenue. Here's the reality. While
you're spending your weekends writing
YouTube scripts, your competition is
using AI to create 10x more content at
10x the quality. But here's the good
news. Most of them are doing it wrong.
Today, I'm showing you the complete
system I used to create YouTube scripts
that would cost $7,000 if you hired a
professional agency. Scripts that hook
viewers in the first 3 seconds and then
keep them watching until the very end.
This isn't theory. This is not some
course I'm going to show you. I'm going
to go and build a complete YouTube
script live using the exact same system
that's helped me scale to a portfolio of
profitable online businesses. and I'll
show you the one mistake that 99% of
creators make that guarantees their AI
content will flop. Let's get into it.
All right, so Poppy is this tool that's
going to help content creators make 10x
better YouTube scripts. And so I've gone
and created my YouTube goat script
writing board here. And let's get into
it. So first thing we're going to go do
here is we're going to create a group
inside of Poppy. This is going to be
title research. From here, I'm going to
go and search YouTube. We're going to go
and create something of how to write
amazing YouTube titles. Here, I can see
a bunch of amazing sort of title
research. So, April and Alter has got
some amazing titles going here. Now, I
take all of these and I go copy them
into
the group we've made here. Now, what the
group does is it pulls all of these
together. Now, the coolest part of this
too is that it's transcribing all of
these videos. So, it's going to know
exactly, you know, the learnings here.
When you see this little icon here, it
means that they're in the group now. And
so, those are good to go. We have our
YouTube title research group. All right.
So, now let's move on to the thumbnail
research. So, we're going to create
another group here. And so, in here,
same deal. And I'm going to go and how
to create killer YouTube thumbnails. So,
I'm just going to go and open all of
these different videos that I think have
a lot of potential for helping us go and
grab an amazing thumbnail research that
then we can kind of go and use these
videos to help us go and create this
kind of content brain that we're looking
to create here inside of Poppy. What
it's doing is as we go and we copy these
all over uh to this board, it's
transcribing them and then it's grouping
them. So, it's transcribing all of these
videos
and then putting them all into this one
category of thumbnail research so that
as we go and we look to create our
insane YouTube script writing brain here
uh this thing is engineered ready to go
with the best learnings from the best
videos on thumbnail research. So you can
see here, these are all now grouped into
my thumbnail research group here inside
of Poppy AAI. All right. So the next
piece here, I'm putting another group
together. So here we make this the intro
research group. Go to YouTube and we're
going to put in how to make a killer
YouTube intro. And then we're going to
go and take a bunch of videos into our
intro research group. We're putting
these all in. It's transcribing all of
these like absolute magic, which is
amazing, right? This is the cooler thing
about using this over something like
Chat GBT or over Claude is that it
easily goes and transcribes all these
videos in just a matter of seconds. You
see that? It's like 5 seconds and the
videos transcribed, which is insane. So,
now we've got all of these grouped into
my intro research area. But we're not
done yet. Let's go create one last group
here. All right, this group is our
script writing research. Here we go.
YouTube script writing. We got absolute
legends here teaching us. So there we
go. We got Colin and Samir teaching us
some things. Ali Abdal. Now we're going
to go and take all these and we're going
to put it into our script writing
research area. All right. So they just
get ported in here. Good to go and ready
to rip. So what I'm going to go do here
is I'm going to make a group as well for
my most popular videos. Right. I'm
looking to go and create this script for
some sort of concept around how to
create a magnetic personal brand,
something that I'm known for online. And
so, we're going to go and start putting
some of my most popular videos into a
group so we can go and leverage exactly
how I speak and the concepts and systems
that I'm most popular for. We put this
group together. We call it popular
videos. And then inside of this, we're
going to go to my YouTube and we're
going to go and sort by popular. and
we're going to go and put maybe my top
10 videos all into this
group. So, I can actually in a really
cool way too. This is my channel as you
can see. I can go and take my entire
channel as well and I can just go copy
my channel and I can also just go and
paste my channel in here as well. Now,
as you can see, we have all of this all
in here, right? We've got our title
research, we've got thumbnail research,
we've got intro research, we've got our
script writing research all in here.
What I'm going to now go do is work some
magic on this. We are going to go and
put this in here. And this is an AI
chat. So you saw that in seconds I can
go and embed an AI chat into Poppy. In
here you can go and click on any, you
know, tool you want to use inside of it,
right? But I'm going to use Claude 4
sonnet. Okay. So I can simply go in here
and say, you know, I want you to go and
create a voice of Matt Gray system that
systemizes the exact elements of my
voice that you've analyzed from my most
popular YouTube videos here. I want you
to go and detail this out as detailed as
possible. All of the common words,
phrases, content, intellectual property
that I use that really separates me from
everyone else out there. go and focus a
lot on the core systems that I teach,
the core phrases that I use, and the dos
and don'ts when writing around my voice.
Um, so that we can go and create content
on my channel that separates me from
everyone else and creates a unique voice
that will stand out online. Now, it's
gone and it's taken my entire voice here
and it's created a complete framework
out of it. Right? Based on analysis of
your most popular YouTube videos, here's
a comprehensive system to capture and
replicate your unique voice in
intellectual property. So, core brand
identity and mission, you know, I help a
100 million founders accomplish their
dreams through proven systems, the core
value prop, systems first approach to
everything, organic content over paid
ads, founder freedom through automation,
build businesses that serve you, not
imprison you, right? It knows all my
four pillars of leverage, the AED system
to automate, eliminate, and delegate.
the four W's framework, you know,
working where you want, when you want,
on what you want, with who you want, my
content systems, like my content
waterfall system, content GPS, content
idea machine, and knows all of my
audience growth systems, the founder
flywheel, and then my signature phrases
that I use frequently like proven
systems, rented versus owned audience,
the zone of genius, systems designers
craft their own. I mean, this is insane,
right? The power of AI. So, what we can
go here and do is go and now copy. We
can go create a new text file and go and
copy that all in. All right. So, now we
have my entire voice in this little text
node here. All right. So, the next thing
we're going to do is we're going to go
and create a system now for title
research. We're going to go create a
another little chat node and type this
in. Go and create a comprehensive system
on creating a banger title for YouTube
using all of the videos that I have
inside of my title research group. Go
and ensure this system is as detailed as
possible as if you're the best YouTube
strategist in the world. Go and make it
detailed so that Matt can go and
replicate the best traits of the biggest
and best titles on YouTube and use this
for his own content and be able to also
hand this off to his team. So, the cool
thing here, we're not just using, you
know, AI to go and create these systems
that we can use right now. But if you
have a team of people going and creating
YouTube content for you, you can easily
use this to whip up amazing systems for
things like your titles, your scripts,
your thumbnails in seconds. So, you
don't need to do that all yourself. You
shouldn't be writing all these systems
all day. You should be the editor of
systems, the designer of systems, right?
The architect, not the writer. That's
what AI is for. Here we can see this
whole sort of style guide around titles
is being made right now. This is going
to create this amazing bit of, you know,
just kind of dos and don'ts. It's going
to tell us what we should be doubling
down on and not. You can see it's even
creating different formulas for titles
here, which is amazing. So, we're just
off to the races. We'll let that pump it
out, but it's going to make this
probably pretty detailed. get into all
how to AB test different titles, how to
go and create implementation guides,
different title formulas that work best.
So, this is next level. You know, I've
gone and paid YouTube strategist tens of
thousands of dollars, and what this
thing's pumping out right now is easily
10 times better. All right. So, what I'm
going to now go do is I'm going to
create another text node here. And what
we're going to then do is we're going to
take all of this YouTube title research.
And now we have our system ready to go
there. So we can go and we can bring
this down to the bottom as well and put
it here with my voice stuff. There we
go. So now we have the macra voice
system and we have the ultimate YouTube
title mastery system. Okay. So we're
going to go and do this now for our
thumbnail research as well. So we go and
create another AI chat. Put that over
here. So I connect these two like that.
And then using Claude, just put in, I
need you to go and create an
unbelievable system that goes and
systemizes the best thumbnail research
from the best creators ever here on the
left in my thumbnail research group. I
need you and synthesize all the best
practices of what make a banger
thumbnail that will get millions and
millions of views. Make sure that the
guide that you put together guarantees
that my next thumbnail gets over a 10%
click-through rate and retains viewers
until the end of the video. use all of
the best practices from the best videos
here that I've given you to go and
synthesize a system that I can use in my
upcoming content and as well hand off to
the members of my team. We just let this
thing cook up, right? And look at this.
We're creating some of the best systems
out there for each of these core
elements of a YouTube video. You know,
all of us know, right, that if you're
looking to create a YouTube video, your
packaging is 90% of the battle. Your
packaging is your title and your
thumbnail. And there's no sense
reinventing the wheel when you can just
stand on the shoulders of giants. People
like Patty Galloway, April Alter, you
know, John Yesha, Mr. Beast, you know,
these people are legends, right? And we
might as well go and act like we have
them as our YouTube board of adviserss.
So the next script we need to make,
let's go and integrate all of their
knowledge. And that's exactly what we're
doing here. This thing's pumping out,
you know, all of the different details
that we need there. We copy it. Let's
put another text node together. We paste
all of this into our text node. And then
same deal. We bring this down to the
bottom as well cuz we're about to cook
up some magic here. So there we go. We
got our thumbnail system. Now we're
going to go do the same thing with the
intro. You know, your intro of a YouTube
video when you're creating your script
is a massive part of it. You need to
make sure that that YouTube intro goes
and matches the title thumbnail and also
retains 70% of people at 1 minute.
That's at least the Mr. beast, you know,
bar of quality that we are definitely
aiming for here cuz we're looking to
make a goat script writing prompt here.
You know, this is what it's all about.
We're going to go connect these two. I
need you to go and create a intro system
based on my intro research group here
and go and synthesize all of the most
important points on creating a banger
YouTube intro and synthesize them into a
detailed system that can be as
comprehensive as needed to make a
YouTube intro that gets a 70% retention
at 1 minute. Make sure you synthesize
all of the core aspects, all of the
insider scoops as if you're the best
YouTube strategist in the world. go and
detail out this system so Matt can go
and create YouTube videos that get
millions of views and help founders grow
their personal brands. This is now
creating our intro system for YouTube
videos. The goal again is to get that
70% retention. So, we want our
thumbnails to go and have a 10% plus
click-through rate. We want our intros
to have that 70% retention. You know,
now we're cooking. We're cooking here.
It's giving our curiosity gaps, helping
us get the context and setup going, you
know, the visual storytelling that's
needed, right? We want those quick cuts
that just hook the viewer, get them
enthralled in what they're watching, and
cause them just to sit back, relax, and
enjoy the video till the end. So, I
could go on forever about that, but
let's go take our next text node here.
We copy in all of our intro research
here, and now we've got our intro
system. Put it all there nice and
neatly. Beautiful. One more system here.
All right. So, I'm going to do the same
thing here. I'm going to basically go
and take all of this YouTube script
writing research here, and we are going
to go and plug it in. So, I want you to
go and take all of my script writing
research here from the best YouTube
videos around amazing storytelling and
script writing, and I want you to go and
synthesize this into an amazing system
that details out every single aspect
that makes a YouTube script extremely
retentive, so that the viewers of my
videos watch all the way until the end.
I want this to be as comprehensive as
you can make it so that my YouTube
videos are guaranteed to get millions of
views and retain viewers until the end
of the video. Act as if you're the best
YouTube script writer in the world using
all of the core tactics here in the
videos that I've given you to help take
my YouTube channel to the next level.
So, you can see here as we zoom out,
right, we've got all of these text nodes
being built. And here we go. This is
making our script writing prompt. Now,
you know, going and giving people, you
know, instant reward, proven hook
openers. It's giving me the storytelling
hook, preview hook, statistic hook,
metaphor hook, proof hook, right? It's
giving me all of the different pieces
that I need to go and create an
unbelievable YouTube script. You know,
I've worked with a lot of script writers
out there, okay? and they've all got
their own technique, but why just use
one person when you can go and
collaborate with all of the best script
writers out there and they are best of
the best tactics that they've shared in
their most viral YouTube script writing
videos. I mean, what's better than that,
right? So, here we go synthesizing our
own script writing OS, right? So that we
can use an operating system below to go
and create some absolute banger content.
We go and copy this. Create another text
node. Put this over here. Go and paste
in all of that. Bam. So, we can go and
bring this to the bottom as well. And
there we go. Now, we can go and use the
AI to start coming up with uh some
different titles that we may want for
this video. So, say I'm going to make a
video on how to create a magnetic
personal brand. So, I can go and create
a little thing here. We can hook up my
most popular videos to this AI chat. We
can hook up my channel. And then we can
also go and hook up our title mastery. I
actually want you to create 15 YouTube
titles ranked from best to worst. My
general concept I'm thinking is how to
create a magnetic personal brand. Go and
make sure that this video is based off
the best title research ever and is the
best YouTube video around this topic
that has ever existed. Go and use the
most popular videos on my channel as
some research. go and also use my
YouTube title mastery system to go and
help me create 15 high ranking titles
around this specific subject and go and
list them from best to worst below. Now,
we have this going and researching
everything that's seeing on my YouTube
channel cuz we've put that there. It
also has my top 10 YouTube videos ever.
And we've also gone and hooked it up to
our text node of the ultimate YouTube
title title mastery system. Let's see
what this thing pumps out. So, first,
how I built. All right, here we go. How
to build a magnetic personal brand. Love
it. Look at that. It's even giving it a
score based on the different research we
have here. Work of magic, right? So,
number one is how I built a magnetic
personal brand that makes 730K per
month. Not bad. Not bad. The secret
personal brand system that changed
everything. Pretty good. How to build a
magnetic personal brand in just 30 days.
That one's pretty solid actually. I like
that. It feels on brand. So, we are
going to go and then create a text node
is going to be how to build a magnetic
personal brand in just 30 days. What do
we have here so far? Right, we have all
of our systems. So, we've got our voice
system, we've got the ultimate title
mastery system here going, we've got our
thumbnail system, our intro system, our
script writing system, and we've got a
title. Um, how to build a magnetic
personal brand in just 30 days. Now,
what we're going to go and do, I'm going
to show you a cool trick that honestly
is pure magic with Poppy AAI. So, not
only can you go and just easily go and
copy and paste the best YouTube videos
out there and paste it into the groups
like I've shown you above, but you can
also go and import groups of documents
into this as well. I'll go and create
this group, right? This is going to be
where I leave all of the core documents
that I got. So, I don't know about you
guys, right? But when I'm going and
prompting AI, I don't only use great
references. I like to go and use my own
writing as well because that's what
guarantees that it's exactly like me,
right? It's not just taking random crap
on the internet. I'm going to go and
inject two million plus words that I've
written so that AI knows exactly what I
think on topics and it doesn't even have
to guess. So, what we're going to go do
here is I'm going to go to document and
I'm going to go and drop files in here.
I've got a whole prompt folder here. All
right. And so, we can go and look at all
my prompts. So, I got tons of stuff,
right? I've got banks of prompts around
chief revenue officer, Instagram
stories, and here we go, the YouTube
script writing, goat stuff. Here you can
see I can put my content in here, my
Founder S book that I have coming out
very soon. Tons of useful stuff in here,
right? I've got our different offers.
Um, so it can be trained on exactly what
we have here at Founder OS as well, so
that inside of my business, we have our
offers. The AI now knows exactly what
those offers are. So when relevant, it
can subconsciously go and inject
different languaging into the YouTube
scripts that help drive people to the
offers. Right? So Founder OS is the
business that I've created that helps
founders go and implement proven systems
into their businesses, leveraging AI,
leveraging all the systems that I've
gone and built over the last 15 years,
building multiple profitable online
businesses. And we go and help founders
go and scale sustainably and build the
businesses of their dreams. If you're
interested in going and checking out
Foundest, you can actually go and apply
via the link below. And so I'm going to
go and take all these documents. I'm
going to go and upload them now all to
Poppy. And there you can see it, right?
We've got a group here now of all of my
writing. So not only does this have my
YouTube videos, it's also got injections
of all of the best title, intro, script
writing, thumbnail research ever. And
we're giving this thing a ton of
documentation as well, right? These are
transcripts from calls, transcripts from
my team, transcript of me coaching
people. It's got my entire book in here.
It's got our main offers at Founder OS,
right? OS program, OS velocity, and the
mastermind that we have, right? Which
are the three main ways that I help
founders go and evolve their businesses,
go and scale their offers, their teams,
and be able to remove themselves from
operations, and honestly, just build
businesses that they love. All right, so
now we've got all of this organized,
right? Look at this board. This thing is
stacked up. So, what I'm going to go do
is create one more AI chat here. We're
going to go and actually go and create
this script. Uh, we got to go and hook
up all this. So, we've got the YouTube
title there. We're going to hook up uh
the intro system. We've got we're going
to go hook up the title system that
we've got. We're going to hook up my
voice system. We're going to hook up my
thumbnail system. And we're going to go
and hook up my script writing system. In
addition to that, we're going to go and
hook up all of my documentation. And
we're going to go and hook up my
channel, too. So, it's got everything on
my channel. Boom. Look at that. I've
actually got some other magic um I like
to go cook up. So, this is my YouTube
script goat prompt. This thing is like
top secret, but I can give you a little
bit of a taste of this thing today. You
are a YouTube script writing expert who
generates billions of views for the best
YouTube creators and entrepreneurs in
the world. Make sure the video appeals
to casual core and new viewers on Matt's
channel. The video must be clicked on a
click-through rate above 15%, consumed
to the very end, and then cause people
to convert to subscribers. Base the
video on the trifecta of outlier
research. The video should have the
structure and scripting inspired from
six outliers in the last 3 to 6 months
on YouTube that have gotten over 20x
outlier scores on YouTube. That's just a
taste of it. This thing's actually like
a beast. So, what we're going to do is
we're going to copy and paste this thing
over to the AI chat and we're going to
go and put it in there. Make, you know,
10 YouTube video titles ranked from
best. I like to just check like why not
again, right? Why not why not get a
little bit more um script f we'll make
three ranked thumbnail concepts a
YouTube script for the video title and
then we can go to our text note over
here. This was our So we go and take our
title over here and then just copy this
over to here. All right. So there we go.
We got the YouTube goat prompt and bam.
We fed it all of this documentation.
We're giving it all of our systems we've
gone and created and let's now go and
create our insane YouTube script to go
and blow up my channel. Let's go. This
is just amazing, right? Like this stuff
used to take weeks of, you know, a
YouTube script writer's time. You'd have
to do a bunch of back and forth. You'd
have to, you know, trade different
emails, trade different Zoom calls, be
on one Zoom call after another, review
it. You know, half the time the first
draft is just garbage. You may even
debate just removing your YouTube script
writer and being like, you know what,
I'll just do this damn thing myself. You
know, I've written hundreds of YouTube
scripts. And these days, you know, when
you go and you look at this Poppy AI
system I'm showing you right now, right,
I don't think you'll ever be able to go
back cuz I know for me, this thing is
something I always pass my scripts
through because it's just so insane. All
right, so what I'm going to go and do
now is just go and copy all this. And
what I like to do is then go and edit
stuff in a Google Doc. Paste this all
in. Bam. And there we go. We've got the
script. We know our title was how to
build a magnetic personal brand in just
30 days. There we go. Put that as the
top of the dock. You know, not only do I
have the main title I can go with, but
I've also got a bunch of backups here,
which will be really useful for AB
testing. In addition to that, we've got
our top three thumbnail concepts. So,
concept one, right? Before after
transformation. So, we've got me looking
stressed, overwhelmed at a messy desk.
And on the right side, Matt looking
calm. confident in a beautiful office
setting probably just like this one.
Concept two here, the system reveal. So
main focus, Matt pointing at a
whiteboard with a 30day system mapped
out. Beautiful. This is the YouTube
script. It's gone and made one for how I
built a $13 million personal brand in 30
days. I don't like that one. I'm going
to go and just replace this with this.
So this is the key thing, right? Like
you're going to go and get AI to
actually go and give you a great V1,
right? Better than probably 99% of
script writers are going to give you.
But that doesn't replace you as the
editor of the script. Now, the cool
thing here is that it's actually going
and taking words from my book, from all
those documents I went and uploaded,
right? There's a 300page book in those
documents. There's about 500 pages of
transcripts in there. So, it's going to
really use my voice to go and nail
things like our hook, right? So, what if
I told you that in the next 12 minutes,
I'm going to go and show you the exact
30-day system I use to build a personal
brand that generates 13 million a year.
Look at this open loops curiosity gap
it's creating. I love it. It's even got
all of my storytelling in here. It has
all the background on my companies. It's
a beast. And this is a great script
concept. Now, for some of you, this may
mean going and taking this script, going
and putting it into a teleprompter and
just reading it out. That's one option.
For some of you, um, I know I did a lot
of that early on in my first part of my
creator journey. These days, I just need
a concept. And once I've got the concept
nailed down, just like this, I've got a
script. I know kind of what I'm looking
to do. I'll be more careful with the
hook and making sure I say basically
what's exactly there. But then for the
rest of the video, I like to go a little
more off the cuff, keep it authentic,
and have fun. But this makes things so
much faster because I don't need to go
and spend hours going and creating that
concept. I can have it just whipped up
based on all the stuff I've already
written on these topics, based on my
book, um, and go and create a script in
a matter of hours, not days. So, if
you're looking for your own version of
this poppy board, I've gone and created
a whole board template for you via the
link in the description. So go and click
that. I'll go send you this board so
that you can go and create a YouTube
video to go and blow up your channel. If
you love this AI powered system, you
would love the systems that we have
inside of Founder OS. We have over 180
systems, five custom GPTs that are
trained on every single system I've ever
made. So that next blockage you have, it
can instantly be removed and you get the
ultimate clarity you need on your brand
building journey because I've gone and
trained AI on everything I've ever made.
We have a vibrant community. We have
founder retreats. And we've got a badass
Slack community where you can go and
chat with me, my team, and other
high-powered founders. If this sounds
interesting to you, you can go and apply
to found us via the link in the
description. I look forward to seeing
you there on the inside. Welcome to the
founder freedom movement. Like and
subscribe and let's win