Think about the creators you can't stop
watching, right? It's not their editing,
it's not their niche, it's something you
can learn to do on purpose. It's how you
make your audience feel. The reason some
creators can say the simplest thing and
have people lean in, it's not just
because what they're [music] saying is
revolutionary, it's because they've
shown up so many times with the same
values and the same conviction that
their audience doesn't question whether
they mean it. Trust doesn't come from
novelty, right? It comes from evidence.
When you build your brand around proven
experience or on something you've
tested, refined, and then lived, your
words are going to actually carry
weight. Go pick a hill that you will die
on. The idea, the perspective, the
philosophy that defines you. Then say it
a thousand different ways through your
content, your decisions, your product,
your messaging until people associate
you with it automatically. Stop chasing
new tactics or viral formats. Just lean
into what you already know is true and
then just amplify it.