Following trends won't make you money,
but this will. When I looked at the
content that made me the most money, it
wasn't the polished stuff. It was things
like my whiteboard sessions. These are
me live, unscripted, helping actual
people solve real problems in real time.
People watch me help Ali Abdaal build a
$5 million funnel, or sit down with
other business owners, and actually
coach them through their challenges, and
going deep into the what and how to
actually solve their real problems. Real
systems, no fluff, no BS, just helping
these founders go and scale up their
business. And I think you, the viewer,
get kind of pulled into that room, and
these are the videos that we've actually
gotten some of the best feedback from.
[music] That's legitimacy. That's holy
this guy actually does this stuff.
You know, content without proof is kind
of just a joke. I always say to people,
details create cash. And if you can show
people the detailed ways that you help
folks, [music] it's going to become
undeniable for them to go and trust you,
and actually go and buy your thing.
General advice like, build your personal
brand, it's weak,
>> [music]
>> and it's forgettable. Instead, here's
how I grew my Twitter from zero to
214,000 followers in 12 months using
three specific content formats. Well,
that's proof. So, when you show proof,
right, you collapse skepticism. People
go from, is this real, [music] to, I
need to work with this person.