I'm about to hit a million followers on
Instagram, all without spending a dime
on ads. When everyone else was chasing
the algorithm, posting 10 times a day, I
did something that most people would say
is impossible. [music] In this video,
I'm going to show you the three systems
across content, design, and funnels, and
show you how each part of this Instagram
flywheel feeds the next part to make
[music] things grow exponentially. Let's
get into it. Part one, exponential
content creation. The first part of the
flywheel solves the biggest problem that
every entrepreneur faces. How to go and
create enough content without just
becoming some creator that's stuck on
the content hamster wheel. This is where
most entrepreneurs get it wrong. They
think they need to be creating content
every single day, but sure enough, this
is just a recipe for burnout. Now, the
reality is there has to be a better way.
And this is where the content waterfall
system comes in. You know, just last
month, I wrote a post on systems
thinking, and that one core idea became
a pillar piece of content in a YouTube
video. I was then able to take clips
from that and turn it into three
Instagram Reels, three TikTok posts, and
three YouTube Shorts, as well as a
newsletter for 6 weeks later, three
LinkedIn posts, and three X threads.
This allows you to take one idea and
repurpose it, so you're not on the
content hamster wheel. The key is having
templates that never change, so you can
just keep on swapping out ideas and
feeding them into the same formats. This
is how you go and create content and
become multiplied as a founder. All
right, so right here you can see that I
have one LinkedIn post pulled up, right?
I've hired 90-plus high performers in
the last 3 years. Here are eight traits
I see in every high performer. And so,
in this post, I get into the eight core
traits like grit, relentless
resourcefulness, optimism, constant
learning, not being an you
know, being fun to be around, growth
mindset, and enjoying responsibility.
This one post was something that I woke
up to on a Monday, had this idea for
this post that I thought would be a
banger, wrote it out, and that was that.
Now, I'm going to show you how this one
pillar piece of content for LinkedIn
went and became 20-plus other pieces of
content. So, here you can see on
Instagram, we've taken that same piece
of content from LinkedIn and then turned
it into
>> [music]
>> an Instagram carousel. And so, we have
eight rare traits I see in every high
performer. This is over 21,000 likes,
over 9 million views, right? But it's
the same content from LinkedIn. So,
we've simply just repurposed this into a
carousel and good to go, right? At the
end of this, the cool thing, too, is
that we use the ManyChat feature, which
I'll show you here in just a couple
minutes, to go and get people to comment
the word coffee, and when they do that,
there's an automation that happens in my
DMs on Instagram that drives people from
the DMs to a workshop that I'm running
in about 10 days. So, from here, you can
see same deal on X. Inside of X, I've
gone and combined that same post with
this really high-value image that I had
my team create. We posted this up, and
it generates another 250,000 views,
right? So, this is the power of the
content waterfall, you know, in action,
right? You can see that that first post
got around 3 million views, but the
subsequent posts have gotten around 10x
that. And so, it also becomes an X
thread. This one, in this case, got 1.8
million views, and again, it's just that
same content from LinkedIn. So, no more
work on my side, no new content
creation, it's simply just maximizing
the content, time, and energy that I put
into that original post and getting the
maximum amount out of it. So, same deal
here. This is now gone and become a
community post on YouTube. It's also
going to become a long-form YouTube
video that you'll see coming out on my
channel in the next few weeks. And then,
we also are able to go and repurpose it
again on LinkedIn in around 3 months
later. You know, what you're seeing here
is content multiplied. So, the cool
thing is is that you have an enormous
amount of potential to use these kinds
of systems when you have your template
set up. You know, I have templates for
things like carousels on Instagram or
the different ways that we do stories on
Instagram, so that I don't need to go
and come up with new formats constantly.
We can just reuse the stuff that we've
seen work and then just sub in new
content. This makes it easier for me to
think about the content ideas I need to
create cuz I know the format they're
going to be in. It's also way easier for
my designer, Jan, to go and then take my
ideas and then format them into a way
that we know will work. When you have
formats that work, it just makes your
life easier. But let me go and show you
a little bit behind the scenes of the
formats that I've seen work on Instagram
over the last 90 days, so you can go and
use them for your account. All right, so
here we are in my Instagram dashboard.
We're looking at the insights over the
last 90 days, and we'll rank my content
by the most amount of views. And so,
here you can see some interesting
patterns as to the kind of content
that's performing best, as well as the
formats that are absolutely hitting on
the platform. Here's an example, you can
see that a lot of the different formats
that are working are this one style of
carousel. So, again, it's pretty simple,
right? It's just got the bits of advice
over about eight slides, and then the
final slide of the carousel then leads
people to a DM automation, getting them
to go and comment 30 in this case to get
my 30-day CEO transformation playbook.
So, when they comment 30 on the post, we
then go and DM them a playbook and also
get their phone number and email in
exchange for that. These people then go
and join the Foundr newsletter, which is
the only newsletter to help you go and
scale your personal brand. And inside of
there, they may eventually become leads
to my different portfolio companies. And
so, this is not just how to grow your
Instagram, but also how to drive from
content all the way through to profit.
So, in terms of some other patterns we
can see here, first off, they're all
carousels, right? Carousels are the core
format that is blowing up on Instagram.
Also, some of the key ways you can see
I'm starting this content are with
numbers like eight, nine, and 10. You
can see a lot of them start with words
like how to or how I. Most of these
posts have some sort of number on that
first slide. You can leverage this to go
and use this sort of format for your own
Instagram. I don't put much text on each
slide. That way, it's super scrollable,
and our goal, too, is on each slide of
the carousel to be making it where it's
easy for someone to go and share that to
their stories and it makes sense. It
just results in more shares, and more
shares equal more virality. 4 hours a
week can create content for your entire
week. Here's how it breaks down. 1 hour
is dedicated to actually going and
planning out over 20 different hooks.
From there, hours two and three can be
spent actually filling in that content
with the relevant, you know, systems,
blueprints, playbooks, and deep dives.
After that, you want to make sure that
you have all the right CTAs set up on
the content, so you can drive people
from content to leads, and then create
any relevant lead magnets that are
needed for those pieces of content, so
you're able to drive the leads through
to the lead magnet and eventually sell
those people. This is the
content-to-revenue bridge, and this is
how you build your own profitable
personal media company. Part two,
magnetic brand design. Now, here's the
part that separates successful accounts
from everyone else just posting into the
void. It's about getting people to
actually stop the scroll and follow you.
Most content gets scrolled past in just
0.3 seconds, but I'm going to show you
how to actually go and stop the scroll.
All right, so here we're going to go and
open up my Instagram, and I'm going to
give you a bit of a deep dive as to how
I look at things. Here you can see,
first off, clean profile picture and the
one-liner, proven systems to grow a
profitable audience with content. So,
it's super clear why you should follow
me and what exactly I can help you with.
From there, we have an automation set up
via ManyChat, which I'll show you here
in a second, that allows people to go
and learn more about Foundr OS and how
they can scale their personal brand with
us. Now, from there, you can see over
the last 30 days, the strategy I'm
showing you here has driven us over 34.9
million views. The cool thing there,
too, is that we've done that all without
spending a dime on ads. Now, the grid
here kind of has this
light-dark-light-dark
sort of effect, right? And then you can
see I'm using those Instagram insights
we saw to go and make sure that, you
know, each post and carousel has that
white background, black text. I have a
few different formats here, right? We
have cut-downs from my long-form videos
as one format. So, this is a cool way of
using that content waterfall system from
a YouTube video and using those for cuts
on our Instagram Reels. We obviously
have our carousel format, which cranks
and typically has eight slides with a
call to action at the end. I then have
raw videos where I just film these off
of my iPhone, send it to my social team,
and then use Instagram's [music] edits
functionality to just simply go and edit
up a Reel using the platform and then
post it. Pro tip there is it's a lot
better to go and actually edit your
Reels inside of Instagram because it's
going to be more promoted via their
algorithm. In addition to that, we like
to go and create just other creative
trending topics. So, I'll oftentimes go
and save different inspiration on
Instagram into my different collections.
So, you can see in my saved collections,
I have a bunch here, right? But I have a
whole brand collection that has a bunch
of cool branded videos and such that
have inspired me. And so, I'll
oftentimes use the inspiration in my
different Instagram collections. We also
have an OS Content Studios Instagram
messaging group where if I find
different content or my team does that
we really like, we may go and use those
formats to go then and become different
formats for our upcoming Reels. You
know, as a team, we're constantly going
and sharing different stuff that we
love. We're saving it to different
collections. We have a weekly content
meeting where we're all sharing
different inspiration. And what this
allows us to do is essentially just go
and crowdsource the best formats and
ideas. And so, it's basically 50%
carousels and 50% Reels, and this is
what's allowed me to grow my followers
upwards of 90,000 per month. Not every
month, but that's many months, and it
just shows you the power of this content
strategy. [music] The truth is that
taste is the ultimate competitive
advantage. And in every nine parts of
your grid on Instagram, you should be
telling a complete story. You know, when
you look at my grid, you can see that
every piece of it is intentional. Three
colors, two core formats, and one key
message in everything that we do. When
you go and hit my profile, about 20% of
people on average go and then follow me
compared to most accounts where it's
just around 1%. So, that's 20x more
follows than the average person. You
know, when you go and you communicate a
clean brand, people can tell. It's kind
of like, you know, a luxury brand,
right? People really focus on things
like being handmade, make sure there's a
story and heritage behind it, and that
people can see the craftsmanship that
went into every piece of it. I approach
Founderless and my personal brand the
same way. I want people to understand
the story behind what we're building.
This idea that, you know, we're trying
to do for founders what, you know, Apple
did for creatives in the '70s and Nike
did for athletes in the '80s. I'd
recommend making sure that you're
intentional about every piece of content
you create. For carousels, it's things
like the copy on each slide, the design,
the caption you put on it, and the way
that you run different automations on
the platform. For things like stories,
it's being authentic, showing behind the
scenes, and giving people a glimpse into
your actual life. For Reels, it's being
authentic, taking your phone. You don't
need any fancy equipment, and just
recording who you are, what you're up
to, and taking pride in your hooks.
Because if you can't go and nail the
first 3 seconds, well, you're not going
to capture anyone's attention. And I
approach my Instagram grid with the same
level of craftsmanship. You know, I want
people to go and arrive on my profile
and have an amazing first impression.
Here's how to make your content so
recognizable that they know it's yours
before they even see your name. The key
thing is to make sure, number one, that
you have your formats nailed down.
Number two is that you have a clean
brand aesthetic that is visually
appealing, but also recognizable. For
me, it's using the same font, the same
colors, and making sure that I'm using
the overall same content categories.
Which leads me to the third part, which
is that you should generally have some
content buckets you go for. For me, it's
things like, you know, helping founders
with systems, it's personal stories, and
then it's giving you organic content
strategies. The three of these combined
equal my brand online and the promise
for why people should even follow me in
the first place. It's one part value,
one part storytelling, one part behind
the scenes. And the merger of this is
what builds my powerful personal brand.
You know, in a world where people are
posting stuff all of the time, you know,
it's important that you actually take a
step back and try to define, you know,
[music] what your brand aesthetic is and
how you're going to stand out versus
other people. I think there are a few
awesome tools for this, including
Cosmos, Pinterest,
>> [music]
>> and MyMind. You know, these tools allow
you to go and save some beautiful
designs and concepts all across the
internet. So, that the next time you're
looking to go and evolve your brand,
first off, you can go and create your
own brand mood board. You know, when
you've created your brand mood board,
you're thinking about images, colors,
videos that encapsulate the general vibe
you're going for. This is what then
translates into the formats you create.
So, let's break down this aesthetic and
how it all comes together. Well, first
off, I'm going to bring you into our
company Figma. You know, Figma is a
design tool that allows you to go and
organize all of your design resources in
your company and then share them and
work on them as a team. And so, here we
have as an example our grid preview,
right? This is typically what our grid
will look something like, a mix of
amazing photos, videos, and carousels.
And so, here you can also see it kind of
has that light and dark pattern, right?
So, that it just visually looks
stimulating. We also have sort of a
photo or video and then carousel
pattern. So, it all looks consistent. I
mean, as you scroll the feed, you can
tell it's intentionally put together.
When it comes to the carousels
themselves, we have guidelines for all
of this stuff. Again, intentionality is
everything. So, here's a bit of the
anatomy of our paper carousels. First
off, we have a background with blurred
text. It has that paper texture, right?
So, there's different irregularly shaped
backgrounds of that blurred out paper,
so that, you know, it looks like there's
a real book you're reading in a way that
has that kind of translucent effect. We
then have the keyword of the hook always
in italic and bold, right? So, in this
case, how to make your personal brand
uncopyable. That uncopyable word, it. In
addition to that, you can see that we
always go and put the text in a
minimal-looking way, centering it inside
of the carousel, right? So, that there's
a title, there's a body, and we will
bold any key phrase. This makes it
highly shareable where people can't help
but go and share an individual slide to
their stories, only further boosting
that carousel in Instagram's algorithm.
There's a lot of science behind this
art, as you can see. From there, we also
love to go and sprinkle in these
minimalist graphics, things like graphs,
charts, different illustrations to kind
of mix it up a bit. And so, it's not
just our carousels, right? We have, you
know, Google Docs as well. You know, for
each of our carousels, we oftentimes go
and have a lead magnet that we give at
the end of them. The lead magnet people
get by going and putting in a certain
keyword in the comments, and then we go
and DM them that via ManyChat. I at this
point have created over 140 lead magnets
over the last 2 years, everything from
hiring to a CEO scorecard to creating
intentional content on things like
YouTube and LinkedIn. And so, it's these
lead magnets that actually currently
drive around 80% of the revenue to
Founderless, which is pretty nuts. You
wouldn't imagine it, but things like
Google Docs and Google Slides can be
that powerful. Here you can see a wall
of these paper carousels. You know, we
make a lot of these, about three per
week, you know, 12 per month, and it's a
high-performing content format. Let's
move on to another format here. In this
case, you can see this different sort of
texture, which is just kind of more of
like an old vintage paper sort of
texture, okay? We've gone and we've
curated different references from
Pinterest that we really liked and then
leveraged these to create our own
format. In this case, you know, we have
these carousels that are kind of on a
crinkled piece of paper that follow more
or less the same pattern I just showed
you. In addition to that, you know,
we're showing my key framework. So, the
key thing here is not just the design in
terms of the visuals, it's also the
design as it pertains to the copy. It's
clear, not clever. It's at an
eighth-grade reading level. I'm making
sure that I'm making content that's
super simple, so I'm describing complex
ideas in a simple way, so it's highly
shareable. And we're breaking it down in
ways that you can understand it simply
using systems, rhythms, blueprints,
things that will allow you to package it
up nicely and be able to tell it to your
friend in a way that just makes sense.
We always, always at the end of these
carousels have, you know, a lead magnet
that we give away, so that, again, we're
being insanely generous with our
content. My hope is that below a given
carousel, people go and comment, "I
can't believe this is free." And we make
it impossible for them to not share it,
you know, with 10 of their friends. And
that's what success looks like. So,
let's move on to the different story
formats that we have here as well, okay?
So, when it comes to stories, those are
a little bit different. The key thing I
do here is oftentimes is take photos
when I'm out and about in different
cities. I save those to my camera roll,
and every Friday I do a mass upload to
my Slack, to my designer and my social
media manager, so they can go and post
these throughout the week. The key thing
is that you want to give people a little
bit of behind the scenes to what you're
up to. And so, here you can see
different examples of, you know, posts
around the founder hikes that we do all
around the world. In this case, we're
inviting people to go and do a founder
hike in Lisbon. When they go and comment
hike here, we then add them to a
WhatsApp group, then drop an AllTrails
location to an upcoming hike that we
have. In addition to that, we also have
these kind of raw stories that I also do
to promote different YouTube videos as
they come out. We publish YouTube videos
every Tuesday and every Friday core
systems that I use to run my portfolio
of online businesses, and a big
promotion engine for those YouTube
videos is Instagram. This is the
powerful thing about having an
omnipresent content strategy is that you
can be using the growth on your
Instagram to help feed the other
platforms that you exist on. In addition
to that, you you can also see that, you
know, we're going and sharing, again,
YouTube videos in different formats. One
thing I've learned here is that when you
share YouTube videos, it's good to
really sell people on the exact concept
and what they can find in it, because
you're not just trying to drive the
click, you want to actually drive watch
time of that video as well. If you're
just driving people and then they bounce
on the YouTube video, it may actually
cause it to get worse performance. So,
little insider tip there. So, here's a
little bit more of the inside scoop of
how we got my profile to over 950,000
followers. In the background here,
right? You can see some of our
top-performing formats. And the cool
thing is, right, that these all look
relatively the same. Today, you can see
the strategy, you know, alone from these
carousels is driving over 14 million
views, and our account is growing at
over 58%
month over month. Part three, connecting
content to revenue. But even if you
master the last system, this is where
millions of beautiful Instagram accounts
go to die, because they get millions of
followers, but make zero dollars. And
so, I'm going to show you how to go and
fix that. Go and survey people that are
your customers and ask them things like,
"What's your biggest goal this year?
What's your biggest challenge? And if I
could wave a magic wand, what problem
would you want me to help you with?"
From there, you can go and get a list of
stuff and say a type form, upload it to
ChatGPT, and say, "Hey, go and create
100 content ideas in how-to formats and
how-I formats that go and solve these
core problems for my dream customer."
The key thing here is that we're
actually going and helping people with
the stuff that they genuinely care
about. And when your content solves
that, it's only natural that they go and
then go and work with you. Let me show
you how I go and connect engagement on
Instagram with real revenue and a real
sales process. So, what I'm going to
share with you is one of the most
powerful systems that lives inside
Instagram. It's called ManyChat. It
allows us to collect information,
emails, phone numbers, and then send
followers free value. This is how I've
grown an insane audience through
automations, and what I'm going to go
and break down the exact automation flow
for you here. Now, one of the main thing
I want to show you here is our DM
center, right? This is where we go and
have all of our different automations
and give away all of the free resources
that you see on my Instagram carousels.
There's two kinds of resources here.
Ones that add value and then ones that
add visibility. And I'm going to break
them down for you a bit here. These are
all of the free systems that I give away
on my Instagram. We organize them into a
folder called free resources and then
inside of that you can go and see a lot
of the best resources like, you know, my
1% CEO transformation systems. This is
also where I give my 21 days of profit
acceleration email course, my 7-day AI
email course. It all happen
via these automation. First thing here
is that the user engages with our
content right via a comment or a DM.
From there, then when they comment the
word 50, that keyword then is a trigger
for the free resource. So we have
triggers for a ton of different stuff
like 15, 30, free, you name it. It
triggers different lead magnets in
different automations in ManyChat. What
we then do is then have a welcome
message that people get. That welcome
message also goes and tags that lead,
gives them the resource, and then also
make sure they're added to our CRM in
HubSpot so that a lead is linked with a
core resource that they came in from,
which allows us to then register them in
a way that we can then have that data to
market to them in new and interesting
ways knowing the kinds of stuff that
they're into. So in this case someone's
really into systems and personal
branding. So we're going to go and give
them access to that free resource once
they've gone and given us their email
and potentially their phone number. So
from there, there are different pathways
people go, right? The first step is that
they want the resource and we give it to
them and they go down that path. The
second path is that they say that
they're not interested and then the
whole automation just stops. The second
step then is once the user has engaged,
we then give them the content and
they're actually going to go and get
this whole resource which typically is
it either in a Google Doc or in Google
Slides. All along the way we're tagging
different people, right? So this is all
getting organized into a robust way, but
it also feels very organic and super
human. Right? We're making sure that the
messages are actually handcrafted by me
so that they sound like me. So we're
trying to give an insane amount of
generosity, make it feel human, while
also going and showcasing the power of
our automations and systems. And so if a
founder goes and wants a given lead
magnet, they just click yes, we'll send
it over to their email, and voila, they
have it. You know, I think that so many
people go and treat their audience just
like some number and we want to go and
treat each person in my audience as if
it was our best friend. Really helping
them out, helping them overcome
challenges and obstacles, and make sure
that every interaction that we have with
them dazzles them. I think when you
stack this up over years, that's how you
create a brand that matters. The metrics
most people care about have zero
correlation with actually driving
revenue. But these three metrics I'm
about to show you are the ones that
actually matter. This is going to show
you the difference between content ROI
and just some vanity metrics. So first
off, you want to look at email sign-ups
per post. You know, we go and track this
all through HubSpot so we can understand
via HubSpot and ManyChat which carousels
we're putting out drive the most leads.
You know, inevitably you want your
content to convert to your owned
audience because you don't own
Instagram, but you should own a
newsletter. And each post should be
driving folks to that list. So that is
metric number one. Your second metric is
your revenue per follower. You know, you
should know your cash collection per
month per platform and then be able to
know which posts are driving you the
most revenue. You can easily do this
when you have the right tagging system
on the back end in ManyChat and HubSpot.
You know, we use HubSpot as our core CRM
inside of FounderOS. It allows us to tag
different people based on where they
came in. This allows us not just to
understand our profit per subscriber,
but also understand which content is
converting best so that we can go and
double down on those content topics. You
also want to know your Instagram
conversion rate from traffic, right? Of
the amount of traffic you're driving
from Instagram, how many of those people
are becoming customers? Where this
becomes interesting is that let's just
say in June you were pursuing one
content strategy and you changed that up
a little bit in August. Well, it would
be nice to know that based on the amount
of traffic that you drove to your
website or to your apply page or a
landing page, how much of that traffic
actually converted and which strategy
was more efficient with the traffic. So
when you understand conversion rates,
you can understand and make tweaks to
your content, to your topics, and your
overall approach. Part four, building a
team. Here's the bottleneck that kills
most companies before they even start
gaining momentum. You need to get the
right team on board in the right order.
Here's why the fastest growing accounts
aren't run by the hardest working
founders, they're run by the smartest
hiring founders. One of the biggest
things you can do if you're looking to
grow your account is get [music] great
at delegating. The reality is is that
you shouldn't just be building a
personal brand. You need to be building
a personal media company and moving from
the creator behind your brand to the
CEO. So this all comes down to then
having the right people in the right
seats. First off, it's having a social
media manager on board to help be that
head of distribution. Making sure that
you're putting the right content in the
right format at the right time of the
day with the right caption so you don't
have to have your finger on the trigger
7 days a week and can instead be getting
some support. From there, you're
probably going to want to go and bring
on a designer. Generally around 3K per
month, this is the person that's going
to help make your account and your grid
visually stunning. The next aspect then
is an editor. You know, going and
creating reels every day takes a hell of
a lot of time. And video editors,
they're maestros at this. So you can get
generally going with someone for around
3 to 5,000 dollars per month and
actually have someone professional going
and helping you make your reels and your
videos dialed in for performance. You
know, this team you're kind of looking
at 10 to 12K per month, which a lot of
founders could look at and go, "Damn,
that's expensive." But the thing is
this, right? You got to look at
everything as an investment. You have
the average customer to you is worth
10,000 dollars of profit per year and
your team costs between 10 to 12K. If
that whole team brings on one
incremental customer per month, they pay
for themselves. So the reality is it's
actually pretty insane not to get the
right team in place and you're leaving a
ton of money on the table if you don't.
All right, I'm going to go and show you
how to go and determine whether that
next hire you're going to make is
actually going to make you money or just
cost you a bunch of money. So this is my
delegation math calculator and you go
and find this resource via the link in
the description and here's how it works.
So let's just say we're going to go and
hire a social media manager and that
person is going to go and cost us 7,000
dollars a month as an example, okay? Now
hold your horses here. We don't know if
this person actually makes sense because
it's not about looking at the expense,
it's about looking at the return on
investment, which is what this
calculator is all about. Let's just say
that your revenue per hour, okay? If you
were not focused on posting content, but
instead were on sales calls, let's just
say that, you know, the revenue that you
would generate per hour yourself is
2,000 bucks, okay? And let's just say
that that social media manager is going
to save you around 20 hours a week or 80
hours a month. Well, lastly, let's just
say the profit margin of what you're
building is 50%. Here we can see this
delegation math in motion, okay?
When you go and you reallocate those 80
hours a week that you're saving to
actually going and generating that 2,000
dollars per hour that you're worth,
that's 160,000
dollars of incremental revenue a month.
At a 50% margin, that's 80,000 dollars
of profit. That is money on the table
that you were leaving by doing all of
this social media manager work that's
candidly just below your hourly rate. So
the profit after the hire, which is 80K
minus 7K, is 73,000 dollars, which is a
10.4X
ROI on that 7,000 social media manager
salary. This is how you think about
building your team, which is going and
stacking your team with hires that have
an insane ROI and delegating the stuff
that you should not be working on so you
can double down on the stuff that only
you can do. This is the kind of stuff
that we actually give founders inside of
FounderOS. You know, we have all the
core systems for X, for LinkedIn,
Instagram, YouTube, and also for
building your personal media company.
And what I'm going to give you is some
of the core systems for things like the
social media manager scorecard, how to
go and hire your own chief of staff, how
to go and hire a designer with that
scorecard, as well as a copywriter
scorecard. And you can go and find all
four of these inside of the description
below and go and download them. If
you're looking to go and get more
systems just like this, you should
definitely consider joining FounderOS.
You'll get access to me, my C-suite,
join founder retreats we host all around
the world, and be able to hop on daily
calls with my team to help get you the
support you need as you're building your
own personal media company. You can go
and check it out and apply via the link
in the description. But here's what
separates the people that actually build
this from the people that are just going
to go and watch this video and do
nothing. It all comes down to taking
real action. Here's the good news. I've
gone and synthesized every blueprint,
automation, and playbook that you've
seen in this video and put it into my
Instagram flywheel blueprint, which you
can go and get via the link in the
description. I want to see you take
massive action, build your personal
media company, and grow an amazing
audience on your Instagram. I can't wait
to see what you create and let's win
together.