All right, I got a confession to make. I
am more of an artist than an
entrepreneur. I'm not actually that
obsessed with systems for systems sake.
Systems are something I create so that I
can get the freedom to get out of the
that I hate and focus on the kind
of stuff I love. My inner soul, right,
is an artist. Someone that loves free
time and space to think, to scheme, to
plot, really to build, too. I talked to
founders all too often. In their heart
of hearts, right, they're an artist just
like me. But somewhere along the way,
you know, they built an offer, they grew
a team, they're making money now, and
they're kind of larping as a CEO.
But when they actually go and take some
time to reflect, right, they get some
space from their business, they realize
in some way, shape, or form they're kind
of losing themselves. And I think
there's so many of us, right, that at
the end of the day we just want to be
creative, right, we want to build great
products with customers that we
genuinely love. We want those products
to be sold to a, you know, smaller group
of amazing humans that really value what
we do and will pay us great prices to do
those things so that we can run, you
know, a really, like, lean, beautiful,
cash-flowing lifestyle business. Yeah,
live vibrant lives, make an impact, and
have fun.