Five signs that 2026 is your year.
Number one, you've stopped asking how do
I feel and started asking what needs to
get done. Stick to the plan, not your
mood. Number two, you're more bored by
your excuses than you are scared of your
goals. And at some point, you've just
got to go and take action. Let [music]
the action and compounding work its
magic. Number three, you've done an icky
guy to align your goals with your deeper
purpose. You know, you want to look at
the intersection of what you're great
at, what the world needs, what you love
to do, and what you can be paid for,
right? The intersection of that is your
calling in life. And when you go and
work on stuff in there and maximize it,
you're having fun every day and you're
living in your calling. Number four,
[music] you've accepted that discomfort
isn't a problem to solve. It's a tax you
pay for a better life. The reality
[music] is is that building is
hard, right? But you got to choose your
heart at the end of the day. Choose
[music] the discomfort that you know you
know you're not going to regret in 20
years. Number five, you're tracking
numbers for health, money, and time
instead of vanity metrics. It's not
about how good you feel healthwise all
the time. Go and get your blood work
done on the money side, right? It's not
just how you feel about your wealth,
right? It's like, okay, are you actually
putting some money aside? And on the
time side, it means doing an actual time
audit, right? And looking at what you
need to [music] automate, eliminate, and
delegate, right? It's in the details and
in the data that you can understand your
progress.