I think every entrepreneur is an artist
at heart, right? But somewhere along the
way, you know, you started making money,
found yourself building out a team,
things started scaling.
I think it's natural that sometimes
we lose the art of it all.
You find yourself with a bloated team
wondering, "What the hell is even going
on anymore?
I don't really enjoy this work."
I know I've been there before, right? My
second business, Herb, early days,
I lost it, right? I lost the artist's
way.
And so,
what do founders really want, I think?
I think at our core, right, we're
artists, right? We want an autonomous
engine behind us. We want to do stuff we
love, help people that we love, work
with people that fire us up, building a
product that people genuinely want. And
so,
shout out to my fellow artists, right?
Cheers to you. Let's go.