So, there are two kinds of businesses.
Those kinds that go and give you
freedom, and then the kind of business
that just takes it away from you. You
know, you get into business to create
something beautiful, something amazing,
but before you know it, you're growing
the revenue, the team, and everything
just starts to feel heavy. You've built
a house of [music] cards. I know because
this is exactly how I felt building my
first business. But, over the last 16
years, I've gone and built three more
successful companies, studied more than
400 different businesses, and I've come
up with the most beautiful business
[music] in the world. And so, in this
video, I'm going to go and break down
the traffic, the entry points, the math,
the team, and the real goals behind this
whole model. And after years of studying
over 400 businesses, I realized that
this was the exact model I wanted to
build. Thousands of founders come to me
to go and install this exact beautiful
model in their businesses for them.
Let's get into it. Phase one, we have
traffic. When it comes to going and
building the most [music] beautiful
business, your traffic really should be
mostly coming from organic content. And
when we think about organic content, you
know, it's really about going and
dominating the main platforms and
creating an omnipresent brand over time.
Meaning [music]
that you are everywhere all the time for
your dream customers. Where are people
hanging out? They're on platforms like
YouTube, they are hanging out on
LinkedIn, on X, on Instagram. And while
it's important to make sure they're
going and driving traffic from the
social platforms, the reality is this
just represents your rented audience.
Because you don't actually own the
audience on these platforms. It's owned
[music] by Zuck and Musk. And if you
just rely on these platforms, well,
that's what we like to call platform
risk. So, it's important that you
actually own these people inside of your
own newsletter, which should be another
traffic source for you, as well as have
[music] email sequences inside of that
that are nurturing people to your brand,
your story, and the movement that you're
creating behind your beautiful business.
On the traffic side, initially, what
you're going to want to do is focus on
one core platform. When I first got
going, it was X. X was a platform, it's
kind of like, you know, the Olympics of
copywriting. It was this awesome
opportunity for me to take these ideas
that were in my head, these ideas to
help founders with systems they could
have freedom to travel the world, work
from wherever they want, whenever they
want, hire whoever they want, and build
the business of their dreams. And so, I
started sharing these blueprints, these
systems, the things that I wish I had
five years ago when I was just getting
started building businesses. Initially,
being omnipresent can feel a little bit
overwhelming. Like anything in life,
right? The real returns are going to
come over the long term. And so, what
you want to think about is starting on a
platform where you feel most comfortable
and where most of your customers
actually are. And so, when I think about
these, right? YouTube for me is all
about relationships, cuz you have that
long-form value people tuning in to a
20-minute video, sitting back, relaxing,
and really getting to know you in a
really rich format. LinkedIn is
obviously just the ultimate kind of
professional network. So, if you're
targeting business owners, other
professionals, this is a great platform
to on the B2B side to really attract
people. And in terms of Founder OS, the
business that I run, it goes and
probably drives around 50% [music]
of the leads to our business. Now,
X is amazing for going and refining your
ideas. When ideas do well on X, they are
likely to do very well on platforms like
LinkedIn, Instagram, and even YouTube.
Now, Instagram is amazing
>> [music]
>> on the lifestyle side, right? Giving up
people a bit of a behind-the-scenes as
to who you are and what you're all
about, right? So, this is kind of the
BTS, behind-the-scenes vibe. So, people
can get to know, you know, who you are
as a founder, you know, what your
mission is, your movement, and get to
know you a little bit more as a
character. Now, on the newsletter side,
this is where we're building rich
one-to-one relationships with folks.
When you go and you publish a piece of
content on social, you're lucky if like
10% of your audience actually goes and
sees that piece of content. Because the
algorithms don't surface you to
everyone. On newsletters, when you
actually go and capture someone's email
and you send that email out, you get in
front of 100% of people's inboxes, and
that's the magic of actually going and
owning your audience. And so, your email
list is the most [music] valuable piece
of your media empire as you grow it. So,
let's get into it, bit of signal versus
noise. The issue is if you're too
focused on the metrics that the
platforms bubbling up, things like
likes, engagement, and comments, you can
quickly get into a game of just making
viral noise versus creating content that
actually matters and is attracting your
dream customer. The question is then,
how do we lean in to signal? [music] I
think the key thing here is to actually
go and talk to your actual customers,
your [music] most valuable customers,
the kind of people that you want to
attract more of them. And ask them
questions like, "What's your biggest
goal right now? You know, what's
currently keeping you up until 2:00
a.m.? And if I was to wave a magic wand,
what would be one thing you would most
want my help with?" Now, the answers to
these sort of questions will start to
give you a clear understanding of what
their heaven is in terms of what they're
trying to get to, and also what their
hell is, the thing that they're trying
to avoid. And based now on their dreams,
>> [music]
>> their desires, and, you know, the
nightmares they're having, you can then
construct a rich content strategy that
is sure to go and make it feel like
you're reading the minds of your dream
customers. And this is what signal is
all about. You want people coming across
your content and going, "Oh my god, I've
been waiting for someone to go and say
this." And it's that kind of content
that it may not get the most likes, it
might not get the most views or
engagement, but it will drive you the
most people to your actual product or
service. So, all this traffic done right
only matters if you have the right entry
points. That is phase two. Your entry
points. What the hell is an entry point
in the first place? This is essentially
the intentional place that you are
sending all of that traffic you're
driving across your content to a core
place where people can learn exactly
what you do, how you can help them, and
are quickly directed towards revenue.
The more [music] efficient you are at
driving content to revenue, the more the
flywheel of your entire business can
really get ripping. So, where do most
people screw up? Most people drive folks
to a freaking home page. Now, let me
tell you, that ain't the way. Because
your home page isn't intentionally
driving people to what you do. [music]
Typically, there are a few core places
that I drive all of this traffic to,
[music] and let me break it down for you
here. On my website, founderOS.com, we
have, first things first, a newsletter
page. Like I just mentioned over here,
right? Your email list is the most
valuable asset in your business. And
over the last four years, I've been able
to grow a list of over 225,000
high-growth founders inside of the
Founder OS newsletter. And it's
responsible for driving around 60% of
our profits. Now, [music] the second
entry point I like to think about is a
workshop. So, in any given month, the
calendar in terms of the call to action
that we have across our content looks
something like this. What that is
exactly is that for 20 days of the
month, we're driving people to the
newsletter, and then for 10 days of the
month, we're driving people from my
content to the workshop. Now, what the
hell is a workshop? Well, whether you
call it a workshop, a masterclass, a
webinar, essentially, it's an awesome
opportunity for you to get in front of
your audience to educate them on some
specific value, give them a bit of like
an appetizer as to how you can go and
help them, and then go and offer them up
the full meal in terms of the product or
core service that you can help them with
and drive folks from the workshop to
actual revenue. Now, [music] the third
point here is by far the most important.
And for Founder [music] OS, it is our
apply page. Now, Founder OS is a
community of high-growth founders that
I've created over the last four years.
We've helped over 13,000 founders go and
systematize their founder-led brands and
remove themselves from operations.
Inside, as I'll get here in a second, we
go and give founders 30-minute
one-to-ones with me every other week.
I'm available anytime via WhatsApp. We
have over 50 live sessions per month
with my team, over 180 systems that the
founders get access to, [music] plus
seven core team members on their team,
epic founder retreats, and so much more.
So, what I've just shown you here is
these three [music] entry points, right?
It's these three pages that I see most
founders missing out on. And when you
get these in place, you're able to
efficiently monetize the traffic over
here. And when you're efficiently
monetizing, you're about a third of the
way there to building the most beautiful
business model in the world. [music] All
right, so here's where it gets
interesting. You've got your traffic,
you've got the entry points, but now you
need to actually give these people
something to buy. And this is where most
founders go and screw everything up. So,
let's get into the products. Here we go.
When you think about your products,
okay? I have a whole [music] kind of
approach at Founder OS, and I talk to my
team about this all the time, and I
help, you know, thousands of other
founders with this. And the general
philosophy is that you always want to be
in the money. It's likely that as you're
building a business, you're attracting
people from all different backgrounds.
People that maybe are just getting
started all the way to people that are
going and scaling up eight-figure type
businesses. When it comes to your
products, okay? You're going to go and
you're going to have people, in in
example of Founder OS, that are just
getting started with business, and then
the kind of people that again are doing
eight figures with their companies. And
[music] how I like to to see it is that
no matter what people are coming from
and their experience, we have ways of
serving them, right? Whether that's with
entry-level products that are $29 or,
[music] you know, intimate proximity
offers where people are working directly
with me every week and every month for
hundreds of thousands of dollars. With
our products at FounderOS, okay? We have
a core thesis. People follow people,
then they follow brands. And that the
future of entrepreneurship will be led
by founders that are building their
founder-led brands. And [music] that the
most beautiful way to go and build a
founder-led brand is for it to be
systematized and you need it to be
profitable so you can build an amazing
team around you. Every product,
essentially, is all around that core
thesis. Let's talk about three core
tiers here. We've got kind of your
entry-level here. And these are
typically products that range anywhere
from $29 all the way to say $300.
Examples here in FounderOS that we have
things called Personal BrandOS, YouTube
for CEOs, and LinkedIn for CEOs. And we
typically launch an entry-level offer
once [music]
every 3 months. Now, I'm not launching
these offers because I'm looking to make
a bunch of money. Candidly, what I'm
looking to do with these is actually go
and give people a taste of what we can
do for them. And this ends up becoming a
bundle of leads for our team to go and
nurture over the coming year. Now, the
next aspect here is, say, a core offer.
At FounderOS, we have offers from 7,800
on this side all the way to 36,000.
Okay? Lastly, then, we have our kind of
like higher-ticket offers. And this is
where we have offers that range [music]
from 100,000 to 250,000. Now, at the
highest range here, what are we exactly
helping with? Why are What What would
someone pay us this much money for?
We've been building these founder-led
brands and media companies for over 16
years now. And there are big, high-level
founders and teams that want our help
actually going and building systems for
their companies, helping them go and
scale up their own media empires,
helping the founders remove themselves
from operations, and helping them
connect with the [music] best
copywriters, video editors, chief of
staffs, EAs, and the team necessary to
build this [music] beautiful business.
On the high side here, you can think
that there's oftentimes with this model,
right? Kind of four core levers that you
have to play with, okay? There is number
one, kind of education, which in the
case of everything we do at FounderOS,
when we're talking at the high level, we
have over 180 systems that we give
founders that help them go and implement
the same tactics that we've used on our
YouTube to get it to 200,000 subs, on
our X profile to get that over 300,000
people, on LinkedIn to get that to over
850,000 people, and on Instagram to get
it to over 950,000
followers. All of this, by the way,
without spending a dime on ads. Now, the
next aspect here is the actual support.
[music]
At FounderOS, the support that we offer
is with what we call founder success
managers. We've got a number of legends,
including Claire, Shawn, [music] and
Yelena here on my team that all they
eat, sleep, and breathe is dazzling
founders and making their journey to
building a scalable founder-led brand
joyful, easy, [music]
and fun. And so, we have over 50 live
sessions every single month inside of
FounderOS so that founders are never
more than like 6 hours away from getting
the support that they need. Now, that's
not it, okay? The third aspect that you
have to play with when you're doing this
is proximity. What I mean by this is how
much access does someone get to you?
Now, this is one of the key aspects
that's going to change depending on
whether someone's high, core, or entry
with you. So, let's talk about high as
an example. In a super high-ticket
offer, like a $250,000 offer at
FounderOS, people are going to get
weekly sessions with me, weekly sessions
with my C-suite. They're going to be
able to text me anytime they need me.
You know, I'm even willing to go and
have them in a whiteboard session like
this, fly out to me, and jam with them
in person. You can see that that
proximity is changing based on whether
someone's in this offer or in this one.
Now, the last aspect is community.
When you're talking about entry-level
offers, okay? Let's talk about that for
a second. These lower-ticket offers
typically just have education, right?
You're simply just giving someone, you
know, 10, 12 modules, a taste of what
you do, but they need to do it all
themselves. As you start to move to core
offers, this is where you may have a
school community set up with all of the
core systems, the support. And in there,
you're now allowing people maybe inside
of a school community, in Slack, in
Circle, Mighty Networks. It doesn't
really matter the platform, but you're
starting to kind of create that
community atmosphere. As people move up
higher and higher up the offer stack,
this is where you may actually start
throwing in-person experiences. And at
the highest level here, we have two epic
in-person experiences that we host in
places like Bali, Sedona, Mexico City,
and coming up in the Dolomites, Italy.
[music] It's these four levers that you
have to play with depending on the stage
that someone's at. Now, you've got your
kind of offer stack mapped out. I've
given you mine as some inspiration here.
And what we now want to get into is the
content GPS, which is phase [music]
number four. The content GPS is by far
the most powerful system I've ever
created in the 16 years I've been
building companies. And what it does is
essentially efficiently drives people
from your social audience all the way
through to your owned audience and
monetizes them and then creates a
flywheel where you can reinvest that
capital back in to your audience growth,
thereby creating essentially a profit
and founder flywheel here. So, let's get
into how this works. So, first off,
you've got your personal media company
being built here. And this is what
founders [music] inside of FounderOS,
okay, get my help with is actually going
and setting up their team correctly. You
know, oftentimes, there's [music] two
different routes that a founder will go.
Route number one is that they're going
more writing first initially. They may
need help with a writer, a newsletter
writer, a social media manager to go and
help them start growing on platforms
like X and LinkedIn [music] with a
newsletter. The second route is that
they decide to go more video first. And
in that case, they're looking for video
editors, a social manager, a thumbnail
designer to start scaling on platforms
like YouTube, Instagram, and TikTok.
We're driving our cold audience here,
okay? And essentially driving these
people down to our owned audience, okay?
And as I mentioned here on the platform
side [music] and traffic, our owned
audience is going to come through our
newsletter as well as monthly workshops.
It is this cadence of essentially using
[music]
the 30 days of content that we put out,
we're going to drive 20 days to the
newsletter, and 10 days of that content
to the workshops. When people are in
these things, that's when we start
driving them to
>> [music]
>> actually go and work with us, okay? And
this is typically where you'd go and set
up
>> [music]
>> your application router. Now, what this
means is that we're using some smart
tech [music] inside of the apply funnel
to make sure that we're routing the
right people to the right [music] thing
in our offer stack. If someone's just
getting started as an example, we're
going to send them to more of our entry
offers. If we're talking to a founder
that's going from six figures to seven
figures to eight figures, we're going to
go and talk to them about other offers
that would be much more suitable to
them. And [music] so, having this logic
here is going to benefit your customers
because you're going to be able to
efficiently get them to the best product
for them. It's going to benefit you and
your peace of mind because you're not
going to waste valuable time going and
meandering with people that are not
right for what you're building. As we go
and actually get people, right? They're
going to be into the apply page. They
then are getting onto a sales call. And
from a sales call, we're then running
our onboarding. We're then giving them
access to [music] the community and to
all calls with me. And then from there,
we're making sure that these people,
obviously, are extremely happy, okay?
This leads to one of the most important
pieces of this all, which are reviews,
referrals, and, you know,
recommendations. The point being is
that, basically, people are going to go
and tell their friends about the amazing
[music]
business you've created. And when you
get this right, ideally, every single
person that comes in to your business,
your offer, is going and telling three
friends. You know,
>> [music]
>> at FounderOS, you know, we have a
Trustpilot over 90 five-star reviews
there. You can't ignore this because the
toughest part of a business like this
that mostly gets ignored, it's not the
audience, it's not the offer, it's not
the marketing, it's the actual delivery.
But when you nail the delivery, you
create [music] a profit flywheel in the
business. There's two things that then
start to happen. Number one, as I
identified, people start to tell their
friends, thereby contributing [music]
more and more to this amazing business
you're creating. And the second thing
is, you have the ability to then upsell
these people to the next stage of offer.
Let me explain how this works, right?
When someone goes and completes one
offer for you and they get help with the
given thing they came to get solved,
solving that solution typically goes and
presents a new problem. And so, this is
just illustrating the fact that as you
solve one problem, a new problem
presents itself. Because the journey of
building a business is just this endless
journey of solving things, coming to a
solution, finding a new problem, solving
that. And you can be that guide along
their whole journey. Let's get into the
next aspect here, right? Which is
probably the one that you've most been
looking forward to, the actual math.
Phase five, let's go. Let's break down
what this all actually looks like. Let's
say I Founder OS, we have our offers,
which are Edge, we have Velocity, we
have the Program, and then we have the
Entry Level. Let's just say Edge was
100k, we have Velocity at 36k, [music]
the Program
at 7.8k,
and then say the average entry point is
$250. On the quantity side, we'll put
the monthly quantity here, and then
we'll get to a monthly revenue number,
and I'll break it down what this could
look like on an annual basis. So every
month, we only give [music] three people
access to Edge, where they're getting a
real intimate container with me, you
know, they'll work with me anytime they
want, multiple one-to-ones per month,
really having me directly in their
corner, and helping founders that are
doing at least a million dollars per
year really collapse time, [music] go
and systematize their whole company, and
along the way too, helping them with
sticky issues that may come up.
Velocity, we allow 15 people inside of
this per month, keeping it still [music]
super intimate, giving them access to a
legendary Slack community of founders,
access to me every week, access to my
team and over 50 live sessions. Inside
of the program, we give 30 folks access
per month. This is where people are
mostly getting access to my team, and
they get one session with me per month.
And then entry level, this can be things
even like the Black Friday Cyber Monday
offer that we put out, which was, you
know, a few live sessions with me
helping folks build their personal brand
and accelerate it going into the new
year. Here, we'll go and sell, say,
[music] of these around 1,000 a month.
Okay, so let's go and do the math here,
okay? This is going to be on a per month
basis.
>> [music]
>> So we're talking about revenue per
month. So back in napkin here, with
Edge, given that we're doing three of
these a month, that's driving 300k. When
we look at Velocity, it's 540k.
The Program is 234k,
and entry level 250k. Guys, this is an
example. I'm not saying by any means
this is guaranteed with this, to be
clear. This is just a hypothetical
background based on, you know, specific
products, sample quantities of these,
what this could look like, right? So we
go and add this all up in terms of the
opportunity here, we're looking at
around a 1.3
million dollar a month business, and on
an annual basis, around 15 .8 million
per year. What this is just doing is
showing kind of the breakdown between
your high, core, and entry level offers.
I think one important aspect is to limit
the amount of people that can get access
to each of these things, and have clear
tiers where, you know, a founder's
looking to go and get from seven to
eight figures, well, they're probably
going to go and join Edge. Whereas
someone who's just getting started is
probably going to join one of these
entry level offers. So freedom is not
some amorphous term here, right? Freedom
comes from intentionally driving the
right traffic to the right offer, right?
With the right content GPS in place, and
with the right math in place that makes
it all possible. Cuz we're not just
getting this math right for us. Yes,
this is going to affect your bottom line
and your lifestyle, but more
importantly, it's going to affect your
peace of mind, your ability to go and
build on an amazing team here to help
support your content and traffic
efforts, to help support your delivery
efforts, which I said is by far the
toughest part of this business. With the
right math, you can build this in a way
that's actually going to help you
achieve the [music] next phase. And
phase six is all around the true goals
of a model like this. So let's get into
it. How I see this, these are
essentially my criteria for what this
beautiful business model all stands for.
When I think about going and creating
this beautiful business, okay? Something
that really matters to me is for it to
be [music] peaceful. We are building
this all up, and we're systematizing
this entire model. So at the end of the
day, we're not fighting fires at night.
I think one of the most beautiful and
important metrics in any business is
sleep at night, right? Is your own peace
of mind. Now, the next aspect here is
that [music] it's got to be fun. What
we're doing is we're building fun into
this whole model. We're creating content
that's at the intersection of what we
actually enjoy making, what's going to
make us money, and what's going to
attract the right people to us. You
know, we're building a simple amount of
offers so that we don't need to do
everything, [music] we can focus on a
few things, do them right, and then just
have time for beautiful things in life.
Now,
>> [music]
>> the next aspect here is that the most
beautiful business has to go and
generate endless [music] reviews. When
I'm building something, I'm really going
and leaning into the product hardcore,
right? Because [music] it's from having
a breathtaking onboarding experience,
going and tightening up the time to
value, making sure that in this case
founders have an unbelievable amount of
support. They know that we always have
their back. They can feel the love in
the systems. They can feel that, you
know, Matt actually cares. I think
that's exactly it. As I've studied
[music] so many different businesses,
one thing I've realized that's our
biggest competitive advantage at Founder
OS is that we genuinely care. [music]
Every single person on my team, whether
it's a video editor, to a producer, to a
writer, to a customer success person, we
all give a Let me tell you. Now,
>> [music]
>> the next piece here is that over time, I
actually want it to get more and more
simple. And so I'm optimizing for insane
simplicity. Where most companies fail is
that as they scale, they just keep
adding more and more noise, especially
in this products area. What I like to
think about over time is versus going
more broad, I like to go much deeper in
each of these core areas. We really
leaning into the education and making it
second to none. We want to make sure
obviously that if we're looking to build
this kind of business, it needs to be
easy to sell, okay? Now, the beautiful
thing is that all these work together,
right? When you have an insanely simple
amount of offers, you have the right
application router and content GPS in
place, it's a lot easier to sell folks
that are coming from aligned organic
content than it is from paid ads. When
businesses are reliant on paid ads,
folks that are coming to you are
naturally skeptical. When people come
from organic content, most people that
are coming to work with me have been
following my content for six months, a
year, sometimes even a few years. And
then when they come to me, they're not
skeptical, their core emotion is
actually a level of curiosity. They
already trust us. There's already level
of pre-suasion that has gone and
convinced them via the content, so they
don't need to be persuaded on a call.
They just need to know which product is
right for them, and they're ready to get
started. Now, the next piece here does
not get talked enough about in
entrepreneurship, and we're talking
about longevity. When you're building a
business, and I don't care what your
goals are, the truth is is that over a
long enough time horizon, you're highly
likely to get to where you're going. So
what goes wrong? Most founders quit. And
you [music] may ask, "Quit? Something
beautiful like this, why would they
quit?" Well, with this business model,
when you got it right, you're not
quitting. But most businesses, they
[music] end up trying to go and build a
wonky audience with the wrong content.
They're sending people to a host of
different pages that are not converting.
They've got far too many offers that are
going nowhere and all around disparate
different value props that make no
sense. And so what ends up happening is
that a founder starts spinning their
tires. They're on a hamster wheel, and
one thing leads to another, they burn
out, and they give up. They stop the
compounding because they never
prioritize longevity. And so the next
thing here that we're thinking about is
scalability. I see scalability as
[music] actually something that we
should double click into here for a sec.
You know, I'm not looking to go and make
more profit at the sacrifice [music]
of peace, or I'm not looking to go and
make more profit at the sacrifice
[music]
of delivering an amazing product, and
I'm not looking to make more profit
[music]
to sacrifice the purpose behind this
whole beautiful business, which for me
is to impact 100 million founders and
help them go and accomplish their dreams
through amazing systems, [music]
support, and the best founder community
in the world. So this is the most
beautiful business in the world.
Six phases, all designed around building
a business [music] that helps you live
the life you actually want to live. Now,
the truth is, I didn't build this whole
thing by myself, right? I had an amazing
[music] team behind me, mentors,
advisors, and the truth is, you need
help, too.
>> [music]
>> Right? Inside of Founder OS, you can go
and message me anytime. Get on weekly
calls, whether you're looking to set up
your audience, craft your offers, go and
dial in your team, or make sure that the
actual math behind your business
actually gets you to where you're really
looking to go. Imagine having not just
[music] you leveled up, systematized
with the right offers, the right
audience, and the right content and
leads coming to your business, but
imagine all of your team being aligned
around that as well. This is what
Founder OS is all about. [music] If
you're looking to go and take real
action today, if you've enjoyed this
video and [music] you want help building
your beautiful business, this is exactly
what me and the team at Founder OS are
insanely passionate about. So, we've
gone and templatized all of this madness
behind me into a blueprint that you can
go get below in the link in the
description. So, go and download that,
begin to fill it out, and come prepared
to the call with my team so we can go
and help get you unstuck and see how we
could go and get working together.