The only way to go viral is to create
bad content. I think that most people
think they need to have it all figured
out and then start posting online. The
truth is often times that you start
posting online and then you figure it
out. It's from the doing that you get
the clarity. You need to be confident
enough to go and just look cringe for a
bit. You need to be confident enough to
go and just start putting, [music] you
know, your first pieces of content out
there and start developing what I call
the shipping muscle. When you ship
things, you build leverage. When you
ship them, you start building your
movement. When you ship them, you're
able to learn and you're able to
iterate.