[Music]
This is the one system I use to turn my
content into profit. All while working
just 4 hours a day traveling around the
world without spending a dime on ads or
sending spammy cold messages. It's
called the content GPS. The content GPS
comes down to seven core elements. The
synergy between all seven of these
created the content GPS that helped me
build an audience of over 2.7 million
around myself as a founder personal
brand. So let's begin with the breakdown
with element number one, unique
positioning. Positioning is how you
define yourself as a leader in
delivering specific value for specific
customers. First, you need to figure out
who you are looking to target. This part
is essential. Here's an example of my
target market at Founder OS. We help
founders doing over 30K per month by
building a systemized, profitable
personal brand. So get a pen and paper
out and write down your target market.
The next step is then how to identify
how to position yourself to serve that
market. Here's the three-part brand
positioning of Founder OS. The best way
to build an online business is a
personal brand. And to build a personal
brand, you need to be creating content
that is beautiful and systemized. And
the only way is with a content GPS
system with Founder OS. This follows my
brand positioning formula that you can
use to craft your three-part
positioning. Insert your oneline thesis.
what two to three things are essential
to deliver on that thesis and what is
your core mechanism that helps your
dream customer achieve your thesis. From
there, you should think of a oneline
description and update all of your
social media bios. This is super
important. Here's an example of my
oneline bio. Proven systems to grow a
profitable audience with content. The
average creator converts just 0.5% of
social media page visits to followers.
Brutal. I use my unique positioning to
drive a 20% profile visit to follower
conversion percentage. That's 40x the
average. You can see it on my Instagram
where I have over 871,000 followers. And
on my LinkedIn where I have over 710,000
followers and drive 2.8 million in
annual revenue and on X where I have
350,000 followers and drive 1.2 million
to my portfolio of online businesses.
But here's the thing. Most of you have
no idea how to create a memorable brand
online. One quick tactic to help you is
to write down five words or phrases you
want to associate with your brand. I
call this your unique languaging. Here
are mine. Systems, profitable personal
brand, content waterfall, personal media
company, and content GPS. Get a pen and
paper out and write down your five words
or phrases. Now that you have your
unique brand positioning, let's move on
to the next element. Scroll stopping
content.
Content is the fuel to your lead engine.
Creating content has literally changed
my life. It increases my surface area
for community, connections, customers,
and cash flow. I love content for
multiple reasons. First, it's the
easiest way to speak directly to your
ideal customer. Content is a magnet
that's going to draw in the exact people
that are the best fit to work with you
and your brand. Second, I love that
content is immortal. For instance, if me
and you were having a conversation,
after that conversation is done and
we're done talking, it's gone forever.
Content allows ideas though to live on
forever. Even better, it's also
sharable, which expands my opportunity
for impact and connection. Finally,
content is a great incubator. People
need time to build trust with your
brand. Content is a no- risk way for
them to familiarize themselves with you
and what you stand for without feeling
pressured to commit to anything. It
builds trust and builds those rich
onetoone relationships you're after. How
do you create scroll stopping content?
And what should you even post? First
off, establish four content categories.
Mine are personal stories, personal
branding, monetization systems, and
audience growth systems. What are your
four content categories? Next, you want
to come up with endless content ideas so
you never hit writer's block. I
developed what I call the Founder West
content idea machine. You can use this
framework to come up with 30 amazing
content ideas in just 30 minutes. When
I'm creating high converting content, I
focus on five core areas: lessons,
systems, playbooks, benefits, and
examples. Here's an example from
LinkedIn. This post consists of four key
elements. Compelling hook. So, the hook
is the first sentence, and it gets
people to stop scrolling and read the
rest of the post. Value bomb. I'd then
dive deep into the specific steps and
actions to design your dream life.
Beautiful imagery. Images speak a
thousand words. Use them to create
dynamic content that stands out online
in a CTA. I end the post by driving
people to my newsletter. Now that you
have your own scroll stopping content
mapped out, it's time to move on to the
next element, content
calendar. This is what my content
distribution schedule looks like in any
given week. And here's how this breaks
down per platform. On X, I post twice a
day. And on Wednesday, Thursday,
Saturday, and Sunday at 8 a.m. EST, I
post a long form thread like this. On
LinkedIn, I post once a day, seven days
a week at 8 a.m. EST. Here are examples
of my top posts on LinkedIn. On
Instagram, I post twice a day, once at 8
a.m. EST, and once at 2 p.m. EST. In
addition to posts, I create around five
Instagram stories daily. On YouTube, I
post once every 2 weeks on Sunday. I
also post on Tik Tok twice per day, and
I publish a newsletter twice a week. on
Wednesday and Saturday. Inside the
newsletter, you get one free system to
grow a profitable personal brand and
audience. Over time, I've delegated all
content creation and distribution to my
team. The exact process of building out
my pro team is broken down in several of
my other videos linked in the
description. But right now, the process
of creating and publishing all of my
content flows through my team just like
this. A social manager posts all of my
content. A writer packages up all the
written content. A long form video
editor edits all of my YouTube videos. A
short form video editor creates all my
reals and YouTube shorts. And a designer
creates all of the images. My social
manager organizes all our content
workflows inside a sauna. He then posts
each piece of content without me having
to do anything. It is all managed by the
social manager. Now that you have your
content operation down pat, and
organized, it's time to set your
audience on fire with the next
element, audience growth systems. Your
audience is an appreciating asset. Once
you earn their attention, their value to
you and your business will compound with
the right content, strategy, and systems
in place. Here are four core systems you
need to design and apply to set yourself
apart from everyone else on social
media. batching systems, content
waterfall system, CTA system, and
delegation systems. If you want to grow
your audience to a million plus and not
burn out, you need to batch your content
creation. It's better to create content
for 3 hours straight on a Friday versus
30 minutes each day, 5 days a week.
That's the recipe for burnout. When you
batch your content creation, you get
into a flow state and are 10 times more
productive. I generally schedule one
2-hour writing session every 2 weeks. I
wake up, grab an iced latte, and write
30 tweets, one long newsletter, and one
YouTube concept. From there, I pass this
on to my team to turn that one piece of
long form content into 26 other pieces
of content with our content waterfall
system. This system allows me to take
one X thread, or really any long- form
piece of written content, and turn it
into 26 pieces of content. Now, each
piece of content must include a CTA or a
call to action. Your CTAs are like a net
that catches the fish in the ocean of
attention that you're building online.
There are 20 strategic locations where
you can insert CTAs across each social
platform to drive leads to your
business. your Instagram bio, Instagram
stories, LinkedIn about section,
LinkedIn bio, LinkedIn featured section,
LinkedIn cover photo, LinkedIn end of a
post, X bio, X cover photo, X end of a
tweet, X end of a thread, Tik Tok bio,
Tik Tok video CTA, YouTube bio, YouTube
description, YouTube about section,
YouTube cover photo, YouTube 50-cond cut
in a video CTA, podcast 15-second cut to
CTA, a Apple and Spotify description
CTA. And if it isn't obvious by now, I
don't do everything myself. That's a
one-way ticket to the depths of burnout.
If you're feeling overwhelmed, you
likely have too many tasks on your plate
that are draining your energy. If you
take a look at my org chart, it's pretty
clear I've assembled a team of weapons
to manage the most important tasks of
the business. Identifying the tasks that
need to be delegated is the key to
building out your team. And this is the
system that I use to do just that.
Here's a time audit spreadsheet I use to
determine which tasks I want to maintain
ownership of and which ones I want to
delegate. Step one, make note of all the
tasks you worked on over the last 8
weeks. Step two, indicate whether that
task gives you energy or drains your
energy. Step three, mark whether you can
automate, eliminate, or delegate a task.
In step four, any task you can
eliminate, you should stop doing
immediately. In step five, group all
similar delegation tasks together and
then pull those into a job description
and then just go hire someone for that
role. Get those tasks off your plate.
Now that you have your audience growth
systems in place, how do you actually
grow your audience? The key here is
growing an email list inside of your
[Music]
newsletter. Email is proven to have a 36
to1 ROI. It's a no-brainer to capture
your audience in a newsletter of your
own. My newsletter is a centralized
place where I nurture my audience. I've
created the best newsletter in the world
for people to get proven systems to grow
a profitable personal brand. Every
single week, I give away a free system
you can't find anywhere else. But what
content do you put in your newsletter?
To simplify things, there are two kinds
of newsletters: curation and deep dives.
Curated newsletters are the ones that
curate the best articles, kind of like
James Clear does with different quotes
and links and other resources. Deep
dives are when you go deep with your
stories, systems, and deeper stories on
how you get things done. In my Founder
newsletter, I follow this simple
four-part framework. I begin each
newsletter with a deeply personal story
that really connects me with my
audience. I then get into systems that
are deep dives into the specifics on how
you can implement how I run my business
and you can do that yourself. I then end
each newsletter with two core CTAs,
generally one to a product and then
another to one of my YouTube videos.
This helps me then cross-pollinate my
audience across all the different
platforms and become omniresent. My goal
is to have each person in my audience
follow me across X, LinkedIn, Instagram,
YouTube, Tik Tok, Threads, and my
newsletter. You might be wondering, what
newsletter platform should you be using?
I use ConvertKit. It's the best platform
for growing a business using an email
list. Create a simple landing page with
a value proposition, then incorporate
that landing page into key spots across
your social media profiles. As you grow
your audience, you want to convert
followers from being a rented audience
on social media to an owned audience in
your newsletter because these are people
that you can market to now onetoone. You
must be thinking, well, this all sounds
good, but how do I rapidly grow my email
list and revenue 10x faster? That leads
me to the next element of building your
content GPS, a profitable
workshop. It's no secret that webinars
are a powerful tool for driving revenue.
But what about workshops? Webinars, I
find, are often overly salesy and leave
people with a bad taste in their mouth.
Workshops, on the other hand, are
educational. You're sharing lessons, and
it's a great chance for you to share
your story, add a ton of value to
people, and then help them find the best
way to get help if they want to take
action. You only need to run them for
about an hour a month to get insane
amounts of results. My workshops alone
last year drove over $2.7 million to my
businesses and over 68,000 email
subscribers. How do you create the
perfect workshop? Keep things insanely
simple with this five-part profitable
workshop formula. Use Zoom for the live
workshop. Create a workshop registration
page like this. Create a presentation in
Google Slides. Just keep it simple,
nothing fancy. Then have three core
teachings that you cover. At the end,
let people know how they can go and take
action and work with you. Spend about 15
minutes at the end of the workshop
answering questions and just being as
generous as humanly possible with your
audience. This is going to endear them
to you, build rapport, and just a rich
relationship with them. Blow them away
with value. And then promote the
workshop on social media with a 7-day
countdown leading up to the date. Set up
automated emails to go out the week
before the workshop and then 3 days
after your workshop to promote your
offer. And then once you structure your
workshop this way, analyze what's
worked, what didn't work, and then just
continuously experiment and improve.
You're just going to iterate, improve,
and repeat. Your ability to monetize
your audience comes down to this last
element that 97% of founders get wrong.
What is it? It's your offer
stack. You have been sold a lie. You've
been told by gurus and experts online
that you need one offer and should focus
everything you've got on that offer.
This is a massive mistake. The goal is
to create a series of offers that are so
enticing that you create this slippery
slope from one offer to the next one to
building a loyal customer base. But most
of you don't just have one offer. You
likely have five. This is called your
offer stack. An offer stack is the
series of offers that you present to
your dream customer as they move through
your content funnel. Here's what it
might look like for you. Your social
media bio on Instagram is an offer for
people to follow you on Instagram. Your
CTA under a post on Instagram is an
offer for people to then visit your
newsletter landing page. And your
newsletter landing page copy has a lead
magnet and offer for people to then join
your newsletter. Inside of your
newsletter, the copy there contains an
offer for people to then join a sales
call with your team. And then your sales
call presents people with an offer to
then work with you. This is your offer
stack. Here's what my offer stack looks
like. I have irresistible social media
profiles that convert 20% of profile
visitors to followers. That's 40x the
average. I have a newsletter landing
page that converts 80% of page visitors
to subscribers. I have low ticket offers
between $29 and $149 that give people my
most powerful systems and present them
with an exclusive offer to join Founder
OS. Then I have Founder OS using proven
systems. I have found plus as well which
then helps founders by installing the
most powerful system I've ever
discovered the content GPS. And then I
have found mastermind which is an
inviteonly community for founders on
average that are doing over 8 figures in
revenue a year. I also offer boutique
content funnels for large-scale founders
doing over a million dollars a year if
they want to have me and my team work
hands-on in their business to train
their team. A powerful offer stack
drives powerful and predictable profits
to your business. Great founders have
great
systems. My vision is to help you
transcend your limits and unlock your
full potential. We believe success is an
operating system, an
OS. We are a movement of founders who
leverage operating systems to build a
life we couldn't have ever imagined
possible in our wildest dreams. If you
despise the false trade-off between
success and freedom as much as I do, you
want to build a business that empowers
you to live your dreams, well, you
belong with us. Like and subscribe and
welcome to the founder freedom movement.