Everyone thinks that high performers win
because they're smarter or harder
working, but it really comes down to
these eight rare traits that I'm going
to break down in this video. Some of
these feel wrong, a little bit weird,
and many of them you may have never
heard before. But don't worry, I'm going
to break them down in a detailed way so
you can go and implement these in your
life and become a high performer
yourself. Let's get into it. Rare trait
number one, grit. Hard work is common.
Grit is rare. Grit is the ability to go
and persevere through any obstacle. You
know, I know from building, you know,
businesses both in good times and in bad
that I would have never gone and made it
through half of the challenges I've been
through if I didn't possess grit. And
it's something that I also value inside
of the teams that I'm building inside of
my companies. You know, people that are
able to go and deal with different
challenges, not avoid them, not try to
scurry away from them, but actually go
right into the storm. The weird thing
is, I think a lot of people view grit a
bit differently than I would. You know,
often times people think that grit means
just sticking with something no matter
what. But the truth is that grit's
actually knowing when to give up on
something so that you maybe lose the
battle but then win the war. An example
may be that you have a business idea and
despite trying and trying and trying,
it's just not working. And in fact, it's
just a bad idea. So, you give up on that
one idea only to pursue your bigger
calling in a bigger, more profitable
idea and end up winning the long-term
race with that. Grit isn't just about
sticking with something when it just
makes no sense or stupidly persevering.
It's about being smart, being
calculated, and despite what anyone else
says, sticking to what you know will
work and sticking with it until the job
is done. Rare trait number two,
optimism. And I'm not just talking about
some toxic positivity here. Optimism is
having this positive outlook on things
even when things are going wrong. You
know, having that ability to see the
bright side in things, you know,
sometimes even when there's just
complete darkness. Being optimistic
allows me even in the most challenging
times just to find that small morsel of
energy, that space to just get back on
my feet and keep going. You know, I've
had many years in my life being far too
negative. And it doesn't just affect me,
but it affects the people around me and
my ability to turn things around. You
know, had I just been positive, had I
just been optimistic and seen the
brighter side of things, I would have
been able to more easily rebound from
these struggles versus getting sucked
into them and struggling to get out. An
example of staying optimistic in a hard
time is maybe, you know, you're building
a company and someone all of a sudden
who's key to your company quits. Well,
in that moment, you have the option of
going and complaining to all your
mentors and advisers and friends about
the hardship you've now experienced. Or
you can just say, you know what, maybe
there's a blessing in disguise here
somewhere. Then start looking for new
opportunities from that challenge. Often
times the biggest crisises in life are
also the seeds to the biggest
opportunities. And so it's finding that
opportunity no matter how bad things can
get. So how do you go and become more
optimistic? Well, sometimes taking a
break from things, getting some space.
You know, if that means taking care of
yourself so that your own general
demeanor and approach to life is
positive by, you know, working out,
taking time for nature, meditating,
reading books that kind of fill your
brain with great ideas, finding mentors,
advisors that show you the opportunity
in any given moment and get you out of
any pessimism you're currently feeling.
I'm not saying that, as an example, I'm,
you know, innocent here. You know,
there's definitely times where I get
down on myself or I find myself
complaining. But it's just knowing that
that part of you is not the best part of
you and eventually rise above it and get
out of the soup of negativity. The
highest performers I know are optimistic
over the long term, but slightly
paranoid about the short term. What this
causes them to be is long-term patient,
but short-term impatient. They're going
to get into a given skill. Let's say
they want to go and grow on YouTube. And
longterm they're going to see, wow, the
potential there. They're optimistic
about where it's going to go and the
benefit they can have in their given
niche. On the other side though, in any
given week, they're being impatient
about learning, you know, finding the
best tools, traits, finding the best
teammates and systems and skills so they
can go and level up fast because overall
they have this long-term optimism. Rare
trait number three, not being an
The reality is, if you want to
be a high performer, you have to
surround yourself with other high
performers. The first thing that is
going to cause people to go and run away
from you is if they just can't stand to
be around you because you're an
I say this all as a recovering
When I was 21 to 23, I was building my
first business and due to the insane
stress load and candidly having no clue
what I was doing. I was a piece of
to be around potentially, you know, just
really hard to get along with,
pessimistic, negative, and generally
just had a kind of overall negative
demeanor because the stress was getting
to me. I wasn't getting good sleep. Life
was rough. This didn't just affect me,
right? But it affected others around me,
their ability to go and solve problems.
you know, while we ended up being
successful, it came at a price. When it
comes to, you know, not being an
I think the things to reflect
on are like, how would people around you
go and grade you? How do you go and
grade your happiness on a day-to-day
basis? You know, how easy are you to get
along with? The reality is is that, you
know, we all have bad days and good
days, and it's not just about agreeing
with people on every single thing, but
at a certain point, people have to enjoy
being around you. You know, there's a
tax for being an The tax is
that people quit. The tax is that people
don't want to tell others to go and work
with you. The tax is that you're
miserable dayto-day. And the tax is that
the relationships around you suffer. And
the reality is when we look over 50
years and 100 years of a great life,
it's the relationships that matter. So
don't be an Rare trait number
four, be a storyteller. Your story is
your strategy. You know, your ability to
go and tell the story of your
background, tell your origin story, tell
the stories of the challenges you've
overcome. separate high performers from
everyone else. The ability to go and
inspire people through a great story is
a rare trait. And high performers double
down on stories when they're looking to
go and chart out a new mission for a
business or when they're looking to go
and hire other people or when the dark
of days come by and you got to rally the
troops around some common mission. It is
stories that are the seed to their
success. Customers buy a product because
of a story. team members join your team
because of a story or investors go and
invest in your company because of a
story. It's your ability to go and build
a narrative around your thing or a
narrative around your big vision for a
product or for a company or the journey
you're on that will inspire others to
join you and to take action and be part
of your movement. In order to create
your story, you need to view yourself
like a character. What are your beliefs?
What are your values? Right? and kind of
world building around that as that main
character. What is the big vision you
have for the world? Making it inspiring,
you know, making it something that
others can go and be a part of. What are
some of the biggest hardships you've
overcome and how did you overcome those?
This is what's going to make you more
relatable to other people and help them
see themselves in your story. Going and
taking a step back to think about the
core stories that have shaped you are
what are going to allow you to go and
motivate people and help get the best
out of them as well. Rare trade number
five, relentless resourcefulness. Here
is the fair warning to start this off.
More money equals less resourcefulness.
Let me explain. When you are flushed
with cash as a company, as an example,
you start to go and just spend money to
go and solve problems. And most of the
time, you just keep on wasting it and
wasting it and causing everyone just to
get intellectually lazy. The truth is
when you build constraints around
yourself, those constraints breed
creativity. Pressure makes diamonds. And
when you find yourself not being able to
just throw money at problems, it forces
you to go and think outside the box. All
great leaders out there have a story of
when their back was up against the wall.
They had to find a way to innovate or
they were going to die. You know,
whether it was Steve Jobs and Apple at
the brink of bankruptcy, Ferrari at the
brink of bankruptcy back in their day,
the stories of leaders that have had to
go and innovate, had to find a way when
everything looked like it was going to
die, all comes down to their ability to
tap into theirs and others relentless
resourcefulness. So, given the fact that
constraints actually help you, the truth
is that you can tap into this trait with
absolutely nothing. You don't need a
bunch of money to start that business.
You don't need to go and make sure you
have the perfect diet before you can
start going to the gym. You don't need
to go and wait until you have the
perfect instrument to start playing
music. The truth is relentless
resourcefulness comes down to starting
with what you've got right here, right
now. Rare trait number six, obsessive
pattern spotting. Obsessive pattern
spotting comes down to connecting
abstract ideas to go and form your own
point of view and approach to the world.
I know in my own life from obsessing
over founders podcasts and then linking
that with different biographies and
books that I've read going and talking
with different mentors and advisers
eventually you're able to go and
interlink these different ideas to come
up with solutions that are a little bit
outside the box to common problems. I
know for example in any business that
I've created I honestly haven't even
known a thing about that industry before
getting in. You know, before starting
Founder OS, I had never built a
community. Before starting BitMaker, I'd
never built a school. Before building
Herb, I had never built a media company.
But it was through the patterns that I'd
already seen in other spaces and from my
research and from talking to mentors
that I was able to connect these dots
and create something special. A lot of
the high performers that I'll go and
interview for different companies,
they'll talk about the fact that, you
know, in their spare time, you know,
they're reading different books and
they're maybe working on different art
projects while also maybe learning an
instrument. But from all of this
practice and this development of mastery
in a bunch of different areas, they're
able to bring those learnings and those
patterns to their current work. When you
look into history at some of the best
entrepreneurs and investors, pattern
spotting is a core trait. You know, with
Steve Jobs, it was noticing patterns and
ways of, you know, Zen philosophy,
merging that with the simplicity of art
and the minimalism of a lot of the core
products he had studied over history
that inspired him to go and remove all
of the buttons from the iPhone as an
example. Or, you know, on the investing
side, Charlie Mer was known for studying
the great across biology, psychology,
and understanding, you know, that
investment wasn't just about going and
making good financial decisions. It was
also going and studying human behavior
and biology and bringing those core
learnings to investing to make smarter
decisions. It's so easy to go and get
addicted to trends or the hot new thing,
but often times history leaves clues. If
you're wondering, you know, what AI's
trend line is going to look like over
the next decade, look back to the 2000s
and the invention of the internet.
You're looking to see where that new
piece of technology is going, well, look
at the adoption of things like phones or
the computer. Often times, it's actually
by looking back and spotting the
patterns that we can then go and apply
those things to present- day problems to
just wrap our heads around it a lot
faster. Don't chase new ideas. Just
chase the patterns that are hiding under
new disguises. Everybody wants new
ideas, but your rare edge is looking
backwards to see the patterns, the
clues, and then applying those to the
present moment and not just getting
caught up in trends. This can go and
help you in day-to-day life because
truthfully oftentimes when you know
tough times happen, you can think you're
so special. I know sometimes when it
first hits me, I'm dealing with a
crisis. I'm like, "Oh my gosh, how could
I ever get through this?" But then when
I come to my senses and take a second to
just calm down a bit, you realize that
there are thousands, if not millions of
people that have encountered the exact
same problem you have, and that there's
a proven technique for getting over it.
Don't reinvent the wheel. Look for the
patterns and apply them today. Rare
trait number seven, strategic laziness.
I get it. This one seems a little bit
weird, but let me explain. And when
you're going and building something as a
high performer, you got to realize at
some point that you can't do everything.
You got to be a bit lazy. You got to go
and make sure that you're building
different systems, teams, people, you
know, companies that can do more of the
work for you. You know, strategic
laziness really comes down to strategic
leverage. seeking help from things like
technology that can go and help you,
tools that can go and unlock new
possibilities, people that can go and
serve your mission and help you build
something. It comes down to media that
can spread where you just create one
thing and it goes and is multiplied a
million times over. When you get a bit
lazy, you start to spot the patterns of
leverage underneath your fingertips from
code, technology, media, people, and
capital. One example of strategic
laziness that I use in my life is by
having my $5,000 an hour rule, knowing
that I'm only going to go and double
down on tasks that are above that hourly
rate and I'm just going to be lazy with
stuff that's below that and find someone
else or an automation that can go and do
it without me. You know, inevitably
having the wherewithal to go and know
when you should automate and delegate
are what's going to allow you to unlock
bigger things in life versus just
working hard blindly on stuff that you
should have no business doing. So
strategic laziness isn't about doing
nothing. It's about leaving space for
your own genius to emerge. It's, you
know, taking that road trip just to get
some space from the problem. It's taking
10 minutes to meditate before a meeting
so you can go into it a little more
clearly. It's taking a weekend off or
taking, you know, a whole week off just
so that you can go and start to
re-evaluate your priorities instead of
just doing something that's no longer
giving you joy. You know, don't confuse
this with being lazy, right? It's
strategically lazy and giving yourself
space to think much more deeply. And
when we look back to the history of
humans and technology, you know, so much
of the major developments as a species
have come from being lazy. you know,
whether it was the computer, you know,
the tractor, the pulley, these are all
examples of going and finding something
so that we could go and do less.
Inventing something so that we could be
more lazy. It all comes down to
efficiency, right? This desire to do
less by inventing something that allows
you to do more. So, just so you really
understand this concept, right? You have
strategic laziness and destructive
laziness. Strategic laziness meaning
inventing new ways of doing things that
allow you to do less. Destructive
laziness is you just doing less and
getting less done. Pick one over the
other. Rare trait number eight,
shameless asking. Asking is the ability
to go knock on doors and sell something
that is not yet built. It's the ability
to go and ask someone for help when
you're scared. A lot of what we have to
do in life is to lean into our
discomfort and despite every morsel of
our body telling us just to shut down,
don't do it, give up. It's that ability
to be brave, right? to be courageous and
to just ask for the thing that you want.
This one really hits home because it
helped me a lot when I was younger. At
21 years old, I started a technology
boot camp called Bitmaker where we
trained full stack software engineers
and got them jobs at top tech companies.
You know, one day a few enforcement
agents from the government came in and
they thought we were operating a private
career college and weren't registered.
So, they tried to shut us down. This was
probably one of the most traumatic
moments of my life. I had no idea what
to do. When I finally came to my senses,
I realized that what I needed to do was
that I had to ask for help and a lot of
it. So, sure enough, over two days, I
went and emailed 3,000 people for help.
Paul Graham, Benode Kosla, Chamath, one
thing led to another and the North
American tech community rallied behind
what I was doing and we were trending on
Twitter in Canada. One week later, I got
the only exemption of its kind in Canada
to operate BitMaker and we eventually
had a successful exit. You know, in
these moments sometimes we find
ourselves thinking that we got to do
everything. We have to know what to do
when often times you just need to have
the courage to ask someone for help.
It's not about what to do, right? It's
about knowing who can help you. To
mobilize people to get the leverage out
of those people around you that do want
to give you a hand. You've just got to
go and lean in and ask for help. Ask
someone for an intro. Ask someone for a
resource. Ask someone for a system that
helped them when they were in your
position. Your ability to go and
leverage the people around you and to
ask for help is a key thing. Now, if
you're starting out and you're curious
like and you're nervous like how do I go
and ask, one thing you can be doing in
good days or bad is also just making
sure you're giving back to people. Every
time you give to someone, you help them
out, you build a bit of an asking bank.
That ability that when things start
getting a little weird or you need a bit
of help, you can then build up that
goodwill and go and ask someone to give
you a hand. And so asking, even when it
feels super uncomfortable, is a real
superpower. If you're building a
business, you need to make sure that
you're attracting high performers to
what you're building. I've gone and
created 21 questions that allow you to
go and attract high performers to your
business, your vision, and your mission.
and you can go and get it via the link
in the description. So, those are the
eight rare traits of high performers. Go
and apply these to your life and make
sure you're surrounding yourself with
people that possess these. Thanks for
watching and let's win