What does it mean to be rich? Well,
[music] being rich is really having
time. Time is your most valuable
resource. Life is short. And inevitably,
as you're building, you want to make
sure that you're systemizing your
empire, removing yourself from [music]
operations so that you can enjoy real
wealth. For me, you know, real wealth
and being rich is all about being able
to do experiences when I want, wherever
I want, with whoever I want. Being able
to go and pick up and go to Japan
snowboarding, be able to go and hike the
Doommites when I want, travel to Europe,
around the world, and be able to do it
with the people that I love. Time's
short. Life's running out. Make sure
you're prioritizing time over just