You'd be richer if you had some systems
in place because here's the deal. If you
don't have systems, well, you are the
system and you're the engine of your
business because if you stop for a
weekend or you go on a week vacation,
everything stops. So, what systems do
you need to have in place? Well, I like
to think about the core three. Number
one, having a founder scorecard. Seven
core metrics across your business and
having leaders on your team that own
each one of those metrics. From there,
you also want quarterly targets. We're
talking targets for your company, but
also for the individuals and how what
they're going to get done in a given
quarter lads up ladders up to the
company's goals. From there, I like to
also have velocity meetings. We're
talking one leadership meeting per week.
We're covering wins and number going
over issues, opportunities, challenges,
and the things that are coming up that
we need to solve to move the needle
forward. We're also then reviewing that
founder scorecard and making sure that
the metrics are moving in the right
direction
and that we're all hyper-focused on the
biggest constraint in the business and
solving these damn things. From there,
you want to have a content waterfall,
right? A weekly or bi-weekly content
ritual that's going to produce all the
content that you need across all
platforms and making sure that you're
building your distribution as well as a
founder and as a company and having the
right team in place to do that. Social
media manager, a writer, a video editor.
These are the systems that I think need
to get going with today.