There's an amazing discovery in
psychology called [music] the sunk cost
trap. It really is when your brain says,
you know, I've had already [music] spent
so much time on this, I can't quit. Now,
maybe you've invested a bunch of time in
a business, [music] right? But it's
still not turning the profit it's
supposed to. And so, you need to know
when to just [music] cut things loose. I
started a business back in the day. It
was probably about 8 years ago.
Everything looked good at the start,
right? But after working hard on it for
6 months, [music] it just refused to get
the traction that it needed. Luckily, I
made the decision to just stop working
on this damn thing, right? And go and
shift my [music] focus to something new.
At the time, it was scary as hell,
right? But I wouldn't have been able to
build my fourth business, [music]
Founder OS, had I not learned to just
say no to things and cut them when
there's just sunk [music] costs. And so,
what the sunk cost trap looks like,
right, is, you know, staying in a dead
business when you [music] should move
away or staying in a dead relationship
when, you know, it's really just [music]
not working out, right? You may tell
yourself, you know, we've been together
for five years, but if you just keep
failing [music] at the thing, it's time
to cut things loose.