If you could build a personal brand to a
100,000 followers, what would that do
for your business? In this video, we're
going to be exploring Laughin Norway.
And along the way, I'm going to give you
the no fluff, no BS playbook that's
helped me grow my audience to over 16
million across my personal brand and my
business. This is going to be the
biggest deep dive on building a
profitable personal brand that honestly
I've ever put out there. I feel
compelled to do this because, you know,
one of my core tenants or values in life
is being insanely generous. There are
four core things that we're going to
cover in this master class. Number one,
my founder flywheel and how you can set
up one in your business. From there,
we're going to go and dive into the
content GPS, which is the most powerful
system I've ever invented over the last
15 years building four profitable
businesses. The third thing is we're
going to dive into monetization moments
cuz we're actually trying to drive
dollars to your business. And then from
there, I'm going to show you my
automation blueprint. Because the truth
is, we want to remove ourselves from the
stuff that isn't in our zone of genius,
and be able to double down on working on
our business, not in it, and building
this appreciating asset, your personal
brand, that can scale without you over
time. Along the way, too, I also want
you to know that we've gone and made a
personal brand workbook below, and I'd
encourage you to go and download that.
You can thank me later. So, let's just
first start with the trust revolution.
It's roughly 71% of Americans don't
trust their neighbor. And in this new
world where people trust people less,
you know, we need to find a way to
connect with people to build that
resonance. The best way to do that is to
share your story, your values, who you
are, your playbooks, your systems, and
that's what we're going to get into
here. You know, I started building my
personal brand about 4 years ago. You
know, up until then, I had been really
focused on building my company brand. I
had always been behind the brand, right?
helping grow the content, grow the team.
But as I started getting older, I hit 30
and I was like, you know what, as I go
and look over the next 20 years of my
life, you know, I'm going to be really
focused on starting a number of
different companies. And I shifted my
mindset from just being the entrepreneur
behind the scenes to this more of a
mindset of being almost like a portfolio
manager where I have a number of
businesses under me. And so it became
really obvious to me that I should be
building my own brand because while I
may sell or exit some of these
businesses underneath it, my brand is an
appreciating asset that I'll have for
the rest of my life. I started building
on X and started sharing my thoughts
there. Within a few months, grew my
following to over 40,000 people. I then
began sharing that same writing onto
LinkedIn and grew my following to now
what's an audience of over 840,000
people. And then some of my best ideas,
I started sharing in short form videos
on Instagram, reels, YouTube, Tik Tok.
It started making a big impact to the
point now where I've grown my personal
brand to about 3.2 million people across
all the different platforms. My content
now reaches over 81 million people
organically every single month without
spending a dime on ads. It's increased
my cash flow, increased opportunities,
increased the ability for me to become a
magnet for top talent. And this has all
come not from a focus on followers, but
from a focus on the process, falling in
love with the daily habit of sharing my
work, sharing my thinking, and inspiring
people. This is a media moat that I've
built that I control. And this is why I
think the future belongs to media first
founders. All right, let's get into the
first component here, the founder
flywheel. So, think of your business
like this engine. The more you grow your
personal brand, the more you grow your
business brand, the more cash flow you
make and the more you're able to
reinvest those profits back into content
to really get this flywheel going.
There's really three key elements that
you want to think about across this
flywheel. First off, you have your
rented audience, right? This exists on
social platforms like YouTube,
Instagram, LinkedIn X, Tik Tok. Your
rented audience is called rented because
you don't own this audience. those
audiences you've built are actually
owned by the platform. And so, while
it's really great to go and build that
rented audience, you need to understand
that on a given post you put out there,
you're probably only reaching about 10%
of the people in your audience cuz
that's how the algorithm works. So, your
own audience really exists whether it's
in your newsletter, an email list, or
getting people's phone numbers. I see a
lot of founders, they don't set this up,
thereby they end up just building some
audience on social, but they're not
actually able to go and market directly
to people. You know, when you own your
email list, you send out an email, it
goes to every single one of those people
and say you have an open rate of 70%.
70% of those people are actually getting
that email and opening it, which is far
greater than the algorithm is going to
push your content on any given platform.
So, the key thing is to own it. Your
email list is probably the most valuable
asset you can build in your business.
And whether it's using platforms like
ConvertKit, HubSpot, you know, Substack,
Beehive, it honestly doesn't matter.
What matters most is not the tools. It's
you, your consistency, and honestly,
just being insanely generous with your
audience, and just helping folks out.
Now, the third step is your monetized
audience. We're not trying to just grow
followers here. We're trying to actually
make dollars. Biggest way to do that is
through CTAs in your newsletter and
sometimes on social, although you don't
want to overdo it because we don't want
to be salesy. and we're going to drive
people from primarily our newsletter to
things like sales calls or direct sales
of our actual product. Your monetiz
audience is really then how you get that
flywheel ripping because now you're
actually growing the cash flows to your
business and a percentage of that you're
able to now go and invest back in
growing your audience because the fuel
of your audience, what do you think it
is? It's content. The higher quality
your content, the faster your audience
grows, the more leads you get, the more
you're able to reinvest back into your
founder flywheel. And this is the modern
way of growing an insane engine around
your business. Growing your personal
brand is very similar to any other
investment out there. It generally looks
kind of like this. At first, it may feel
a bit slow, which is why it's super
important that your mindset initially is
around I'm going to be doing this for
the long term. This is for people that
are looking to build a real asset, not
just even for the next six months or
year, but for the next decade, five
decades. One of the biggest advantages
you can have as a founder these days is
to think long term. While everyone else
is addicted to dopamine, you know, stuck
in, you know, what's going to be the
trend over the next week or the next
month, there are some things that are
timeless, right? And building a
profitable personal brand and your
flywheel around it is timeless. All
right, so at this juncture, you're
probably asking, which platforms do I
start on? And how I see it is do you
want to be pen first or camera first?
Pen first would involve being on more of
the written platforms like X and
LinkedIn. And camera first would involve
being on platforms like Instagram,
YouTube, maybe even Tik Tok. On the
other side too, you want to think about
well if you're looking to build a
profitable personal brand, you've also
got to be thinking about where is your
dream customer. As I've gone and grown
on all five platforms, the platform that
I actually think is most attractive
these days, which probably drives 4x
more leads than the next platform for
me, is well, right here on YouTube.
YouTube represents the largest search
engine for videos in the world. Also,
when you think about the relationship
and the resonance you're building with
people, I think there's just such a
beautiful thing to showing up on camera
and in audio in longer form content and
not just showing up for say 30 seconds
or 60 seconds with someone in a tweet,
on a real, on a story, providing value
and allowing them to also get a sense of
who you are, your energy, what you're
interested in. This leads me to the next
aspect, which is building your personal
mode. I've found it difficult over the
years. Often times I've been told by
people, "Hey Matt, I'd love to see you
be more authentic. Matt, you should lean
into your authenticity." But that's such
a loaded word, right? Authenticity.
Like, what the hell does authenticity
even mean? What I've learned is that
it's about developing this personal moat
around the things that you feel
comfortable sharing online that really
speak to who you are at your core. And I
ended up coming across this book called
Icky Guy, right? Icky is a term that
stands for your reason for being. It's
your calling in life and it sits at the
intersection of four sort of concentric
circles. Um one being, you know, what
you're great at, what the world needs,
what you can be paid for, and what you
love to do. And when I started to look
at the patterns across these four
different quadrants, I started to see
that in the center were things like
building distribution from day one,
coaching founders, viewing
entrepreneurship as this beautiful
soulful journey, traveling the world,
helping founders achieve more freedom in
life, and building amazing communities,
building movements, and hosting epic
founder retreats. The cool thing is is
that the center of my icky guy is
exactly the kind of content that I
started sharing which then created my
personal mode. You know, it's less of a
niche. The fact is that you can become
the niche. You don't need to pigeon hole
yourself as the SAS guy or you don't
need to pigeon hole yourself as the
agency guy. Just be you. Talk about the
things that interest you. I believe that
entrepreneurship is this soulful
journey. And that's why I believe, you
know, the journey of building a personal
brand and of building a business is like
the most epic meditation you could ever
go on in your life. And just like you're
going to become the niche, right? And
you're going to find your personal moat,
you're also on the more spiritual side
going to get to know yourself on a
deeper level, exploring your calling,
exploring your interests, exploring the
things that make you you. Learning to be
confident in who you are. Learning to
have that presence, that resonance, and
just to speak your mind, to have a
unique point of view. Keep in mind, a
lot of this will come from the doing,
not just the thinking. I want you to
make sure that you're spending at least
80% of your time actually executing. The
other 20% can be left for things like,
you know, thinking, delegating,
designing, but 80% off the get-go has to
be about taking massive action. I want
you to go and download the personal
brand workbook below in the description.
Click on that link and inside of there
you're going to go and find this whole
icky guy exercise. I want you to go and
complete that putting at least three to
five bullet points for each quadrant and
then discover the commonalities are in
the center of this and then that is the
kind of content I want you to go and
start sharing online. So now that you
figured out, you know, really who you
are and the kind of content you're going
to want to share, now I think you need
to figure out who you want to target.
And so let's talk about going and
clarifying your ideal customer. One of
the most useful tools that I've used to
go and help come up with a content
strategy that's genuinely going to
resonate with my dream customer is
honestly just to ask them. What I'll do
is I'll go and create generally a type
form survey. And in that survey, I'll
ask people, "What is your biggest
challenge right now? What is your
biggest goal that you're trying to
accomplish by end of year? And what's
keeping you up at night?" And then I'll
go and I'll take all of those survey
responses. I'll generally download it as
a file from typform upload that to chat
GBT as an example and then I'll go and
prompt ChatGBT to go and say go and come
up with a hundred content topics for me
that would really resonate with my dream
customer based on the survey feedback
I've gone and attached here. Then CHBT
will go and come up with a 100 high
converting content ideas for me that
really just answer the questions and the
problems that are on my dream customer's
mind. So this eliminates the guesswork,
right? You don't need to wonder how
you're going to go and attract more
people. Just simply go and solve the
problems that your dream customer is
facing. Go and use the type form survey
questions that I've put inside of the
personal brand workbook which is below
in the description and go and put these
into your own type form. Send that out
to 10 to 20 of your dream customers.
Synthesize the results. Upload it to
Shaffy GBT and then bam, there you go.
You've got your high converting content
topics. All right. So, you now have two
really important pieces. You have your
personal mode charted out and you have
your ideal customer drawn up and you
know what content is going to resonate
with them. But that is all for nothing
if you don't have this next piece sorted
out which is your content GPS system.
Without this system I would not be able
to travel the world. I wouldn't have the
freedom that I have. You know, the
content GPS is all around creating
amazing content that has a good
foundation that then has the right
content multiplication
and then has your right distribution in
place. So, it really comes down to those
three pieces. Your content foundation,
your content multiplication, and your
content distribution. So, let's start
off with your content foundation. When
you're going and you're creating content
online, what you really want to be
thinking about are what are your four
content categories? Your content
categories make up essentially the drum
beat of your marketing strategy online.
These are likely the four key things
that you continually come back to that
create an overall theme to your content.
I also want to remind you none of this
is meant to be super rigid, right? Have
fun with it. You know, if you want to
talk about your travels, talk about it.
You want to talk about a struggle you
had today that's a bit different than
what you generally share, go for it. You
know, don't let your content strategy
become so rigid that it doesn't become
fun. When I think about my content
categories, I think about things like
personal branding, personal stories,
audience growth systems, and really
showing entrepreneurs how to design
their dream life and remove themselves
from operations. The next step there on
your foundation is then coming up with
actual ideas around your content
categories. And for some people, this is
a real struggle. They can't figure out
what the heck they're going to talk
about online. I want to get into the
Founder OS content idea machine. This is
how you can go and create 100 content
ideas in just 30 minutes. So, first off,
you know, you pick your categories, and
we just went over that. Secondly,
there's really two approaches when
you're creating content. There's an
expert approach and a curation approach.
So, the expert approach is when you're
already an expert in the given subject
matter you're about to go and show
people. So, maybe you're an expert
software engineer and you're going to go
and teach people how to code JavaScript,
HTML, CSS, and keep up on the newest AI
trends. On the other side of things, you
may be watching this and going, you
know, I'm not really an expert in
anything. In that case, you may take the
more curator approach. Okay. And the
curator approach is really fun. It's
where you're going about learning some
new skill or taking up, you know, some
new expertise and you're going to share
your journey along the way. You're going
to share the tips, the tricks, the books
you've read, the mentors that have
taught you different lessons, and you're
going to bring people along that
journey. Let's get into now how to go
and come up with a hundred content ideas
in 30 minutes. In each of these bits,
there are different kinds of content
that you can come up with. I provided
you with all of the different types of
content inside of that personal brand
workbook linked in the description. But
the cool thing is is that you can go and
using this chat GPT prompt right here,
go and enter in your content categories,
go enter in what your core mission is of
your brand as well as your unique value
proposition. And from there, this prompt
will go and help you come up with a
hundred content ideas, not even in 30
minutes, but just in 30 seconds or less.
We've got a no plethora of different
content ideas now. And now you're going
to actually go and start creating the
content. So, first off, you really want
to think about batching your content.
This is a bit of like a YouTube filming
week for me. So, I'll probably go and
end up filming around four YouTube
videos over the next 5 days. and that'll
give me content for the next month,
month and a half. Batching is a really
core thing that you want to be doing as
a founder because we want to be the CEO
of this media empire we're building, not
just the constant creator. Because a
founder brand is one part entrepreneur,
one part creator. And the number one
reason that both of these people give up
is because they burn out. We really want
to think about building in systems,
building in ways of being that reduce
our odds of burnout. Now, another core
aspect on the content foundation side of
things is your content IP, which stands
for your content intellectual property.
You probably know it, right? There are
books out there that those concepts,
those words have almost been a part now
of like just common language. Examples
of this include things like extreme
ownership from Joo Willink or Deepwork
from Cal Newport or getting your 10,000
hours to become an expert from Malcolm
Gladwell. These are an examples of these
authors creating content intellectual
property which are words that they've
invented or phrases that they've
invented that inevitably when people
hear these in popular culture they
trigger and link that back to the
author. really go and think about the
common words or phrases that you use
when describing different concepts
within your content categories and in
your niche. And so for me, that's things
like your personal moat. You know, it's
things like your content waterfall
system. You know, I talk about the four
W's. And when people hear that, they
link it back to me. You know, the
beautiful thing is when you do this
enough, you'll find that people start
actually coming to you and using your
phrases in just their normal language.
And so is it just creates this brandable
language that is associated with you,
which I think is incredibly powerful.
Let's get into the next aspect here,
right, which is content multiplication.
When it comes to multiplying your
content, there is no better system than
the content waterfall system. With this
system, you're able to go and repurpose
one pillar piece of content into 36
other pieces of content. This is a beast
of a system. Let me give you an example
here because I'm much better probably at
showing you than just telling you. Let's
just say we take this long form YouTube
video here, which is how to build a
profitable personal brand in just 30
days. This video on my YouTube got over
250,000
views in just a few months. What we then
do with this piece of content is we can
go and turn it into three Instagram
reels, right? and taking out the best 60
seconds of content from this long form
piece and using that for short form
Instagram content. Those three Instagram
reels can now also become three YouTube
shorts as well as three Tik Tok videos.
Now the cool thing is is that in any
given 12minute YouTube video, that's
approximately 2500 words of copy. Those
2500 words have little nuggets in it
that can be used to write another 10
tweets for X. It can also be used for
one newsletter that I can go and publish
in 6 weeks. And in addition to that, I
can probably go and create three long
form LinkedIn posts off of this as well.
This is an example of my content being
multiplied. When you're going and you're
building up your content strategy across
all the different platforms, at first
you're probably just focusing on one
platform, right? It's much better to do
one platform really, really well than to
spread yourself thin across all five
platforms. That said, as you scale,
you're probably going to want to create
more of an omniresent content strategy.
So, when someone's on YouTube, then
switches to Instagram, goes to X, then
LinkedIn, there you are. When you go and
you start eventually thinking about
being on more platforms, you don't want
to end up on a content hamster wheel.
You know, quality suffers, energy
suffers, which leads to burnout. And
this is where I see so many founders
just give up. The content waterfall
system allows you to multiply your
effort, allow you to delegate more of
your content to folks on your team. So
you can focus on making, say, one great
piece of content every week as an
example, and know that that great piece
of content will be multiplied using the
content waterfall system into 30 plus
other pieces of content. I give you more
details on this inside of the personal
brand workbook. So, you can go and check
that out to help go and scale your
efforts and build more leverage in your
business and with your time. All right,
let's get into the last piece here in
terms of um the content GPS side of
things, which is your content
distribution. Each platform has its own
nuances, and I'm going to get into
what's worked best for me across each of
these platforms. So when it comes to
YouTube, right, the main way of growing
on YouTube is just creating highquality
long- form content. It's a platform that
values quality much higher than any
other platform. And what that means is
it's actually better to create one
highquality video every month versus
creating like 16 mediocre pieces of
content on a monthly basis. 80% of the
battle is your packaging, which is your
title, your thumbnail, your idea. And if
you don't have time to go and really
think about great packaging by
researching on platforms like
oneof10.com, looking at different
outliers, going and taking time to
develop a great thumbnail, a great
title, and even testing those using AB
testing that's embedded into YouTube,
you may be missing out on a lot of the
battle. On X, my approach has always
been to create two pieces of content a
day, every day at 8:00 a.m. EST and 2:00
p.m. EST. This is a platform and really
the only one that I found that allows
you to use an external tool and it
doesn't seem to affect your reach. So
the tool that I use on X is called Hype
Fury. Inside of Hype Fury, I go and I'm
able to create and batch all of my
tweets and then it will automatically go
and ensure that those are released again
at 8:00 a.m. and at 2 p.m. and I don't
need to do any more work. So it's a
beautiful thing. What I also do is
produce four longer form pieces of
content for X about four days a week on
Wednesday, Thursday, Saturday, and
Sunday because that's what I've seen
work best is on every single piece of
content across X. Um, I have core CTAs
that lead people to my newsletter. But
we'll get into that a little bit later
here in this master class. When it comes
to LinkedIn, I've talked about that I
distribute every single day. As I've
built up my personal media empire, it's
actually my social media manager that's
posting to LinkedIn every day. What we
found is when people use scheduling
tools, it actually can screw up your
reach on LinkedIn. And so we avoid
those. We always include a high quality
image with the post because we find that
it helps it get more reach. And then at
the bottom of the LinkedIn post, we have
a CTA that leads people to join my
newsletter. When it comes to Instagram,
I use Nick, my chief distribution
officer, to distribute all of that
content. So, the process there is I'll
go and create all the copy or my team
will go and edit down the reels from
longer form content. And then from
there, Yan, the creative director, will
go and actually stylize the grid so that
it looks super aesthetic. We use
figma.com to go and design a beautiful
grid. We are very intentional about what
we're putting out there. And so we use
Figma to go and create the look of the
grid, including the different thumbnails
for the different reels I put out, as
well as all of the Instagram carousels
that we make. That content is
distributed around 8:00 a.m. every
morning and 1:00 p.m. every afternoon.
So, a carousel and a reel every single
day. On Tik Tok, it's truthfully just a
lot of my Instagram real content that
I'm just also posting up to Tik Tok. And
then from there, my newsletter is
something I publish twice per week. If
you're going more writing first, you're
likely going to do X in LinkedIn and
drive people to a newsletter. If you're
going more video first, you're probably
going to do Instagram, uh, Tik Tok, as
well as YouTube and drive people to a
newsletter. With all of this
optimization, right, I want to just also
point out that when I'm looking to grow
on a given platform, I actually don't
focus too much on metrics. When you get
too caught up in the views and the
metrics, I think it just leads to misery
because the reality is is that the
algorithm is always going up and it's
going down. And you can't control all of
that all the time. What you can control
is your effort and your approach to the
daily work. And what I found most
helpful is to actually just focus on the
artistry, the mastery, the craftsmanship
of making content that's insanely
generous, that helps make an impact in
people's lives. And the coolest part of
this is what I've learned is that when
you focus on the craft, the score takes
care of itself. So on the more
quantitative metric side of things, I
like to keep it simple. When you have
too many metrics, it just leads to
confusion. Every single person in my
company has one core metric that
determines success. And similarly off
the platforms when I'm thinking about
YouTube or X, LinkedIn, whatever, I like
to think of one or two metrics max that
really determines the success in that
given platform. For YouTube, it may be
things like, you know, subscriber growth
and then the amount of views per video.
For X, it may be the amount of views
we're getting per week and the amount of
followers we're driving per week. On
LinkedIn, same thing, views and
followers. On Instagram, same deal
really. It's kind of views and
followers. In addition to that, the most
important thing that I do across all of
my businesses and my personal brand is
take time, you know, every month
personally to go and look at what were
our top 10 performers on a given
platform and what were the bottom 10
performers and what are the patterns in
that content and what's the stuff we
should double down on and the stuff that
we should stop doing. So, what this
allows me to do is really delegate all
of those metrics, all of the performance
analysis, and allow my team to go and
execute that so that I can focus most on
creating art, creating beauty, creating
stuff I'm proud of, that's informed by
the data, but doesn't necessarily need
to be all around the data. Keep your
metrics simple. Pick one or two metrics
per platform. do a bit of a content
audit every month, looking at your best
content and then your worst content,
doubling down on the patterns that work
and removing the stuff that is not
working. And honestly, when you put in
those reps over the long term, imagine
doing that for 3 years, 5 years, 10
years. Imagine how smart you'll be. Go
and determine your metric per platform.
Keep it simple, have fun, and get after
it. All right, so you master the content
GPS system, and you're not going to have
to worry about what you're going to post
ever again. But if you don't have this
next piece, I'd say there's probably no
chance you're building a profitable
personal brand. Because what we need to
get into now is how to actually turn all
that cold, hard attention you've been
driving online into predictable revenue.
And we're going to do that through
proven monetization systems. We're not
just building a personal brand for
followers or vanity metrics. We're
building this to actually build a real
business around us. What I want to first
describe to you is my own monetization
philosophy. Most creators view it like
content drives followers and then they
just kind of hope that money appears.
But successful founder brands really see
it like putting out content, owning your
audience, getting systematic conversion,
and then predictable revenue from all
that attention you're driving. And the
difference really is having the right
bridges set up to convert your audience
from awareness all the way through to
purchase. There are really three main
revenue bridges that we're going to
cover here. Number one are your
strategic CTAs. This is where you're
going to convert people into your
product ecosystem. Number two is your
newsletter engine. So this is where you
actually are able to go and build rich
one-to-one relationships with your
audience. And lastly is your conversion
systems. This is where we're going to
turn trust into transactions. And so,
let's get into bridge number one,
strategic CTAs. When you're going and
creating content online, you're creating
this ocean of attention. And with all of
that attention, you want to make sure
that you have CTAs, which are kind of
like a net that's going to catch the
fish from that ocean of attention. Now,
CTA stands for call to actions. I place
CTAs in 20 different locations across
all of my social platforms. On LinkedIn,
as an example, you can put call to
actions in your bio link. You can put it
in your about section. You can have your
featured section on LinkedIn plug your
newsletter, your core product, and
things like workshops or webinars you
may launch. You can also go and put it
at the end of a post. And also if you
have any images that you're sharing on
LinkedIn, you can also embed CTAs into
those images. On YouTube, as an example,
you can put your CTAs within your
videos. You can have them as well in the
description of any video that you put
out. You can put them in your about
section um and as well in your banner on
YouTube. Now, on Instagram, CTAs appear
in things like your stories, in your
Instagram bio. You can be putting it at
the end of your captions and also
embedding different CTAs into the actual
reels themselves. On X, I like to put
all of my CTAs in the bio. You can also
plug it if you'd like in your X cover
photo within each tweet as well as in
any threads. You can also go and drive
people at the end of them to go and join
your newsletter. And on Tik Tok, I also
put it just in the bio. So those are of
the 20 strategic CTA spots that you can
go and plug into your content. And I've
gone and listed all these inside of the
personal brand workbook in the
description below. So let's start to
talk a bit about the CTA optimization
framework. Okay, this is where you know
you actually make the CTAs rich,
contextual, and make sure that people
are as enticed as possible to convert to
the call to action that you put in your
content. So number one is you want the
CTA to match the content context. If
you're sharing audience growth tips,
well then your CTA should be related to
some sort of audience growth resources.
You then want to make sure you're using
benefit driven language. Okay? So
instead of just subscribe to my
newsletter, you may say, you know, get
my free weekly systems that help
founders scale to $5 million. Creating
some urgency scarcity can also be really
good. Like join 120,000 founders getting
my Saturday systems email is much better
than just hey subscribe for tips. These
are a few tips to help you go and really
make sure that you're increasing your
conversion rate from your social
audience to your newsletter and then
within your newsletter to your product.
All right, let's get into bridge number
two, your newsletter engine.
Newsletters, honestly, I think are the
most underrated form of media ownership
that exists out there. And newsletter
audiences convert about 120% better than
social media followers for one core
reason, permission. they've given you
permission to really build that richer
relationship with them. Eventually, that
relationship can convert into revenue.
Let's talk about the first part of your
newsletter engine, which is building it
strategically. First off, you want to
create a focused signup page. For an
example of this, you can go to
founder.com/newsletter.
And you can see that this is a landing
page. People can't scroll anywhere in
the header bar. And so, what I have here
is a bold value proposition. I've got
credibility showing other entrepreneurs
speaking highly of what I've built. you
see a clear promise saying that they're
just getting one email every week that
gives them a proven system to grow their
profitable personal brand. One core
aspect that I always do. It doesn't
matter what newsletter I create. I
always have some form of lead magnet.
Your lead magnet can be anything, right?
A checklist, a chapter of a book. It
could be a resource, a diagram, it could
be, you know, a system, a playbook that
you've made, a blueprint. Just that's
what you want to put on the other side
of someone going and giving you their
email. And so the key again is to give
something to people and ask yourself,
you know, what would be so insanely
generous that people can't help but sign
up for my newsletter. Inside of your
newsletter, one of my favorite ways of
converting people that I've made
millions of dollars doing over the last
few years is via your newsletter welcome
series. So what you're going to do is
have a five email educational email
series when people sign up to your
newsletter. And then you're going to
have what I call a four email FOMO
series, meaning fear of missing out. So
that five email educational series, it's
probably going to have one email around
immediate value, right? Delivering the
lead magnet that you had promised
people. The second thing is you're
probably then going to get into your
origin story in the second email, how
you got to doing what you do, some
social proof around it, you know, why
you're doing it, kind of like your
hero's journey. From there, you're going
to get into a third email around social
proof, probably highlighting someone
that you've helped. The fourth part is
then you're going to start setting
expectations for what people can expect
as being a part of your community, the
movement, and this, you know, newsletter
community that you're building. And then
fifth is you're probably going to give a
soft introduction to your actual paid
offering. So, you're not going to sell
people hardcore in this, right? We don't
want to come across salesy, but you just
want to introduce like this is what I
do. this is how I do it and these are
the kind of people that I serve. From
there, what you're then going to have is
a FOMO series which could be anywhere
from four emails to six emails. And
these are going to go and sell people
more directly. In these, you may talk
about different success stories that
people have had with your product. You
may talk about some of the biggest
benefits of your product or some big
problems you've solved and then give
people a clear articulation of exactly
what you do, how you do it. And then
probably if you're more of like a
community or it's a course, maybe it's
an agency, you're probably going to
drive people to an actual sales call. If
you're a SAS product or an e-commerce
product, at that point, you're probably
driving people just to go and purchase
the product on a given product landing
page. The cool thing is is that every
single person that you have signing up
to your newsletter is then receiving
this nine email series over the first 9
days of joining your newsletter. And so
you can imagine as you shovel in more
newsletter subscribers, you just have
more people automatically going through
this welcome series. Once that series is
done, they're then joining your weekly
newsletter series. The key metrics to
consider tracking with your newsletter
are things like number one, your open
rates, you want to be aiming for 60%
plus. Your click-through rates, you want
to aim for over 8%. Your reply rates,
aim for over 2%. conversion rates to
paid offers generally trying to get to
20% plus there and then your subscriber
lifetime value just like you know your
packaging is your most important element
for you know YouTube and your hook is
your most valuable element of a thread
when it comes to your newsletter it's
your subject line examples of really
high converting subject lines are things
like you know curiosity driven you know
like this mistake that cost me $100,000
could be something that's more benefit
focused like how to 10x your content
reach
There's things that are more personal
like, you know, my biggest failure and
what it taught me or things like number
driven ones, right? Seven systems that
built my $13 million business. When
you're going and building your list,
right, you want to be super intentional,
build something you're proud of, and
understand that you are building
probably the most valuable asset in your
business because inevitably your
newsletter list is your customer list.
More newsletter subscribers, probably
the more profit you're driving to your
personal media company. All right, so
we've gone through the newsletter engine
side of things. Now, let's get into your
conversion systems. So, let's move on
then to the second aspect of actually
going and driving sales, right? Which is
your discovery call framework. I want to
give you a bit of detail here on my
60-minute call structure. So, minutes 1
to 20, you're going to do a lot of deep
qualification of people, right? You're
going to understand what's their biggest
challenge right now. What are they
really trying to do in their life, in
their business? What's working? What's
not working? You know, what does success
look like for them? and what's the cost
for them not solving that problem.
You're really gaining a lot of intel.
You're understanding their pain, what
they're really trying to do, and what
they're trying to avoid. Then you're
going to be able to then position what
you're building in the most strategic
way possible. Minutes 21 to 40, you're
now going over your fourpillar
presentation, right? Which you're going
to then present probably your proven
system for actually addressing their
problems and helping them get towards
what they're really trying to do. When
it comes into minutes 41 to 60, this is
really where it's all about your close
and your objection handling. People are
going to have questions, right? It's
inevitable. And your job is to help them
gradually navigate that based on what
you learned in the discovery call
aspect. And so you ask those questions
to understand where they're at so that
later on when you're going and covering
objections, you can make sure that
they're tailored to that person's
specific situation. When you're going
and starting your offer, you should
probably be making the first 50 sales of
your product. And you're probably going,
"Damn it, can I just hire a
salesperson?" No. You need to understand
what someone's objections are, how they
handle it, what they ask questions
around, right? So, you can go and keep
on tailoring your offer for your
audience. The chances that you go and
just start pitching the thing at first
and it's perfect and ready to go are
very slim. And so by you actually being
on those calls and hearing the feedback
firsthand from your audience, you're
able to go and sculpt your offer to make
sure that it overcomes the common
objections you're hearing, that it's at
the right price point, and that it's
helping people as simply as possible get
to where they're trying to go and
convert. And then what happens is is you
finally hit product market fit. You have
something that people genuinely want.
and you've sold it enough yourself that
you're now in a position to actually go
and build out your sales team. When you
think about kind of KPIs or key
performance indicators of this part of
your process, first off, you want to
make sure you have a show up rate on
calls of at least 80%. Okay, this shows
proper qualification. The second piece
then is your close rate. We want that to
be above 35%. Okay, that's going to
indicate strong product market fit.
Lastly, we want your customer
satisfaction, right, to be above 90%.
So, putting this all together now,
right? You've gone and created all of
these bridges for your product and we
are well on our way to building your
profitable personal brand. So, in the
next section, I'm going to go and show
you how to automate and scale these
systems so that they can run without
you. Let's go.
Not a bad view, I guess. Not bad. Hot
damn. I don't know if you can tell yet,
but we just summited the third mountain
in 3 days here in Lafeton, Norway. This
was some random challenge that we came
up with. And I'd be lying to you if I
didn't say, you know, along the way, I
was thinking, you know, why did we even
do this? You know, should we just give
up? You know, I felt that many, many
times, right? Whether it's building
businesses or even building my personal
brand, I want to address the elephant in
the room. I want to address the
psychological barriers that come up as
you're building your brand. Starting off
with procrastination. We put off some of
the most important things in our life.
And with your personal brand, you may be
putting it off because you're nervous or
you're worried about what other people
are going to say. What I want to tell
you are these three words. Do it messy.
I oftenimes find when I'm
procrastinating, it's because, you know,
I don't feel like I'm quite ready yet or
I'm, you know, worried that I could do a
better job if I just waited a little
longer and waited a little longer. And I
tell myself that, you know, someday I'll
get it done. Someday is one of the
biggest diseases often times and we all
know it. Someday never comes. What I
want to again encourage you to do is to
do it messy. Just show up. Just hit
publish. Just do the thing. Give it a
shot. You know, even if it's a bit
janky, it's a little all over the place.
It's not that tight. That's okay. A lot
of the clarity from building your
personal brand is going to come from
just putting things out there, taking
action, and then the action breeds
clarity, which breed results, which
breeds momentum, which gets you more
addicted to the process. And when you're
addicted to the process and you do it
long enough, great things happen. So,
the next psychological barrier that
often times come up is perfectionism. I
want to go over one key concept with
you, which is done is better than
perfect. This might strike you as a bit
odd because a lot of the time I'm
talking about quality and aesthetics and
beauty and taste. And hey, all of these
things are important. What's most
important is that you actually ship the
thing. The beauty, the taste, the
evolution of your brand, the journey.
That's what people are really after. You
go look a couple years ago at my old
YouTube videos. You know, these things
were definitely far from perfect, and
they weren't anything to be overly proud
of either. But I'm actually super proud
of myself looking back. And the reason
why is because I just got started. You
know, I didn't have it all figured out.
But I didn't let that stop me from
putting things out there. Along the
journey of building my brand, I started
making different tweaks, learning things
that would work. I started fixing the
sound, got better equipment, you know, I
started to, you know, put more thought
into the thumbnails, the titles, the
length of the videos, the animations,
the motion graphics. I started building
out an awesome team. But it all came
from putting in the reps. Most of the
learnings that I got along the journey
of building my personal brand, there was
no way these things would be obvious to
me day one. I had to get started for
these things to become apparent to me.
It was from the doing that the clarity
came about. And so if you're struggling
with perfectionism, I want you to
remember my voice in your head, which is
done is better than perfect. Now, it's
all good to focus on creation, but you
know, I see so many people that are just
worried about what other people think.
This is probably one of the most nasty
psychological barriers. You know, people
are worried about what their family's
going to think or what old people from
high school are going to think about
what they're building. I get it because
I struggled with this, right? I was
worried what my team would think. I was
worried what old business partners would
think. And it paralyzed me for a while.
And I probably didn't get started with
my personal brand for about 2 years
because of this fear. So trust me, I
understand it. Often times as humans, we
fear that which is not to come. We
exacerbate these fears, right? We give
way too much credence to them. You need
to build with blindfolds. Don't worry
about what other people are saying about
you or thinking. I've built an audience
now of over 3 million around my personal
brand. We push 81 million views a month,
all organic, without spending a dime on
ads. you know, any given day, any given
week, I can't even remember who's been
talking [\h__\h] And I say this just to
really, you know, give you a sense that
it really doesn't matter. And again,
you're probably kind of exacerbating
these fears, right? They're not that
real and it's not something you should
be spending more than a second worrying
about. What I often times see people get
caught up in as well is they feel like
they're not doing enough. They start to
feel like they're constantly behind.
Content is like a forever game. It's an
infinite game, right? There's always
more you can do, more YouTube videos,
more time you could spend on packaging,
deeper you could go in the art of it
all, in the data, the analytics. It's an
endless endless game. And with that, it
does have the potential to lead to
burnout if you're not careful. What I
want to say to those that get really
caught up there or get a little
overwhelmed by just the sheer amount of
stuff you could be doing is to remember,
no recovery, no results. You know, my
belief is that entrepreneurs are like
athletes. We need, you know, time to
train. We need a coach to help us go and
achieve new levels. We need to surround
oursel with the right community of
fellow founders to scale. But we also
need time for recovery. Without
recovery, we can't, you know, see on the
horizon. We can't really look out and
see other potential opportunities
because I'm in this for the long term
and I want to keep it sustainable and
fun and energizing. I make sure that I'm
working at a pace that just feels right.
Because if I can stick to that pace,
then I stick to the compounding. And if
the compounding keeps happening, I know
over the long term, I'm probably going
to accomplish things that I could never
even have imagined today. The last
psychological barrier I want to go over
because I hear this from founders all
the time is people pleasing. As we start
to make space for building our
profitable personal brand, we start to
notice different people clawing at us or
pulling us away from it. And this leads
me to the anecdote to this psychological
barrier, which is the no advantage.
Saying no is a superpower. Too many of
us just become yes people early on in
our careers. And while that's super
helpful often times for the first decade
of your career, later on as you start
kind of scaling out your brand, scaling
out your audience, building more
leverage, building a team, building your
personal media company, you need to be a
lot more selective about the
opportunities you say yes to and the
things you say no to. You know, look at
some of the richest people on the planet
like Warren Buffett, right? Warren
Buffett is known for saying no to 99.9%
of things that come, you know, his way.
That way, when a real opportunity comes
by, and that's undeniably, it's
unignorable. It's something that is
going to have an outsized opportunity at
changing the trajectory of his career,
he's able to say yes to it and have the
space to do that. And I want you to take
a similar approach to building your
profitable personal brand. be conscious
of where you're spending your time
because it's finite. And you've been
going through this master class and
you've been seeing there's quite a bit
of pieces involved here. And it's worth
it. It's worth being able to go and
multiply your time, multiply your
influence, multiply your audience. These
things are insanely high lever things.
And this is what the future, you know,
of entrepreneurship looks like. And
you're here because you believe that and
you want to tap into it. But I want to
tell you that most people around you,
they won't understand this. We know
though that what we're building are
founder-ledd brands. And to do this, it
takes a bit of time. And it takes saying
no to distractions to go and be able to
focus on building something that's going
to be an appreciating asset that you own
for the rest of your life. You may be
thinking, Matt, this is great and all,
but I honestly feel a little
overwhelmed. I get it, right? You've got
content categories and your icky guy and
your calling and the different tools and
monetizing and your product and your
offers. There's quite a bit of stuff to
think about. The biggest pill against
overwhelm is thinking about your one
domino. Your one domino is the one thing
that will help make everything else
easier or unnecessary. You know, there's
a popular book that I've been reading
right now called The Slight Edge. And it
goes over this concept, this idea of in
each moment, we can pick just that one
thing that can help change the
trajectory of our life. When you go and
you choose that slight edge in every
moment, right? Focusing on that one
thing. That's the most important thing
you can get done. Now, you'd be
surprised at how the compounding effect
works. 1% better every day is 37 times
better in a year. When you're feeling
overwhelmed, I want you to remember this
one domino rule. Don't feel like you
need to go and do it all in one go. It's
impossible. From watching this master
class and just choosing one thing a day
and then another thing a day, you can
stack up some massive wins along the
way. If you want my help or my team's
help going and scaling your founder
brand, you know, that's exactly what we
do inside of Founder OS, which is
honestly my life's work. We have an
insane community of fellow high growth
founders just like you scaling their
personal brands to the next level. I
include over 180 systems. There's also a
custom AI agent that's trained on over 3
million words and all of my public and
private systems. We also have epic
founder retreats that we host every
single year as well as over 50 live
sessions every single month. If you're
looking to take massive action, if you
want to join an unbelievably vibrant
community of founders that are all
collectively building founder brands for
the future, you should check out Founder
OS and you can go and check out a link
for Founder OS and apply via the link in
the description. Let's keep moving here.
We got a lot more to cover. Automations
in team building. I'm going to go over
some core systems I've used to get more
of my time back and be able to build
massive amounts of leverage. When I
first started building businesses 15
years ago, I really didn't know how to
delegate and I really struggled to, you
know, get my time back. You know, I had
a team of about 23 people, but I found
myself being the chief everything
officer, not the actual CEO. You know,
night after night spending all of my
time building, creating, hiring, firing,
you name it. It all came down to me. And
I reached a breaking point. I eventually
learned some core systems that helped me
go and get more of my time back. And I'm
going to share those with you today.
When it comes to looking at your time,
you need to get the AED system right.
That stands for automate, eliminate, and
delegate. I learned this because, you
know, from my days at Bitmaker,
overloading myself with a ton of stuff
and just leading to burnout. I realized
that first off I needed to look at my
time and where it was being spent
because at the end of the day time is
your most valuable resource as a founder
and your focus is your scars resource. I
like to go and audit then what is every
single task I've gone and completed over
the last month and where has all the
time in my calendar gone to? I go and I
list these all out in a Google sheet
typically and then I have the columns
automate, eliminate and delegate. First
things first, you want to look at the
stuff that you can eliminate because if
you shouldn't even be doing it in the
first place, no sense delegating or
automating it. You might as well just
get that off your plate. The next aspect
here then is automating, right? Are
there tools that you can use whether
it's Hype Fury, HubSpot, Chat, GBT,
Zapier, pick a tool. The point is, can
you just go and get this stuff off your
plate, automate it so it just runs on
autopilot going forward. The next aspect
then is delegate. And if you mark
something as being something you should
delegate, you want to mark who on your
team can do this or who do you need to
hire to do this ideally then have
documentation and systemize exactly what
that task is. Film a Loom video around
the given task and then go and hand that
off to someone so that they can do it
even better than you thereby relieving
your time and you're making now that
person the systems designer going
forward. Meaning they are in charge of
it. They own it and they are the one
responsible for it so that you have the
peace of mind that that's off your plate
and you can focus on tasks that are more
in your zone of brilliance. You know,
building a personal brand is cool, but
what's even better is building your
personal media company. The difference
is that you're not just the creator
behind everything that you're actually
able to be the CEO and have a whole team
around you who's going and helping you
build things. I'm going to go and break
down the core roles that you're probably
going to want to have over time. But
first things first, I want to get into
some delegation math. What I like to do
is think about first off, what is my
hourly rate? So for me, my hourly rate
is $6,000 an hour. So let's say with
something like a social media manager,
right? Say that person costs $8,000 a
month as just a random example. At
$8,000 a month, let's say that person
saves me 80 hours of time. So 20 hours a
week. If we take, you know, those 80
hours and we multiply it by the $6,000,
I think it's like $480,000. That's a lot
of money. $480,000 a month of time being
saved because that social media manager
at 8,000 is like something like, you
know, we're talking like a 20x ROI on
that person, which is insane. I'm not
just spending my time and chilling. I'm
using those 80 hours that I've saved
from that hire and then reallocating it
to much more highlever revenue
generating activities. Then when I go
and I think about, you know, the actual
personal media company I need to go and
build, how I typically think about this
is there's a few core hires that I like
to make. I'm going to make a social
media manager hire. If I'm going writing
first, I'm going to eventually have a
writing hire. If I'm going video first,
I'm going to have a video editor hire.
I'm going to have a tech person on my
team. I'm going to have my chief of
staff. And I'm probably going to have a
closer to help us actually go and
generate cash. Starting from the top,
your social media manager is in charge
of going and distributing all of your
content. Okay? So, this is the person
that essentially is going to take any
content that you have and make sure that
it's on the right platform at the right
time with the right captions and
everything is dialed in. They're
essentially my chief distribution
officer making sure that all content is
distributed flawlessly and we are
growing on these platforms. The next
aspect is a writer. When you're going
and scaling up on platforms like X,
LinkedIn, and your newsletter, it
quickly becomes a lot of writing. And so
often times what you want to do is have
a writer helping you there with a lot of
the packaging of your writing. So it's
still your words, it's still your ideas,
but they're helping package it up into
things like X threads, LinkedIn posts,
and newsletters, thereby saving you
another 10 hours a week, 40 hours a
month that you can reallocate to more
revenue generating activities. And when
you do that, you're going to get a hell
of an ROI from that hire. The next
aspect is if you're a video first
creator, you're definitely going to want
a video editor. A video editor
essentially is just in charge of cutting
down, you know, long form content like
this and making sure it's actually
formatted right for platforms like
YouTube. And then they're going to be in
charge of also doing your short form
content as well for things like
Instagram reels, Tik Tok, and YouTube
shorts. The key thing here is there's a
massive difference between someone that
just edits videos and then someone that
is experienced with editing videos for
the given platform. And the latter is
really, really important. You want to
make sure that you get someone with
YouTube experience. And you want to
actually look at their portfolio so you
can determine, hey, is this stuff at the
bar of quality that I expect in terms of
the edits, the pacing, the B-roll, the
style, the taste. You want to make sure
obviously it fits your brand and it's
something that you really feel good
about, right? Because a 10x team is
going to produce 10x results. Whereas,
if you just hire a bunch of mediocre
people, well, you're going to get what
you tolerate. The next person in line
now is your tech person. It's important
that you have someone to build things
like your landing pages, your
automation, set up your CRM, and make
sure that all the piping of everything
you've built is all nicely and
seamlessly integrated. Now, let's move
on to the next hire here, which is your
chief of staff. The key thing that I
have my chief of staff do is audit my
calendar every single week and plan out
my next week to make sure that it's as
optimized as possible, that I'm working
on the highest leveraged tasks available
to me, and anything else is off my
plate. The last thing is all internal
communication. Slack, email, company
updates, team all hands, different oneto
ones. I delegate a lot of that work to
my chief of staff. That then frees up my
time to work on things like being able
to write my book, being able to create a
couple YouTube videos a week, being able
to go and make big hires, close massive
strategic deals, and just have time to
think, which is super important. The
chief of staff can help you go and make
sure that this whole team is integrated
and running flawlessly, so you don't
have to be distracted with internal
operations and can instead work on the
business, not inside it. The last hire
you want to be thinking about obviously
is a closer. The closer is going to be
in charge of running your sales calls.
Being super strategic there in terms of
getting on calls with folks, determining
if they're the right fit for what you're
building, getting them across the line,
collecting payment, and getting you
rocking and rolling. So now you can
serve that customer in the delivery side
of your business. On the closer side,
what I'm really looking for there
primarily are two things. I want people
that are insanely hungry and are
coachable. When they're hungry, you know
that they're going to go the extra mile
for people and get those deals closed.
When they're coachable, you know they're
going to be receptive to feedback. And
I'm requiring all of my sales people to
also send end of day reports every
single day so that we know what's going
well, what's not going well, what
they're blocked on, and what they need
help with. The right closer makes all
the difference, and you should be aiming
for someone that's capable of getting
your close rate above 30%. the revenue
engine of your business is running
without you and you can go and focus on
the things that are going to seriously
move your business forward, not just
over the next year, but help you ladder
up to your vision over the next 10
years. All right, now we're going to get
into the art of intentional content. As
I've grown as an entrepreneur, I
actually see myself as more of an artist
than an entrepreneur. There's the art of
creating beautiful content, content with
taste, with style, with your tone, your
own point of view. You know, the
artistry, I think it matters because
amidst a sea of constant noise online,
there's something for it to be said for
just making things your own. We didn't
have to climb nine mountains in 9 days
filming this series, but it's for the
artistry, folks. The art. I want to give
you some tips that I've learned, some
things that I think about when I'm
creating intentional content. The first
things first that your taste is the
ultimate competitive advantage. Taste to
me is being able to use your own
creative intuition. You know, you've
probably got all of these things in your
head, things you've seen, sites you've
seen, music you've listened to, art
you've looked at. Maybe it's things on
Pinterest boards, Instagram collections,
YouTube playlists. Who knows where
you're getting it from? You're saving
all of these references in your brain,
in your taste, I think, is this
unwavering desire to make sure that
whatever you produce, it hits that bar.
But each piece of content that we put
out, it represents a piece of art with
our name on it. And it's an opportunity
to put our own stamp, our own signature
on it. When I go and I think about
creators these days, I actually think
that the best creators are the best
curators. When you're going and you're
looking to make amazing content, I often
times find it's useful to be able to go
and know and understand what amazing
content even looks like. The more that
you're able to move from being a
consumer online to actually a curator,
you start to be able to refine your own
pallet for the art that you share.
examples of places that I go and I
curate, you know, my own pallet. I read
a ton of books and so I'll go and read
books like The Courage to be Disliked,
Zen in the Art of Motorcycle
Maintenance, The Creative Act, The
Slight Edge, and The Psychology of
Money, Same as Ever, Atomic Habits,
Systemmology. And when I'm reading a
book, I'll highlight it. And those
highlights through a Read Wise
integration get ported over to a notion
board that looks like this. What happens
then is all of these highlights across
these books are all saved to this notion
that I can reference at any time. And
this serves as this amazing library of
all of my favorite quotes, copies,
sentences that I can then go and
reference for future art that I create.
What ends up happening is when you start
to refine what you like, your own taste,
your own references, you create this
massive mental board of what beauty
looks like to you. And so what I want
you to do as an action step is go and
save a YouTube playlist with your taste.
Go and save an Instagram collection with
your taste and start to then be able to
go and curate your taste online so that
as you start to create you have a
abundance of different sources of
inspiration so that you never run dry.
For me, my vision and what I'm building
is to inspire 100 million founders just
like you to accomplish their dreams
through proven systems. Over the next 3
years with Founder S, my goal is to help
over 100,000 founders through Founder OS
to build out my audience to over 50
million people to release, you know,
five best-selling books over the next 5
years. most importantly build a team
that when I look to the left and look to
the right of me, I'm got to pinch myself
that I get to work with these people.
All of that is going to come about, I
think, just by focusing on what's in
front of me, approaching it like it's
this opportunity to create a
masterpiece. And if I can keep on making
stuff that I think is amazing, stuff
that I would want, then it passes my
elevated bar of art that we want to put
out there. And I think as we keep doing
that, we create a brand that stands for
something. We create a movement of
founders that really believe in freedom.
Freedom to work where you want, when you
want, on what you want, with who you
want, and to live a vibrant life, being
able to explore, adventure, and have
fun.
So, you've probably been listening to
this and you're also wondering, you
know, Matt, what separates the founders
that are successful in setting up a
profitable personal brand from those
that eventually fail. And so, I'd love
to double click into that a little bit.
First things first is the people that
are successful do the work. The people
that are not successful focus on their
feelings any given day and don't do what
is necessary. And this is true for life.
This is true for relationships. And it's
also true with your personal brand. This
takes an investment of your time and
energy. But it's worth it, right? Look
at the media levers that you can build.
Look at the amount of community and the
movement you can build. The audience now
that you can go and find top talent
from, build your business, get more
customers from. It's a no-brainer. But
you have to show up. The next aspect
that really separates people is
consistency over perfectionism, right?
The ones that are successful just focus
on showing up, being consistent day
after day, and great things happen.
Those that end up falling apart are just
focused on perfectionism. They're trying
to make the perfect piece of content. It
stays in the backlog. They never publish
it. Thereby, they never get the
leverage. They never get the feedback
and everything just stays behind the
scenes versus being actually shown to
the world. When you push the content,
when you publish it, when you get it out
there, that is when the leverage begins.
What you want to be focused on is daily
shipping. When you ship it, you get
those leverage wheels turning. You're
building your founder flywheel. You're
learning. You're getting feedback that
you can then apply to future content.
And this machine is running. Just ship
it. The next aspect that separates folks
that are successful from not is that
they just execute the systems. There are
systems for content creation, your
content waterfall system, for hiring,
for building your team, for growing on
each of the different platforms. Just
execute the systems. There's a lot of
area to be c creative here, but also
don't reinvent the wheel. You execute
the systems, the growth happens, right?
And what you want to be doing is as a
founder limiting the amount of decisions
you need to make in a day. Your personal
brand is an appreciating asset that you
own. And now you have the entire
blueprint to go and implement your
content GPS, build massive leverage,
build your personal media company, and
build something most importantly that
you're having fun with. Along the way,
if you want my help and my team's help,
you should definitely go and check out
Founder OS. You'll get over 50 live
sessions with me and my team per month.
You'll be able to join Q&As's with me to
go and answer any questions you have
around building your personal brand. You
get access to over 180 systems, a custom
founder AI agent we've built, and so
much more. If this is interesting to
you, you should definitely go and book a
call via the link in the description.
Get on a call with either me or my team,
and we can learn more about what you're
really trying to do with your brand this
year and help you out. Thank you so much
for being a part of this personal
branding masterclass experience. I
appreciate your time and I look forward
to working with you. Let's win together.