[Music]
so you want to build a personal brand
but you don't know
[Music]
how if you're like the thousands of
others watching right now you're stuck
with a low follower account in bad post
maybe you've tried and failed a bunch of
times already or maybe you're too scared
to take the First Steps this video is
for you one of my biggest regrets is not
building a personal brand sooner when
the evidence was right in front of me
Tesla has 30 million followers Elon Musk
has 187 million followers Spanx has
400,000 followers Sarah Blakeley has 2
million virgin has 700,000 followers
Richard Branson has 15 million so I took
action and I relaunched myself online as
the face of my new company and became
the mentor of Founders scaling to $5
million profit a year and a master of
systems in this video I'm going to go
and give you the blueprint to building a
profitable personal brand in the next 30
days that's all it takes to go from no
leads inconsistent growth and no systems
to building a strong personal brand that
is a magnet for opportunities customers
community and endless cash flow I know
this blueprint works because I've used
it on my own personal brand which has
brought me four profitable companies an
audience of over 2 million people and a
portfolio of online businesses that
generates over $13.8 million of Revenue
a year and the best news is I documented
analyzed and packaged every step of the
process to create this personal brand
system that you can use to do the same
it all comes down to Five Pillars your
brand system compounding content
audience growth systems monetization
moments and a core Team all buildable
and doable within the next 30 days after
you finish watching this video and
subscribing to this
[Music]
channel number one brand system your
brand is what people say about you when
you're not in the room whether you know
it or not you have a personal brand the
question is are you intentionally
growing it are you comfortable with how
you portray yourself online are you
intentionally leveraging your personal
brand to grow your business we are all
brands and you own 100% of it so how do
you create a personal brand that is a
magnet for your dream customer you need
to get clear on your vision your mission
your values goals target market content
categories content IP and content ideas
what is your one sentence statement that
outlines what your company does why it
does it and how it gets it done my
mission with found
is to help over a 100 million
entrepreneurs accomplish their dreams
through proven systems your values
determine the tone voice and personality
that you're going to have online from
there you want to determine who you are
looking to Target and then be specific
at foundos I Target high growth Founders
that are looking to go from Seven
figures to eight figures to exit through
proven systems so now that you know
exactly who you want to Target you want
to get outside the building and actually
go in speak to these people survey them
ask them questions talk to them
understand what is your biggest
challenge what are your biggest
aspirations what are your questions when
it comes to the space or industry that
you operate in if you could wave some
magic wand what would be the biggest
accomplishment you would hope to achieve
this year the answers to these questions
are going to help you then formulate
content ideas that are going to serve
your dream customer now that you're
clear on who your target market is you
want to come up with your four content
categories content categories are the
drum beat of your marketing right these
are the things that people are going to
come to know and love you for they
identify the general themes you want to
talk about online my content categories
are audience growth systems personal
stories content creation systems and
scaling these are the things people come
back to me for again and again go and
get a pen and paper out and write down
your four content categories now that
you have your categories nailed down I
want to cover a little known but highly
impactful secret it's called content
[Music]
IP casy neistat's sunglasses Daniel
dal's thumbnails Peter McKinnon's what's
up what's up everybody Peter McKinnon
here they are trained elements that
consistently are woven into every piece
of content associated with their
personal Brands as you grow your brand
audience and offer developing unique
phrasing and language is essential when
you create unique names for your
processes you own those processes you
want to Define your core ideas and a
bonus if you can think of a group of
words that you want to be associated
with online for me it's systems audience
growth and organic content funnels what
values or principles are consistently
present in your story create a short
list of principles that best capture
your identity often you'll find certain
terms or Expressions that you use often
even ones that you've invented you're
going to look for these defining terms
terms that you can use across multiple
Concepts or categories for instance at
founder OS we focus on operating systems
so it's only natural that when I go and
create different lessons or titles for
different concepts that I use the word
OS the combination of the words
sentences and phrases that you own
creates your own content IP this
universe of content that you can become
known for online a little test that you
know if you have your content IP down
and effective is people are going to
start actually copying you online but
don't worry no one is you and your
personal brand is safe as long as you
remain consistent and this is where
compounding content and my content
waterfall system come into
play if you build it they will come
might be a great strategy for a baseball
stadium but it is terrible advice for
anyone trying to build an audience to
get attention you need to be in front of
your ideal audience and regularly I
recommend picking two social media
platforms to begin with and committing
to publishing two times daily it's
better to be the best on two platforms
than mediocre on five let's pick a
channel with low barrier to entry you
don't want to have to buy a camera
expensive gear or pay for extra tools to
get started and trying things out pick a
channel where you feel comfortable where
you can get writing immediately my top
two recommendations for your first
channel to grow on are X and Linkedin
these are the Grand Slam platforms they
use written text which means that you
can just make it yourself and start
practicing your copywriting immediately
lastly you want to implement the most
powerful content system in the world my
content waterfall
system building a brand and growing an
audience of Raving fans is key for
achieving both with your business and
revenue goals however there's a classic
catch22 that comes into play to build
and sustain a personal brand you have to
post engaging content daily across
multiple platforms and anyone that tells
you differently is either getting lucky
or just lying to you the answer lies in
implementing A system that maximizes
output while minimizing effort I call it
the content waterfall system the
foundation of the content waterfall
system lies in creating a pillar piece
of content imagine this cascading
waterfall
right the pillar piece of content is the
source of the waterfall and the
subsequent content pieces are the
streams that Branch out from it this
could be a blog post an X thread a
podcast episode a YouTube long form
video any piece of content that offers
value that can be broken down into
smaller pieces I use an xread as the
pillar piece of content this idea and
the copy from that xread becomes
inspiration for 10 more short form
tweets they become content like three
principles I live by how to start a
business from nothing seven marketing
metrics building an audience writing
online how to deal with being unfocused
and going for a run nature is the
greatest Mentor applying the 8020 rule
to everything and if you want freedom
build systems and outcomes fall in
love with the process the same idea from
the xred becomes three short form
animated videos this adds 12 additional
posts to the content waterfall so now
we're at the xred plus 12 video posts
and 12 short form tweets the short form
animated video also becomes a tweet as
seen here the same video becomes a short
form talking head video as you can see
right here and this goes out on
Instagram YouTube shorts Tik Tok and X
that's four more so now we're at 26
posts the lessons I share in the
original X thread also become pieces of
this YouTube script that was around how
I went from 15K in debt to $8.7 million
a year and it becomes a newsletter now a
month later so that's 28 it also becomes
a long form LinkedIn post and an
Instagram Carousel so now we're at 29
posts and a b-roll video on Instagram
that's 30 you can use this chart below
to map out all the content you want to
make from that one X red or long form
piece of content and turn it into 25
other pieces of content focus on cont
content that inspires educates
entertains makes people think and
triggers some sort of emotion if you're
looking to come up with a 100 content
ideas in just 30 minutes I'd recommend
using my content idea
[Music]
machine let me go and show you this
content idea machine prompt for chat gbt
heads up this thing's a beast The Prompt
reads like this you are a viral content
expert I need your help generating
compelling content ideas take
inspiration from viral YouTube video
ideas and viral Twitter threads with
over 5 million views make the
copywriting impeccable and memorable and
then what you're going to do is then
replace this info below with your own
overview of your mission for your own
brand I have here I'm a Founder creating
content to help Founders reach $5
million per year through proven systems
for audience brand and Community growth
our mission is to help a 100 million
Founders automate their business and hit
five $ million profit a year I want to
generate viral content ideas by creating
a table in the table the x-axis has
content groups meaning ways to present a
Content category and the y axis has
content categories to be matched with
the xaxis the x-axis has content groups
formatted the following way and then it
gets into the ways to format this right
so it's going to have one educational
content like lists best ofs tools facts
guides systems summaries and Frameworks
the second area is going to the
emotional it's going to drive some type
of emotion and get the reader to feel
some type of way that caused them to
share with five friends the third is
deep dive so data math reasons Trends
expert quotes research and Industry
breakdowns the fourth reflection so
hidden secrets lessons mistakes
successful routines personal experiences
and advice to yourself 5 years ago the
fifth is vulnerable so failures
obstacles insecurities skills you want
to learn what things shape you what
things you wish you knew in the best
advice you were given
six is edutainment so you're going to
create content with amazing storytelling
practical value that is captivating
compelling and makes people want to
share it with five friends and then
seven is lists so provide useful lessons
steps systems processes tools and
resources about the content category so
the Y AIS is going to contain the
content category so these are the ones
that you went and wrote down earlier in
this video mine as an example are number
one $5 million founder systems two
automating your business three
controlling the four W's which is to
work on what you want when you want
where you want and with who you want and
four Community Building let's see what
this thing generates here you can see it
now going and generating a table with
viral content ideas in each cell of the
X and Y AIS so it's going down all of
those different content types and then
in each of those categories that I went
and formulated like $5 million founder
systems automating your business
controlling the 4ws and community
building it's generating me a table of
ideas for each of those areas so pretty
freaking powerful if you want a copy of
that prompt in my content machine
template you can get it for free via the
link in the description there's a lot of
value them there so you're going to want
to go check it
[Music]
out now let's move on to pillar number
three audience growth systems
consistency is key put in the Reps and
if you are consistent good things will
happen I promise you but it's hard to be
consistent if you don't have the right
system in place the only way to
Excellence is first through repetition
and I recommend that as you build your
personal brand online you batch your
content creation this is key create 15
videos in one day write 20 pieces of
content in 2 hours this will help you
avoid Creator burnout and it's going to
get you off the content hamster wheel
you don't want to be dreading having to
create content every every single
morning that gets exhausting batch your
content creation to achieve time freedom
from there you're going to schedule your
content so you can grow on autopilot and
build your audience while you sleep
here's a breakdown of all the tech that
I use across founder OS hype Fury to
schedule X content tweet Hunter X to
find inspiration for X content X
analytics for X stats Tapo for LinkedIn
analytics Tapo X for LinkedIn inspo
convert kit for our newsletter School to
for the founder OS Community stripe for
payments web flow for our website at
first I was using kajabi though
testimonial. to collect testimonials
notion for my company Wiki which houses
all of the systems across founder OS
Google Drive for things like photos
videos and b-roll Google docs to
document all of our systems zapier for
automations figma for designs loom for
screen recordings and I also use this to
reduce my meetings type form for a
Founder OS application to get feedback
from Founders and a sauna for project
management to maximize your audience
growth follow the data after you've been
consistently posting for a little while
it's important to take some time and
look over your data you're going to want
to see Trends around what's working and
what's not you're going to see what
really resonates with your audience
you're going to double down on what's
working and do less of what isn't
execute optimize repeat
number four monetization moments
monetizing your personal brand is
essential so you can reinvest into
people product and your vision
monetization moments are a crucial
element of your organic content strategy
they guide your audience to take
specific steps such as subscribing
sharing or purchasing ctas or call the
actions are the best way to drive people
from your social audience to customers
think of your audience as this vast
ocean of attention Okay and your ctas
are like this net that's going to help
catch the fish and then drive them to
revenue the key is to strategically
place the ctas in your content and
ensure that you do them in a way that
fits the subject of the content that
they're
in what do you need to scale from just a
personal brand you need to build a core
team you don't just want to have a
personal brand right you want to have a
personal Media Company the personal
Media company is nothing new it's been
used for ages to build the world's
biggest companies Benjamin Franklin
owned and published the Pennsylvania
Gazette to influence public opinion and
it became his personal Media Company
Jeff Bezos bought the Washington Post to
have his personal Media company and Elon
Musk bought X to have his personal Media
Company the difference between you and
these folks is this you don't need to
buy a media company you can become the
media company picture this you own a
personal Media company that grows
everything around you it drives
attention to your products and companies
it brings you a flood of new customers
cash flow and opportunities and it
attracts top talent so you no longer
need to chase people it is a beacon for
your people creatives dreamers investors
Builders Founders and innovators you
build a community of people online you
grow your digital reputation and you
become known and respected this is the
power of your personal Media Company
infinite leverage at your fingertips and
to scale a personal Media Company you
need to build a team of weapons weapon
an individual who when brought onto a
company has the ability to 10x their
area they go above and beyond to fulfill
the needs of the company and the mission
they hire more weapons and elevate your
culture and speed of innovation here are
the areas where weapons can help you in
your business Tech sales video photos
design writing funnels animations
operations video editing and social
posting in the last 20 months I grew an
audience of over 2 million people around
my personal brand I haven't done this
alone though I've had an incredible team
around me here's my or chart from
founder OS but you don't need all of
these folks to get started over time
time you're going to likely build a team
such as a social manager to post all
your content a writer to help you craft
your content a video editor to edit your
videos and a videographer to then shoot
your content these four weapons can do
damage this is the profitable personal
brand Playbook if you want more systems
to grow an audience to 1.8 million just
like I did check out this video on my
system to get your first 100,000
followers so if you enjoyed this video
you're going to love my next video so be
sure to like And subscribe and I'll see
you in the next one
[Applause]
[Music]