want to be happy and successful here are
three mindset shifts you need to make
right now not why am I doing this but
what's the alternative achieving your
goals is hard but the alternative is to
not do things that you care about that
sucks worse not the comfort zone but
life is suffering the comfort zone
doesn't exist the people who seek
Comfort above all else are the most
miserable accept that life hurts and
choose meaningful pain not finding
yourself to but defining yourself there
is no fate there is no destiny the C
proved his own existence with the
statement I think therefore I am it's
your job to fill in the rest I am
therefore don't find yourself Define
yourself