Your vibe is the unfair advantage that
you have in this for [music] you social
media era. Here's why. The reality is is
that there's so much stuff out there
constantly causing people distractions.
And what really can separate you from
everyone else is [music] your own
authenticity. Step one is to create a
three-word vibe compass. Pick three
words that describe how you want people
to feel when they encounter your brand.
For example, calm, creative, world
class. Post them on your wall, your
notion board, your Google Docs,
wherever, and use them as a filter for
everything you design, write, [music] or
say. Step two is to build a personal
mood board. I like to do this on
platforms like Pinterest or you could
use Instagram collections to save a
bunch of content that you feel really
encapsulates your three-word vibe. This
becomes your brand's visual DNA. From
there, [music] step three is to audit
your social media presence for
alignment. You want to make sure that
your profile photos, cover photos, the
overall content you're putting out there
is in alignment with those three [music]
words. Now, it's okay if there's a gap.
Welcome to building something. It's all
about iteration and getting 10% better
with every piece of content you put