I spent the last 20 years building
companies and the last 18 months
systematizing my body the same way that
I've systematized my businesses. I work
with founders doing $30,000 a month or
more and the single most predictive
variable I see in who skills past
[music] eight figures it's not their
offer, their team, or their content.
It's whether their body is operating at
full capacity or whether it's quietly
running them into the ground. In this
video, I'm going to give you the whole
thing in five parts. The abundance
[music] hour I run every morning, how I
eat, the exact supplements I take, my
sleep [music] routine and how I track
all of it without a single wearable.
Let's get into it. There's a saying that
health is wealth. Let me tell you,
there's probably not a more true
statement. You know, I've had some
serious major concussions. Um when I was
about [music] 28, I remember being in a
hotel room dealing with the stress of
one of my businesses. I remember calling
my dad. I was crying. I couldn't figure
out what the hell was going on. It felt
like my mind was like racing and
realized, you know, I needed to get some
help. I sure enough went to this clinic.
I went into like an MRI machine, had my
brain scanned, met with a doctor. It
became obvious that the brain situation
was a lot worse than I thought.
>> Okay, you want to see your pictures?
>> Yeah.
>> When I kind of look at these now, we got
a lot of bumps everywhere, my friend.
Now, when I see this, either we've had a
whole lot of head traumas. Your left
temporal lobe's got lower blood flow
there. So, mood swings, irritability,
anxiety, okay? Some paranoia sometimes,
too.
>> Yeah.
>> So, it was really this moment, right?
This kind of yeah, realization that I
couldn't keep going on like this that
made me realize that I had to start
taking my health super seriously. I
figured I'd just open up the kimono,
show you what I'm up to. Part one, the
abundance hour. This right here is what
I call my Sadie app, okay? Um around
five years ago, um I had a health coach
named Sadie and one of the first things
we did together was actually an
elimination diet and she put me on uh a
diet where I basically cut out just
everything for a bit and it was like,
you know, chicken soup, uh you you know,
a steak at night, and like water, you
know, like it was the most basic diet,
like no crazy What I started doing
was having this kind of abundance hour
in the morning. Uh for me, the staple of
that is waking up and listening to an
abundance meditation um that I actually
recorded myself, right? Um I wrote this
up. It's all this kind of journey of
transformation, um one that kind of
programs my subconscious mind for
success, um and allows me to kind of
live a life of abundance, love, and
fulfillment. And so, I listen to this.
It's about 35 minutes in the morning,
you know, eyes closed after I've woken
up, and just kind of like let my body
just drift into a state of relaxation
and calm, and just listen to this. Now,
cool thing is, I've actually published
this to YouTube. If you're interested in
it, check it out over here. Um and I
would go and give it a try if I were
you, you know, 90 days, either every
morning or every evening listening to
this, I think will have a really
transformative aspect, and will be a
nice little thing for you to give a
shot. That is part of my, you know,
abundance hour, right? We're starting
with an entrepreneur abundance
meditation. So, after that, you know,
I've done my entrepreneur abundance
meditation, I like to drink a little bit
of water, lemon, and salt, right? Chug
that back, and then from there, I'm
taking about 10 g of creatine, and then
basically just like going for a bit of
deep work. From there, you know, if I'm
craving a little bit of movement, I
every day will just hop on my scooter,
go to a gym called Omni here, and go and
put in about an hour workout. After
that, get my smoothie, probably some
rice and some chicken, and then
typically have, you know, maybe a video
I'll film, or maybe I'm just meeting up
with a friend, or what have you. Dinner,
I like to eat a bit light in the
evening, you know, get a walk in before
bed, uh maybe read a bit, and then
settle down for the evening. This 80 app
is just my own little private app that I
use myself. It was built by me, and
essentially what it does is just
synthesize all of those core things, you
know, in the morning no phone for the
first hour, you know, quick little
reading, my little entrepreneur
abundance meditation, my water and salt,
then going for my lift after a little
bit of founder flow, after my lift right
I'm doing a bit of a sauna and cold
bath, not too long, just a nice little
pick me up like nature's espresso. From
there, steak and rice or chicken and
rice and my supplements and I can just
kind of go along and just check these
off as I go. And by the way, if you're
watching this and you're like this Sade
app is pretty sick. How do I just get
Matt's protocol? Well, you can actually
go check it out over here. I'm just
giving this away. Just want you guys to,
you know, obviously build healthy
founders cuz I believe that healthy
founders build healthy businesses and so
if that's interesting, go and check it
out via the link in the description um
and let me know how it goes, you know,
be sure to, you know, maybe share some
results, share your thinking along the
way, let me know how it's going, maybe
tag me on Instagram and I'll I'll share
some love and we can support one
another's health journeys, right? That's
what this is all about. Part two,
nutrition. On the nutrition side, I
typically am fasting um in the morning
all the way up till around 1:00 or 2:00
p.m. And again, try not to eat after
8:00 p.m. Whether it's your workouts um
or whether it's like how I'm eating, I
try to just keep it fun, keep it
sustainable, keep it enjoyable. Part
three, supplements. I've also got all my
supplements, you know, I'm obviously
traveling quite a bit and I can show you
guys um a bit of my supplement stack if
that's interesting. So, first off, you
know, one thing I'm really big on, I
have a bit of ADD um for sure and these
are two supplements um that help me stay
focused and lock in. Um I typically
alternate them um every day so one day
I'll have two of these, Alpha Brain.
This is like Aubrey Marcus and Joe
Rogan's uh brand and these are really
good for focus and then the other day
I'll have ginkgo biloba. Have that with
a iced Americano in the morning and you
are locked in and cooking and honestly
it just makes working a lot of fun as
well. Typically in the afternoon after
like my first meal, um I'll have this
adrenal cocktail. This is just good for
like, you know, handling stress and
making sure your adrenals are just super
healthy. It was recommended to me by
someone and, you know, seems to do the
trick and and kind of keep me calm, keep
me vibing. I take some B vitamins, just
again based on my own blood work. This
is some stuff that would kind of help me
with some core vitals and So,
we're uh we're taking those and then a
bit of taurine. This is also just great
for overall energy and so we rock that,
too.
>> Part four, sleep routine.
>> Before bed, I talk to founders all the
time and they struggle with sleep. I'm
taking two of these magnesium before
bed. I will take two of these glycine
before bed. If I'm finding I'm a little
worked up, which is generally not the
case, but I may even go and take some
ashwagandha as well. Um and then every
other night I'm taking one of these zinc
complexes. And [music] typically hitting
the sack around like eight 9:00 p.m. Um
and asleep by 10:00 and then up at 6:00,
right? So, we're getting like 8 hours of
sleep every night, which is really
important. I know for me, beyond all
this BS, right? All these supplements
and you know, this app or all this
stuff, right? Really when it comes down
to it, right? It's sleeping really good,
moving your body and breaking a sweat
daily, you know, modulating, kind of
moderating your stress overall, and you
know, not forgetting about things like
community, your social life, family, a
good friend circle. Yeah, just may kind
of make these like this whole health
kind of lifestyle a social lifestyle as
well, right? So, you're kind of stacking
things, right? Stacking good
conversations, great friends, and you
know, a little bit of recovery all at
the same time.
>> Part five, tracking.
>> On the blood work side, every 4 months
I'm getting my blood work done. You
know, here in Bali I go to a place
called Form.
Um and, you know, it gives me all the
core vitals of everything that I've got
and some things maybe even that I got to
work on, right? And so, the nice thing
here is that you're able to keep a tight
handle on your health and with all these
like supplements or routines that I'm
doing, it's kind of always just trying
to make sure that everything's super
optimal, right? So, just as an example,
today, right, I went and was at Omni. I
had my body composition report done,
right? I'm able to look at things like,
you know, my weight about 185 lbs,
body fat around 11.3%
and what I'll typically then go do with
this report um is I will then go and
upload this to that Sadie app where I'm
able to then go and track my progress.
So, here I can see how my weight has
been, right, and keeping it at a nice
steady spot. I can see my body fat has
been like around like 11%
um for the last while, right? And just
kind of keep monitoring it, right? I
think that for me, I don't like to weigh
myself like every day or anything like
that. The same way I don't really like
to use fitness trackers, so you won't
see me with like a Whoop or some Oura
Ring, at least not yet. Um I was using
them for a while and I just felt like
this idea that waking up and having some
device tell me if I'm happy, if I'm
rested, just didn't fit my vibe. I was
finding there was a lot of days I
actually felt really good and then the
device was telling me that I was not
well rested and not, you know, prepared
for the day. Um and that just kind of
cognitively over time I felt screwed
with me a little bit. So, I decided to
ditch all that tech, keep it simple.
About every Friday or every other
Friday, I'll do like a bit of a a
weigh-in, my little uh my Conor McGregor
weigh-in and then and see where I'm at,
track that progress and then move along
and just kind of live my life. So,
overall, I like to keep it, I think,
like to the essential. Some of this may
be slightly extra, but it works for me.
Um and if you're watching this, um I
hope is that you found a few of the
things here helpful. Um you know, do
what's right for you, keep it fun, keep
it simple, and just remember, right,
healthy founders build healthy
businesses. And like I said, this is the
operating system behind the operator,
but if you want the operating system
behind the company that will let you
become a true founder athlete, that's
where FounderOS comes in. Here's what
happens when you join FounderOS. In the
first week, you sit on a 60-minute call
with my team, you walk away with your
full brand foundation that we built for
you, your positioning, your ICP, your
founder narrative, you know, you're
going to see it live on screen. And you
really start to realize someone finally
understands your business, okay? Your
week starts to clear up, you know,
you're able to start training again, you
know, your mornings are getting quieter.
On day 60, we make sure your VSL is
live, your landing page is live, and you
have applications coming in, right? From
people that are loving your content. And
now your content machine is fully
installed. That is FounderOS. And if you
want to go and take it a step further
and dial in your mind before every day
at work, well, go and check out this
entrepreneur abundance meditation that I
listen to every morning. Thanks so much
for watching. Be sure to like and
subscribe, and let's win together.