If a system isn't simple enough for
anyone to learn, it's already broken.
You've probably heard of the 80/20
principle before. Well, when you 80/20
the 80/20 principle, what you get is the
4% [music] formula, which really goes
and dictates that 4% of your actions are
going to lead [music] to 64% of your
results. Think about that, right? What
is the 4% that's going to go and lead to
64% of the benefit? Too many people go
and motor through life thinking that
it's all about just doing all the
things, about being busy. And I think as
a society, we're just addicted [music]
to busyness. But if you're looking to go
and build a real business, or you're
looking to build a vibrant life, you
need to focus on the core things that
[music] really matter. Keep the most
important thing the most important
thing.