at the start of 2024 I had the fastest
growing account on LinkedIn I grew my
profile to 272,000 followers in 12
months and today I'm at 468,000
followers and growing at a rate of
11,300 followers a month all without
spending a cent on paid ads here's the
Ultimate seven-step Guide to get your
audience to its first 100,000 followers
so that you can add $2.8 million of
annual revenue to your business first
off I'm not just an outlier here I've
given this advice to thousands of
Founders and each of them had minimal
experience probably just like you you
know I remember helping Steve GNA a tech
entrepreneur who started with zero
LinkedIn audience no presence and really
no idea on how to stand out fast forward
today and Steve has over 44,000 loyal
followers and not just that he launched
a podcast with over 3 million downloads
and drove over $7 million of annual
recurring Revenue to his business or
someone like k Thomas that I helped to
grow to over 600% on LinkedIn in just 5
months and I've advised hundreds of more
Founders do just the same all you have
to do is really follow these seven steps
I'm going to outline in this
video first you got to set up your
profitable profile this is really the
first impression that people see when
they go and visit you this is what
people often Skip and then you just
don't get the results that you're after
you know what I found over the years is
that LinkedIn is a salesperson that
never sleeps you know while you're out
there you're exploring the outdoors your
LinkedIn profile is there converting
people to your newsletter into Revenue
while you sleep so you don't want to
come across like some scrub your
LinkedIn present should be your
competitive Advantage people make
subconscious judgments based on the
looks and under a second you want to
make sure you look clean confident and
confident once you sign up for LinkedIn
you need to update your profile with an
amazing head shot the goal is to go from
this to this here's a quick trick to get
a fantastic head shot at home so you're
going to go and grab your iPhone and
then have someone take a photo of you
that way you're using the back side of
the camera not the front side that you
generally would use for a selfie which
is going to make you look a lot worse
get some window light on a cloudy day
and S at a 90° angle so it likes you
from one side switch to portrait mode so
you blur out any distracting background
then take the photo close enough so that
you don't have that much Headroom
finally then send your image to your
computer and drop in an app like pixler
if you're a beginner or something like
Lightroom or photoshop if you're more
advanced you're going to crop the image
and then voila great head shot without a
budget if you can invest in a
photographer then you should do it I
recommend it so that they can do all
this and a lot more the truth is that
that headshot is your first impression
and you want to nail it great
photography is a quick way to signal to
people that you have great taste and
taste is the most rare skill in the
world it's a trust signal and using good
photos on LinkedIn and on your website
is going to make a big difference and
then help speed up your growth from
there you're going to want to add your
company to your profile make sure it's a
nice logo and that the company page has
a description that really sells people
on what you do reach out to your team
and make sure they also have their
company profiles updated on their
LinkedIn so that it's all consistent
finally you want to set up your tagline
this should be a simple single line that
conveys who you are and then the value
you're going to add to your audience Pro
tip you want to aim to own a word in the
mind of your audience James clear owns
the word habit I own the word systems
Ryan holiday owns the word stoicism what
word are you aiming to own in the hearts
in minds of your audience if you don't
know this exercise will only take you a
few minutes and it is well worth it here
are a few examples of copy that you can
adapt qualification and one key idea
this is a simple straightforward
approach that leads with your
qualifications here's my headline it has
my job title and company name then it
has one key message that's important for
my audience to know about me right now
that's that I help people with proven
systems to grow a profitable audience
with Organic content but before we
convert traffic we have to get traffic
and that comes from posting one of the
core metrics that no one talks about is
reposts the more people that want to
repost your content the better the
LinkedIn algorithm favors posts that get
reposted so we want to ask ourselves why
would someone repost this and then
reverse engineer that repost this is how
we'll hijack the linked an algorithm and
grow to 100,000 followers fast and the
way to do this is to post and learn what
works best practice is to post once a
day at a consistent time every day if
you need to you can start with a Monday
Wednesday Friday posting schedule and
then gradually increase your Cadence but
the more you can post the faster you'll
learn and the faster you'll grow so what
should you post what word do you want to
own in your customers minds and what
content will help you get this there to
start use the iy guy exercise make four
lists what you're good at what you can
be paid for what the world needs and
what you love to do then populate your
iy guy which is the meeting point of
these four areas it's the overlap where
then you can find your best topics the
topics that meet in the center are ideal
for attracting your first 10,000
followers and creating predictable
profit in the future I discovered that I
love systems audience growth building
communities and Entrepreneurship and so
these are the topics that I talk about
consistently now let's take it one step
beyond that icky guy to your content
categories these are the subtopics
inspired by your icky guy these content
categories become the drum bead of your
content schedule these are the things
that you talk about constantly and you
become Niche famous for they're going to
establish the world that you own these
are going to be what people know and
love you for so what are some ways to
generate post ideas from your content
categories well Mr Beast is notorious
for staying up all night obsessing over
his video ideas I've obsessed for 10
years over finding the best ideas and in
the process I develop what I call the
LinkedIn idea machine you can use this
framework to come up with over 30
Amazing Ideas in just 30 minutes for
each content category that you outlined
above you want to brainstorm lists tools
facts guides systems summaries and
Frameworks then go to the next level
with deep dive cont content with ideas
data stories reasons Trend reports
expert quotes research summaries and
Industry breakdowns our goal is to be
the absolute best in our category and we
want to be as generous as possible we
basically just want to take all our
knowledge and give it away the more
generous we are the more repost we're
going to get and the more repost we get
the more growth the more growth the more
revenue and after you come up with a
backlog of valuable ideas you should use
the 5year reflection framework this is
another framework to come up with
endless ideas this single exercise has
been responsible for my biggest hits on
LinkedIn so first get a pen and paper
reflect on The Last 5 Years what systems
templates checklists do you wish that
you had 5 years ago now think about it
to the U of 5 years ago you are now an
expert you already know the advice that
you wish you had to avoid dead ends
challenges and a bunch of obstacles your
goal is to help the you of 5 years ago
find Clarity find belonging and the
growth needed through the content that
you're about to create so you're going
to write down things like the lessons
you've learned mistakes you've made your
achievements underrated skills
successful routines your personal
experiences failures obstacles
challenges insecurities what things have
shaped you and the things that you wish
you had known then once you have all
these content ideas it's time to start
crafting your post now scroll stopping
hooks are the key to every content
format on LinkedIn the top three lines
of text are the main thing that your
audience are going to see when they see
you post and you want to make sure they
stop in their tracks anything that you
write below those three lines gets cut
off and hidden behind the SE more text
and so this makes these three lines
which are the hook the most important
part of your post David ogi the father
of advertising one said this on the
average five times as many people will
read the headline as read the body copy
when you have written your headline you
have already spent 80 cents of your
dollar having a scroll stopping Hook is
80% of the battle if no one makes it
past the front door to see the rest of
your content you're not going to go
anywhere and so look at these 10 hooks
I've written these 10 hooks have
garnered over 24 million views no hook
no virality great hooks build iconic
Brands just do it the hook lives on
three lines that's about
225 characters without line breaks but
our goal isn't to stuff as many words
into that space as we can it's to make
the words we use as compelling as
possible additionally notice how I use
Simple language fifth grade level it's
easy to read and you don't have to stop
and wonder what I'm talking about I keep
the sentences short kinetic they have a
nice Rhythm to them and they're just
easy to read long sentence short
sentence question answer this is the
Rhythm that you want to perfect the more
simple and easier reading the more
likely people are to continue and stick
with you here's a second example again
with this hook I established both a
benefit and Authority in the first line
while using specific numbers to back up
my claim so that it's not generic before
we get into the body the post there are
two magic words I recommend that you use
in your hook I've put these two words at
the front of six 67% of my viral posts
can you guess what they are oh wait they
are I and I here are three examples
combine these two magic words with a
scroll stopping hook and you'll get
1,000 followers a month in no time but
if you want to get beyond that to your
next 10,000 you'll have to master how
your hooks interact with the rest of
your post and that means using my four
power formats you're are the four
formats that work to grow my account and
add 30,000 followers a month this first
power format is the long form list for
this first format we combine the hook
with a second visual hook hit the media
button and then attach an image to the
post which is going to look like this
you'll want to focus on Square images or
images that have some sort of vertical
layout horizontal images will get
crushed and cropped and then look
horrible on LinkedIn this image is your
post thumbnail so it's something that's
going to catch your audience's eye and
then get them to keep on scrolling down
the feet they'll read the hook and then
click see more to read the full post you
want to maximize the value per image and
create insane Intrigue you know a
picture speaks a th000 words and we want
the image that you choose to speak
10,000 the image you combine with your
hook can be something custom designed a
photo of yourself that's related or some
visually striking image that relates to
the post maybe it's even a screenshot of
a customer question or even a handdrawn
resource like this over time you'll find
the perfect pairing you don't need money
to do this you need creativity and
iteration flashy videos and Graphics do
not work and please avoid AI once you
attract someone's attention the full
post is where you deliver that massive
value and then once they click see more
the audience will arrive at your long
form list this is a list of interesting
items and statements that really relate
to the hook that you've promised people
the truth is that LinkedIn rewards the
length of time that someone is engaging
with your post I call it engaged time
spent or ETF s a high ETS will drive a
high growth of profile views and
followers long form lists keep audiences
reading longer than scrolling the
newsfeed and that's a huge signal to
LinkedIn that what you're sharing is
valuable if you combine your hook with a
series of snackable insights you'll keep
people reading once they click and
they'll love it here's two more
compelling examples in why each Works
take time to pause the video and study
each or go to the description in this
video below the like button to get the
Guide it explains each of these formats
in depth with full illustrations and
while you're down there hit the like
button of this video And subscribe if
you like these systems the second
content format is the long form Carousel
a carousel is a series of images that
you can click through to view one at a
time you've got a long form format list
but instead of making it from text you
make it from a series of images with
carousels people spend time reading your
post without having to click on a new
page my LinkedIn carousels have pushed
over 30 million views a month here's an
example of an effective Carousel that
generated over 2 million views you'll
notice that the hook is actually more
than three lines because I Nest words
inside of the first image in the
carousel without any extra clicks so you
have extra room to craft a strong hook
now you see how each time I click
forward in the carousel there's another
list item it's a long form list where
each item gets an individual image in
your Carousel in the final image I
include a call to action which is
crucial because this is how I'm driving
people from the carousel to then sign up
to my newsletter and this is a technique
that I'll talk about more in the final
step of this video but you're not going
to want to miss it to create a carousel
you'll need to create a PDF document
that's a series of square-based images
you'll then upload that document to your
post by clicking the add document button
to actually create these image PDFs
you'll want to use figma to create the
images and then export those images to a
PDF I like to test out my best
copyrighting on xir I see it as a gym
for copyrighting and the best X threads
get reposted as carousels on LinkedIn if
you're converting an xost there's a
special service that you're just getting
started that I'd recommend I cover all
these steps on how to do this as well as
detailed examples of effective carousels
in the download below this video so
you're going to want to click that below
the video in the description and get
that download the third power format for
LinkedIn is a long form hook stacking a
hook stack is a long form list without
the numbers instead you string together
short statements that build on what the
hook established then you end with a
payoff with a good hook stack you can't
help but read each line until you've
accidentally read the entire thing
here's an example of a hook sack that I
built this is one of my top six
performing posts ever you can see how
each line leads to the next with this
format you often don't need an image to
be effective it's that good so if you do
add an image you're just superp powering
it here's another hook stack this is one
of my top performing posts with over 2.4
million views it starts with a killer
hook and just keeps layering on more and
more but the real reason these hook
Stacks do so well is that I superpower
them with the next format the long form
image this is my favorite current format
right now instead of clicking to see a
long form list you put the entire list
inside of the compelling image I handw
write these for about 20 minutes every
morning this way people immediately see
the entire thing and then they sit there
absorb bit and click through to read the
rest of it now I've curated all of these
insights and then handrawn them and
jam-packed them into these handdrawn
images but you can use designed images
as well if you want to use canva or
figma but again hand drawing is what
I've preferred when you combine a scroll
stopping hook with any of these powerful
long form posts your audience growth and
engagement will Skyrocket the next step
is to power up you have a profitable
profile you post on a consistent
schedule and you pair that with your
scroll stopping hooks with the four
power formats in other words you're
either already at 10,000 followers or
you will be soon that means it's time to
level up first soak in Inspiration
follow the best people you can on
LinkedIn who should you follow I'm going
to be honest the best place to start is
my profile if it's not already obvious
I've spent thousands of hours obsessing
over LinkedIn it's kind of sad and I
want you to steal everything I know so
go to my profile follow me and hit this
Bell so you get alerted to Notifications
whenever I post this way you'll see the
updates to my strategies in real time
based on everything I've learned over
thousands of hours of research then
you're going to power up your LinkedIn
it's all about absorbing insights from
other top creators using Tapo X's Chrome
extension Tapo X is the single best app
you can use for LinkedIn it combines
analytics Ai and inspiration all in one
app they should sponsor me but they
don't so I just love what they're doing
so I'd recommend that you download them
for your desktop then when you visit
your top Creator you're going to see
them on this right side bar of your
screen you can see all your detail
analytics you can see their top content
and it's going to just help you develop
higher performing content it's a game
changer because it customizes it for you
Tapo XX also has insane analytics that
allow me to track my growth I can see my
followers engagements Impressions and
profile views over time for the last 30
days 60 days and 90 days and I can
access my top performing content in
seconds the next step in powering up
your LinkedIn is using Creator mode on
your profile scroll down to resources
and turn Creator mode on this enables
the follow button on your profile which
is going to increase your view to
follower conversions it also gives you
access to several powerful profile
features that you're going to be able to
take advantage of okay now we're ready
to really win on LinkedIn these tips
will help you get from 10,000 to 100,000
followers on LinkedIn no more Basics
first first of all you want to post 7
days a week in a perfect world you
should post your posts manually without
scheduling them on some other platform
LinkedIn gives less attention to
prescheduled posts and so I write all my
own content and then I post it manually
next you don't want to share links on
your post LinkedIn wants people to
actually stay on the platform and so if
you go and have some external link it's
going to think that you're getting
people to leave LinkedIn and then it's
not going to share it that far now
here's a way to share external links
without getting penalized which I'll
share at the end of this video but by
default don't add links to your post
please we want to help you grow I don't
want to hinder it with these external
links a second Advanced LinkedIn
strategy is to use the twx Chrome
extension this will help you understand
top performing content from creators on
X X is like a gym for copyrighting the
best copyrighting bodybuilders are on X
and when those creators repurpose their
content on LinkedIn they absolutely kill
it because the competition for attention
is much higher on X sorry LinkedIn it's
just the truth my X account is one of
the largest and most engaged on any
business account on X so go follow my X
account and then use twx to discover my
best performing content formats you can
study these formats and then bring them
to LinkedIn now my next Advanced tip is
to engage with comments for 30 minutes
every morning after you put your post
live take notes of the most common
questions you can then add those
questions to your LinkedIn ID idea
machine and use them to go and create
your content buckets connecting with a
group of other like-minded Founders and
creators is one of the best ways to grow
exponentially on LinkedIn you can then
deepen that relationship off platform by
sharing what's working in a WhatsApp
group Mr Beast attributed his massive
growth on YouTube to a group chat that
he had going with seven other creators
if you want to go and have a meteoric
rise on LinkedIn then you should use
this method too instead of just learning
from your own post you can actually
learn from a group of other creators
that are crushing it as well share your
greatest hits share what's working
what's not working the dead ends you're
experiencing your bottlenecks and then
all learn together as a group support
one another and win together this has
been huge for my personal development
and growth on every social platform use
this Outreach template you see here to
message 20 accounts per week now
reaching out to people sometimes can
make people nervous so you're going to
want to pick accounts that have 10,000
followers more than you do and start a
conversation with them aim to become
friends and grow together send this to
start via LinkedIn DM hey name loving
your content big fan of your post on
insert subject what are your goals on
LinkedIn then you're going to send this
after they respond my goal is to get to
10,000 followers by December 31st and
drive people to my business would love
to grow together cool if we collab in a
WhatsApp group and share what's working
for one another on LinkedIn once we
Implement all these steps winning on
LinkedIn we're ready for the final step
winning off of LinkedIn so the goal of
all this attention that we've just
driven on LinkedIn is to convert that
attention to a business and life that
you love if you get 100,000 followers
but you're just hating your life well
then this is all just a wasted effort so
let's return to your profitable profile
and our posting strategy it's time to
transition our massive audience from
LinkedIn to our convertkit newsletter if
you watch the first video in this series
you know that as early as your first a
th000 followers you want to create a
convertkit newsletter to convert your
rented audience to an owned audience
that way when you grow past 100,000
followers and Beyond you can transfer
that audience from LinkedIn to your
owned audience in your newsletter which
is your most valuable audience LinkedIn
drives as much as 65% of the revenue in
my portfolio of online businesses our
business grew over $2 million of revenue
from LinkedIn alone last year and that's
when my audience was at only 50,000
followers let's level up your profitable
profile so it becomes a lead generation
machine we'll use my own Prof file as
the ultimate example first as you can
see here I've set up my cover photo
Banner to mention the foundos newsletter
I mentioned that there over 107,000
people signed up so it must be good and
I tell people that you can sign up via
the link in BIO additionally notice how
I promise how often I'll be posting I
give people an impression of what they
are going in signing up for I give
people a reason to follow and a reminder
to click on the Bell to subscribe second
you can see that my tagline mentions my
most important value proposition I'm the
founder and CEO of founder OS and I help
people with proven systems to grow a
profitable audience with Organic content
which for me is my biggest opportunity
right now more on that in the next video
in the series below that we have my bio
you want your bio to be the ultimate
credibility pitch so here's how you know
your bio is doing an amazing job it all
comes down to your follower to profile
conversion rate a good LinkedIn profile
should convert 5% of your profile
visitors to follows a fantastic bio like
mine converts 19% of all people who
visit it into followers if your bio
sucks your conversions will suck too as
you can see my bio starts with
credibility building about who I am and
what I've done why should you listen to
me well the bio provides the context
additionally I share in single lines
what value I'm offering so that anyone
who visits knows exactly what I do this
is the hook stacking formula that we
talked about but applied to my bio be as
concrete as possible and use as many
hard numbers as possible so that you
build the credibility keep track of
these numbers and update them over time
next once I've established what I'm
offering I add my core call to actions
these are the three clear next actions
my audience needs to take the first
should always be your convertkit
newsletter then link to one or two
products that are lead magnets that your
audience can get instant value from
finally you're going to want to plug all
your other social media channels even if
you haven't started building them out
yet this is an easy way to start growing
an initial audience across all these
channels at once and helping you become
more omnipresent if you already have big
audiences on those platforms this is a
free strategy and way to grow them much
faster next we want to add a call to
action that will appear under our name
everywhere we post since you've already
turned on Creator mode you now have
access to this feature hit this edit
icon scroll down and set your button as
a clickable link add the URL and set
your text my call to action sends anyone
who clicks to my founder L program this
is where I teach Founders everything
that they need to know to get to
millions in Revenue next is the featured
area which is between our header and a
Bo section this is where you want to add
links to your two most important pages
so you can promote those set the first
as your convertkit newsletter and then
the other one as a core product that you
offer to do this click Add profile
section click recommended then add
featured click the plus icon and then
add your link write a title that's
strong a short call to action of no more
than 20 characters and then ignore that
description part finally set a great
thumbnail image when you add your links
they'll look like this tweak your links
so that the text looks good and it
doesn't overflow design the call to
action thumbnails so that they're
irresistible on brand and compelling to
click this entire section of your
profile now drives your audience to your
business this is where you're going to
get the real Roi from LinkedIn next
we're going to promote our newsletter
and our core product in our post I
mentioned that LinkedIn will penalize
your post if it's viewed with an
external link so here's how you can get
around that after you post wait and
watch after a short time LinkedIn will
start to push your post to as many
people as possible if these people
engage with the post linkedin's going to
promote it to more and more newsfeeds
once you see that your post has taken
flight now you can append that call to
action to the end of it by editing the
post by this point LinkedIn is already
rewarding you for sharing your post and
so it's not going to stop sharing it and
so it's fine to now add your external
link I use this technique all the time I
see my post take off and after 45
minutes I edit it and add this external
link this way I get the most possible
views on any post but I also convert
those views to my newsletter to my
products and my workshops which drives
millions of dollars of business every
year because to be honest 10,000 or even
100,000 followers is just the beginning
the next video in this series is my full
guide to taking all this audience and
growth you've now experienced and then
use it to drive Revenue to your business
and become a true Auto preneur I'll show
you how to harness this LinkedIn
audience you've now grown so you can
work from where you want when you want
how you want with whoever you want
thanks for watching and good luck
growing your LinkedIn audience