If you want to make millions of dollars
with social media, you need to master
these five levels of content creation.
The problem is that most people use
level two tactics to try to get to level
[music] five, and they fall flat. I've
published over 32,000 pieces of content
over the last 16 years and built
audiences of over 14 million people by
mastering each of these levels.
Throughout this video, I'm going to be
going through a bunch of different steps
that you can take to get from level one
to five. And you can go and get a cheat
sheet for this inside of my content
mastery checklist via the link in the
description. So go download that and
follow along. Let's get into it. Level
one is the wilderness. [music]
This is where you find your voice by
making noise. When I was 20 building my
first company, Bitmaker, I started
posting online with zero idea what I was
doing. Sometimes I sounded like a
journalist, sometimes like an
inspirational speaker. [music]
Sometimes like I had no idea even who I
was. But this is all part of the [music]
journey. The most important part at
level one is just to show up. I've been
there. Been stuck in perfectionism.
stuck not knowing if what I was even
going to put out there even mattered.
Stuck not even really knowing what my
voice was or what my niche was. [music]
But the truth is that this is perfectly
normal. I think that most people think
they need to have it all figured out and
then start posting online. The truth is
often times that you start posting
online and then you figure it out. It's
from the doing that you get the clarity.
You need to be confident enough to go
and just look cringe [music] for a bit.
confident enough to go and just start
putting your first pieces of content out
there and start developing what I call
the shipping muscle. It happens to me
all the time. Nearly every piece of
content, every video, I always feel like
there [music] was some piece we could
have done better or some aspect that I
could have made stronger. [music] But
that does not stop me from just shipping
the damn thing. The problem is is that
most [music] people don't even make it
to level one. They let their fear, their
insecurity, their perfectionism, their
procrastination get [music] the best of
them. And I'm here to tell you this is
your opportunity to go and peer into
that fear and drive right through it. So
[music] what do you need to do today? I
want you to start building up your 30day
streak. 30 days of posting consistent
content. That's it. We don't need to
make perfect content. We don't need to
grow an audience to 10,000 people. We
just need to develop that shipping
muscle today. And stop with the excuses.
Stop with the limiting beliefs. Don't
worry about your mood, right? Just stick
to the plan. Your only goal at level one
is to go from silent to visible. Now,
the goal here is not to go viral. It's
to start putting yourself out there and
gradually find your voice. Level two is
the hamster wheel. When I first
committed to X 5 years ago, I had no
idea what I was doing. I had no editors.
I had no social media manager to start
with, and it was just me out there in
the wild posting some stuff. I was just
figuring it out as I went. Now, on the
great side of things, I was consistent,
and I never missed a day. [music] I had
developed that shipping muscle. It's at
this stage, right, that you start to get
on a bit of a hamster wheel. And that's
completely normal. You don't really have
any systems in place. You're new to this
thing. And what's inevitably going to
happen is the creator dip. You have that
initial piece of excitement right in
level one, and now you're into level
two, and you start realizing the work
that's involved here. And this is where
90% of creators give up. Google's
7-Eleven rule says you need 7 hours of
content across 11 touch points in four
different locations to build trust with
someone. So, at this stage, you're just
racking up [music] that trust. If you
find that some of your excitement starts
to wne, just remember, right, this is
all part of the journey. The things you
want to start taking note of are in
those moments where you're feeling some
cognitive dissonance, some frustration,
elements that you're like, "Oh, I think
this could be better." Make note of
those areas. These are going to be areas
that we're going to want to systemize.
we're going to want to get ready to go
and delegate these areas [music] so that
long-term we're not just building
content for 3 months, right? That we've
got a sustainable system for [music] 3
years. So, your big challenge here,
okay, is don't go and try to be on all
[music] platforms all at once.
Inevitably, as you're growing at level
two, the key thing is to develop depth,
not just breadth. I want you to choose
one platform, choose one format, and
[music] go deep. What platform are you
going to focus on? what's going to be
your one core format and go [music] deep
and start developing your systems around
that core thing. The benefit here is
that you're going to be able to focus.
That focus is going to lead to mastery
[music] and it's also going to allow you
to be known for one thing because you're
the world's best at it [music] in your
given niche. Make sure that you keep on
posting daily because truthfully, your
growth across the platforms depends on
it. The reality is is that building a
business is hard, creating content is
hard, growing a team is hard. But you
know what's a lot harder? Giving up,
stopping something you know you should
be doing for 3 months, 5 months, and
then in 5 months from now having [music]
to start from scratch again. I can
promise you that that regret that you'll
feel is a thousand times harder than
giving up. Level three is the platform
master. When I first started my personal
brand 5 years ago, X was my dojo. I
studied the different creators on the
platform. I studied the different
formats. X being this Olympics of
copywriting, I knew that I'd have to
really understand the game to do well
because it's not enough just to have
great ideas on any of these platforms.
You need to know how to actually package
those ideas. You need to be a student of
the game. My mindset here in your
mindset when you're at level three
should be around mastery. It's not about
the followers or the engagement or even
the dollars at this point. It's all
around can I be the best possible writer
in my area? If you can nail that, the
score takes care of itself. One thing to
think about too is as you start going
and putting yourself out there, you want
to understand your own signature format.
So from going deep on one platform and
one format, you continuously refine
things. What I started to learn on X was
it was these long form X posts combined
with great imagery as well as great
video clips that started allowing me to
go and stand out as this triple threat.
Sure enough, this helped me grow on X to
over 180,000 followers in my first year.
I went from virtually unknown to one of
the top 10 creators on the entire
platform. Now, when people started
thinking about systems, they thought
about me. [music] It was from all of
these reps that I developed a ton of
growth. And the beautiful thing is that
from the depth on one platform, it's not
like all that content goes to waste.
Truthfully, through the content
waterfall system, which is a system that
I use to go and repurpose my content and
maximize my effort, I was then able to
go and take that exact content on X and
bring [music] that to LinkedIn long form
as well as Instagram carousels and start
growing from nothing to over 400,000
people organically on LinkedIn and from
virtually unknown to over 600,000 people
on Instagram. This is the power of depth
and [music] this is the power of
developing that mastery mindset. Now the
point of this level is that if you can
understand if you can be the best in
your craft, right? The best in your
format on one platform, you can make
millions [music] of dollars. You're
going to be able to capture all of this
attention and then effectively drive it
to monetization leveraging what I call
the content GPS. This is the most
powerful system for going and being able
to drive people from your rented
audience across social media to your
owned audience in an email list and then
monetizing these people to your product
or service through effective [music]
CTAs. If you're looking to go and get my
help directly going and installing a
content GPS in your [music] business,
you should definitely go and apply to
Founder OS via the link in the
description. We'll get on a 15-minute
call, understand the one system that's
currently keeping you stuck from growing
on the given level you're at, and then
we'll see how we can help. So go book
the call and look forward to connecting.
So your goal really at this level is to
go and pick one platform and study the
top 20 creators on it. From there,
you're going to want to go and study the
different formats, [music] the different
posting times, and all of the details.
Right? Your goal here is to be a student
[music] of the game. I think it's this
mindset that allow you to set yourself
apart from there. Every single day with
every piece of content, you should be
aiming to get 10% better. That could be
getting better hooks, better value,
better rhythm, better copy. With video,
if you choose there, it should be better
lighting, better sound, better
scripting, better titles, better
thumbnails, you name it. There's
probably [music] about 10 core variables
that will allow you to keep on getting
10% better. And over 100 piece of
content, that math is undeniable. It's
13,800 [music]
times better by the 100th piece of
content you put out. And that is the
magic of compounding. And that's the bet
you're making at this level. The next
level is where creators either scale or
die, the personal media company. When
Founder OS started taking off, content
went from being something on the side to
being a full-time job. And I knew that
if I wanted to go and build the vision
that I had for the company, something
would need to change. [music] You need
to shift at this level from just a
creator doing everything yourself to a
content CEO, someone that has the right
strategists, [music] editors, writers to
make sure that you're actually going and
building a company because this is where
most creators [music] fail. A ton of
successful creators will go, they'll get
going, and before you know it, they're
editing, they're writing, they're
shipping, they're filming, and while it
all looks successful from the outside,
suddenly, you know, that YouTube creator
that you've been following or that ex
creator you've been following suddenly
just goes dark. This is creator burnout
101. And let me tell you here, as a
founder brand, where you're both one
part a founder [music] and one part a
creator, you essentially double your
risk of burnout. It's a real [\h__\h]
thing. and you have to go and be
proactive about preventing [music] it.
So, what can you do at this stage to be
proactive? Across the first three
levels, you started to notice a lot of
areas where you probably were getting
some cognitive burnout, whether it was
going and shipping the piece of content
each time or filming it. And you want to
start asking yourself, how can I make
this easier? What would it look like to
make this more fun? We want to go from
how do I do this and how do I do that to
who do I need to bring on to help me?
You're probably thinking, well, how do I
go and afford all these people? This is
why it's important to also have a
scalable offer behind all your content.
Too many creators are focused on ads.
And the truth is that ads is not going
to make you rich. Ads is likely not
going to get you to your millions.
YouTube ads are nice and all, but even
at the level I'm at, I think I make
around $3,000 a month from ads, and I
can tell you [music] that ain't going to
pay my team. So, the core thing here is
that you need to go and make sure that
you actually own your own offer. I don't
really care what your model is. Choose
the thing that's in your zone of
brilliance, the thing that you love,
that you know your audience is going to
buy, and that you can see yourself
spending the next 10 years of your life
on. And then start refining and selling
that thing. Now, I get it, right?
Sometimes it can feel like you're
spinning plates. You're growing your
audience. You're building this community
and you've got a product to [music]
sell. The beautiful thing here though is
that when you have a good margin on your
product, you're able to start
reinvesting those profits into your
people, into the process, and into your
own peace of mind. It's from those
profits you're able to start building
this personal media company. Along the
way, too, when you actually think about
the content creation process, you want
to be thinking about how can I make this
way more simple and enjoyable. We all
know, right, from those of you that
start creating, creating is a ton of
work. Running a company is a lot of
work. You need to be meticulous about
going and writing out every single thing
that you're currently doing and then
going and building systems for each of
these things and delegating every single
thing that you can. So, you need to make
sure you have the right people, process,
and systems in place to make this all a
lot more sustainable. And let me tell
you, it is possible. I help thousands of
founders build systemized founder brands
and remove themselves from operations.
This ain't easy, but there is a simple
system and series of processes that you
can put in place [music] so that it's
enjoyable, it's fun, and you can do it
long term, right? Because like any great
thing in life, it's over the long term
that the real returns happening. And so,
what's most important is that you don't
give up and you have the right systems
and support in place so you can play the
game long term. If you're interested in
getting my help, actually rolling up my
sleeves and helping you with your
business and your founder brand. In
addition to that, booking calls with me
every other week and being able to text
me anytime you need help is exactly what
we do inside a founder OS. You get
support from me, my entire seuite, my
whole media company and team over 50
live sessions a month, not to mention an
epic community of other founders that
are all scaling their brands. So, if
this is interesting, should definitely
go and book a call via the link in the
description and we'll see you there. So,
there's two main action steps at this
level that I'm just going to distill to
make it super simple for you. Number one
is that you want to go and hire your
first [music] key team member. I want
this person to be absolutely [\h__\h]
cracked. Okay? We do not have time to go
and make that [music] first hire a B
player. You need to go and find someone
that is an absolute [\h__\h] beast. This
is an example of someone that yes,
they're a [\h__\h] unicorn. It may be
really difficult to find, but when you
find this person, you're going to get
the leverage you need to go and scale to
level five. And so [music] I want to
encourage you to hire that first person,
but be patient enough to say no to 10
people, to say hell yes to that one
person that hits that high bar of
quality. The second piece here is to
make sure that you're getting at least 3
hours of founder flow every single
morning. Founder flow is the time that
you have to work on the stuff that only
you can do. You have two forms of time
according to Paul Graham, the founder of
Y Combinator. [music] You have manager
time and maker time. And what's likely
happening at this level is that you're
doing a ton of manager time, but the
first thing that starts getting cut is
that maker time. And let me tell you,
it's more important than ever. This is
your time to go and develop a profitable
offer. This is the time to start scaling
that infrastructure in your systems. And
it's the time that you need to start
getting support from mentors and other
adviserss. Make sure that you're getting
that every single day. You know, for me,
I block off my calendar from 7:00 a.m.
till 11:00 a.m. And this is the one
critical function that I do every single
day that I would say is responsible for
about 90% of my success. So, [music] I
want you to go right now, like literally
right now, and I want you to go and
block off your 4 hours of Founder Flow
today. Now, this is the final level, and
it is so [\h__\h] hard that most creators
never reach it. But I'm going to give
you the cheat code here. You know, this
is not about entertainment. It's about
infrastructure. It's about being
omniresent. At this stage, you're likely
going on all the platforms. And so the
key thing here, right, is making sure
that you have that CEO mindset. I think
at this part, you're one part an
architect and one part an investor. On
the architect side, you're making sure
that you're working on the business and
you're removed from the ops so you can
continue to refine the machine. On the
investor side, you're very much a
capital allocator. you're constantly
thinking about who do I need to go and
bring on the team and what is the return
on investment from bringing this person
on. [music] If you can go and hire a
social media manager that's going to go
and relieve you of 20 hours a week of
your time and that's going to then free
you up to go and make an extra 80k a
month in profit, well, the return from
that 8K higher is likely 10x ROI. It's
these kinds of bets you need to be very
confident in making. Another thing
that's going to come up here, right, is
as a team gets bigger, one thing you
need to focus on is decision velocity.
[music]
You know, you can't be that small-minded
creator that's just making decisions
super slow when you know, if you're
trying to move fast, you got to be able
to pull the trigger. You're going to
have to quickly be able to refine your
judgment and make the call. So, at this
stage too, right, aside from all the
systems, the infrastructure, that
architecture, you also got to focus on
your own health. You know, it's your
health that's going to allow you to
build a healthy business. For me, you
know, I focus on doing yoga four times a
week, lifting a few times a week. My
diet is always dialed in and I'm making
sure I'm getting at least eight hours
[music] of sleep every night. It's all
of those details on the health side as
well that will [music] help you stay in
the game. And the truth is that I think
as I grow more on these platforms, I
think of myself as one part founder and
then one part athlete. [music] And the
reason is is that the more I can kind of
just uplevel myself, I'm able to bring
that energy back [music] to the team.
I'm able to bring that energy back to
the content because at this stage too,
your content is this transmission. For
you guys, what I'm always focused on,
[music] right, is a certain
psychoraphic. The kind of person that's
looking to build a company that they
love, have an amazing life, be able to
control where they work, when they work,
who they work with, and what they work
on. And they want to be surrounded by a
community of people they genuinely love,
and have the freedom to do whatever the
[music] [\h__\h] they want with their lives.
It's this kind of targeting of that core
identity that has allowed me to build a
movement around [music] Founder OS. And
that's what we're really after here.
Now, when you're going and marketing to
someone's core identity, there's a
benefit to you and there's a benefit to
them. Okay? The benefit to you is you're
going to build an audience of people
that you actually love to hang out with.
Not to mention too, when you go and put
out something, an opportunity, a new
business that they can get involved in,
it's this opportunity to go and build a
lineup around the corner of people that
are already persuaded to what you're
doing because you've built such a
valuable brand. Organic content and
building at this level of mastery is
going to make you a category king or
queen in your niche. I think that most
content when it's insanely strong, it
spreads like a virus. Bit by bit, people
are going and hanging out with one
another and it just continues to spread.
Your message, your, you know, method,
your different mechanisms and the
overall mission of what you're doing are
all now traveling without you doing a
thing. So, don't make the mistakes that
a lot of people make at this stage.
Don't fail to build a newsletter. Don't
fail to refine your offer. Don't fail to
not surround yourself with the right
community and with the right advisers
and mentors because the truth is, you
need all the support you can get along
the way. Again, make sure that you're
building the right infrastructure
[music] and take pride in being the
architect, the athlete, and the
investor. If you enjoyed this video, you
should definitely go and check out the
content mastery checklist via the link
in the description. I want to go and
help you get from level one to level 5
seamlessly so you can enjoy the journey
and go from creator to CEO. Along the
way, if you want my help going and
implementing these systems, you should
[music] definitely go and book a call
with my team via the link in the
description. We'll get on a call, learn
what level you're at, and help you
unlock that next stage of growth. Thanks
so much for watching. [music] If you
want to go and learn how I built an
audience of 14 million people over the
last 16 years, you should go and check
out this next video. Be sure to like and
subscribe and let's win