if you want better results from your
content ask yourself these three
questions they will get you crystal
clear on your personal brand what do you
enjoy talking about Oprah said the key
to Great interviews is to ask the
question she's dying to ask engaging
content is the same if you don't love
your content neither will your audience
what does your audience need if you're
not clear on your Niche then look at
your audience match your passions to
their pains become a subject matter
specialist that people can't ignore who
are your enemies Rivals sharpen your
brand identity take on adversaries
working against your audience's dreams
be a voice your followers claim as their
own reflect on the answers to these
three questions and think before you
publish when you have Clarity on who you
are you become magnetic