I learned this from Mel Robbins. She
says something that rewired my brain.
It's called the 5-second rule. Now,
whenever you think of something that you
need to get done, you go simply and
countdown from 5 4 3 2 1 and then take
the smallest action possible to
immediately move forward and get that
thing going. Too many people get caught
up in perfectionism when the truth is
that done is better than perfect. It
started to hit me that damn, I was
really getting in the way of my own
momentum. I had become my own worst
enemy. So I made a new pack with myself.
I would start seeking the pain and
getting through this discomfort. It was
from this discomfort that I was able to
finally go and start getting the real
results that I crave. As Walt Disney
said, the way to get started is to quit
talking and begin