If you want to be as successful as Steve
Jobs, you can't just build a social
media following, you got to build a
movement. This is not about
entertainment, it's about
infrastructure. You're one part an
architect and one part an investor. On
the architect side, you're making sure
that you're working on the business and
you're removed from the ops so you can
continue to refine the machine. On the
investor side, you're very much a
capital allocator. You're constantly
thinking about who do I need to go and
bring on the team and what is the return
on investment from bringing this person
on. Another thing that's going to come
up here, right, is as this team gets
bigger, one thing you need to focus on
is decision velocity. Oftentimes you're
going to have about 80 to 90% of
available information to make a decision
and you're going to have to quickly be
able to refine your judgment and make
the call. If you stew on things for too
long, you will collapse.