Seven books that will completely change
the way you think about money. The
Almanac of Naval Ravocon teaches you how
to build wealth through leverage as well
as media instead of just trading your
time for money. Die with Zero by Bill
Perkins. This really flips the script on
what it means to be wealthy. Going and
maximizing your experiences versus just
focusing on your bank account.
Predictable Revenue by Aaron Ross. This
book taught me that real freedom comes
from sales systems that allow you to
have consistent inflows of leads and the
right team structure in place so you're
not constantly getting involved. It's
The Millionaire Fast Lane by MJ DeMarco.
This book really taught me that peace of
mind is what you're really after, not
just being rich. The Psychology of Money
by Morgan Hel explores how mindset and
patience matter way more than math. The
Outsiders by William Thorndikeke. This
book really highlights eight
unconventional CEOs and how they became
master capital allocators. It helped me
start thinking myself more like an
investor than an entrepreneur. The
4-Hour Work Week by Tim Ferrris. This
book really taught me about lifestyle
design. Not just trying to make money to
be rich, but being able to go and live a
life of total freedom.