So, this is Poppy AI, and what I'm going
to show you here is how I quickly come
up with new titles for an upcoming
YouTube video and help me get into that
brainstorming mode. So, what we're going
to go do is we're going to go to my
YouTube channel. And so, we'll pull that
up. Now, the cool thing is I can go and
copy this link. I can paste it into
Poppy AI. Okay, so here it is. It's
pasting it. Now, it's going and
synthesizing all the titles and
everything that exists on my YouTube
page. I can then go and hook up a
YouTube chat window here. So, this AI
chat, I can connect it to my YouTube
channel. Here you can see it's
synthesizing all of the different
titles, the YouTube videos that I have,
and now it's connected to on this AI
chat, which is hooked up to Claude 4
Sonnet. So, there we go. We've got my
channel, and now we've got this. So,
what I'm going to go and do is I'm just
going to put, all right, let's see what
it comes up with here. Now, it's going
and analyzing my channel, and it's
coming up with a bunch of different
titles here. Okay? You know, as with
anything with AI, right? You need to
make sure that you're actually using
your own human ingenuity here as well,
right? We're not just taking anything as
it is. We're always going and adding our
own spark and creativity. What I see as
like the future with AI is that creators
go from always being the one that has to
build things from the ground up to just
having an assistant along the way with
you. But, you still have to be that
editor, that chief detail officer, that
person that is looking at the details
and making sure that, you know, the
stuff is just right.