Aspiration and status is what makes you
the one that can't be replaced. Most
people just default to the same old
tired gross cringe playbooks. We don't
want to do that. I'm not looking for you
to go and show your Lambo. I'm not
looking for you to go and have a
briefcase of cash. That is gross, okay?
Think about Elon Musk and his plan to go
to Mars. On paper, it sounds insane. A
single person trying to go to space.
How's this ever going to happen?
Billions of dollars at risk, deadlines
missed, rockets exploding, critics
lining up to say, "You're never going to
make this work." But here's the thing,
he still hasn't made it to Mars, but it
almost doesn't matter because the
audacity of that vision is what draws
the right people to him. He [music]
committed relentlessly to this vision.
It wasn't just building rockets, he was
building belief. He's building a
movement. He's building this following
of folks that all want to get to this
ambitious vision. Even if it takes a
lifetime, they're down. That's the power
of aspiration.