Here's what most people don't understand
about Steve Jobs. His obsession wasn't
about perfection, it was about something
a lot deeper. Steve [music] was violent
when it came to his standards. And the
reality is is that with Steve, wherever
you look at the different products he
put out there,
>> [music]
>> it was the bar at which he tolerated
that he was just uncompromising on. You
either hit that bar or he would send you
back to the drawing board. It was that
relentless pursuit of simplicity [music]
and this violent upholding of the bar
that really made Apple different and
[music]
has made it one of the most beautiful
products that humanity has ever created.