if you feel lost when you sit down to
post content you need a brand strategy
here are five pillars to my brand
strategy system I use these to grow my
audience to 1.8 million in under a year
find your zone of Genius the most
important aspect of your content is the
experience you bring to it focus on
something you have already achieved and
your audience growth will be exponential
choose your Target customer the Target
customer is the person who needs what
you already know speak to them and help
them level up pick your positioning your
positioning is what makes you stand out
it's your unique solution to your
customer's pain point you want to be so
specific with the problems you solve
that you become number one in your
category Define your vision your vision
is the destination of your business my
vision with founder OS is to build a
community of 10 million Founders who are
changing the world the bigger the better
Define your mission your vision is what
your company is working towards your
mission is how you'll get it done the
clearer you are in your brand strategy
the more you'll feel excited about
posting content your growth will
compound until it becomes Unstoppable