[Music]
let me ask you
something when was the last time that
you felt truly
free like really free know for a long
time the answer to that question
question it really stumped me I think so
many of us spend so much time so much
money trying to achieve the same state
of being of
happiness peace and Tranquility I'm
talking about being free only to find
ourselves completely miserable
stressed and burnt
out I know because I've been there it
was December 2017 and I was running a
business I started that made me all the
money that I thought I needed and for
most of the Journey of it I had no idea
if it was even going to work out the
company I started was putting about a
million dollars in my pocket every year
I was making the money a lot of us think
will buy us freedom but I found myself
working night and day on a business that
slowly felt like it was just complet
completely draining my energy I was also
sitting on the floor of my office every
night at 2:00 a.m. burnt out depressed
unhealthy and all this while I thought I
had to do everything CEO to me stood for
chief everything officer and that's
exactly what I was doing for months I
was trapped in the state without any
light to chase out of the tunnel and if
I had continued I probably wouldn't be
here
today I was in a really really tough
spot and I found myself one day cooped
up in a hotel room and had a panic
attack I was balling crying didn't know
what was going on could hardly catch my
breath I needed to take a step back I
needed to take care of myself so I could
take care of business and take care of
those around
me I meet a mentor his name's
Ryan and he gives me this piece of
advice he goes Matt know you seem to be
on this constant pursuit of
more consider this now Freedom isn't
about doing more Matt it's about doing
less but better now when I first heard
this I was like what the hell does that
even mean it didn't really get any more
clear to be honest with you
he introduced me to the concept of
systems automating delegating and
eliminating the noise of my life and by
systems Ryan meant Frameworks around
thoughts mindsets habits a way of being
that all of us can use in our lives to
live up to our fullest potential I come
from a community of people who believe
that building a business is the right
tool to build their freedom but I don't
really want to talk about that business
stuff today today I want to talk about
the universal concept of
[Music]
freedom I think it's one of the most
important things to us as humans but we
don't actually dissect what it is why
it's important and how we can even get
there my goal with this video is to move
you closer to freedom I want you to be
able to achieve time Freedom location
Freedom Financial Freedom you know
mental and spirit spiritual
[Music]
freedom in order to gain energy you need
to see
energy the issue that so many of us
struggle with though is we have no idea
where all of our energy is even going
you need to identify where your energy
your time your money and feelings are
going before pointing the finger at
yourself when we feel drained or burnt
out it's often because we feel
frustrated and we're not sure what to
blame for that and you find your life
just slowly spiraling downwards and with
it your hopes your dreams your faith in
a better day all just go down the drain
you need to figure out where your energy
is going and the key thing there is to
track every task that you're working on
every meeting you're in every little
thing you're doing whether it's the
meals you're having the activities you
find yourself in dayto day the people
you're
around inevitably when you stack up
every 30 minutes of your day and where
your time is going and you develop an
awareness of where your time is being
spent you can quickly glean the causes
of your unhappiness you can understand
what is actually draining your energy
and this is exactly what I did I took a
look at my to-do list from the previous
30 days and I put them all into a Google
sheet so I could start tracking these
things I took a look at my calendar over
the previous couple months and I made
note of every single meeting I had been
in it made sense I was drained because I
was spending so much time on stuff that
I hated spending hours prioritizing my
schedule and not scheduling my
priorities consuming content mindlessly
and not creating art that shared my
story spending money on vices that
damaged my body and not funding
experiences with the people that I loved
and when you stack up hour after hour
working on stuff that you don't want to
be doing all you can expect is to be
pretty miserable and that's exactly why
I built a Time audit
system you're going to go and measure
the time that each task takes and then
you're going to go automate the tasks
that are mundane eliminate the tasks
that are
unnecessary and delegate the tasks that
someone else could do much better than
you the result I reclaimed 15 hours of
my week back I was able to to focus on
myself take care of my health spend time
with friends that I had missed not been
able to catch up with in so long I was
able to focus on the task that brought
me joy get back to being more of an
artist and not feeling so run down all
the time I finally felt more like myself
I felt more like Matt I found myself
building a life that I was proud of
versus being a participant in a life
that I
hated you know you don't have to be
managing a team running some business or
building a brand to take advantage of
this advice this can work for anyone
know if you desire to have a life that
is yours if you desire to be able to
control your time and to reclaim your
freedom this system is worth
implementing today wherever you're at
right now you can achieve true Freedom
go and eliminate those tasks you don't
need to be doing delegate stuff to other
people automate the stuff that's mundane
and go and get back your time your joy
because you deserve it I was out of the
depths of Despair and more importantly I
was off the office floor at 2: a.m.
[Music]
but there was still one problem I was a
lonely entrepreneur now I think
entrepreneurship is one of the loneliest
paths a human can go on you know in the
depths of Despair sometimes it feels
like you have no one there to support
you no one to help it's just you your
business and a vision fortunately my
battles with Mr loneliness gave me a lot
of systems support and accountability
and you can actually go and steal the
exact system via the link in the
description it's called my personal
board meeting every single month I sit
down and I reflect on what's working
what's not working and what I need to
learn the next month and I ask myself
the hard questions the kind of questions
that oftentimes we don't want others to
ask of us what's working what's not
working what went well this month and
what's not going so well what made me
cry what made me laugh what brought me
Despair and what are the things that
brought me joy all of these patterns
they leave Clues these feelings they
give you an understanding of the path
that you want to take and also those
aspects of life that you probably need
to avoid you my belief is that pain plus
reflection equals progress the board
meeting gives me this opportunity to be
accountable to myself public companies
they go and have board of directors that
keep the CEO accountable but often times
as entrepreneurs in our own lives and in
our bootstrap companies there's no one
there to make sure that we're on the
right path so my personal board meeting
allows me to go and get clear on my
vision my 10-year goals three-year goals
and one-year goals from there I go and I
set what I need to get done every 30
days in my personal life and then do the
same thing for my business
this allows me to get a clear picture of
what I need to work on right now to
actually make everything worth it and to
get to the vision that I'm really after
and don't worry you know the personal
board meeting allows you to take all
these crazy existential questions and
put them all into an easy simple
framework that you can use right now and
I'm not talking about some intimidating
checklists that become some existential
measure of your success I'm just talking
about a simple framework that allows you
to understand exactly what you need to
do over the next 30 days to build your
dream life inevitably getting to a life
that you're really looking to live comes
down from just putting in the Reps there
is no easy way to get to freedom but if
you can go and learn from your mistakes
you can double down on your wins and at
the end of the day too just be kind to
yourself you're going to get to where
you're looking to go by now we can agree
how important freedom is and it's not
something you should just continue
waiting for it's time to get after it
today we've covered a bunch of good
systems they're going to help you focus
on what's most important help you go and
reclaim your time figure out the things
that are draining your energy so you can
focus on building a life that fires you
up you've got the time audit system
you've got my personal board meeting and
you've likely got the clarity now to go
and make Freedom a reality in your own
life freedom is an art it's not for sale
freedom is something you deserve it's
not something you should keep putting
off welcome to the founder Freedom
Movement we're a global community of
Legends looking to go and build freedom
in our lives like And subscribe welcome
and I can't wait to see the life that
you build for yourself