how I deleted my way to $15 million a
year. So, first off, I think the process
of building a company is as much about
deletion as it is about creation. It's
saying no to a thousand things so you
can have a dialedin focus strategy. So,
I have deleted so many different product
lines over the years and at Found our
core product is velocity helping
founders build their organic content
funnel, their social media machine and
over time remove themselves from more of
their operations. I've been able also
from this focus to go and delete 60% of
the stuff from my calendar, right? And
whatever's left, I aim to delegate or
automate most of it. So, I just
basically get paid to be in flow all day
being creative and just mentoring
founders that I love to hang out with
that are genuinely friends. I've deleted
about 16 team members across my
portfolio over the last year and a half
using AI to replace folks that are not
needed, right? And just keeping things
simple. You know, I'd much rather have a
team of 12 A players with a 70% plus
margin than some big bloated team
because honestly, I think the magic gets
lost past 12 people on your team. I've
deleted an office, right? Back when I
was 24, I had a beautiful office in
Toronto. I ditched that years ago. I now
work remotely from Bali. And I've
deleted tons of software and mostly
email, right? Because honestly, most of
that stuff is just noise, right? You can
use claude.