When you think about the most iconic
brands in history, there's one thing
that ties them all together. It's not
their product. It's not their price.
It's this. Nike doesn't sell shoes. They
sell a swoosh. Apple doesn't sell
computers. They sell a bitten apple.
Pixar doesn't just make movies. They
sell a jumping lamp. Now, we think that
we are rational beings, but the truth be
told is that we make purchases based on
how things make us feel. When you're
going and building your brand, think
about what's the emotion you're trying
to build. Apple stood for creativity.
Nike stands for victory. Founder OS's
green dot equals freedom. What does your
brand stand for? Pick one visual
element. Put it everywhere. Become the
symbol. Simple, memorable, everywhere. I
don't sell products. I sell a membership
to a tribe. The dot represents 10,000
founders that chose systems over chaos,
who work 4 hours a day instead of 14,
who build calm companies and travel
while they scale. The future belongs to
founders that have symbols, systems, and
brands, not chaos.