Most people think confidence is about
believing in yourself, but it's actually
about something else entirely. I used to
think confidence was just something, you
know, you were born with. Some people
just have it, but then I realized
confidence [music] is just proof. Right
now, I'm focused on writing every single
day. I'm wrapping up my first book. When
I started writing every morning, I
wasn't confident that I was a writer. I
just showed [music] up 30 minutes every
day, and after 30 days, I had 30 pieces
of evidence. After 90 days, I started
believing it, and after a year, it was
undeniable. Every single day that you do
what you said you were going to do, you
build a little bit of evidence, and
evidence that you can use to then build
more trust in yourself. Evidence that
your word actually means something.
That's confidence. Discipline [music]
equals confidence.