[Music]
she's such a
freak mad and freak
[Music]
yeah all right road trip day one out
here hour outside of Seattle heading
into Olympic National Park Adventures
await we got rainforests Scenic Lookouts
and this
guy let's get
[Music]
it we're out here on this trip with my
brother taking some time to soak it all
in and celebrate celebrate you know the
successes that we've had catch up we see
each other probably every 6 months now
given that we're both on the road all
the time and it's nice and a good chance
to yeah slow down catch
up
and yeah just you know takes a community
to raise a founder and you know for me
the community that's important to me are
my family you know
friends and nature
so we'll be ripping through
Washington over the next few days and
you know grateful for the systems that I
have in place in my company you know
over the last 15 years built a few seven
figure and eight figureure businesses
bit maker herb founder OS and I've
learned the importance of systems to be
able to run a business that runs an
autopilot and have an automated Empire
where you can control you know your life
and have things automated run on
autopilot so that you can do more
important things like enjoy life get
into nature explore and have a good
[Music]
time every hust like
will all right here we go day two Sol
trip in the
books big hike steep hard one here just
outside Seattle 1 hour little little
mounts see let's get
it here we
[Applause]
go know I
man soon
[Applause]
[Music]
I I'm super passionate about this topic
because you know if I hadn't have found
my calling in life honestly I don't even
know if I'd be here today you know back
15 years ago I was working a brutal
9-to-5 job at craft Foods managing a
territory of grocery stores to say I
hated my life would be an understatement
you know every day waking up from night
tears essentially I've having to go to
work the next day and some soul sucking
job you know
eventually I was able to start you know
building and launch my first business
bitmaker when I was 21 we trained over
2,000 software engineers and that
company was acquired by General Assembly
along the way I've learned some key
strategies def finding my calling and
this allows me to wake up every single
day to work that feels like play and
truly live the life of my dreams you
know finding my calling changed my life
and so I I want you to think about you
know what truly excites you what would
it feel like to wake up every day to
work that feels like play to a life
you've dreamed of and what are you
waiting for you know in this video I'm
going to dive deep into the strategies I
would take to bring you from Lost
confused overwhelmed to Clarity
freedom and in control of your
life here we go
go be wondering well hey dude what's
your calling in life for me my calling
is helping Founders build systems
building
communities you know traveling writing
design and art you know for me these are
the things that when I lean into them
you know makes every day feel like play
you know I love hiking love it
journeying traveling and meeting up with
Founders globally and helping founders
with proven systems to grow Their
audience their brand and their
communities with an organic content
funnel helping people drive from Their
audience to transaction that's my real
passion and one of my big strengths in
[Music]
[Applause]
life there's one lesson I learned that I
think is super relevant to how I
approach business today versus how I
used to approach it you know when I
first started building businesses
everything felt like a rush a rush to
send that email to get a customer you
know to deliver I was impatient and I
approached everything like a Sprint and
what I learned over the years is that
slow is smooth and smooth is fast and
you know often times when you just slow
down you take a breath you breathe
breathe know you realize that
everything's going to work out for you
and there's no reason to you know be so
fearful be so rushed feel like you're
behind you know all that stuff just
leads you to forget about the process to
lose track and to not enjoy the journey
and I think the real magic happens when
you know you just get lost in the task
at hand you know you get lost in just
doing quality work you know I believe in
you know something that Cal Newport
calls slow productivity you know
obsessing over quality now being a
Craftsman um working at a natural pace
know when you just allow yourself to
slow down to enjoy the work you know you
do better work people talk about your
work you're creating a masterpiece
people tell their friends and one thing
leads to another and from just slowing
down all the things that you're after
they all happen
naturally
hell
damn this is a a
[\h__\h]
Vibe
wow how we doing neck gangster gangster
there we go let's get it now I'd love to
tell you that I always knew this whole
slow is smooth and smoothest fast thing
but truth is I had to learn it the hard
way you know about a decade ago I was so
busy so caught up in building I got an
offer to acquire one of my companies
for a life-changing sum you know $40
million plus but I was so caught up in
just the stress and
substances that I basically ignored this
didn't think about even the impact this
would make on my life because I was just
so lost so lost building so lost and
confused and stuck and just yeah in a
bad place burnt out and had zero Clarity
like Beyond no Clarity I was foggy as as
hell and I totally ignored the abundance
that was just at my fingertips I never
even really looked at the offer I just
kind of put blinders on and kept
building meanwhile was probably
something I should have said yes to and
so you know looking back it pains me but
it also presented one of the most
visceral lessons of my life which is
Matt a slow down good things happen when
you work at a natural pace and you allow
yourself to breathe and to relax and
that's what I now do work at a more
natural pace take time for nature and
take a soul trip every 6
[Music]
weeks so you may be wondering where this
whole concept of a soul trip came into
play well you know I think when you're
building a business it's important to
also detach from the business room from
time to time and a soul trip is an
opportunity to ditch your phone ditch
your
computer get a
friend
and escape the dayto day to you know
kind of let your creative Juices Flow
get out into
nature and you know just rest up because
if you're just stressing yourself out
all the time there's no way you can be
at Peak Performance and so it's
important that you know you take those
little moments for yourself to relax
maybe catch up on some
reading to
disconnect and you know really just
reflect even on what your true goals are
in life you know for me it's you know
being an
amazing man you know good friend brother
son it's about being there for the
people that matter to me for my
team you know for my
family and it's about you know hitting
long-term goals that matter to me so
that when I'm
85 I don't have any
regrets and I'm proud of the man I
become of the accomplishments that I
have and of the decisions that I've made
so Soul trip
go and mark your calendar for 6 weeks
from now what's the trip that you're
going to
[Music]
take so I've had some time to reflect
while on this sold trip and mentally did
this exercise I'm thinking about what
are my favorite things in life you know
just like the absolute favorite you know
things like cliff jumping you know
riding my bike in nature hikes
hanging with my brother
traveling skydiving you know and then
writing down mentally even you know when
was the last time you did these things
you know it kind of shocked me some of
the things that I enjoy most in life I
haven't done in like a decade you know
and a week here I take off to Europe
I've been about 14 years since I've been
went on a road trip when I graduated
University with three roommates we
traveled to 18 countries around Europe
but I've never been back and so I'm
excited as an example to head back to
something that was my favorite thing
back then and re experience Europe now
as a
34-year-old this is your friendly
reminder to take time to actually do the
things in life you love and to actually
check off that bucket
[Music]
list so I get asked by Founders All the
Time Matt out of all the systems to help
me you know slow down and Achieve
freedom in my business and in my life
what's the number one system you'd
recommend and for me without a doubt it
all comes down to the personal board
meeting you know personal board meeting
is a chance for you every single month
to reflect on your personal goals and
your business goals you know I think
it's important that every single month
you set you know at least 10 big
business goals that you want to complete
in a given month and then have 10
personal goals you're looking to
achieve and the most powerful part of
the system is that you're getting clear
every single month with yourself you
know public companies have board
meetings where you know they get all
prepared and they report to the board
and the board holds them accountable but
often times as founders of you know
smaller businesses or you know just
private private company entrepreneurs
you know we don't do that and so it's
important that you have some sort of
mechanism in place a system to hold
yourself accountable to the personal and
business goals that you have so you can
gain traction and achieve your dreams
and so one of the most powerful parts of
the personal board meeting is that every
single month at the end of my month I
will go and reflect on those goals right
Ray deio says that pain plus reflection
equals progress and so taking time to
then reflect on you know what went well
what didn't go well and then what did
you learn allows you to continually
refine your approach to growth to get
stronger and to iterate and improve
month after month after month and so if
you're looking to go and implement the
personal board meeting in your life I'd
recommend that you go to the link in the
description below I've gone and given
you my own template that you can go make
a copy of that and begin to fill that
out and I would mark on your calendar on
the 30th day of every single month
you're going to go and you're going to
make your personal board meeting for the
next month okay and you're going to then
also reflect for 30 minutes on how you
performed based on the goals both
personal and professional that you had
set out from the previous month okay and
when you iterate on this every single
month and you implement this and you
continue to improve on it this will
legitimately change your life I've been
doing it for over a decade now it's been
responsible for helping me grow my
companies to Millions you know grow my
team to 50 plus and to create a vibrant
life where I control you know the 4 WS
control where I work when I work what I
work on and with people that I love to
work with The Who and I can't wait to
see the impact it makes in your life all
right I can do a much better job of
showing you rather than just telling you
about the personal board meeting so I'm
going to go and show you an actual
example of the template I've created you
can find this personal board meeting
template via the link in the description
just below this video so go grab that
and I'm going to show you how to go and
fill this out so starting off this is
something that I fill out every single
month so on the 30th day of Any Given
month I go and I take generally around
half an hour to an hour to pause and
reflect on my previous month and then
plan my next month so I'll go and dive
into the books I'm going to read so say
for this upcoming month I want to go and
read untethered Soul um and the
presentation
secrets of Steve
Jobs okay and so I'll continue going
through this and figure out well what do
I want to learn well for this upcoming
month I really want to learn you know
how to present like Steve
Jobs
and um I want to go and basically run
like the ultimate you know company
offsite so these are a couple things
that I really want to learn as well as
I'm going to take some tennis
lessons Okay so I fill that out then on
the personal 30-day goal side these are
just really big goals that you have for
the next 30 days right so for me I want
to do a 3-day treack in the
dolomites and go and
visit two countries in
Europe
okay so now I've laid out my personal
30-day goals and generally I'll go and
make these you know pretty robust so
typically around 10 personal goals right
and you'll fill this out and then around
10 business goals and so for me here um
we're going to have you know 50
Founders um helped inside of founder OS
plus um which is one of the core things
that we have here I founder OS I'm going
to install you know Hands-On you know 50
organic content funnels
for Founders and help them scale Their
audience their revenue and their brands
I'm also going to make uh two essential
hires at founder OS and in addition to
this um we are going to scale our
audience say to 3 million people across
all platforms across X Instagram YouTube
Tik Tok newsletter everywhere we are
and so what I then do is go to the
reflection area of this okay so this
reflection area you know my belief is
that pain plus reflection equals
progress right so taking some time at
the end of your month to reflect on what
went well right what didn't go well and
what did you learn and so when you go
through these questions what you'll see
is just natural patterns come up right
maybe you didn't lift as many times as
you want wanted to or you let your
health slide or you w weren't as present
as you would have liked right so it's
important to take some time to reflect
to slow down um and be able to then
learn from you know the things you wish
you had gotten done or you know
delivered on the previous month so you
can continue to improve and get 1%
better every single day so this is the
personal board meeting the last thing I
like to do here is think about my
personal Board of advisers so you'll
fill this in for different areas your
business right um you know sales you
know marketing who are the people that
you're surrounding yourself with right
that are helping you in these given
areas and so you may have someone in
binance marketing you know customer
success right and fill out your own
personal Board of advisers okay these
are really the people that are going to
keep you accountable um and help you
grow for those of you that don't have a
personal advisors this is really what we
help folks with at founder OS we have a
team of people um that help Founders
install an organic content funnel in
their business so you can grow your
online business via personal brand in a
way that is systemized in a way that is
beautiful and most importantly that is
hyper profitable so here you can see an
example of my personal Board of advisers
I have folks like on the strategy side
Rich ananello sold his last business for
hundreds of millions of dollars Kohl's
gone and driven 40 plus million dollar a
year in sales on the marketing side
Ryan's sold his last business for $60
million bootstrap Finance with Hayden
customer sucess Ben so I'm surrounding
myself with a team of weapons that can
help me scale you know founder OS and
Herb to $100 million plus and so really
making sure that you have the community
the accountability the mentorship and
The Proven systems around you is
critical for you to scale and if you're
looking for help building up your own
organic content funnel getting the
systems getting the accountability all
right I'm all about taking Massive
Action so I'd recommend that you go to
the link in the description below go and
get your own free personal board meeting
and go and Mark in your calendar on the
30th day of every single month to fill
out this Resource as it is an absolute
GameChanger and the most powerful system
I've ever discovered I've been using
this for the past decade and it has
literally transformed my entire life and
so I can't wait for to do the same in
your life and let's get after it
as I took time to reflect over the last
month as part of my own personal board
meeting I couldn't help will reflect on
just how grateful I am for all of you
you know we've built this channel from
nothing to a community of almost 100,000
Founders that are all United and
achieving real Freedom you know time
Freedom location freedom and Financial
Freedom and so I want to thank you for
the bottom of my heart for being a part
of this and I'm excited to continue to
inspire you I appreciate you being on
this journey and let's continue to win
together much
love the thing I would say is when you
grow up you tend to get told that the
world is the way it is and
your your life is just to live your life
inside the world try not to bash into
the walls too much uh uh try to have a
nice family life uh have fun save a
little money
um but life that that's a very limited
life life can be much broader once you
discover one simple fact and that is
everything around you that you call life
was made up by people that were no
smarter than you and you can change it
you can influence it you can you can
build your own things that other people
can use and the minute that you
understand that you can poke life and
actually something will you know if you
push in something will pop out the other
side that you can you could change it
you could mold it um that's maybe the
most important thing is to shake off
this uh th this uh erroneous notion that
life is is there and you're just going
to live in it versus embrace it change
it improve it make your mark upon it
um I I think that's very important and
however you learn that once you learn it
uh you'll want it change life and make
it better because it's kind of messed up
in a lot of ways um once you learn that
you'll never be the same again
[Music]