Stop teaching theory and start showing
receipts.
>> [music]
>> Every piece of content should include
specific numbers, time frames, and
before-and-after case studies. If you're
making a claim, back it up with
evidence. Screenshots, [music]
testimonials, live demos. Show people
you've actually done the thing you're
teaching. The strategy I use, be
generous to [music] a fault. Give away
so much value that people think, you
know, is this actually free? [music] I
can't imagine what's inside is paid
stuff if this is the free stuff. If you
go and you hold stuff back and become
some gatekeeper, you're just like 99% of
other people going and creating
online. [music] That's like the default
state. And so many of you are watching
this channel because you want to stand
out. You want to win, right? You want to
be the dominant brand in your category.
And so when everyone else in your space
is just giving people little nuggets of
trust, you can flood them with trust by
just being insanely generous. This one
principle and this one rule with all of
my content is what's allowed me to go
and scale an audience to 3 and 1/2
million people over just the last few
[music] years.