Three easy habits to build lasting
wealth coming from an 8 figureure
entrepreneur. [music] Number one,
founder flow. Every morning from 7:00
a.m. till 11:00 a.m., I make sure that I
get 4 hours of uninterrupted work every
single day to work on my zone of
brilliance. Number two, a morning
workout every single day. This is my
non-negotiable. Every day, 6:00 a.m.
waking [music] up, getting a hit workout
in, making sure that I break a sweat,
get the blood pumping. The key thing is,
don't ask yourself, should I work
[music] out today? just work out every
day. Number three, reading a book before
bed. Now, I used to be guilty watching
Netflix, HBO, Apple TV right before bed,
and all that blue light, it just leaves
you groggy when you wake up. So, the key
thing here is to read a [music] nice
book. These days, I'm reading The Book
Thief, a nice fiction book, so I can
just kind of escape the day-to-day and
fall asleep soundly.