I was making 100K per month and still
felt like a complete failure. I was
trapped, exhausted, and building a
business that owned me instead of the
other way around. I thought I was
failing because I wasn't working hard
enough. But it turns out there are seven
ways to fail at business even while
succeeding. And I'm about to show you
exactly what this is. Because once you
see it, you can't unsee it. I'm Matt
Gray and I used to be trapped in my own
successful business. Great revenue on
paper, but zero freedom in real life. I
realized other founders were stuck in
the same cycle. Which is why I created
Founder OS to share the frameworks that
actually give you your life back. Let me
take you to the exact moment I realized
I was failing. I was on what was
supposed to be a strategy call with a
dream client, seven figures in revenue,
respected in his industry, everything I
thought I wanted to become. He asked me
a simple question. What does your ideal
day look like? What does success
actually feel like for you? I started
explaining my 12-hour days, the constant
firefighting, how I was always available
for my clients, and then I saw his face
change. Dude, now that sounds miserable.
I thought you were successful. I wanted
what you had, but if that's what success
looks like, I don't want it. That hit me
like a freight train. This person
thought I was winning, but I was
actually showing him how to lose. That's
when I realized I wasn't failing at
business metrics, you know, I was
failing at business freedom. And once I
understood the difference, everything
changed. Here's what I discovered. There
are seven ways to fail at business, even
while succeeding. I made every single
one of those mistakes. And you know, if
you're feeling trapped by your own
business, you're probably making them,
too. Failure point number one is you're
pricing like you're desperate. For
years, I undercharged. Not because I
lacked value, but because I lacked
confidence. I thought charging more
would scare away people. You know, I
thought I was going to scare off all
these customers. My low pricing was
actually though repelling my dream
clients. I was failing at positioning.
When I tripled my prices and started
selling transformation instead of time,
my close rate went up, not down. A
founder booked a call with me. He'd been
lurking on my content for months. On the
call, I asked him what finally made him
reach out. He paused for a second and
then said, "Honestly, I almost didn't.
Your prices seemed too low." I figured
if you were really charging that little,
maybe you weren't actually that good. It
flipped everything I thought I knew
about pricing. My low pricing was
sending a signal. This guy's
replaceable. He's, you know, desperate.
He's not playing at the level I need.
And I get it. Most of us started out
selling our time, trading hours for
dollars. We price like freelancers
because we think clients are buying
effort. But highlevel clients, they're
not buying ours. They're buying your
clarity, your conviction, your certainty
in results. So, I made a decision. I
tripled my prices and repositioned the
offer from Matt's time to Matt's
systems. My close rate went up, not
down. Because when you raise your prices
the right way with systems, outcomes,
and confidence, you don't lose leads.
You lose headaches. You stop attracting
the tire kickers and start attracting
the category leaders. Here's the belief
shift that changed everything for me.
Premium pricing isn't about greed. It's
about positioning. Because if you don't
believe in your price, why should anyone
else? Failure point number two, your
content is just noise. I was posting
consistently, getting decent engagement,
but leads were random. I was failing at
turning attention into revenue. There
was no system, just effort. until one
day I realized I wasn't building a
brand. I was babysitting platforms. So,
I stepped back, rebuilt from first
principles. That's when I created the
content waterfall system. One long- form
idea that becomes 20 plus strategic
assets. Shorts, carousels, emails,
tweets, all feeding back to one clear
outcome. I call it my personal media
company. It's how we turn every piece of
content into a growth engine, not just a
post. Suddenly, the chaos stopped. No
more wondering what do I post today? No
more why is this working or why is this
flopping? My content stopped being a
chore and started becoming a machine
that moved our revenue forward every
day, every week. Content without a
system is just noise. Content with a
system is leverage. And once I installed
the waterfall, everything changed. Want
to see what happened when I paired it
with the right team? Well, stick with me
here because that's failure point number
three. Failure point number three, you
think you have to do everything. The
hardest failure point for me to admit
that I had was realizing that I could no
longer be the chief everything officer.
I hired my first assistant and fired her
3 weeks later. Why? Because I was
failing at delegation. I had zero
systems, just chaos in my head. 2 weeks
in, I was spiraling. Not because she was
bad, but because I had zero systems to
give her. 3 weeks later, I let her go
and told myself the lie most founders
believe. No one can do it like me. But
the truth was brutal. I didn't have a
people problem. I had a clarity problem.
You know, when you're just starting out,
getting to 50K a month, you got to do it
all. You got to be the accountant, the
lawyer, cleaner. You're doing
everything. As you start to scale, you
got to start building leverage around
yourself. And I struggled at first to
delegate. I enjoyed doing many things
myself and I had to come to accept other
people could do it as good if not better
than me. Relinquishing that control
early on, it felt super uncomfortable.
But what I realized over time is that my
ability to go and empower those around
me and to delegate the stuff I didn't
actually really enjoy doing. Gave me a
lot more freedom and time to focus on my
zone of genius. So I made a rule. If I
do a task more than twice a week, I
document it. simple looms, bullet SOPs,
not fancy, but just repeatable. And
something wild happened. Delegation
stopped feeling like risk and started
feeling like relief. You know, my team
runs entire workflows I haven't touched
in months. Because here's the shift.
Delegation is about giving up control.
It's about creating control through
systems. But just when I thought I had
delegation all figured out, I made a
scaling mistake that cost me big time.
Failure point number four, your offer is
actually just you. There I was.
Delegation dialed in. Things were
flowing. I thought I was in the clear,
but the real failure point showed up
again. This time though, it was me. On
sales calls, every single lead needed a
different pitch. Every client asked, you
know, can I tweak this part? And I kept
saying yes. Why? Because my offer wasn't
codified. It was custom every time. It
worked, but it wasn't repeatable. It
couldn't scale without me pitching it.
At one point, I remember closing a
$68,000 client and feeling exhausted,
not excited, because I knew what was
coming next. Custom onboarding, custom
delivery, custom chaos. I stepped back
and asked, if I had to deliver this at
10x the volume, what would break? And
the answer was everything. That's when I
created my three-step framework. Same
results, same transformation, but now in
a box. It was repeatable, teachable,
scalable, and something crazy happened.
Close rates went up, client trust went
up, delivery time went down. Because
here's the shift. A custom offer feels
hightouch. But a codified offer builds
trust at scale. The client doesn't want
custom. They want clarity. But solving
the offer wasn't enough. It started
working too well. And that led to a new
kind of trap. Failure point number five.
More success equals more trapped. This
sounds backwards, but you know, every
new client made me less free. More sales
meant more calendar blocks, more
dependencies, more chaos. I was
succeeding my way into prison. More
sales, more momentum, more clients. It
should have felt like freedom. Every new
sale just meant another calendar block,
another Slack thread, another promise
that I had to fulfill manually. I looked
at my Stripe dashboard. Revenue was up.
But my life, it was shrinking. I was
building a highinccome cage. So, I made
a rule. Only sell what I can deliver
while offline. The buying experience
finally matched the freedom that I was
promising. I shifted everything to
evergreen and async. Cohort courses
became on demand accelerators. Strategy
calls became Loom libraries. Live
delivery became modular systems that
anyone on my team could run. The wildest
part, conversions didn't drop, they
increased because now the buying
experience matched the lifestyle that we
were promising. Here's the mindset flip.
If your business breaks when you rest,
you haven't built a business. You've
built a treadmill. There was a specific
moment where I realized I had finally
built a business that could run without
me. I was able to finally pass what I
call the one-mon test. I could walk away
from my business for a month and come
back to a business that was stronger
than when I left. I experienced this
when I was in New Zealand. I had been
backpacking for a month, living out of a
van, going all the way from north in the
Coramandal all the way south to
Queenstown. I was able to rest, relax,
recharge, and by the time I came back to
my business, it was stronger, more
peaceful, and even more systemized. This
really inspired me to continue to
systemize my empires over the last
decade, and is also what inspires me to
help thousands of founders do the same.
Now, I had finally fixed fulfillment,
but the real bottleneck was still
staring back at me in every team
meeting. Failure point number six,
you're the CEO and the employee. I kept
saying, "I've got a lean team." But if
you looked under the hood, I was still
the operator, the strategist, the
editor, the bottleneck for every
approval. It wasn't my team's fault. It
was mine because I had built a system
that required me. I used to think it was
a badge of honor just hiring. Having a
big team, I thought was like the [\h__\h] I
had to learn that lesson the hard way.
Building my first business, Herb, some
of my interview processes were purely on
vibes. Know you had a good vibe. I liked
your energy. We move forward with you.
And I wasn't doing enough testing of
people. I wasn't challenging them. I
wasn't making the interview process a
little bit uncomfortable. These days,
when I interview folks, I'm almost
hoping that they don't want to work with
us. I'm letting them know the edges of
our culture, the extreme ownership, the
work ethic, the level of intelligence,
you know, down [\h__\h] attitude you
got to have to work inside of the
movement, the brand, the community that
we're creating. I'm hoping that people
aren't up to the bar because I want to
make sure that by the time people have
gone through the ringer that they've
earned their seat and they're going to
really contribute to the mission that we
have here. You know, the most expensive
thing that you can probably put in your
business is just a bad hire. So, I did
what I always do when something breaks.
I turned it into a system. I installed
team rhythms, weekly standups, async
updates, and clear decision boundaries.
Now my team knows exactly what to own,
what to escalate, and what I never want
to see again. For the first time, I
could take a real break, and the machine
ran even better when I did. Control
isn't about being involved in every
decision. It's about building a team
that decides like you without you. But
there was still one final failure point.
And this time, it wasn't inside the
business. It was the business itself.
Failure point number seven, nobody knows
what you actually do. By this point, I
had momentum, but complete confusion.
Four offers, three funnels, different
messages everywhere. People would DM me,
you know, I want to work with you, Matt,
but what do you actually do? Confused
prospects don't buy. So, I nuked
everything that didn't point to one
clear outcome. I distilled it all down
into one clear system, one scalable
offer, one simple organic content
funnel. One message across every channel
overnight. Everything got simpler, and
simpler scales. Here's what I learned.
Complexity feels like scale, but it
kills momentum. Clarity is what
compounds. I wasn't just fixing my
business. I was designing my freedom. I
stopped being the bottleneck. I stopped
being the operator. I stopped being the
approval manager for my own life. And I
became what I believe every founder is
meant to be. Not just a builder, but a
designer of companies. Because scaling
isn't about doing more. It's about doing
less intentionally with systems that
scale without you. These days, systems
save my ass every day. Now, the
businesses that I run, they run like
clockwork. No matter if I've gotten busy
for a couple weeks with something or I
want to take a few weeks off to be in
nature, doesn't really matter. Those
businesses are autonomous. They run on
autopilot. They're automated and they
don't require any of my involvement.
This is what it's all about, right?
Building a business that's systemized so
that you can exit it. Whether exiting it
means selling the business or exiting it
means just taking some time off. You
should not be an employee of your
business. You're the CEO. You shouldn't
be lost inside the business. You should
have the ability to work on the
business. For me, right now, I'm nerding
out on AI, building new agents for
Founder OS, working on systemizing new
levels of the business, and really
taking advantage of this insane time to
be alive. Essentially, I've become the
company's R&D department. I just get to
work on future cool projects that I
think will mindblow founders and help
them with some of the core problems that
I see them having today. My job is to
explore new technologies. It's to
explore new ways of using AI and
integrating that into our business. And
I just get to go and wake up every day
working on stuff that honestly I would
do even if I wasn't getting paid. This
is what founder freedom is to me. And
this is the power of having a systemized
empire is that you can work on the [\h__\h]
you love. Here's what happened when I
stopped failing in these seven ways. My
revenue went from 100k to 250k a month.
But that's not even the most important
part. My time went from 80 hours a week
to 25. I started taking real vacations
where nobody could reach me. I began
waking up excited about my business
instead of dreading it. This was just my
experience. Your results will vary and
won't necessarily be the same as mine.
What it shows is what is possible when
you stop failing in the right ways. The
biggest change wasn't the money. You
know, it was remembering why I started a
business in the first place. Freedom.
Most entrepreneurs are failing at the
wrong things. They're obsessing over
revenue, customers, growth, but they're
failing at freedom, energy, and joy.
They think success means working more,
doing more, being more. But real
success, the kind that actually matters,
means identifying what you're failing at
and then fixing that first. Let me ask
you, which of these seven failure points
hits home for you? That's your starting
point. That's where you stop failing
first. Most people try to fix everything
at once and end up fixing nothing. But
if you pick just one and get obsessive
about not failing there anymore,
everything else is just going to fall
into place. I could give you some
generic checklist right now. But that's
not what you need. What you need is
someone who can look at your specific
situation and tell you exactly where
you're failing. More importantly, how to
stop. If you're making decent money, but
you feel trapped. If people call you
successful, but you feel like you're
drowning, I've created something
specifically for founders just like you.
It's not another course. It's not
another mastermind. It's direct access
to the team and systems that help me
stop failing in these exact ways.
There's a link in the description if you
want to learn more about it. Get the
same clarity for your own business. And
if you know someone who's successful but
secretly miserable in their business,
send them this video. Sometimes the best
thing you can do for someone is to help
them see they're not alone in failing
the way they're failing. Now, if I was
to go and give Matt advice that was just
doing 30K per month over a decade ago,
I'd say first off, you know what?
Everything's going to be all right. That
may be some advice I'd give to you as
well. If you're here, you're part of
this movement. You're part of this
channel. We're a group of people that
rain or shine, we get down. We do the
work. We do what is necessary. We build
the systems because we are a community
of systems designers. We're a community
of builders, of creators. And so when I
look back at Matt, you know, 13 years
ago, I say relax a little bit, man. When
you just keep compounding, when you stay
consistent, you keep working hard, and
you keep building systems, everything is
going to be amazing. I would also tell
them, triple down on your hiring
process. One of the biggest points of
leverage in any company is the people.
The better people that you hire, the
better your company because the people
build the product and the product builds
the brand. If you can go and be
maniacally focused on bringing the best
people on board your empire, that empire
will grow at rates you never could have
imagined. You know, when I look at our
team at Founder OS, I am blown away that
when I look to the left and I look to
the right that I get to actually wake up
and collaborate with these people. Be
rigorous about the people you bring on
board. Getting on board your company
should be harder than getting into
Harvard. When you're interviewing
someone, put them through the ringer.
Don't just let anyone on board your
ship. Only allow the best because as
leaders, you get what you tolerate. And
so, don't tolerate the [\h__\h] Don't
tolerate lazy people. Don't tolerate
people that are not as excited about
what you're building as you are. You
need missionaries, people that are
willing to go the distance for you
because if they're not, they're not
right for your company. Thanks for
watching and remember, failing at
business is temporary, but failing at
freedom doesn't have to