At 21, my first business was raided by
the government. At 24, I sold that
business for a life-changing sum. 25, I
started my second business out of a van
in New Zealand. And 3 years ago, I
started the business of my dreams.
And now,
well, get to travel, work from anywhere,
and the Italian Doommites.
This place is like a movie. I thought
I'd just pull over from a mountain
biking journey to share a few stories,
few lessons, lots of mistakes
so you guys can learn from the last 15
years of trial, error, learning, and
everything in between. Let's get into
it. Let's rewind 15 years ago. I started
my first business, Bitmaker, basically
by mistake. It was me and a few friends
smoking some weed and we came up with
this idea of creating a technology boot
camp and training people that really had
no skills at all in giving them the
skill of being able to go and code
online. We teach them skills like
JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS
over the course of a 9-week intensive
boot camp and then go and get them jobs
at the top tech companies across Canada.
Companies like Shopify, Google,
Facebook, Hootsweet, you name it. So the
company was a big success. Things look
good. The truth was though along the
journey I had no idea what I was doing.
I made just about every mistake in the
book. Now probably the biggest mistake I
made when building that business was
that I had no criteria. I was grateful
to finally be starting my first
business, but I also didn't have much of
a criteria for what I was really looking
for in a business. Now that I look back,
I know that things like, you know, no
co-founders, uh, being able to do work
that feels like play, being able to love
the customer, you know, be able to build
something in 3 months or less. These are
things that are important to me and what
I built. But back then, you know, I just
fell into something. And while it was an
amazing experience, you know, along the
way, I just found myself doing a bunch
of stuff that I really hated and found
myself basically running a business that
at times felt like a prison. I also was
stuck in Toronto, you know, cold
winters, working in an office. I really
didn't have much freedom, which was the
whole reason I got into business in the
first place. You know, to be able to
work from anywhere on anything with
anyone. But this was anything but that.
You know, one day my chief of staff ran
back to me in the back office of this
technology school we were building and
said, "Matt, you know, there's a couple
people at the door. They want to talk to
you. It doesn't look good." I was like,
"What the hell's going on?" There's
these two enforcement agents from the
government and they told me, you know,
"Hey, are you the person running this?"
I was like, "Yeah, you know, what's up?"
Well, it turns out, you know, they had
seen an article of me in the Globe Mail
and they thought we were operating an
unregistered private career college.
Basically, they thought we were a
university, which is crazy because we
weren't giving grades out. We were
simply just giving people skills. They
did not give a [\h__\h] They told me that I
had one month left. I was probably going
to court. I was going to be put in jail
for a year and the business and me would
be fined a million dollars each. I like
felt my life flash before my eyes. You
know, here I was creating this business
that was altruistic, having a big
benefit, helping not just the Toronto
tech ecosystem, but helping people's
lives all across Canada. You know, we
had trained around 800 engineers at this
point. Everything was rocking and
rolling. I thought we were good. So, I
had to go to this, you know, group of
students we had in the classroom and let
them know that we'd have to shut down
the business for a week because even
having our website up constituted us
operating a college basically and the
government would find us $10,000 every
single day. And so I told these
students, "Listen, you give us just one
week whenever I've had my back up
against the wall in life, I've always
found a way out of this situation." That
night, I stayed up for, you know, about
48 hours straight and emailed over 3,000
people. Before you know it, it was
trending on Twitter across Canada, and
people were wondering, "What the hell is
going on? Why is the government shutting
down this kind of business?" Emailing
these 3,000 people, you know, honestly,
this didn't feel natural. This was pure
survival. I knew that if I didn't get as
many people as humanly possible to know
what the hell was going on, I was
screwed. It was kind of this like David
and Goliath moment. And so I figured,
well, hey, if I'm going to go and try
and defeat this giant, I need to go and
build an army. And sure enough, emailing
3,000 people did just that. It built
this army of people that also believe
that what I was building was worth
saving. People like Paul Graham, Venode
Kosla, Chamath, Poly Hapatia who built
Facebook from a million to a billion
users were like, "What the hell is going
on?" Well, I had seen this tweet from
Chimath going basically like, "What the
[\h__\h] Why are they shutting this down?"
And I noticed he was at a conference
about 3 hours away from where I lived.
And so I emailed him and he said, you
know, "Hey Matt, meet me at this
conference." So ended up meeting Chamath
at this conference. So I told him the
story of how the government was shutting
us down and his reaction was like, "This
is complete [\h__\h] I can't believe
I've invested $25 million in the
Canadian tech ecosystem and this is how
they're treating entrepreneurs. He told
me to give this guy Noble a call. I
didn't know who Noble was, but that day
gave Noble a call and he told me, you
know, give me 48 hours. We'll get this
fixed. The next day, I was on the phone
with the Minister of Training Colleges
and Universities, Brad Doo Good, in
Canada. He told me, you know, sorry, I
can't believe you're going through this.
We'll get this sorted. 48 hours later,
we were given the only exemption for a
business of its kind in Canada. And we
ended up operating that business for
another year and a half. and exiting it
for a life-changing sum to general
assembly. Pretty insane situation, you
know, to have to deal with at 21. You
know, the government raiding your
business. It's definitely not what I had
on my bingo card when I was beginning
that business. First off, it taught me a
lot about my own medal and my own
ability to find a way through any
situation, no matter what I was put in
front of. In this case, it was jail
time, being fined millions of dollars.
And, you know, I was able to go and step
up to the plate and get over this
battle. It really cemented for me the
importance of community. And we wouldn't
have been able to get over this crazy
situation if it wasn't for all the
people in the community, not just in
Toronto, but all over North America that
saw the story online, shared it with
their friends, spoke up, and sure
enough, changed public opinion, changed
the government's opinion on how they
were treating us. You know, at that
time, I just whipped up this email list,
which was every single person that I had
met over the previous 2 years building
the business, and just one by one
emailed them. But today when I build
businesses, a big thing that I do,
whether it's operating Herb or you know
operating Founder OS is making sure
there's an actual email list that we're
constantly growing to the point where
Herb has over 2 and a half million
emails and Founder OS has close to
200,000. And so the lesson there is to
really own your audience because you
really never know when it may come in
handy.
BitMaker ended up being a great success.
You know, we're able to exit it, but I
knew, you know, I still had a lot more
building in me. You know, I was 23 years
old and at this point, you know, I knew
I wanted to build my next thing based on
freedom, but honestly, I had no idea
what I wanted to build. And the more I
thought about what I wanted to do,
honestly, the more I just got confused.
And so, what I ended up telling myself
was that similar to how I just emailed a
bunch of people and that solved all my
problems building BitMaker, that I would
just go and email 400 people. You know,
I emailed for jobs at Uber and Pinterest
all the way to someone just building a
business from their garage and really
everything in between. And I told myself
if I just started having conversations
with people, maybe from those
conversations I discover the right
opportunity for me. And so one of the
emails I had sent was to a best-selling
author named Tucker Max who then
introduced me to a guy who introduced me
to a guy. And these were a couple guys
building a cannabis recipe site in New
Zealand called the Stoner's Cookbook. I
became pretty fascinated by the concept,
the idea, and the vision for where
cannabis was going over the next 20
years and figured [\h__\h] it. you know, why
don't I just go fly out to New Zealand,
go backpack with these guys, travel for
a while, and maybe there's an
opportunity to get more involved, even
potentially purchase this website off
them. You know, it kind of makes me
think that over the last 15 years of my
life, I think two words really defined a
lot of my most important decisions I've
ever made. [\h__\h] it. And so, this was a
cannabis recipe site where people could
go and submit recipes, almost like a
Reddit, and people could learn how to go
and cook cannabis recipes globally. It
turned out that these guys, they didn't
want to be running this business long
term. They viewed it more as like a
hobby website. And I ended up buying the
business off them for six figures. And I
had a bigger vision for what it would
become. You know, I knew that, you know,
cannabis was likely to legalize globally
over the next two decades. And there
needed to be a more tasteful, authentic,
beautiful brand that existed for
everyday cannabis consumers because
cannabis consumers in many cases are no
different than like coffee lovers. And
so, sure enough, I bought the site. I
rebranded it to Herb and we transformed
it into this hub for cannabis culture,
for people to find the best products and
brands for them and for people to learn
a bunch of information, how-tos around
cannabis. We built it from an audience
of over 100,000 people now to over 14
million people, a team of 27 people. You
know, I still am the founder and CEO of
it operates on autopilot with
automations all through it and amazing
team members that allow me to go and
travel to amazing places like this all
while it just runs itself. Probably one
of the bigger mistakes I made with Herb
is for the first four years I had a real
focus on outcomes over processes. I was
constantly, you know, focused on, you
know, can I sell this business for $100
million? You know, can this business
make $20 million a year? And if it
didn't, every moment that it wasn't
achieving those goals, I was miserable,
depressed, also just a brutal person to
be around. I eventually, after, you
know, hitting rock bottom, uh, you know,
we had received two offers for the
company for $50 million. And this was in
the heyday of cannabis probably around
maybe 7 years ago. I ended up calling up
an adviser, Harley Finkelstein from
Shopify. And he told me, you know what?
Just put on blinders. Don't even look at
these. And so sure enough, you know,
after talking to a few other people, I
kind of didn't even look at the offers.
I just took the advice and I just kept
on building, thinking, you know, there's
a clear sight of this business being a
billion-dollar company or more, I should
just ignore these offers right now.
Crazy thing happened. Few months later,
the cannabis industry went cold as hell.
Everything dropped off a cliff. We had
overhired. We had overestimated how
frothy this market would be. And we had
to slim down the team. And day after
day, it just felt like hell. I remember
sitting lying in bed just thinking, "Oh
my god, why did I not accept those
offers?" Now, I realized I'd gotten so
lost in the business, so focused on the
hustle of it. Also just lost at the
reason why I had really started it that
when I look back, I was just so
confused, so in the middle of it. At
that point, I knew I had to change the
way I was building. You know, this
outcome focused, it was doing me no
good, right? All it was leaving me was
feeling miserable, down, depressed, and
had me wanting to quit every single day.
So, I realized I had to find a way to
fall in love with the process of
building this business. How could I make
every day amazing? And around that time
was when I had randomly watched this
documentary with Carl Icon, you know,
the famous financer, probably the 10th
richest guy in America. And what I
realized after watching this jolly old
fellow was that he has this portfolio of
companies that he operates and he's at
the top building icon enterprises and
views himself more as a portfolio
manager versus an entrepreneur. And I've
started to think what if I change my
perspective on this and instead of going
and just being an entrepreneur actually
am an investor with a portfolio
companies. I started to think about,
well, okay, obviously as I build this
portfolio of businesses, you know, Herb,
Founder OS, my investments, and anything
else I start over the next 50 years of
my life, all of these businesses,
they're going to need awareness. They're
going to need traffic. They're going to
need a brand, obviously, and I'm going
to want to build a community and a
movement behind them. And so, while I
may sell off each one of these
businesses at some point between now and
the next 30 years, the cool thing was
that I realized that having a personal
brand would be something that I would
own for the rest of my life. It's like
this appreciating asset that just keeps
building value, paying you dividends
over time. And I really think that
building a personal brand is the most
valuable asset you can possibly build.
you start to realize like, wow, some of
the most powerful entrepreneurs out
there, they built their brand and that
brand over time actually helped propel a
lot of their businesses. And so I
figured if I'm in this for the long haul
and everything I do, I think super long
term, it just seemed to make sense to
get started even at zero just to get
going because when I looked at the
future, there was this thesis that I had
in my mind, which is that people are
going to follow people and then they're
going to follow brands and that the most
powerful businesses of the future will
be run by entrepreneurs that actually
are building their own brand. And so I
started building mine in a systemized,
beautiful, tasteful way that wasn't like
other people I'd seen out there. It was
my way around my interests, my design,
my way of doing things that would be a
little bit different, sort of like this.
And so at that point, it gave me the
vision to, you know, hey, herb is great,
but what if I could operate many
businesses? And this was just one of the
cash cows that I went and built. So I
started falling in love with the process
of building systems. The process of
putting the right team members and
systems owners in charge of owning
different aspects of the business and
getting back my time. Sure enough,
focusing on this process allowed me to
develop a lot of mastery in building
systems and removing myself from
operations without everything falling
apart. I was able to build a lean mean
team. You know, the business ended up
tripling. You know, our audience
doubled. More importantly though, I was
happier than ever. I was finally
enjoying this business that for a few
years had felt honestly like hell. Along
the way, I, you know, really started
learning the lesson of just falling in
love with the craftsmanship behind a
brand. Falling in love with the process
of mastery. You know, for me, you know,
I love things like building systems, you
know, traveling, building automations,
design, branding, curating. Somewhere
along the way, I discovered one of the
most powerful systems ever, which is
called the icky guy system. you know,
really finding the intersection of what
I love, what I can be paid to do, what
the world needs, and what I'm great at.
And what I started to see at the
intersection of those four areas were
things like automating businesses,
building distribution from day one,
coaching founders, being in nature,
hiking, exploring, traveling to badass
places. And I started to think, okay,
well, this first portfolio company that
I owned right now called Herb was great.
Right now it's on autopilot. We're good.
It's this autonomous empire that runs
itself. And it was time for me to go and
build the next mountain, build the next
business, something that was more dialed
around my calling in life. And that was
the genesis of Founder OS. Founder OS is
really this amazing community of
founders that are all focused on helping
one another build founder-ledd brands.
You know, founder brand is one part
founder, one part creator. And the
intersection of that is where I think
the future of entrepreneurship is going.
I think that people follow people and
then they follow brands. And founder OS
is built with that as like the thesis
for what we're doing. And I was able to
take all of my amazing learnings over
the last 12 years of building businesses
and use all that culmination of the
pain, the agony, the mistakes, all of
it, and use that as the genesis for
something that would go on to help
10,000 plus founders build their brands
and be able to build it off of actual
systems. Through building this business,
what I've really been able to lean into
is becoming a systemized founder. You
know, I didn't realize it at the time,
but after talking to different friends,
talking to different founders, I was
able to discover what one of my core
strengths was in life. You know, it was
building systems. To me, it felt like
that was just the only way to build
companies. But for many other people, I
see tons and tons of founders doing it
the hard way. You know, finding
themselves working on the same old thing
every single day, dredging through the
days, working on stuff that's heavy
lifting and not automating things, not
delegating things correctly, and not
just eliminating the stuff that's
probably just a complete waste of time.
What I really help founders with is
becoming systemized leverage founders.
Building businesses that are
anti-fragile that they can choose to
either build that business large and
have fun. They can remove themselves
from the operations of it and just
travel and enjoy life or they have a
business that's completely systemized
that they can go and sell and move on to
the next thing. And so systems really
give you freedom. I think freedom is a
founders's optionality. Knowing that,
you know, you can keep on working on
what you love. You can travel. You can
work from anywhere. you can do anything
knowing that you've built this
systemized empire. My favorite part of
Founder OS is working with, you know,
just the talented people that we get to
collab with and the founders that we get
to help every single day. Again, it's a
business that's largely built around my
passion. And I think when you're
building a business like Founder OS, the
biggest joy is that the deeper that I go
in pursuing my own passions, the things
that I love, and getting really great at
them, the more I'm able to actually
benefit the community of founders around
us. As an example, the more I go and
systemize my business, powering it with
AI, building an agent around everything
that we've built over the last 15 years
and unlocking that for my own business,
well, that's the same AI agent as an
example we can go and unlock for
founders inside of Found to help them
build their own brands. And so, I'm on
this journey that I see as a forever
journey. At this point, I'm living kind
of everyday retirement, which to me
stands for being able to work on stuff
that even if you were retired, you would
still be doing that stuff. Being able to
create, being able to help others, being
able to collaborate with people that I
respect. And I think this is what life
is all about. And so, when I look back
on these last 12 years, I think there
are a few things that I wish I had
known. Number one is the importance of
delegating. So many founders feel so
alone and they have so many tasks on
their plate that they want to get off
it, but they find that either they do it
themselves or they give it to someone
else, but sure enough, they stop
trusting people because anytime they
delegate to it, it just falls flat and
sure enough they got to roll up their
sleeves and get back into it. The key
thing there is having the right systems
built around ideally the core 21 things
in your company. You know, when you go
look at the customer journey for
whatever you're building, from awareness
to collecting their email to being on a
sales call to onboarding them to
bringing them into your community to
them referring their friends, you know,
to invoicing them, these are say the
seven core steps of your customer
journey. And each of those steps likely
have three different core systems, so 21
total that when you get those 21 systems
dialed in, you have a business now that
is completely systemized and you are a
systemized founder. Now, this may sound
like a bunch of stuff and we can get
into other details, but if you're
interested in actually going and
learning how to become a systemized
founder, I went and put a complete
blueprint together, which you can go and
find in the link in the description of
this video. Go check that out. It's
everything that I wish I had 15 years
ago when I was building my first company
over 15 pages. every little bit of what
it probably takes you to go and start
removing yourself from more of the
[\h__\h] that you hate doing and be able
to lean into more stuff that actually
brings you joy and fires you up. The
next thing that I wish I had known is
honestly the power of growing your own
email list. I see so many people, they
either are building on social media,
making content here and there, and they
have some product, but it's all
disjointed. And the key thing that I
experienced during BitMaker, right, was
if I didn't have those 3,000 emails for
those people, I would have been screwed.
My life would be over. You know, I
probably again would have been fined a
million dollars and would have been out
of it. But the fact that I had this
email list legitimately helped me avoid
turmoil, right? It gave me the
opportunity to then go and hit up these
people and be able to rally this
community, rally this movement around
what I was doing. And so as I've gone on
in my career, you know, any business I
build, the email list is everything. At
Founder OS, we have a newsletter that we
send out every Wednesday and Saturday.
We essentially go and give people
systems and stories around what I'm
doing so they can go and connect with me
on a deeper level and also get free
systems to be able to scale their
business and take it to the next level.
It's an easy thing to get going. Simply
just go build a landing page. Get going
with a newsletter on a platform like
ConvertKit, HubSpot, Substack, doesn't
matter, and just start sharing some
stuff weekly and collecting people's
emails. Sometimes when you start it, you
actually never know how it's going to
benefit you down the road. And I can
just tell you, doing you a favor, start
an email list. The last thing that I
wish id known is again the importance of
having clear criteria as a founder. I
think too many of us just go with the
flow. And while that's really good,
often times it's really important also
to be super intentional with what you're
building. I like to often times focus on
being more of an investor than an
entrepreneur. And when you're an
investor, you are building a portfolio
of different assets and you make sure
that you have a clear thesis and
criteria by which you'd go and invest in
something. And so for me, when I'm going
and investing in any business, investing
my time, my energy, the things that are
important to me are that it feels like
play. I have to love the customer. It
has to feel obvious that I would build
something like this. It has to have a
clear path of getting to $5 million in
annual recurring revenue. I have to be
able to build and monetize the thing in
three months or less. There has to be
founder product fit and founder
distribution fit. And it's got to be
something what I can see myself doing
over the next 10 years, 20 years. And so
then when I go and apply these criteria
to different businesses, it becomes
obvious most of the time what businesses
just do not make sense for me. And
that's important, right? Because often
times we can find ourselves going down a
path for 6 months or even a year when we
really should have just said no to that
thing right out the get- go. And so your
criteria help you understand not just
what to say hell yes to, but how to
quickly say no to things that are not
the right fit for you. So given
everything I've just shared with you,
you know, if I was to go back and, you
know, tell my 21-year-old self anything,
you know, I'd have a lot of probably
different lessons and things to talk to
Matt about, but I think the number one
thing is don't worry. everything is
going to work out okay. Now, at some
moments I've gotten so in my own head,
you know, just paralyzed at times by
worry, paralyzed by a feeling like, am I
ever going to amount to anything? Is
this how the rest of my life is going to
be? And if I was to look back and tell a
younger version of myself something, I'd
say, you know what, you know, just
loosen your grip a little bit. You know,
don't worry. It's all going to work out.
You've got a good head on your
shoulders. Every day you're getting 1%
better and you got to just kind of be
patient and let compounding work its
magic. You know, I had to learn these
the hard way. But, you know, here I am
now getting to operate a business based
on freedom, being able to work anywhere.
You know, mountain bike all through the
Doommites, operate on my own schedule
from anywhere, serve a community of
people that I love. You know, every day
I feel like I'm learning, I'm growing,
I'm living my life's calling. You know,
I think I was put on earth here for a
reason. And if you're watching this, you
know, my message to you is that you
don't need to settle, right? You can
have exactly what you're after. And I
think if you can go, you know, start
systemizing where you're at, document
what's most important to you in terms of
your criteria and start finding, you
know, your true calling in life and
building something around that. I think
it's something that, you know, at the
end of the day, you're not going to
regret that when you're 85 years old on
your rocky chair. So, appreciate you
watching this. Welcome to the founder
freedom movement and let's win