If you don't know who you are, your
audience won't either. But the creators
who get this right, they don't just
attract followers, right? They're going
to attract the right followers. They're
going to build an actual movement around
them. It took me an entire decade
running three businesses to fully
understand my own core values. Two of my
values that changed everything for me
personally. The first is bring
solutions, not problems. Changes how the
entire team operates and communicates.
We stopped tolerating complaint culture.
We started attracting solution-first
people. Now, the second is insanely
simple. If you can't explain it simply,
then don't ship it. If a piece of
content is confusing, [\h__\h] cut it. If
an offer is hard to explain, just remove
it or rebuild it. Those two values alone
shape how I hire, how I build, and how I
create everything.