15 years ago when I just got started
building businesses, I was working 80
hours a [music] week working myself to
the bone. Fast forward 15 years and I
just worked 20 hours a week on my zone
of genius. And in this video, I'm going
to share the four systems that are going
to help you avoid the four time traps.
And honestly, just live a more enjoyable
life. So, let's get into this. Time trap
number one is [music] your calendar.
Now, I've been there. Looking at my
calendar, it looked like a damn jingga
game. just fitting in one piece after
the other until 5 days a week I've got
seven hours of meetings a day and hardly
have any time for the real work I need
to do. This wasn't sustainable. Going
from meeting to meeting, you know,
developing insane levels of Zoom
fatigue. And [music] at the end of the
day, you know, at 7:00 p.m., you know,
you've worked your ass off all day, but
candidly, I don't feel I've actually
gotten any work done. Something needed
to change if I was going to really go
and get myself the time freedom I was
after. What I've invented these days is
a few rules that are really important.
Number one, no agenda, no meeting. If
someone's not able to go and come up
with the core outcomes we're looking to
get out of a given meeting in any day,
we do not even book it. Number two is
Tuesdays are my meeting days. What that
does is build constraints around the
rest of the week. Mondays, Wednesdays,
Thursdays, Fridays, forget it. My chief
of staff doesn't allow any other
meetings to be booked all throughout my
week. So Tuesdays are my day to lock in
into manager mode and the rest of the
week I get [music] time to be in founder
flow and in maker mode. The third aspect
here is cutting the dreadful hour-long
meetings. I don't know who the hell made
that rule, but let me tell you, [music]
you don't need to abide by it. 15minute
meetings, 30-inute meetings are
perfectly good and sound. If you have
the right agenda, you got the right
people in the room. You got that 30
minutes on the shot clock, you're going
to get after it a lot faster and be able
to jam more into your Tuesdays so you
can leave [music] the rest of your week
to peace and productivity. Nobody wants
to be stuck in meetings all the time.
So, what I've gone and created my own
meeting OS that I use inside of my
companies and that I'd encourage you and
your teams to use to go and cut back all
of those dreaded meetings. So you can go
and get that via the link in the
description and go and apply it in your
team today. There we've gone and cut
down our hours from 35 hours of meetings
a week to just 5 hours on a Tuesday.
There we go. 30 hours. Good to go. So
the next time trap is hiring. As a
founder and CEO, my main job, right, is
making sure I'm building an insane team
around me. Making sure that we have a
massive pipeline for all the different
core roles in my company. Whether it's
video editors, writing, salespeople,
customer success. We have over 23 people
on my team at Founder OS. And I have
another 25 people working in my other
company, Herb. And so there's a lot of
people here, which means if you're not
careful here, things can run wild. What
you want to be doing is going and
creating your own careers page on your
website. I like to go and make sure that
that page is populated with all the
different jobs that we have currently
open inside the company. I also put a
video on that page that's basically
selling people on our culture, what
we're [music] all about, who we are, and
who we are not. That last piece is
really important. I actually kind of
want to scare people away from working
with us. And the way I do that is I make
sure that I talk about the edgy parts of
our culture. You know, the fact that we
have an all-in mentality. We take
extreme ownership. We're really bought
into this vision and die hard about it.
If people aren't down with that, I'd
rather them just go away. And so what
I'm doing here is I'm then going and
driving people to this page. They watch
the video. If they feel like they're
suitable for the role, they apply via a
type form and then we'll go and get them
on a call. Here's where I cut my time
from 12 hours to just 2 hours a week
around hiring. Our interview process
looks something like this. We'll have an
initial culture-based interview to
understand, would we even have any
chemistry with this person? Would they
fit into the squad that we've built? And
I don't need to run that meeting. My
chief of staff runs all those to do that
quick assessment in 30 minutes. From
there, if the person seems right, we'll
generally have them go and complete a
[music] take-home challenge. We're
giving them some sort of challenge.
Generally has about four parts to it
that gives us a sense of how this person
would actually do the work in their
role. It's one thing to have a person do
a bunch of talking, but for us, it's
like just show us your damn work. Now,
we have someone submitting the
challenge. They're then getting on
another call or interview with their
given hiring manager. And assuming
they've gone through a few people on our
team and every single one of those
people are like, "Yes, this is a hell
yes." Then there's [music] a final gut
check interview with me, which is the
final piece of the puzzle. So, I'm only
getting on hiring calls or interviews
with [music] folks that the rest of my
team have already been like, "Hell yes,
this is the right person on our team."
I'm no longer just fielding tons of
different requests, having to be the guy
that do all the pieces of the hiring.
I'm able to delegate a bunch of that and
just focus on giving people the final
check of approval if we think that
they're great. Now, another aspect here
to really optimize your hiring is the
555 rule. Here it all comes down to when
you're actually creating your job
descriptions for a given role in your
company, coming up with five values that
this person needs to embody in that
[music] role. You need to come up with
five KPIs this person needs to hit to be
successful in their role and then five
core systems that this person's going to
own as part [music] of that role. One of
the most popular roles that I see
founders ask me for help with is hiring
a chief of staff. you know that front
line of defense and that core project
manager on your team to make sure that
not all things are getting to you. And
so let's apply the 555 rule to the chief
of staff role. When you go and think
about the five values you have, they may
include things like extreme ownership,
attention to detail, having someone that
is obsessed with quality, that [music]
in my case wants to dazzle founders, and
that has an elevated taste for design.
After that, then you're going to go and
document the five competencies. [music]
For this role, I like to think of
someone with amazing communication
skills. You know, they need to have
amazing project management skills, and
be insanely organized, [music] have an
amazing ability to go and motivate a
team, and also have the ability to hire.
Now, we've got those five competencies
gone and charted out. So, let's move on
to then the five metrics for this role.
Every company is going to be different,
but some things that you could go and
consider are, you know, the overall NPS
score of the company, like how happy are
your customers? Number two is the cash
in bank, right? As a CEO, that's often
times one of the biggest metrics in your
job and the chief of staff can be there
to help you. Number three is maybe your
profit margin and helping you keep a
good eye on that and making
optimizations in the company to get your
margin up. Three, it's probably the
on-time execution of critical projects.
And five, maybe something like, you
know, being able to fill the key roles
that you're hiring for within the
company. I've gone and synthesized this
into a 555 rule playbook in the link in
the description. I took some of the core
roles in a personal media company and I
actually went and drafted them up for
you so you could go and see things like
the critical function, the core metrics,
and the core systems that you need to be
focusing on to get the right people in
the right seats in your company. This
system allowed me to go from 12 hours a
week spent on hiring to just 2 hours a
week, saving me over 10 hours [music]
every single week. So, you've saved a
bunch of time now in the hiring process,
but you've now got a bunch of people on
your team and you need to get better at
this next piece. Time trap number three
is your inability to delegate. Years
ago, I thought that CEO meant chief
everything officer. There I was late at
night in my office. My team was going
home at 4:30 p.m., but for some reason,
I was stuck in there till 11:00 p.m. And
it wasn't their fault. I just wasn't
actually getting things off my plate. I
[music] candidly had no idea how to
delegate. You may be wondering, "Well,
Matt, I've actually been struggling with
the same thing. How do I go and get
these things off my plate?" That's where
[music] the 3C system comes into place.
The first C stands for what is the
critical function that you're trying to
go and delegate? So, as an example, if
I'm looking to go and delegate a YouTube
video to a video editor, their critical
function is going to be to make sure
they go and create a 12minut 30-se
secondond video with a say a 7 minute
average watch time and a 6%
click-through rate as an example. The
next aspect then is choosing [music] a
core metric that determines success. So,
in this case, I may say, I want you to
make sure the average view duration of
this video is at least 7 minutes [music]
long. Inevitably, what that's going to
cause that person to do is they know,
I've gotten this task for Matt. The
critical metric is I need to make sure
it's retentive. I'm not just going to go
and make sure that the first 30 seconds
or minute are good. I need to go make
sure that every single sentence, every
second of this video counts. If I'm
going to actually hit the core metric
that Matt has delegated to me, [music]
the next aspect here then is the core
system. And when it comes to, you know,
our YouTube as an example, we have a
whole YouTube style guide that we use to
synthesize [music]
things like our motion graphic
guidelines, how we do title cards,
subtitles, and all the pieces that make
up the Matt Gray Founder OS brand in our
videos. The combination of having your
function, metric, and system gone and
created for every single thing you
delegate will ensure that you're making
it crystal clear to that stakeholder
that you're delegating to exactly what
success looks like. Now, when you
combine not just delegation, but also
automation and elimination into your
business, this is where you're able to
free up many times 10 20 hours a week.
In my case specifically, being able to
just nail down the 3C system saved me
over 12 hours a week. Suddenly, you
know, I had a team around me that was
embodying the values and the mission.
People were taking core tasks off my
plate so I could focus on the stuff that
only I can do. in my current business.
That's stuff like appearing in these
videos, working on highlevel strategy,
finalizing big hires, and working on
cool new offers that we have coming out.
But most things across content, revenue,
sales, customer success, finance,
operations, all those core areas,
they're all off my plate. This is one of
those things that you can go and look
at. And one of the best exercises to go
down is go and [music] look at every
single task you have on your plate and
start marking down which of those you
can delegate who on your team you can
delegate them to and then go and create
a Loom video of you actually going and
doing that task. Hopefully it also
documented in a Google doc and you're
able to pass the Google doc with the
critical function, the core metric and
the core system as well as the Loom
video of you actually doing the [music]
thing to a given stakeholder on your
team. They now have all that and it's up
to them now to be the systems owner of
that piece of the business. These three
C's when implemented correctly allowed
me to go and get a ton of stuff off my
plate, saving me over 12 hours a week.
[music] So now you know how to delegate.
But the last time trap is the one that I
see 99% of founders screwing up. It's
actually your biggest opportunity and
[music] you probably guessed it,
content. How the hell do you go and get
back more of your time on the content
side? It comes down to having the right
team in place and then having the right
guidelines for your content. Let's
rewind to Matt 12 years ago and I'm
creating content for my first business,
BitMaker. When I look to the left and
look to the right of me, there wasn't a
single other person on my team that I
had trained or even hired to help me
with content. I knew that, [music] you
know, these days if I was going to go
and build a personal media empire around
myself. I needed to have the right team
in place to do this cuz I'm not looking
to be the person in the weeds. I'm
looking to be the CEO of this personal
media company. You need what I think is
one of the most important roles of your
personal media company. It's the social
media manager. You may be wondering,
"Well, Matt, why a social media
manager?" The social media manager is
the person that's in charge of actually
taking all of that content pipeline
you're creating and making sure it's
distributed without mistakes at the
right time of the day with the right
captions, titles, and all the packaging
needed [music] to help it soar on social
media. And so your next question may be,
well, what exactly do they do? Well, let
me break it down for you. A social media
manager is going to be in charge of
things like your titles, [music] making
sure your thumbnails go live, making
sure that you're AB testing all of that
in things like YouTube Studio. They're
helping you schedule all your posts on
the given platforms. They're making sure
that all the captions on Instagram are
good. They're also going to be going
every single week and reporting to you
on what the top content is across every
single platform that you're on, the key
trends that they're noticing, and then
laying you up for the next 10 ideas that
[music] they think that you need to make
on each platform you're on. So Nick, my
social media manager, every single
Friday is sending me a detailed update
on every single thing that he's seen
that's working on the platforms and then
[music] giving us specific ideas for
what we should do next. This is a
massive timesa, not just to me, but for
my entire team as well. This has helped
me over the last 3 years go and save
over 12 hours on content alone because I
don't need to push any of my content.
I'm just most focused on taking the core
data that Nick goes and surfaces mixed
with my own creativity and then working
with my team to get that content
created. Finally, distributing my
content was no longer my job and I'm now
able just to focus on the stuff that
only I can do, getting me back 8 hours a
week. So finally after solving all four
of these time traps, I've been able to
go and get back 60 hours a week, going
from 80 to 20, being able to finally
have my time back to, you know, enjoy
more of my life, go and hike, play
paddle tennis, [music] do the things
that I just genuinely love to do and not
just be stuck in my business all the
time. I want you to go and implement
these four systems across the form time
traps in your life and I can't wait to
see what you do with all that time you
suddenly got. Thanks for watching and
I'll see you in the next