Imagine perfecting rice for 70 years.
Jurro did. And people pay $300 to taste
it. Jurro Ono has been making sushi in a
subway station for 70 years. And after
all those years of seeking out the best
ingredients and practicing every day of
the week, he tells people that he still
hasn't perfected rice. Now, people could
think this is crazy, but this is the
delusional belief in mastery that
creates iconic brands. Real mastery
comes from doing things for 20 years, 40
years. And for me, what I think about
with all of this is this idea of
everyday retirement, of focusing on
something that's really in your calling.
Often times in life, you know, the
success that you're looking for doesn't
come from becoming obsessed around the
metrics. It comes from being obsessed
around the practice.