Every founder eventually looks up and
realizes they've built a business that
owns them [music] instead of the other
way around. About 8 years ago, if I'd
looked at a breakdown of my week, I was
busy, [music]
genuinely busy, but on the wrong things.
The moment I finally sat down and asked,
"What are the things that will actually
move the needle?" everything changed and
I started to [music] restructure my
entire business. For me, those things
are building communities, growing
distribution through organic content,
designing [music] frameworks that
simplify how founders operate, and
writing. This is my zone of brilliance.
Everything [music] outside of that, it
needs to be delegated, automated, or
eliminated. And there's a Japanese
concept called ikigai that maps this out
[music] exactly. There's four core
questions. What do you love? What are
you genuinely exceptional [music] at?
What does the world need? And what can
you be paid for? The intersection of
those four areas is your ikigai, or as I
call it, your zone of brilliance. So,
here's what I want you to do right now.
Write down the things you do where you
lose track of time, even if it all the
daily fires. Then write down the
activities that genuinely move the
needle in your business. The overlap
between those two lists, that's where
your work should live. Anything outside
of that zone, delegate it, automate it,
or eliminate it. Protect that
intersection obsessively. [music]
I think that this exercise is the
highest returning asset you can build.