The default of building a business,
truthfully,
is that it sucks. Every business, right,
defaults to entropy, to chaos,
an absolute madhouse.
And I think every entrepreneur knows
this, right? Sometimes we don't just say
it out loud, right? But I'm saying it.
And I think
for me,
the kind of
reframing life is that,
you know, if you're trying to do
something big in life, it ain't going to
be easy.
And as you notice these things
that frustrate you,
I like to keep
a little frustrations
list in my phone.
And in this list,
I add all the right, that
ain't working, right? It could be a
meeting I no longer want to be in, a
project we shouldn't even be doing in
the first place,
a team member that shouldn't be on the
team anymore,
whatever it may be.
And then every month I like to audit
that frustrations list
and find ways to either automate things,
eliminate things,
delegate things, basically just simplify
things.
Cuz again, your business,
it's going to be hard by default unless
you consciously make an effort to make
things insanely simple.