This two-minute productivity hack will
save you 20 years of your life. The
reason why this works is because of
Newton's first law, the physics of
momentum. When you're stuck, it's
because you're at rest. You're trying to
overcome this inertia. And there's
actual neuroscience to back this. Your
brain treats starting as the hardest
part of the task. So, if you can just
get going, even as tiny or insignificant
as it may seem, tiny actions now lead to
big results over the long term. When you
feel stuck on anything, just ask
yourself, "What can I do for two minutes
to get this going?" Stuck going and
creating your first YouTube video? Just
sit down and turn the camera on. The
magic isn't in the 2 minutes. It's in
the pattern of breaking the
overthinking.