I don't know about you,
but
every 3 weeks
I do a reflection
that I call my personal board meeting.
And I'm pretty freaking embarrassed by
the person I was 3 weeks ago.
And I think that's actually a good
thing. Now, if you're someone with a
growth mindset, you're learning, you're
reading, you're building, you're trying
new things, you're hiring folks,
it's inevitable
you're going to make a ton of mistakes.
The 25-year-old version of Matt used to
get super down and look at all these
mistakes that I was making and just go,
"God damn it. Why can't I just figure
this [\h__\h] out?"
The 36-year-old version of Matt is
actually proud of the velocity at which
I'm making these errors
because
you know, with every little failure is
some new learning. And at the end of the
day, people that are experienced are
just folks that have made 20 times more
mistakes than you.
And so, I think
you should start embracing that
embarrassment, right? Making videos for
the first time, you're going to
embarrass yourself. Going and sharing
yourself online in writing, you're going
to embarrass yourself. Going and putting
out that business that you're not quite
sure of yet is going to embarrass
yourself. So, embrace the embarrassment
because on the other side of that is you
know, a new future that you're trying to
go and craft. So, just get out there.