Here's what nobody will say aloud. Most
personal brands who are posting
consistently, they [music] do the
following, get decent views, and are
still generating zero predictable
pipeline from it. You've been told to go
post more, be consistent, go viral,
build some audience, and your revenue
from content [music] just keeps staying
flat. That's not a content problem,
that's an architecture problem. In this
video, I'm going to show you the three
beliefs about content that are subtly
killing your pipeline, and then the
exact system my team uses to turn
content into a predictable sales
pipeline, and the one specific piece of
content that proves everything. Let's
get into it. Part one, the reframe.
There are three things founders believe
about content that sounds completely
reasonable and truthfully, all of them
are wrong. The first one is consistency
is the answer. Consistency is everywhere
in content advice, and it does matter at
a baseline level. But, here's the thing
that nobody's going to tell you.
Consistency without the architecture in
place is just showing up to a building
with no rooms. I was consistent for
months when I first got going building
my personal brand. Posting regularly,
showing up on platforms, I was putting
in the reps, and nothing was
compounding. The moment you think
consistency is the strategy, you've
already accepted that you're going to
keep working without compounding. And
that's a brutal deal that you got to
make with yourself here. So, let's get
to the next belief here. The second one
is virality is the goal. This one
[music] is insanely dangerous. Now, at
the end of the day, right, you got to
understand the dopamine hit is real. A
post blows up, the numbers go crazy, and
it feels like you did something
meaningful. [music]
But, virality just optimizes for reach,
it doesn't optimize for cash flow. And
the most dangerous outcome that you can
have is some viral post that actually
just starts attracting the wrong
audience. Suddenly, your DMs are full,
but no one's converting. And none of
these people will ever become clients of
the business that you're actually trying
to grow. Your team then spends time on
calls with a bunch of tire kickers, and
you realize that the goal of content is
not to reach everyone. The goal of
content is to resonate with the right
people. All right, the third one is
great content sells itself. Yes, right,
quality matters enormously. But, great
content without a system behind it is a
one-time event. And here's the brutal
reality that nobody talks about. When
you're small, random content is
survivable. You post something, it
occasionally works, you get a client or
two, and you're starting to get your
business off the ground. You got to know
that as your business grows, as you add
a team, right, a content manager, a
video editor, a social media operator,
and random content starts to become
really expensive at scale. You're now
running a content operation, and you
have no decision logic in place, and
>> [music]
>> it gets worse the bigger you get. Let me
show you what the architecture actually
looks like.
Every piece of content I publish starts
with one question. Who specifically is
this for, and what do I need them to
believe after watching it? That is the
starting [music] point for every single
thing that I make. Here's how I actually
go and then answer that question, okay?
Before I make any piece of content,
whether to YouTube video, a LinkedIn
post, an Instagram carousel, I go back
to the same document. It's what I call a
voice of customer research file that my
team has built over hundreds of
conversations with real founders that
have actually paid us to work with us.
So, what we're doing from real Fathom
transcripts is then extracting [music]
real quotes, word for word, the exact
language that these people are using to
describe their problem. You know, really
then being able to predict the solution
that they're looking for before they
even know it in their own minds. Things
like, you know, [music] I'm stuck
spinning on the content hamster wheel,
or I know I can take this to another
level, but I just need the right
systems. This is not copy that I've
invented, this is what founders actually
say to me and my team. Every piece of
content that I make is built from that
document outwards, okay? So, I'm taking
the exact psychological pain point, that
specific fear, and then what I'm doing
is reverse engineering that to the
content to meet e- every single founder
exactly where they are in their head.
Not where I think [music] they are,
right, the data says where they are, and
this is why certain pieces of content
feel like [music] I'm really reading
your mind. The content is
psychologically calibrated to the real
language of real buyers, so the right
founder feels immediately seen, and then
the wrong one feels, well, nothing at
all. Now, let me give you a quick gut
check right now. Three questions, answer
them honestly, not for me, but for you.
Can you look at your last 10 pieces of
content and tell me which ones generated
a qualified conversation? Do you know
which format and topic combination
produces the highest quality inbound for
your specific offer? And then when you
sit down to decide what to make next
week, is that decision driven by data
from your business
>> [music]
>> or just by some gut feel of what feels
right in the moment? If you're sitting
there thinking, I can't [music] answer
those, well, that's the gap, and the gap
is exactly what this system closes. This
is the actual calendar my team uses.
These are the metrics that determine
whether a piece of content gets made
again, not views, not shares, not
follower growth, and not engagement
rate. This is about capital allocation,
right? All right, so behind the scenes
here, I want to go and show you my
YouTube platform performance tracker,
because I want to show you [music]
literally how I go and judge the
performance of any given YouTube video.
So,
>> [music]
>> let me show you the kind of tale of two
videos here. Let's start with the
10-minute system that makes success
inevitable. When I look at this video,
right, it would appear to many to be an
absolute banger, over 400,000
views. This video is definitely insane,
right? Let's go and look at the actual
cash collected from this video. A solid
$258.
Well, you guessed it, right? That ain't
paying my team bills, that ain't helping
us much here at Founder OS. Let's go to
video B. [music] This is a video that
probably you guys have not even noticed
on my channel, okay? Copy this content
strategy, it will blow up your business.
Now, when we go and look at this piece
of content, a whopping 44K views, right?
You go and look at my channel, you're
like, oh, that video is pretty regular,
pretty basic. That that ain't some high
performer, I'm not going to even look at
that. But, here's the thing, that video
drove over [music] $29,000
to our business in just the first 30
days. I want to show you this because I
want to encourage you to move away from
vanity metrics. This is not content
planning anymore. Here's what changes
when this system is running correctly.
The output [music] is no longer just
views, we're not caring about followers
or subscribers, it's about qualified
leads, and we call this the content GPS.
Every piece of content is a coordinate,
and the system is what makes sure that
those coordinates are pointing the right
people every single time to your
business, okay? This system and 180 more
key systems that are all part of this
operating system are what the team and I
love to help established founders
install in their business to find the
next chapter of their scaling potential.
Inside of Founder OS Velocity, which is
something I've been creating for the
last five years, okay, we sit down with
you, right, in intimate rooms, right, we
help you go and map out your whole
content flow all the way from where
you're driving awareness to inquiry to
sales to onboarding and cash collection,
okay, and then help you optimize all
that. So, we work with founders who are
done guessing and ready to invest and
install the systems properly, okay? And
if that sounds like it could be relevant
to where you're at, well, you can go and
apply to Founder OS via the link in the
description. Now, let me go show you the
thing that made this all click for me,
okay? When this is working, your sales
calls change completely. People show up
already convinced. They're not asking,
"What do you do?" They're [music]
asking, "How do I get started?" That
shift is worth more than any funnel
you'll ever build. 90% of the content I
post leverages a lead magnet, okay? This
is a free piece of value, specific,
immediately useful, zero fluff, tied
directly to the biggest bottleneck of
the exact founder I'm trying to attract,
okay? The formula here is simple. One
solvable problem, one tangible resource,
one low-friction ask. That's the
diagnostic built into the lead magnet.
It's not just giving value, it's giving
value in a way that creates
self-awareness around a gap that the
founder didn't fully understand before.
Now,
>> [music]
>> there's one thing that I want to go and
show you. One decision I made inside
this system that made a single piece of
content generate more applications than
anything else I have ever published.
All right, you've heard of Moneyball,
right? Billy Beane, the Oakland A's,
it's 2002. It's a small market team with
a fraction of the budget of the New York
Yankees, and they figured out how to
compete. Not by finding better players,
but by identifying the most undervalued
variables that actually predicted wins.
The whole league was optimizing for
batting average and home runs. But,
Billy, good old Billy, was optimizing
for on-base percentage. One metric
preframe changed everything. Most
founders are doing the content version
of optimizing for batting average,
right? [music] Views, followers, and
engagement rate. They got a tunnel
vision on vanity metrics, and they
wonder why they're getting nowhere with
their content. I started optimizing for
metrics that almost everyone buries
under views, likes, and comments.
Applications and cold, hard cash
collected. Attracting real founders,
real businesses, reaching out because
something I made resonated so
specifically, all right, to exactly
what's going on in their business that
they had to respond, and they had to
join Founder OS. Here's how to moneyball
your content strategy. Stop optimizing
for views, start optimizing for
qualified conversations. All right, so
you're going to study which format,
which topic, which identity you spoke to
in your highest converting pieces, and
then build more of that, and then
deprioritize the rest. Content stops
being a creative exercise the moment you
start measuring it like a business unit.
The shift from creative output to
capital allocation is the thing that
separates founders who generate
predictable revenue from content from
founders who are just out there guessing
and creating viral BS. The founders I
see generating truly predictable revenue
from content, they're not just using
these individual elements. They have
architecture that's then connecting all
of it. Every qualified conversation
informs that next piece of content and
every application strengthens the
positioning. That flywheel only spins
when all parts are connected, okay? And
the version that works for my brand and
my business now isn't something I could
have built alone. It required testing
against real revenue data, iterating
with founders who were further along at
the time than I was, getting honest
feedback when I was wrong. And that's
the thing about building in isolation as
a founder, okay? You don't know what you
don't know. If this video resonated,
don't just nod and move on. Step one is
simple. Go and download the content GPS
alignment audit below and complete it
honestly. It will show you whether your
content is built for visibility or just
[music] revenue. Step two, if you're
already doing real revenue and serious
about fixing it, bring that completed
audit into a content architecture audit
call with my team. We'll review it with
you. We'll show you where the
architecture in your business is broken
and then help you with the system to go
and fix it, okay? The founders building
real leverage right now aren't creating
more content. They're building better
systems. I'll see you in the next video,
which is all around how you build
systems to go and win this year. And
let's win together.