Now, I'll be real with you, right? I
think that every business as it grows,
right? You end up scaling up, you end up
kind of going through these stages of
expansion, building out new product
lines, right? And oftentimes you're
going and adding new team members. And
then before you know it, there's like a
few stragglers. I know I'm speaking with
like my COO Dawn and Diego on my team,
and you know, you can kind of tell on
the team the kind of people that are
like one of us, right? The kind of
people that care a lot, right? They go
above and beyond, they have an all-in
mentality. Um they obsess over quality,
they really um want to pursue like
elevated design and are product
obsessed. And then, you know, every
time, you know, you're maybe building a
company of like 16, 17 people,
oftentimes here and there like one or
two folks come along, and you're like,
"Oh man, not the best of hires, right?
Not someone that's actually in the
game." What I'm passionate about on that
side is overall like having a lean team
of like say 12 or so folks, and then
having an autonomous engine that's built
across the company, so that by default,
right? We're automating roles versus
hiring new people. More than ever,
right? It's, you know, kind of viewing
hiring as a failure and finding areas
that you can just automate these
aspects. Having an automated organic
content funnel, having automated emails
around your business, having automated
follow-ups after sales calls, having
automated ways of grading your sales
team to make sure that folks are staying
on track, and if they're not, being able
to remove them and having automated
hiring funnels to bring on new folks.
You know, having automated ways of going
and discovering the best kind of content
that you should make. Having automated
ways of tracking your financials,
tracking the growth across the business,
getting dashboards served up to you so
that you can, you know, really go and
double down on the patterns across, you
know, finance, ops, content, marketing
that are going to keep pushing you
forward and doing less of the stuff
that's not working. You know, versus
trying to scramble in your business and
really just kind of burn out. It's this
kind of artist plus autonomous engine
that I think's the winner. I have
ambitious goals of, you know, building
this founder infrastructure layer, being
able to give that whole side of our
business that is automated to founders
and to help them grow their own
autonomous engines because I think this
is the future. This is what I most focus
on helping founders with these days. Um
I think that, you know, if this is
something that's interesting to you,
this is exactly what we help people with
in Founderwise, giving you that founder
infrastructure layer so that you can be
an artist with a beautiful autonomous
engine. And so if that's interesting to
you, you want us to go and build your
social media machine, your engine to go
and drive your content through to leads,
you should go and check out Founderwise
via the link in the description. We'd
love just to book a call, see if we can
help you.