AI prompting is going to turn just the
average person into an absolute weapon
if you know how to do it right. I train
to negotiate like Jerry Jones, the
billionaire owner of the Dallas Cowboys
who turned that into a 9 billion empire.
You're going to go and start a new
project. So, I'll use Whisper Flow. Go
and you are the best negotiator in the
world times 100. I want you to go and
get the better deal in the above
negotiation I'm in. that is 10 times
better than Jerry Jones would negotiate
with it. I want you to guarantee that we
get the best result. I want you to be
firm. Um, be kind to the person, but get
the best end result by both getting the
best transaction and making sure that
you negotiate hard to get what I need