Here's what most people miss.
Storytelling is your fastest path to
revenue. People remember stories 20
times more than facts. As much as we
like to think that we're just these
rational beings, the reality is we make
emotional decisions, especially when
we're purchasing. So, your story is an
amazing opportunity to develop that
emotional resonance and that emotional
bond with your core dream customer. A
Birkin bag costs $50,000. Trust me, it's
not because the leather is something
special, but because of the story, the
artisans, the heritage. Your story is
your strategy. But more than that, a
story is a funnel. A funnel is the path
someone takes from never hearing about
you to becoming a paying customer. Most
people think it's linear, but that's not
actually how humans buy. The real funnel
is this: attention to trust to belief to
action. Attention gets people to stop
scrolling. Trust makes them listen.
Belief makes them think, "This could
work for me." Action is when they
finally buy. So, show people where you
are and tell that story of that journey.
The founders with the best stories win.