I think you're forgetting what you asked
for in the first place.
Now, I had to go and say this to a
founder
just a few days ago that I'd built his
business just crossed $200,000 a month.
From
every dream he ever had, he had
accomplished it. And then some, right?
This was far
past any financial goals he had had for
his business.
That said, on the freedom side of things
he had completely forgotten that piece
of the equation.
You know, most founders don't get into
business to get lost in Slack. We don't
build a business so we can just be
dealing with fires all day. We build it
for freedom. Right? Freedom to control
the four W's in life. Work where you
want, on what you want, with who you
want, wherever you want.
But it's so often some way, somewhere
along the way, we lose track of it all.
And
you find yourself maybe just pushing for
bigger numbers while your freedom just
continually gets depleted.
And so
it's important to come back to your
roots, right? Why did you create
this business, this brand, this movement
in the first place? Don't forget that
essence. Right? Because it's so easy to
get caught up in the busyness that you
forget why you why you even built that
business in the first place.