When Steve Jobs returned to Apple in
1997, the company was 90 days away from
bankruptcy. Steve stood in front of a
massive crowd, his black turtleneck, his
insane stage presence, and charted out a
new direction for Apple. It would go on
to not only revolutionize that company,
but revolutionize humanity and how we
would use tools for the next 20 plus
years. Steve uses five core elements
throughout his career to sell anything
to anyone. And in this video, I'm going
to break down those blueprints,
frameworks, and key aspects so you can
go and apply it in your business today.
These are the same strategies I
personally use to build businesses that
became profitable for me while staying
true to the lifestyle I wanted. These
strategies are powerful as hell, and in
this video, I'm going to unlock them for
you. All right, let's get into Steve's
secret number one.
valuebased selling. To me, marketing is
about values. This is a very complicated
world. It's a very noisy world. We're
not going to get a chance to get people
to remember much about us. You know,
people don't care about what you have to
sell. They care about what you can do
for them. What's the biggest question
you think in most people's minds when
they're listening to your sales
presentation? They're wondering why
should I even care? When it comes to
your values, you need to get clear on
what is it that you really believe in at
your core. For me at Founder OS, as an
example, some of our core values include
things like elevated design where we're
always crafting experiences that blow
founders minds. We really believe in
dazzling founders going above and beyond
to cultivate an experience that's based
on unreasonable standards to make sure
that every single step along the
founders's journey is clear. It's
systemized and we're helping level them
up. Similarly, you know, we have the
value of really going and creating
exceptional experiences and communities.
You know, we are aiming to create the
greatest founder community of the 21st
century. And Steve was really big on
this and his, you know, think different
campaign and, you know, ads like the
crazy ones. It was all about showing
people not just the benefits of a
product, not the features, but what is
the values of this brand? And if the
heart and the soul of the brand can
deeply connect with the core identity of
the person you're trying to go and
attract to it, it magnetizes people. And
it's not just about, you know, your
mission, your values, your vision, but
it's much more about the soul of the
brand and what it's all about. So, what
are your values? What are five core
values that your brand stands for that
when you're selling people, you can
connect deeply with those values first?
Because there's a big opportunity that
most entrepreneurs miss. they miss the
opportunity to talk about, you know,
what they really believe in. You know, I
know that when I am selling someone,
often times the thing that stands out
most is that people can tell that I
deeply care. And this is something that
I learned from Steve Jobs. You know,
there's a famous clip of Steve. You can
probably check it out right here. What's
it like to get rich?
>> It's very interesting. I was worth about
over a million dollars when I was 23 and
over $10 million when I was 24 and over
$und00 million when I was 25. It's it
wasn't that important uh because I never
did it for the money. It was about
making an impact for humanity. Now,
Steve never cared about being the
richest guy in the graveyard. It was
about creating something that stand for
beauty, for simplicity, for
sophistication, and could generally make
an impact in millions of people's lives.
You know, I think Steve is super
underrated actually. You know, there's
all this talk these days about
entrepreneurs like Elon Musk or Jeff
Bezos, but meanwhile, I think that Steve
is basically still the one majorly
responsible for the market cap of Apple,
which is now over a trillion dollars.
They're still benefiting from Steve's
innovations 20 plus years ago, like the
iPhone and iPad. And to think that
someone who's now passed for over 20
years is still having that big of an
impact 20 years later helping build a
trillion dollar plus market cap company
when he didn't even care about the money
is insane. Imagine the impact you could
have not just on your bank account, but
on the movement you're creating if you
focused on developing your beliefs, your
values, and also a key point of view.
Because what happens when you go and you
market and you sell like this is you
create resonance. People can deeply
resonate with what you're saying. And
it's not just about the words. It's that
they can connect with what you care
about. And in a world filled with AI and
everyone just being like everyone and a
world of sameness, you can stand out
amidst that noise by really caring about
your values. For me, it's things like
obsessing over quality. You know, it's
things like elevated design. It's being
insanely simple with everything we do
with Founder OS and helping founders
build these systemized empires. And the
more we show we care, the more that we
put these values out to the world, the
more that people with similar values are
attracted to us. Now, it's all good to
have, you know, all your valuebased
selling and all your values nailed down,
but it's nothing if you don't have this
next secret nailed. And the next secret
is Steve's secret number two. Insanely
simple. Simplicity is the ultimate form
of sophistication. This is a quote from
Leonardo da Vinci. I know it's something
that had a massive impact on Steve's
approach to products. You know, from
Steve's study of things like, you know,
Zen, you know, he came to learn that
keeping experiences as simple as
possible was what was going to help
Apple stand out long term. Now you can
see this when Steve was developing the
iPhone. At one point you know it had you
know one button on the screen and at
that point Joanie IV and the team at
design there thought that they had done
it. They had created a phone so simple
it was ready to go. But Steve encouraged
them to even remove that button so that
the screen was buttonless. And at the
time this was insane. This is a time
where Blackberry existed. You had your
Razer Motorola phones with buttons on
it. Shout out, you know, Razer, such a
great phone. And Steve was like, "Yo, no
buttons." And this is just one of many
examples of Steve getting down to
simplicity. And it wasn't just in his
thinking towards products. It was in his
approach to selling as well. Now, you
can see this in the ads like think
different, right? where it's just two
words but inspired a generation or in
ads like the crazy ones where the simple
concept of just showing people over
history that had reinvented their given
areas and were crazy enough to change
the world and then associating these
people with Apple the same way that you
know Nike used athletes to inspire
people to just do it. It was a simple
concept and delivered magnificently.
When you're going and selling people,
you got to keep it insanely simple. If
you go and you're talking about all
these benefits, all these different
features, you end up just confusing
people. And when people get confused,
they close their wallets. But when you
give people clarity, you help them
understand exactly how you can help
them. And as much as we like to think of
humans being rational when it comes to
purchases, most purchases are actually
just deeply emotional. And so when
you're simple, you can tap into the core
emotions that people have and inspire
them to take massive action. And so, how
do you go and apply insane simplicity to
how you sell? That's where the next
secret comes in. Steve's secret number
three is the rule of three.
>> Today, I want to tell you three stories
from my life. And the first thing is
it's dramatically faster. Two, thinner.
Three, it's lighter as well.
>> So you want to go and sell someone. And
when you think about your product, you
can think of 20 ways and 20 reasons that
people should go and buy it. So what do
you do? Do you go and create a sales
pitch that intricately weaves all the 20
benefits of what you do and packs your
sales script or packs an ad or packs
your content with as much of those
benefits as possible? Well, no. That's
probably exactly what Steve would advise
you not to do. You know, even when he
was going as an example and selling the
benefits of the iPhone, he distilled it
down to three things. Three things. A
widescreen iPod with touch controls, a
revolutionary mobile phone, and a
breakthrough internet communications
device, right? Three things. Keeping it
simple, and using the rule of three. We
live in an age where people have so many
different ways they can go in any given
moment. And you can't go and get people
to remember everything about what you
do. You can help them remember what you
care about. you can instill some sort of
feeling in them and drive an emotion and
then you got to keep it simple in terms
of the rule of three as to what the core
aspects of what you do are. You know, at
Founder OS, you know, my mission is to
inspire 100 million founders to
accomplish their dreams with proven
systems. And when I think about the big
promise of what we're looking to do, we
are here put on earth to dazzle founders
with amazing community, extraordinary
support, and simple systems. Everything
that we do at Founder comes down to
these three pieces. And so when you go
and you're thinking about your product,
what are the three core aspects of your
product that people need to know, they
need to remember, and they should deeply
care about? When you go and you've gone
and synthesized those three core
benefits and you've stacked that along
with keeping it insanely simple and then
stacking that with your values and why
these matter and why you care about them
so much, you're now beginning to sell
like Steve. And so you've got that all
stacked up now. And you know, you think
you're really actually hitting the
ground running here. Things are moving.
But you're missing one core secret that
I've learned is Steve's probably most
powerful weapon. Steve's secret number
four. Energy matters. Steve was
notorious when he was going and
unveiling any of his products for
rehearsing those presentations hundreds
of times. You know, I didn't sleep a
wink last night. They actually began
with just pen and paper sketching out
not just what the benefits of the thing
were, but what's the story? Why should
people care? And he was deeply involved
with every detail of the presentation,
of the product development, and
everything in between. Your founder
energy matters. There's this big concept
that people have been talking about
recently, but I think has existed for
hundreds of years, which is founder
mode. You know, founder energy.
Inevitably, when you're building a
company, no one's going to care as much
as you. And that's just the hard truth
of it all. And so you've got to infuse
your product, your brand, your team with
your energy. When I've gone and surveyed
people and asked them, "Okay, what
caused you to go and convert to Founder
OS?" 63% of people that I've gone and
surveyed have told me that Matt, it was
you. It was your energy, your vibe. It
helped build trust. I knew that you
cared. I could sense it through the
video I watched or the ex thread that I
had read from you or the LinkedIn post
or the Instagram reel. It's your energy,
Matt. And I'm here to tell you that it
was the same for Steve. You know, John
Scully took over after he booted Steve
out of Apple. And this was some seasoned
executive came from Pepsi. Everyone
thought it was time to bring in a
professional CEO. But Scully didn't
last. Why? because he didn't have that
founder energy. This was some suit, some
corporate dude that didn't understand
the soul, the values, the intricacies of
Apple that made it a shining star. He
brought other company modalities, other
ways of doing things and slowly eroded
the company and nearly drove it to
bankruptcy. Over a three-month period,
Apple's profits plunged by more than $50
million.
>> Now, Steve's energy, I would distill it
down to he cared a ton. He was a
visionary. He thought in centuries, not
decades, and not years. And he viewed
building a product as a work of art, a
work of service. It was something that
he poured every morsel of his being into
to build something that when people
opened up that box, they unpackaged that
Apple product. They felt something. They
felt the love. They felt the care. And
that was something that mattered. You
know, I love this talk that Steve did at
Stanford and he's asking people, you
know, where where's everyone working
here from? And he asks, "How many of you
are from manufacturing companies?" Oh,
excellent. Where where are the rest of
you from?
And then he asks, "How many people here,
you know, what is everyone else doing
here?" And it appears that there's a
bunch of consultants. How many from
consulting? Oh, that's bad.
Yeah. My mind is too important to waste.
>> You can tell from Steve's reaction, he's
not big on consultants. And why is that?
Because when he's thinking about
consultants, he's thinking about people
that just give suggestions but don't
stick with a product all the way through
the life cycle of it from ideiation to
shipping feedback and then iterating.
And he was big on people pouring their
energy into every piece of that product
development process. The ideation, the
creation, the refinement, the
distribution, the marketing, the copy.
You know, your product has a ton of
details that will make it successful.
And the best sales strategy is nailing
the product. And the product, it comes
down to the details. You know, every
pixel matters. Steve was notorious for,
you know, not just worrying about what
the iMac looked like, but actually it
mattering what the inside of an iMac
looked like as well. And his team was
bewildered. Why the hell would you even
care about this? No one's going to see
it. But that's not what it's about,
right? People can feel the
craftsmanship, the love, the care, and
the inside of the iMac did matter to
Steve. And it's that level of giving a
that separates Steve from 99.99%
of founders out there. And it's this
level of detail, this level of care,
this energy that when you bring that to
your company, it's the difference
between you being another fish in the
sea in your industry or redefining a
category. And if you're watching this,
you're here to do the ladder. And so
there's a few questions to ask yourself.
What energy am I trying to bring daily
to my team, to my product? What is the
energy that I will not tolerate in my
company? And I think this is an
important one, that last one, because
there's a lot of stories of Steve being
an and really hard to work with,
but I think that's a load of The
reality is is that Steve was well aware
that in life you get what you tolerate
and Steve was the last person on earth
to go and tolerate mediocrity. So
somebody's got to say here's what we can
do and we can make it happen and here's
the level of thing we can ship in 16
months. And what I hear him saying is
well anything more than a port of Mac
author forget it. And boy that just
makes me smoke. And so when he thought
about going and building a brand and
building something that was timeless and
iconic, he could only tolerate
extraordinary. And so anything below
that, he had to be ruthless about those
extraordinary standards.
>> Well, George, I can't change the world.
You know what? What do you want me to
do? What's the solution?
>> You see what we can learn is
>> what I want is probably irrelevant. I
mean, there are certain realities here.
And while for some that may have come
across as difficult, ignorant, an
to Steve it was about standing
for something, it was about building
something that mattered. It was about
creating something that would stand the
test of time. And he did just that. Now,
all of this is awesome. But Steve's
secret number five, I think, is the one
that when you implement this today, you
will surely transform your brand and
your business. Steve's secret number
five, build a founder-led brand. Now,
when people think about Tesla, they see
Elon Musk. When people think about
Virgin, they see Richard Branson. And
when people think Apple, they think
Steve Jobs. There's a reason for this.
People follow people, then they follow
brands. When you go and you open up your
phone and you go and you look at who you
follow on Instagram, take a look. How
many brands do you follow versus people?
probably a lot more people. Go and open
up your LinkedIn. Go and look at who you
follow there. Is it more companies or
people? Go and look at your YouTube and
who you subscribe to there. Do you
subscribe to more companies or people?
I'm sure the answer to all three of
those questions was Matt. Of course,
people. Exactly. You follow people and
then you follow the brands. And Steve
knew this ages ago. There was a reason
that when Steve left, Apple fell apart.
And while Apple was falling apart, Steve
invented Pixar and revolutionized
animation and animation technology.
Right? It was him and his brand, his
energy that people gravitated towards.
And Steve understood the importance of
putting himself out there. You know, it
was Steve that delivered the
presentations. It was Steve that was
intricate to each of the marketing
campaigns. It was Steve that helped
invent the Think Different campaign and
Crazy Ones in 1984. It was Steve. When
you're building your brand, are you
putting yourself out there? Are you
letting people know what you stand for?
Are you crafting the words, the copy,
the designs? Are you paying attention to
the details? Are you creating content
around your brand? Are you sharing what
you believe in? Because the key
ingredient to building what Steve built,
it was Steve and it was the content that
he created. Whether that was through the
Apple keynote presentations or that was
through the ads he was intricately
involved in or the speeches of which
have millions and millions if not
billions of views by now. Steve putting
himself out there was a massive
component along the way. You know, I
think one thing that I really admire
about Steve was, you know, his choice of
words. You know, even the way they
branded things at Apple, right? It was
all so intentional. iPad, iPhone, iMac.
Even just the nomenclature of naming all
their products like that shows a level
of intention. And when you're going and
building your brand as a founder, are
you being intentional about the words
you use, how you name your things? I
like to call this your content
intellectual property. It's how you
speak about your product. At Founder OS,
you know, we have YouTube OS, LinkedIn
OS, audience growth OS. You know,
there's also terms we have like your
content GPS or your personal media
company. And all of these describe the
core systems that are needed to create
an amazing, memorable founder-led brand.
By doing this, we've attracted a
community of over 2,000 founders to
Founder OS. A community of people that
believe that we are stronger together,
that together we can go and create a
better future and build movements around
what we're doing because as founders,
you know, we have the power to go and
create movements unlike a lot of other
people out there because again, my
belief is that the future belongs to the
builders, the creators, the dreamers.
and I'm passionate about arming the
future of founders. Now, if you're
looking to go and market like Steve, I
created something special for you. We've
gone and created a reality distortion
field playbook, which are 12 secrets for
how Steve sold anything. And you can go
and get it via the link in the
description. Thanks so much. Welcome to
the founder freedom movement and let's
win