I think it's this combination of being
an artist with an autonomous engine
around us. By artist, I mean someone
that every day gets paid to do the kind
of you love. I think that's when
you're like really leaning into your own
creativity. My belief in any business,
right, is that, you know, there's a lot
of things that have limits. Your cash
flow is maybe limited initially, your
resources maybe limited, your people are
limited. One thing that's limitless,
though, is your creativity. You know, at
any given moment, you could make a
YouTube video that's so creative it
blows up and change the trajectory of
your business. At any given moment, you
could make a newsletter that's so
powerful that it completely transforms
the trajectory of your business. At any
given moment, you could architect a
funnel, right, that's so good that it
changes the trajectory of your business.
And so, that all comes down to you
leaning into that core artistry. When I
think about building organic content
funnels around my business, going from
social to our founderwest.com/apply
page, to the video there, to then the
emails that people get, the flows they
get in, all of that to me is like a work
of art. And when I'm able to pull and
push my artistry kind of into those
projects, that's when I've gotten the
greatest returns in life. Now, that's
the artist side of it. But, the other
side is this autonomous engine.
Something I'm passionate about, right,
is really going and running a lean team,
a highly cash flowing business that's
generating over 50% plus margins, making
sure that my business is strictly A
players, and really having it be this
like lean, mean machine.