This is my new AI employee. It's called
Loom AI, and it's already saved me
thousands of hours of creating
documentation by instantly turning
[music] my core ideas into systems. Let
me show you exactly how I use it. I went
and recorded a video going through a
system by which my team can start taking
case studies and testimonials and using
those for different pieces of content
that we create. The cool thing is as I'm
describing it, I'm getting into the
different details. I'm sharing my
screen. I'm going through the different
places that they can find the
testimonials and how we should go store
these into Google Drive. But this is
where the magic comes [music] in. I can
simply go to generate and go to SOP.
What it's going to go and do is create a
standard operating procedure for this
specific task. Now, I can go and copy
this whole thing and then go and make a
beautiful Google Doc system based on
this linking to the Loom, big images,
bullet points, [music] super easy for
people to digest. This is actually 10
times better than me making a system.
>> [music]