the easiest way to create viral content
is to study other people's viral content
Steve Jobs quoted Picasso during one of
his speeches Picasso had a saying good
artist coffee great artist steel do this
follow at least 10 people whose content
you want to emulate then when you would
normally waste time scrolling social
media instead study their content and
save their posts that have great hooks
look for Trends and study what works
when you're creating your own content
reference your favorite creators to find
inspiration as a good friend of mine
once told me everything is iterative if
it worked for them it'll work for you