Most businesses fail not because the
idea was bad, but because the founder
built a trap. Over the last four years,
I bootstrapped a portfolio of businesses
doing over $15 million a year combined.
No co-founders, and I get to take a full
month off every single year. None of
that was luck. It came from a framework
I built before I ever launched. Today,
I'm going to walk you through six
decisions that make the same thing
possible for you. Miss one, and the
whole thing falls apart. And to make
this video 99% more useful, I've
included a free founder dependency test,
link below, so you can go and use this
once you finish the video to understand
your results. Let's get into it.
Decision number one, play the right
game. The very first decision you make
as a founder will determine whether the
next 5 to 10 years of your life feel
like freedom or a prison sentence.
Here's what nobody tells you. 90% of
founders who fail were actually doomed
the second they chose their business
model. They never had a chance. I know
because, well, I was one of them. My
first business was a brick-and-mortar
technology school in Toronto.
Co-founders, harsh winters, and me
babysitting a team that I honestly
didn't want anything to do with. Every
single morning, I woke up dreading it.
Not because I was lazy, not because I
didn't care, but because everything
about the business was built around
things that I genuinely hated. I hate
managing people I didn't choose. I hate
being locked into a single location. I
hate the weight of fixed costs when
revenue isn't flowing right. And I built
an entire business on top of all of
that. I exited, but not before wasting
years being miserable from day one. And
let me tell you, you don't get those
years back. That's the part nobody talks
about in the startup highlight reel,
right? Years that you waste making
mistakes when, really, if you had just
taken a step back, you could have
avoided things that, really, you knew in
the heart of hearts that weren't just
right for you. You know, when I was
building BitMaker, you know, I had
co-founders, and I'd later learn that I
want nothing to do with co-founders. You
know, I was running a business in one
location, and I'd come to learn that,
you know what? I want to be
location-independent. Be able to work
from anywhere, whenever I want, with
whoever I want, on the things that I
love to do. And I'd learn too that the
business itself that I want to build, I
want to build it around stuff that I
genuinely love. You know, work shouldn't
feel like work. It should feel fun. It
should feel like play. And I want to
make sure that the stuff that I'm
focused on every day is stuff that I
would do even if I was retired. That
experience taught me something I now
called hard mode versus easy mode
businesses. Hard mode is building an app
from scratch, launching deep tech,
opening a physical location, running
complex e-commerce with real logistics.
I'm not saying never go that route, but
some incredible businesses were built on
hard mode, right? I get it. But knowing
what you're signing up for, right? Heavy
capital, early hires, months of starting
at zero revenue while you figure it out.
It's like your first day on skis, and
you drop straight down a double black
diamond. Most people don't make it down
that hill. Easy mode on the other side
are things like digital products,
courses, communities, newsletters,
consulting. You know, no massive upfront
capital, no raising money, no 6-month
runway of silence, wandering, and
wondering if the thing's ever going to
work. If you're starting out, default to
easy mode businesses. Give yourself a
real shot. You see, hard mode
businesses, they can work, right? But
the thing is, I see so many founders
that are looking to get going with
something that will give them peace and
calm and enjoyability.
And essentially, they end up picking
some really hard business when they have
all this expertise, this knowledge, and
they could have just built something a
lot easier that would allow them to get
cash flowing. So, here's the thing. Easy
mode alone isn't enough. You need a
filter. Here are mine. One, the business
has to feel like play. If it feels heavy
from day one, it's a hard no. I need to
love the problem and I need to love the
customer. Obsession beats opportunity
every single time. Two, I want
distribution product fit, meaning I can
grow it through organic content, not
burn cash on ads just to stay alive.
Three, I need a clear path to
profitability within 90 days, not 6
months, not eventually, 3 months,
because I want to be able to build this
thing and get it going, get it into the
market, and start cash flowing it. I
don't want to be waiting 9 months, 2
years to try and see if I can ever get a
customer. That's just not how my brain
works, and I know it's not going to be
an enjoyable journey if it looks like
that. And here's the test that I use. 15
paying customers is product market fit.
15, right? Not 100. So, if you can get a
product to 15 core customers, you have
product market fit, and you've done it,
right? You've built something now that
can likely scale to 100, 200, 2,000
customers. If you've been grinding for 6
months and still don't have 15 people
willing to pay, I don't think that's a
marketing problem, right? It's the wrong
business. Before you build anything,
right? Go and write down your criteria.
Define your non-negotiables up front, so
you're not negotiating with yourself
later on. And if something doesn't fit,
walk away no matter how good the numbers
look on paper. Decision number two, kill
the co-founder fantasy. Now you're ready
to build, but this is exactly the moment
where most founders make a decision that
guarantees they'll burn out. More
businesses are destroyed by this one
decision than bad ideas, bad timing, and
bad luck combined. And the startup world
won't stop telling you to make it. I got
into two businesses early on with
co-founders, and I hated it both times.
And I know, this is a little bit of a
controversial opinion because most
people will tell you otherwise, but I'm
just giving you my own experience here.
You see, the first one, it felt great on
day one, right? Shared enthusiasm,
someone to bounce ideas off of, we were
going to take over the world. Within 6
months, we were fighting over every
decision. Nothing moved without a 2-hour
argument. Everything I wanted to do had
to clear someone else's filter. If
you're anything like me, that gets
really frustrating really fast. I
eventually realized I wasn't building a
business, I was just managing this
co-founder relationship. MJ DeMarco
talks about this in the book The
Millionaire Fastlane. He wrote an entire
book about accelerating your path to
wealth, designing control, leverage, and
scale. Do you know how often he talks
about having a co-founder? Almost never.
You know, what most founders don't think
through is the 5-to-10-year reality. You
bring on a co-founder, and day one it
feels great. But 5 years in, that same
co-founder becomes a leash around your
neck. And now you're not just losing a
partner, you're going through a custody
crisis over years of hard work. Just
like you wouldn't marry someone who you
met at a bar 5 minutes ago, you also
wouldn't entrust years of building a
future to just anyone. So, here's what
I'd tell you. You don't need a
co-founder. You need a clear goal and
the discipline to achieve it. If you're
starting out and aiming for a few
million in revenue, a couple million a
year in profit, just keep it simple and
keep control. Build something you can
steer without fighting over the wheel
with someone. Because without you,
there's no business to build. Decision
number three, the peace, profit, purpose
trifecta. The third decision is what
you're actually optimizing for. And this
is where most ambitious founders
unknowingly sabotage themselves, even if
they got the model right and made
decision two right. They're still
optimizing for the wrong thing. I once
worked on a business I knew could make a
lot of money, okay? Objectively, the
numbers were there. This was easily
going to be a $200 million business. And
I was tolerating a life that was slowly
destroying me. I was using different
substances, I drank, and I told myself
it was just the cost of building
something. But, that's what real
entrepreneurs do, right? That's kind of
how it looks. Well, that went on for
years. I've learned that staying in the
wrong business doesn't just drain you
financially, it changes you on like a
soul level. It drains you. It slowly
kills you. The habits you pick up, the
standards you start lowering and
tolerating, the way you begin justifying
things you once swore you'd never
tolerate. What starts as a revenue
problem becomes this deeper identity
problem. You stop recognizing yourself
in the mirror. And here's the hard
truth. Most founders who think they'll
sell in 3 years end up running their
business for 7. So, the real question
isn't can I make money with this? The
real question is, can I keep doing this
for 7 years without losing my mind? So,
do you enjoy your week? Do you love the
problem? Do you love who you're serving?
Those questions matter more than your
revenue projections. That's why I think
about business as a trifecta. Peace,
profit, and purpose. Making money isn't
that hard. Building something that gives
you peace where you can control your
time, where you actually enjoy your week
and don't need to escape your own life,
that to me,
that is real wealth. The business you
love, even if it takes 3 years to hit
its stride, will outperform the one you
hate and spiked in year one. Because the
spike is usually just fueled by ego,
pressure, and an unsustainable grind. It
looks great early, right? But then, a
few years later, it just completely
burns out and fizzles away. But peace
and freedom and calmness, they compound.
And that's the wealth that I want,
right? Because that's a wealth that
lasts. So, before you go and just start
building something, right? Run every
decision through that trifecta.
Peace,
profit, and purpose. If any one of those
three legs is missing, well, the whole
thing's just going to fall over
eventually. Decision number four, build
your distribution engine. Once you've
locked in the right business, the fourth
decision separates founders who grow
from founders who stall out completely.
And here's something that's going to
sound counterintuitive, okay? But work
with me here. First-time founders are
obsessed with their product, and that's
exactly why they fail. Today I talk
about organic content all the time,
right? You guys see me on YouTube, X,
LinkedIn, Instagram. You got my
newsletters, you know, you've seen my
personal brand, and you know that I
think that building a personal brand is
the most valuable asset you can build
over the next decade. Okay, don't get me
wrong, those things are all powerful.
YouTube is driving 60% of my leads right
now and they're the highest quality ones
I get. That shouldn't overshadow the
reality that sometimes you need to get
your hands dirty in hand-to-hand combat
first, okay? Too many people want to
skip that part, right? They want all
these scalable strategies, but often
times when you get going, you got to do
the stuff that's not scalable. You got
to be willing to do the things that
other people are unwilling to do. How I
see it is that your personal branding
content are kind of one piston of a
two-piston engine to driving demand.
That's your inbound engine. On the other
side, a little bit of elbow grease and
hand-to-hand combat, reaching out to
people early on is that other piece of
the equation, your outbound engine to
help get that initial traction going and
to get you to those first 15 customers.
If you're not willing to do what others
won't, well, you're probably not going
to get the outcomes that others don't.
So, here's my simple playbook if you're
starting from zero right now. Two
channels, YouTube and a newsletter.
That's it. For the next 3 months, just
start with those, okay? You want to
focus on doing less, but better. So,
you're going to grab a simple camera, it
could even be your iPhone. I'm talking
you can just even get a $20 lavalier mic
off Amazon. Hire an editor for a few
hundred bucks a video and put something
out, you know, once a week. If you
genuinely hate picking up a camera, no
worries, right? Pick another platform
that's maybe more writing based, like
LinkedIn, X, Substack, you name it.
Don't overcomplicate it. The goal is
simple here, right? Make your business
findable, then make it magnetic.
Decision number five, McDonaldize your
business. Everything I've laid out so
far can get you started and get you
growing, but there's a fifth wall that
nearly every founder hits and most don't
see it coming until they're already
drowning in the business they built to
set them free. If your business can't
survive 30 days, okay, 30 days without
you, you've built yourself the most
effective stress simulator on the
planet. Here's what happens. You build
and then you keep building and then soon
everything becomes dependent on you,
which is not the goal, right? We want to
be able to take a week or 2 weeks off
from our business and come back to a
business that's stronger than when we
left, right? But you can't have that if
every lever, right, requires you
personally pulling it. And 3 years in,
if you build it like this, right, you're
drowning working 80 hours a week inside
a machine you own but you don't control.
This is not founder freedom. What we're
really after here are the four W's:
working where you want, on what you
want, with who you want, whenever you
want, right? But the opposite of that is
founder chaos. The business that was
supposed to create freedom but then just
becomes a trap. The fix is actually
simple. Build a little, then systematize
what's working, build more, systematize
again, and that cycle is everything.
Now, when I talk to founders, most
founders, myself included, right, I'm
not just some systems guy that likes to
just build systems all the time for the
sake of building systems. I'm not
building systems to build systems. I'm
building systems to build freedom. When
I go and talk to founders, right, they
say, "Oh, I don't want to document or it
seems so hard or this is just You were
just able to do this because you've made
all this money." I said, "No, no, I've
made all this money because I built
systems. And so, I want you to think
about why this is important, okay? Let's
think about McDonald's, okay, and how it
became a global empire. It wasn't the
burgers, right? Ray Kroc built a system
so repeatable, okay, that anyone,
anywhere could run a location. Ray
removed himself from the outcome. The
business didn't need him. It needed the
system. You need to franchise your own
business the same way. Document it,
systematize it, and then make it run
without you. I take a full month off
every single year, okay? Like every
year. That means my business has to be
built so that my absence, it doesn't
break anything and more importantly,
again, I want to come back to a business
that's stronger than when I left, right?
More profitable, more cash, and just
more peace, okay, with the right systems
in place, team empowered, and no single
point of failure. And here's the
leadership shift that makes it click.
Stop asking, "What should I do?" and
start asking, "What's best for the
enterprise?" This is the golden
question. So, someone comes to me and
says, "Matt, you know, I'm not sure what
content we should put out. What do you
think?" I say, "No, no, no. One sec.
What do you think is best for the
enterprise and what's your
recommendation?" That thing gets people
to gradually ingrain this question in
their minds. And so, when someone on my
team comes to me with a question, I
don't answer it. I ask, "What do you
think is best for the enterprise?" They
won't get it the first time. In my
experience, even with A players, it
probably takes me 20 repetitions back
and napkin before it really sticks.
Coaching means hammering the same
principle until it becomes how your team
thinks. Your team stops asking what you
want and starts figuring out what the
business needs. You know, you don't have
to have all the answers. Great leaders
ask the right questions. What's the
biggest constraint? What's your plan?
Where could it fail? What's best for the
enterprise? That forces people to think
for themselves. And the whole point,
right? We want to help you step back
from the business without it crumbling
in your absence. Decision number six,
hold the bar. If the first five
decisions are the foundation, this one
is the keystone. Pull it out and
everything collapses. This is what
separates founders who built empires
from founders who plateau for years and
never figure out why, right? Imagine two
founders who both hit the same milestone
in year two. The first one keeps raising
the bar system, every hire, every piece
of content held to a higher standard
than last quarter. Compound growth,
compound quality, the business just
keeps getting better. Now, let's go to
the second founder. They got
comfortable, they started cutting
corners, small little mistakes started
going through, barely noticeable, okay?
But they were tolerating these mistakes,
accepting good enough instead of pushing
towards excellence. Their systems stayed
the same while their ambitions grew. And
those outdated systems, well, trying to
run new situations they were never built
for, well, that really became hard
because things were kind of defaulting
to mediocrity. It really started to
bring down everything. A business that
looked fine from the outside started to
kind of rot within. What I see
constantly with first-time founders is
that the bar is just way too low. Not
because they're lazy, because they got
there slowly by tolerating small things.
The bar for outreach, too low. The bar
for quality of work, too low. The bar
for the people they hire, too low. And
that low bar will drag even the most
promising business into the ground. You
know, I get it. Being a founder is
lonely. You're holding a vision that
most people around you don't share. Your
team isn't the founder, right? And that
isolation makes you second-guess
everything. Some days giving up looks
tempting. I've been there. It looks
rational. But, that is not a cue to
cave. That's a cue to hold a higher bar.
You get comfortable making others
uncomfortable. That's the key. You got
to sit in that tension between where the
company is right now and where it needs
to go. And maybe sometimes even be the
only one in your company that can see
that bar. You make the hard calls with
the vision in mind, even when you're
doubting it yourself. I fire people when
the standards demand it. I don't enjoy
it, but I do it because anything less
than the bar that we've set is
unacceptable and my team knows that.
Sometimes being the one who holds a
standard means being the difficult one
in the room. I've made peace with that.
Being a CEO is not a popularity contest,
right? It's about doing what's right for
the enterprise. Because the alternative
is just letting things slide, being
liked in the moment, tolerating
mediocrity, and one thing leads to
another and your business just slowly
degrades. It hurts your team and it
hurts your customers and eventually just
hurts you. Now, here's the uncomfortable
question. If you stepped away from your
business for 30 days, would it survive?
If the answer makes you nervous, I built
something for you. It's called the
Founder Dependency Test and it's linked
below. It'll show you exactly where your
business still depends on you, what
function is the bottleneck, and whether
you've built a company or just some
high-paying job. Fill it out, and if you
realize you're still the constraint,
book a call with my team. We'll tell you
what needs to change structurally to
extract you from operations. You came
here wondering how to build something
that doesn't burn you out. Well, this is
how. Play the right game, kill the
co-founder fantasy, build through the
trifecta of peace, profit, and purpose.
Build your distribution engine,
McDonaldize your business so it runs
without you, and hold the bar even when
it's hard, even when you it's lonely,
even when you doubt at yourself. Do all
that, and success stops being something
you chase, it's just what happens. If
you want to see a more detailed
blueprint of how I build a business all
around these elements, check out this
next video. Let's win together. Be sure
to like and subscribe, and I'll see you
in this next one.