We have a choice. We can either protect
our comfort or we can protect our
future. Comfort feels like safety, but
long-term it's a [music] slow kind of
self- betrayal because growth ain't
easy. And so what you want to make sure
that you're doing every day is in some
small way seeking [music] discomfort.
Writing 2,000 words, it means going
after those 2,000 words and hitting up
the gym, even [music] when I'm feeling a
bit sluggish, right? knowing that, you
know, each time I do one of these hard
things, [music] it's helping me
gradually go and shape the person I'm
aiming to become. Someone that's
healthy, [music] someone that's
creative, and unlocking their full
potential. The truth is, they're not
braver than you. They're just more
willing to feel like for a little
while while [music] something feels a
bit hard. So today, I want you to go and
pick one moment where maybe you'd
normally go and choose comfort [music]
and deliberately doing the uncomfortable
version of that thing. Go to the gym.
Take that awkward meeting. Go and write
that book. Go and post [music] that
content. After you write it down, just
stick to the damn plan. That's how
you're building confidence and [music]
esteem in yourself, knowing that you'll
do the things that you set out to