95% of creators fail because they rely
on motivation, but successful
entrepreneurs rely on systems. You need
the right systems for hiring people, for
onboarding people, for content, for the
audience growth on each platform, and
for actually distributing that content
at a really high degree, and then the
analytics behind it all so that you
learn from the best content, the worst,
and are able to iterate. Without [music]
this all in place, you're likely just
running some rickety machine. But you
get these in place and suddenly you're
able to build an operation that will
stand the test of time and allow
yourself to get the peace of mind to
step back from it all and just be the
talent that has to show up for a video
like this, and the rest of it kind of
just takes care of itself.