Why do some founders accomplish more in
two hours than others do in an entire
week? It took me way too long to figure
out. I had a pattern that was slowly
destroying my momentum. I'd wake up, I'd
check my phone, look at social media,
fire off some responses, jump on a
morning call, and the same critical
tasks are just sitting there untouched.
Every day you spend entirely in reactive
mode is a day you didn't build the thing
that compounds. [music]
It's a day you didn't write the
framework. You didn't go and rejig your
offer, didn't create the amazing
exceptional content that would have
worked for you while you slept. [music]
The most valuable economic output in
today's world comes from
distraction-free,
cognitively intense work. [music]
I call this founder flow. Here's what
founder flow actually looks like in
practice. [music] I use my founder flow
to write a full 21-day email course and
build out an AI course curriculum, and I
did it just [music] in two days. That's
work that would take most teams weeks,
and I'm not telling you this to brag or
to impress you. I'm telling you because
I want you to feel the inspiration
[music] of what is possible when you
actually stop letting other people
dictate your mornings [music]
and your schedule. Block 4 hours in your
calendar tomorrow morning. Not
afternoon, not whenever it's convenient,
morning. First thing. What happens is
this, right? 3:00 [music] p.m. then
rolls around, and you've already done
most of the important work for your day.
While most people are just figuring out
what they should even prioritize.