This AI tool will 10x your income
potential. So the key thing here is
hooking up chat GBT with ChatGBT pulse
which is available to pro users. You can
hook it up to your phone and essentially
go and create a project inside of chatbt
just like I have here. I have this 10x
profit project. What I'm [music] doing
is prompting it to go and give me
different tips, tactics to go and 10x
the profit of founder [music] OS. I'm
getting it to advise me like the
greatest entrepreneurs in the world. I'm
really just trying to get it to go deep
into things like systems design, helping
me overcome the core constraints that I
have in my business. I can go and just
hook this [music] up into Pulse. And on
my phone right here, I'm able to go and
get daily updates [music]
in terms of different ideas, tactics,
systems that can help me go and achieve
this lofty goal. And so the beautiful
thing is versus just scrolling Instagram
mindlessly, you can go and have Pulse
hooked up to your phone and be able to
scroll through customized reports that
are going to help move the needle
forward in your business [music] versus
just doom scrolling all