All right, I want you to go and ask
yourself these important questions. If I
repeated today's habits for the next 12
months, who would [music] I become? What
am I pretending not to know because
changing it would be inconvenient? Where
am [music] I blaming circumstances when
the truth is what I'm really scared of?
What identity am I secretly addicted to?
The busy one, the victim, the gifted but
wasted potential one. We all [music] get
sometimes lost in different identities,
right? And it's important to monitor
those identities and the words we use
and tell ourselves. If you go and
program yourself that a certain task is
really, really hard, well, sure enough,
it's probably going to be really hard.
But on the other side, if you convince
yourself that you're honored to get to
do this, right, and it's a privilege,
well, [music] that's how you're going to
approach the given thing, right? So,
being careful about the identity you
assigned yourself [music] and the
language you use with yourself. Ask
yourself, what uncomfortable truth about
my life have [music] people tried to
tell me but I keep ignoring? Right? So
many times we get, you know, advice from
people, but it [music] goes in one ear
or out the other or it irks us in some
way and then we don't take it. But
oftentimes that's [music] the [\h__\h] we
most need to