When you feel overwhelmed, you don't
need more effort. You need a board
meeting with yourself. I'll take some
time, generally about an hour around the
end of a month to go and really get
outside of my environment. I'll
oftentimes go to my favorite cafe in a
given city. I'll go and do some
reflection. I'll go and think about, you
know, over the past 30 [music] days,
what were the things that I loved the
most? What are the things that I learned
the most? And what do I need to go and
[music] focus on to make the next month
the best month of my life? I have board
meetings from like a decade ago, which
[music] is a pretty awesome experience
to be able to go back to 2015 and go and
look at where was I then? What was I
currently thinking about? The board
meeting [music] serves as this awesome
anchor that keeps you grounded. It also
serves as this amazing lighthouse that
kind of shows you the way. And when
[music] you give yourself time to
actually do this exercise, I think
you're giving yourself an amazing amount
of time to level up as a leader and
leave those negative thoughts behind