Daniel Kenan wrote these words in the
best-selling book Thinking Fast and Slow
optimistic individuals play a
disproportionate role in shaping Our
Lives the people who have the greatest
influence on the lives of others are
likely to be optimistic and
overconfident so how do you cultivate
more optimism in your mindset here are
five easy ways be grateful you have a
lot of things to be grateful for but
those things become common place and we
forget about them every morning and
evening grab a piece of paper and write
down three things you're grateful for
take the long-term view today's
challenges are less of a big deal if you
think in decades instead of months or
even years you have plenty of time to
succeed smile you don't need a reason or
an excuse just smile more research shows
people who smile more feel happier stay
curious don't ask why me ask why did
that happen instead of punishing
yourself get curious look for Solutions
and problem solve train your mind you
don't have to keep thinking the way
you're currently thinking using these
tools is a skill practice thinking
positively and you'll get better at it