Most of what you've learned about
productivity, it's a lie. It's not about
task after task, being more efficient
all the time, trying to constantly go,
go, go, do more, more, more, burning the
midnight oil, spending time hustling all
day. In fact, productivity and
happiness, the intersection there is
actually subtracting more than you add,
removing the distractions. I want to
teach you a little secret. It's called
the 644 rule, or what I call the 4%
formula. You've probably heard about the
8020 rule. Well, if you 8020 the 80/20
rule and you focus even more on the
tasks that you really should be focused
on, you'll find that there's about 4% of
the tasks on your list that are going to
contribute to 64% of your results. All
right, let's get into the first system.
And this is all about your core season
focus. And so, it's worth slowing down
for a second to go and look at, you
know, what are those tasks that are
going to be the biggest needle movers
that you can do? You know, if you have
20 tasks on your to-do list for
tomorrow, you need to go and probably
delete 80% of those, right? Get down to
the one or two things that you really
need to do to move the needle forward.
The 4% formula really allows you to go
and, you know, maybe look at all the
tasks that you have that you could be
going and working on and start to rank
them number one to number 100. Now,
people will often ask me, "Well, Matt,
how do you rank these tasks?" Well, as a
founder, I'll go and look at the stuff
on my plate and I'll go rank it based on
criteria like which tasks are going to
have the greatest impact on my customer,
which of those are the least effort,
right? So that I can get quick wins
going, which of them have the highest
revenue potential, and which of these
tasks give me the most energy, they fire
me up. Because if two tasks are equally
as important, but one really sets my
soul on fire and the other one just
feels draining to do, I'll probably
prioritize the energy giving task to
start getting that momentum going,
feeling good, you know, really just
building that traction. I know, you
know, years of my life when I was
younger, I wasted it consuming
substances and procrastinating.
Inevitably, all this procrastination,
consuming mindless media, it all led me
to being a shell of the man I was meant
to be. I eventually started surrounding
myself with people that were much better
influences. I had met some folks through
a sauna and cold bath spot I would
always go to. And these were people that
were healthy, you know, they were into
transforming their lives into
biohacking. And from a friend of a
friend, I got introduced to my now
business coach, Ryan Begelman. You know,
Ryan and I have worked together now for
the last 6 years, and he's transformed
so many aspects of my life, helping me
focus on better regulating my emotions,
focusing on the tasks that are really
going to move my life forward, and
helping me be the best version of
myself. So, what I want to go and share
with you today are some of the learnings
that I've had going and studying from
hundreds of mentors, spending time
reading hundreds of books on this
subject as well. Because what I want to
tell you is that most of what you've
learned about productivity, it's a lie.
Removing social media, removing the
people that are bringing you down,
getting rid of food that's just slowing
you down. Getting rid of habits that are
no longer serving you. When you can get
more conscious about your time, you can
get more conscious about the life you're
building and actually start making it
happen. Now, I want to teach you about
seasons. My belief as a founder is that
we work best in seasons. Similar to the
4% formula, what I would do here is
essentially every 90 days, I would pick
one core focus. So, if the biggest thing
I needed to grow was cash flow, I may go
and focus more on managing the sales
team. If the next 90 days the biggest
focus needed to be on retention, I may
go and find myself paying most attention
and supporting the customer success team
in my company. If the next aspect that I
found could use the most work is
branding, I would find myself over that
next 90 days making that the theme of
that season and spending the majority of
my time coming up with content ideas,
working on our brand identity, the
messaging, the beauty of the brand. And
this season focus allows me to be okay
with saying no to other areas of the
company that maybe just don't need my
attention right now. and thereby being
able to go deep in the core aspect
that's likely the bottleneck in the
business right now and eliminate it and
not just eliminate it but actually
probably make it the strength of the
business in those 90 days and then move
on to the next part. All right, so let's
move on to your next system here. The
next system I use are my untouchable
hours every day from 7:00 a.m. to 11:00
a.m. These are my four hours where I am
untouchable. No phone, no distractions,
no social media, you can't contact me.
Now, my belief is that those 4 hours of
untouchable time are probably equivalent
to most people's 30 days of productivity
because I'm not distracted at all. I'm
in the zone and I'm focused. Now, you
may be asking, well, what stuff do you
focus on? For the most part, over my
career, I focused on revenue producing
priorities. These are the kind of
priorities that when you work on them,
they bring your company cash flow. Why
cash flow? Well, I mean, cash flow is
the lifeblood of your company. And so, I
focus on things that I know are going to
drive that. And so, you may be asking,
well, what stuff drives that? It may be
creating new offers, creating new
workshops, growing the audience, putting
out content, scaling my personal brand,
going and helping tool up the sales
team, making key hires, tooling up the
customer success team for retention. And
so these are the sort of tasks that I
know when I work on them, you know, it's
going to be worth5 $10,000 per hour plus
of my time to work on those. And I
delegate the kind of tasks on my list
like social media management, maybe even
writing, the kind of stuff that I know
that someone can do 80% as well as me.
Thereby, I'm working on the stuff that's
in my zone of genius. That's the stuff
in the company that the company most
needs me to focus on. So other people
may ask, "Well, Matt, what about
emergencies?" Well, my first rule is
that there are no such things as
emergencies. Emergencies are BS. The
reality is I think way too many people
are firefighting all day long, going
from one fire in their company to the
next one to the next one. The key thing
is you've got to start putting some
distance between you and those fires
that may exist. For me, that's people
like my chief of staff. So, my chief of
staff is my first line of defense. It
happens to be my sister, Claire. and
she'll make sure that anything that pops
up, you know, it doesn't go and get to
me right away so that I have these hours
to focus, to go deep, and to spend time
really pushing things forward. So, I get
a lot of questions from people asking,
you know, Matt, what do you actually do
with all these unstoppable hours? Well,
I'm going to go and show you my personal
board meeting for February 2025. This is
going to break down how I go and
prioritize my time over, you know, 90
days, the next 30 days, and then even
what I'm going to work on every single
day. So starting off here, I go and
outline my core energy for the next 30
days. You know, my focus is to obsess
over quality. You know, quality content,
quality newsletters. You know, the more
quality that we make those items, the
more we grow our audience, the more we
serve founders, which is really the core
value that we have here at Founder OS.
As you can see here, it's all about
doing less but better. So, I'm
constantly saying no by default because
I already got enough on my plate. I
don't need anything more. In addition to
that, I only say yes to things that for
me are a whole body yes. So what's a
whole body yes? It's when you are
thinking about working on something. Is
it a hell yes in your mind, in your
body, and in your soul? Well, that's a
whole body yes. But if there's any
tension that arises in my gut, and I'm
like, ah, I don't know if I should be
doing this, then I just say no. So the
kind of things that I'm often finding
myself working on are these revenue
producing poos or priorities. things
like building a high performance team,
shooting amazing videos like this one
right here, mastering the organic
content funnel, which is the most
powerful system I've ever created in the
last 14 years, building multiple
sevenfigure and 8 figureure businesses.
It goes and helps me grow a massive
audience around those businesses, drive
people to emails, and drive the right
people to the different products and
services we have. And so, I'm constantly
going deep in that area. You know,
someone that inspires me here is Jiro
from Jiro Dreams of Sushi. You know,
year after year, Jirro just mastered
creating sushi. And that to me is like
the radical focus that's required to
become a master. And so for me, that
piece of sushi is the organic content
funnel. And that is what I'm most
focused on going incredibly deep with.
making the best content on X, LinkedIn,
YouTube, Instagram, Tik Tok, creating
the best newsletter for founders in the
world, creating the best YouTube for
founders in the world, and continually
just obsessing over the founder
experience. Now, the next aspect here is
I spend a lot of my time scheming and
plotting, and anything that I find that
is not in these core focuses, I delegate
to my chief of staff. Over the next 30
days, you can go and see my small list
of priorities. So, I plan on finishing
two key books, Reality Trans Surfing and
Be Here Now. I'm going on a retreat here
in Bali to go and reconnect and just
kind of disconnect from all work stuff.
I'm going to go and take a painting and
sculpture class because, you know, I
think it's always good to take a little
artist date with yourself. You know, for
me, I view myself as more of an artist
than an entrepreneur. And so, I want to
make sure that I'm constantly staying in
touch with that part of myself. And I'm
going to finish my book. Uh, this has
been a project I've been working on the
last 2 years. It has been a labor of
love, let me tell you. So, it's going to
get wrapped up here in the next couple
months. On the business side of things,
as you can see here, I'm definitely
doing less but better. The core goal
here is to get monthly applications to
4,500. So, these are the amount of
people that go and apply to work with me
and my team at Founder OS. We only work
with a select few people because, you
know, we only want to work with folks
that are serious about taking action.
And so, you know, for me this month and
actually over the next 3 months here,
that's the core focus. I know when I
create amazing content, when I serve and
I'm generous with others, I go and
create inspiring messaging out there and
I give people the systems for free that
they're looking for. And I really just
listen to what the audience, what you
are asking for, everything kind of stems
from that. So, I'm just obsessed around
giving you exactly what you need to go
and live the life of your dreams and the
systems that you're asking for that are
going to help bring you more clarity in
your business. This is what my org chart
looks like. And so here you can see, you
know, I have a CFO that helps me out
with the finance side of things. We have
a whole creative team, people doing long
form videos, short form videos. We have
a content producer helping me with the
different concepts we're going to be
coming out with. I have a CTO, Dawn, who
is an absolute legend, helping us with
all the HubSpot automations and all the
magic of our organic content funnel,
which at this point is a Ferrari. We
have amazing people across the whole
team. I've got about 32 weapons here.
And by the way, I am hiring. And so if
you're ever interested in joining the
team here at Founder OS, you can go to
founderwest.com/careers
and apply. Now, here you can see I've
gone and charted out my 10year,
threeyear, and one-year goals for
Founder OS. And so I get really detailed
into where I'm looking to go. And then
this goes and feeds what I'm going to go
and work on over the next 90 days and
the next 30 days. I also go and outline,
you know, what are the core things I
need to achieve to make this vision come
true. And that becomes part of my
radical focus. Every day, every week,
every month, I actually go and then
print out this whole document. And every
morning before I get into my task, I
read through my vision so I'm clear on,
okay, this is where I'm looking to go.
These are the core things that matter.
And this is how what I'm about to go and
work on over these no next four hours of
my unstoppable time are going to help
contribute to this big vision that I
have. This vision of serving millions of
founders. This vision of creating a
retreat center in the Doommites. This
vision of getting a Netflix deal based
on the amazing founder content that
we're creating. This vision of running a
high performance team of absolute
legends. This vision of really living up
to my full creative potential jazzes me
up. And so if I can get in that zone,
that energy and then blitz through my
unstoppable hours, I can move mountains.
So, if you're ever interested, by the
way, in joining Founder OS, we love to
work with absolute legends that want to
go and roll up their sleeves, get my
help, get my team's help accelerating
your growth. We're passionate about
helping founders. Our belief is that we
are stronger together as founders, and
our mission is to make the founder
journey magical. And so, be sure to
apply if this sounds interesting to you.
We have proven systems to help you
scale, and I'd love to personally help
you. So, go apply below at
founder.com/apply.
The next system is the taste of 10. So
much of being a successful founder-ledd
brand, a successful creator and founder
is longevity. And before doing anything
and saying yes to anything, I asked
myself, is this something I could see
myself being excited by for the next 10
years? If the answer to that is no, or
even brings me a little bit of tension
in my mind, my body, my soul, the answer
is no. And for most things, I'd say 99%
of things, the answer is no. The key
thing here when you're building anything
is that you're most focused on the tasks
that are going to move you forward. I
like to keep my life insanely simple.
And that's actually my theme for 2025.
This is something that I learned from
Steve Jobs and his maniacal focus on
making products that are insanely
simple. And what that involved was him
working with his head of design, Joanie
IVive, and constantly removing things
from the experience. Not focused on
always what they could add in features,
but constantly going and just cutting
one more thing, subtracting one more
thing. I also have this team
accountability chart. So, like I said
here, right, the big focus is not just
on me doing less but better, but it's
having my whole team doing less but
better as well. And so inside of the
team accountability chart, every single
person on our team also just has one
core metric. So my metric is cash and
bank. My content producers metric is 1
million YouTube subscribers. My chief of
staff is focused on executing a hiring
plan. Our CTO is getting 2,000
high-quality leads per month. Our CFO is
also focused on cash and bank. Our brand
strategists are closing deals. Founder
success managers are getting amazing
reviews from the founders that are super
happy inside of Founder OS. You know, we
have writers focused on views. We have
social media managers focused on growth
across all platforms. Short form video
editors focus on getting each short form
video to 500k views each. So, this
radical focus on each person's role
allows each person to know what is their
northstar so they can do less but
better. Say no to more distractions and
then just double down on the
needlemoving tasks that are going to
help make us the most aspirational,
beautiful, and systemized founder brand
in the world. So what I'd encourage you
to do is go and set up your asauna for
some of the core departments that you're
running and make sure that you have a
team accountability chart so that you're
really clear on who is on your team.
What are the core focuses of each of
those people and what is the key KPI
that's going to help measure that
person's success inside of the taste of
10. Something that I may say hell yes to
is something like going and evolving our
brand to making sure it is the best most
aspirational founder brand in the world
bar none. You know what Nike did for
athletes in the 70s. What Apple did for
creatives in the '9s is what I'm looking
to build with founder OS for founders in
the 20s. It's all about helping founders
achieve freedom, time freedom, location
freedom, mental and spiritual freedom.
And so this is an example of my design
board in a sauna. So I've got a team of
weapons that works with me. And when I'm
looking to go and evolve the aesthetics
of the brand, you know, I'm not doing
this all myself. We've got some legends
on our team that are constantly going
and evolving our content. So I'll go and
I'll stipulate, hey, this is what we're
focused on this week, next week. These
are weekly recurring tasks. And so they
know exactly, you know, the tasks that
they need to get done this week, next
week, and over, you know, the coming
months to make sure that we're
constantly evolving the Founder OS
brand. And so here you can see on the
weekly recurring stuff, I have them
working on things like YouTube
thumbnails and making sure they feel
organic and on brand. I have them
working on carousels that we hope will
get shared by people with, you know, 10
plus friends each time. We want to go
and make sure that we have the decks for
the boot camp I'm currently running for
founders are all dialed in, beautiful
and gorgeous because our belief is that
each touch point we have should be like
a work of art. Similarly, I go and often
times create decks for YouTube videos
and so we want to make sure that those
decks are beautifully designed and then
we take a lot of craft and creativity
and pour that into our Instagram grid.
You know, we've now crossed over 900,000
followers on Instagram. It's really from
creating amazing, inspiring content
that's also very practical, no BS, no
fluff, just real systems to help
founders scale their audience, their
brand, and their revenue. So, I have
time to focus on my mental health, so
I'm feeling good. I'm feeling grounded.
I have time to focus on my physical
health and my spiritual health so that I
can be this well-rounded founder. You
know, my belief is that entrepreneurs
are athletes and strong founders build
strong systems build strong businesses.
Making sure that you have the time to
fill up your own cup is key because you
can't build a great business if you're
not doing great. Like and subscribe and
welcome to the founder freedom movement.