[Music]
I know what your problem
is you think you have nothing and you
want to start a
business 5 years ago that might have
been a problem and there's never been
more pressure to become an entrepreneur
than
today the good news is entrepreneurship
is changing you don't need some
assistant some full-time filmmaker an
expensive office or an expensive desk
the truth is there's a new wave of
innovators that are doing
entrepreneurship right
leading a business with the personal
brand of its founder using their own
personality as a hero for the business's
brand transforming the ingredients
needed to attract a paying Community
this is the founder-led business model
and it allows you to prioritize yourself
your happiness and your goals when
building a business I spent the past 3
years testing this formula creating
systems to build my own founder-led
business founder OS a business built
entirely around myself my wants my
dreams my desires my goals my life
lifestyle everything that I want and
nothing that I don't want and the crazy
thing is it
works I get to live my dream lifestyle
while founder West brings in over
$850,000 a month in Revenue I can work
when I want on what I want wherever I
want with whoever I want this is the
evolution of Entrepreneurship this is
the founder Le business model this is
how to start a business from nothing
starting with yourself
today starting a business isn't
necessarily the hardest thing every
influencer and their sister has a
product or a course or a merch line they
would call a business but starting a
business and growing it while actively
tending to your happiness that's the
challenge and this is where founder
Freedom comes
[Music]
in founder freedom is full control over
the four W's in life work where you want
on what you want with who you want when
you want it's time location and
Financial Freedom the hype of hustle
culture drove so many people into the
deep end of Entrepreneurship without the
education or the tools to participate in
this world sustainably even I lost
myself while building my first business
bitmaker which was an in-person coding
school from the outside everything
looked good but inside it was one of the
most frustrating experiences of my life
I hated running an inperson
brick-and-mortar business it was the
worst it took everything in my soul not
to break but I realized a ton about
myself looking back it's obvious that
bitmaker wouldn't fulfill my dreams but
if it wasn't for bitmaker I'd never have
known what I truly wanted and how to
avoid what I don't want your
entrepreneur Journey doesn't have to
start with lessons learned the hard way
Embrace founder freedom and focus on the
founder you give yourself clear answers
around how you want to live where you
want to work and who you want to work
with and how much you need to make for
me I wanted to live between global
business hotspots working wherever I
want and having the freedom to travel
and to be close to Nature answer those
four questions and you've defined
founder Freedom you can now start
building your founder-led business model
the vehicle everyone must use to thrive
in this new age of Entrepreneurship
every founder-led business model starts
with an analysis of the founder that's
you that's me that's
[Music]
us to connect your business directly
with your personal needs wants goals and
dreams you have to look inward my
favorite method to discover your
personal Niche is the iy guy exercise iy
guy is a concept in Japan that stands
for your reason for being so your iy guy
consists of four different lists but
once you're done this you can see that
this area here that's your iy guy and so
you're going to go and you're going to
fill this in with what you're good at
what you can be paid for what the world
needs and then what you love to do you
you may go and find that as you look at
these four different quadrants there are
some commonalities and what I'd
encourage you to do is try to go and
fill at least five things out in each of
these different sections the topics that
meet in the center represent your unique
Niche this changed everything for me for
my icky guy I discovered that I love
systems growing audiences building
communities and traveling the world and
helping Founders this is my Niche I help
Founders get to $5 million profit a year
using the proven systems I've created
over the past 15 years creating four
profitable companies if I were to
simplify it down to one word it would be
systems but I don't just see myself
making stuff only around systems I talk
about my Curiosities the things that
inspire me my travels my interests my
strengths I'm able to do all of this
because I'm doing things that I'm
passionate about I'm passionate about
traveling and meditation cold baths
saunas nature and the list goes on at
the intersection of this diagram isn't
just a business that you love it's a
business where you love the customer and
then to communicate with that customer
you need to become the
[Music]
niche and to do that you need to
understand people follow people and then
they follow Brands it's important that
every brand has a Founder that is
building their own personal brand having
an online presence establishes you as
the true expert in your area it gives
you a packed pipeline of clients that
you can tap into at any moment and it
makes you even more in demand allowing
you to charge more drive more customers
and build a massive Empire there are two
routes forward with your Niche both work
but there's one that I really love first
you can own your Niche this is when you
pick a subject and then go all in on it
you own a word in the customer's mind
you're the productivity guy or the
habits guy or the stoicism guy on the
positive side this builds a highly
targeted audience fast you become the
go-to expert and the trigger when people
hear that they come to you and people
want the solution that you provide the
downside is that you can end up stuck in
a single Niche and you get a little
pigeon hold so the alternative to then
owning Niche is just to become the niche
think about it you're the only one who
has access to your own unique insights
curiosity I ities mistakes achievements
lessons tools and tactics there's no one
else who knows as much about you as you
this shift alone was a dramatic change
and helped me then grow an audience of
over 3 million people around myself and
then feed all of my businesses which are
now doing over $13 million a year in
Revenue with this approach you want to
discuss a handful of related topics
regularly but those topics are more
focused on your personal brand than on a
single company topic you're trying to
make people feel connected to you
because again you are the niche the
downside of a person first brand is it
become challenging to monetize if you
don't also have a bunch of businesses
around you and a clear problem you're
looking to solve for your audience and
you risk people coming to you more for
entertainment than to charge that's why
I recommend starting somewhere between
these two areas right you're both going
to become the niche while also owning a
word in the mind of your customers then
look at the edges of where your
interests are and see where it overlaps
with your ideal audience members
problems and desires then you can create
a brand around solutions that address
those problems but overlap with who you
are you'll have a unique Niche and a
personal mode around everything that you
do but to embrace your Niche you need to
embrace
content and this is where the system of
building your own personal media company
comes into
[Music]
play there's still too much of this
Creator approach to content whereby you
must master all of the elements of
content yourself if you're an
entrepreneur your superpower is
assembling a team making decisions and
then executing a Clear Vision how are
you going to do that well you're making
tons of YouTube videos from adz building
a newsletter your audience on X and
Linkedin all by yourself if you're
starting out you likely will have to do
a lot of it yourself but once you've
landed on your Niche two to three
formats you want to pursue you are ready
to leverage your cash flow to hire some
creative weapons dedicated to scaling
your brand and your message and here's
the real numbers behind a successful
personal Media Company let's just say
for example you have 12K to dedicate to
your own personal brand the 12K
investment can be broken down into a
couple of options option one is you hire
a weapon of a writer as a contractor for
around 7K and then have them handle all
the social content on your newsletter
then also hire a newsletter writer to
handle a newsletter one time a week at
around around 3 to 5K per month option
two is you hire a full stack writer as a
contractor that can handle all of your
Social content and your Weekly
Newsletter this person is going to work
likely part-time solely on your content
and this will probably cost around 8 to
10K per month if you go with option two
you'll have a full stack writer to
publish 14 x posts per week seven long
form LinkedIn posts per week and one
highquality newsletter per week you'll
need to ensure that you bring on this
writer that has loads of experience
writing on the platforms that you're
looking to grow on which is likely X and
Linkedin the strength of this strategy
is that it can help you build leverage
you're getting help now with writing the
content so you can go and spend time on
bigger things in your business you are
also able to focus your energy on
ideation and then helping with execution
the downside is that you still got to be
pretty involved in your content strategy
you need to come up with ideas edit
content and ensure tight alignment
between your content and brand
guidelines with 2 to 3K more of your
business's Revenue dedicated to your
personal Media Company you can increase
the salary of the writer to then come up
with the ideas that you'll execute on
inside of your content strategy while
still employing a social manager to post
all of that content that way you can get
off the content hamster wheel entirely
this is where you move from just the
Creator to the CEO back into your zone
of Genius you now have four out of the
five ingredients of the founder-led
business model you understand founder
Freedom you identified your reason for
being your icky guy and you are
dedicated to either becoming or owning
your Niche and you have the first steps
of a highly scalable personal Media
company to power your brand through
content and now you have to sell it and
to sell it you first need to Target the
Right
audience most Founders use some spray
and pay method and that never works you
want to move with surgeon like Precision
focus on quality over quantity find the
right people and then draw them in there
are 8.1 billion people on the planet and
you can't help them all narrow down your
audience to a specific type of person if
you're teaching health and fitness
narrow it down Health and Fitness for
film industry professionals Health and
Fitness for working moms Health and
Fitness for recovering athletes in the
first 6 months following an accident the
more specific you can be there the more
comp telling your online presence will
be for the right person second go after
a topic people are already passionate
about fashion heads don't need to be
convinced to go and get the newest pair
of sneakers Apple enthusiasts follow
every single keynote and product drop
you don't want to have to persuade
people that they need your offer find
that passion then direct it towards a
specific version of what you're creating
criteria three for your ideal audience
member is who can buy at the the end of
the day you have to be realistic about
whether or not your audience can
actually afford to purchase what you're
selling about 6 years ago I had the idea
for something called Trail AI it was an
AI that would essentially help real
estate agents and financial services
folks with synthesizing all the data and
reports that they have and then getting
those to their clients I'd get on calls
with these folks and I'd get green
lights they were excited the only issue
was that they weren't really the buyer
they didn't have the money or the
ability to pay I quickly realized that
was building something for the wrong
audience and this was much more of a
large corporate play every business
owner has experienced this an audience
that's passionate but has no money so
pick an audience that's ready to spend
money either to solve their problems or
to get deeper into what they love an
audience full of people who are in love
with what you're talking about is the
goal that audience is a Tinder Box of
Revenue that you need to ignite with the
perfect social funnel the perfect social
funnel consists of a newsletter
strategically placed ctas killer lead
magnets and an irresistible offer create
your newsletter on convert kit it's the
best platform for Founders when I
discovered convertkit it blew everything
I tried beforehand out of the water it
is hands down the best place for your
newsletter on the internet you want to
create a focused landing page that
really sells what your newsletter is and
is an incredible resource for your ideal
audience member here's an example of
what my signup page looks like all right
so this is my signup page here anyone
that goes and signs up on found.com
newsletter this will drive you to my
convertkit newsletter and so the key
components of this page as you can see
there is no ability to scroll on this
page so all you can do is enter your
email from there there's a bold headline
right the only newsletter you need to
grow your personal brand and then from
there a little bit more information on
why you should join including a valuable
lead magnet to get you 50 systems to
generate 1 million per month and then we
have overwhelming social proof here from
a group of absolute Legends so that's my
sign up page 101 now go make yours your
focus sign up page is important for
converting traffic since you'll be
sharing it across all of your Social
channels I call this process my call to
action system you want to go on a
massive campaign to add that link to as
many places as possible across your
social media presence here are 20 places
I incorporate my call to actions across
Instagram LinkedIn X Tik Tok YouTube and
my podcast you're going to want to put
in your Instagram bio Instagram stories
LinkedIn about section LinkedIn bio
LinkedIn featured section LinkedIn cover
photo LinkedIn Carousel ending your X
bio X cover photo X end of a tweet X end
of a thread Tik Tock bio your Tik Tok
video CTA YouTube bio YouTube
description YouTube about section
YouTube cover photo and a YouTube 15sec
commercial with the CTA as well as in
your podcast descriptions if you want to
get my CTA system and learn how to
implement all 20 of these call to
actions across all the six platforms
then go to the description of this video
right below the like button which you
should press anyways while you're down
there this is the guide I wish I was
given when I wanted to grow my email
list as fast as possible if you really
want to increase newsletter conversions
I recommend lead magnets according to
HubSpot companies see a 50% increase in
leads when they use a lead magnet
compared to companies that don't a lead
magnet is a Hy useful piece of content
that's gated behind an email sign up it
could be an in-depth PDF download
multi-part video series webinar Workshop
Workshop recording an email mini course
specialized Insight quiz ebook white
paper checklists free systems playbooks
or even a free trial you can prove your
Authority by solving a piece of the
problem for the customer for free and
then the rest of the solution is an easy
purchase away my belief is that the more
generous you are The More Everything
grows around you you know it can be
scary creating something that truly is
amazing and then giving it all away for
free sounds nuts but I think having an
abundance mindset always wins
reciprocity is one of the strongest
forces in humanity you give and then you
get so for me I always challenge myself
to give away what I know you're now
ready to connect your passion to profit
by pitching your audience on an
irresistible offer so they can become
your monetized audience this is your
most valuable audience audience and this
is the part I love because you're
already creating a system that
automatically is creating trust between
you and your audience and finally what
should you actually provide in your
offer well now that you have an audience
they're probably already telling you
what they want from you I like to listen
to what my audience regular ask for in
my YouTube comments email responses and
in in-person Live Events and I just
observe the topics that resonate with my
audience and if people are passionate
about a certain topic well they're
probably willing to pay for related
products or services around that thing
if that's the case all you have to do is
then package it up into a compelling
format that works for you here are five
tiers of offers I recommend low ticket
offers are great because they're a low
barrier to entry you can get people into
your ecosystem with very minimal
friction for example you can expand a
low ticket course into then a high
ticket course upsell or you can take
part of a higher ticket course and then
create the lower ticket course from that
paid communities are amazing as well
they're a great form of recurring
Revenue you're bringing people together
to learn and have fun you get paid to
talk about things that you love while
making meaningful connections amongst an
amazing group of people the community
can also be an incredible internal
referral source and you have a pre-sold
audience that you can then upsell other
products or services to service-based
businesses and Consulting are the lowest
barrier to entry with great margins if
you're doing it right Consulting in
particular is one of the easiest
businesses to get traction with and what
I recommend every every successful
founder starts with if they don't know
where to begin finally let's dive into
masterminds these are ultra high ticket
products where you do group coaching
experiences and education over a longer
period of time with a consistent group
of high performers often the point of a
mastermind is personal connections to an
exclusive crowd the price point is the
barrier to entry and the math of getting
to six figures once you have a
compelling offer is simpler than it
appears for example consider 20 people
buying a $5,000 course or 50 people
paying $2,000 for consulting or just
over 500 people buying your low ticket
$197 course all of these are routes to
100K if you mix and match you can get
there even faster once you have your
irresistible offer it's time to share it
and convert your rented and Ed audience
to monetized First create a sales page
for the offer using similar principles
to your focus signup page for your
newsletter right you're going to have a
bold headline hero images social proof
to make it so irresistible people can't
say no then incorporate that link into
your profitable profile create an email
sequence that automatically launches
after they download a lead magnet and
then launch it to your entire list for
the first time when your offer debuts
then continue to feature it as a main or
recurring CTA in your newsletter I've
created businesses where sales are
generated directly from the sales page
but in my experience the higher ticket
your product is the more likely you're
going to want to actually sell sell the
customer directly when I was just
getting started with bitmaker you know
we priced the program at about $11,000
we'd go on to increase the price of
things to around $5,000 but I remember
the Joy on my team's face when we saw
that first $1,000 come in for the first
person that would join our technology
school and learn to code I don't know if
I could sell anything else that would
bring me as much joy as that first sale
I got I think the hardest money that
you're ever going to make is the first
time you get to 20K per month you have
no idea what you're doing I know because
I've been there and I can tell you this
you're going to get through it you will
need a sales system in place but I'll
let you get started with your business
and then I'm going to give you that in
another video this channel is about
building businesses not prisons freeing
us the founders to do what we want in
life if you want to do the same and
haven't already watched my full series
I'm building your audience from0 to
100,000 followers you can click this
video here to start learning thanks for
watching and good luck on your founder
journey I wish you all the success
possible
[Music]