Everyone's obsessed with followers and
views, but without this one underrated
thing, you're guaranteed to fail. You
know, when I'm looking at my content,
it's neat when a piece of content goes
viral. What's much [music] more
impactful is for me to go and look at
the kind of people that are messaging me
around that piece of content. The kind
of stuff that I saw that people were
really resonating with was the stuff
that was more, you know, behind the
scenes. Getting into really how I was
operating my team behind the scenes.
[music] How I was traveling the world
and managing this portfolio of
companies. And the different struggles
and wins I was having along the way. I
found that the more [music] I was
sharing who I really was and what I was
really going through, um the more that
sort of vulnerability and that
authenticity [music]
um attracted and magnetized really
awesome people towards me.