Most founders are still creating content
like creators when you need to be
posting content like an architect
because a founder-led business needs
content that behaves like a sales team,
a trust engine, and a customer journey
all at once. It's a hard balance to
find. I get it, which is exactly why I
built the Content GPS, which does it for
you. It has 180 components mapped across
seven core stages, and today it runs the
social media engine behind my 3 million
followers and a business doing over $14
million a year led by organic content.
First things first is we've really got
seven core components to a Content GPS.
We have traffic, right? Actually going
and generating traffic on platforms like
YouTube, Instagram, X, and LinkedIn.
When I'm going and helping founders, I
think it's important that you think
about are you more of a writing-first
founder and thereby going on platforms
like X and LinkedIn, or are you more of
a video-first founder? And in that case,
you may go and choose platforms like
YouTube and Instagram. And so then when
it comes to leads then, okay? The big
thing here obviously is we want to be
driving people to an email list. You're
going to convert around 37 times better
via your email list than social media,
and most founders aren't even thinking
about really owning that audience. Now,
the best way by far that I've ever found
to go and capture people from my
audience and convert these people is
contextual lead magnets. So here you can
see my lead magnets and opt-in pages.
What I've gone and done here is that
basically over the last four years
building my personal brand, I think
about creating topics around like my
Ikigai or helping people get more of
their time back, my personal board
meeting. And I've gone and synthesized
some of these things that I just
naturally do daily, and basically I've
given it all away, okay? And what I'm
doing there is essentially going and
taking the given system, so let's just
say it's something like this perfect day
assignment or something like my, you
know, CEO time leverage audit. What I go
and do is put this behind a landing
page, right? And so every single lead
magnet gets a landing page. In this
case, it's how to run a content system
that actually works, right? People enter
their name, their email, right? Their
phone number, and then in exchange for
that, they're going to go and get this
free thing. Now, that allows me to then
go and market to these people off of
social media in a more intimate, rich
way, like email or like text. And in
exchange, they go and they get the
actual lead magnet itself. So, in this
case, it's simply just a Google Doc. The
cool thing here for you, right, is don't
overcomplicate lead magnets, right? They
don't need to be some fancy PDF or some
insane tool. If you're just getting
going, just start with a simple Google
Doc around your expertise, giving away
something that you think would be really
valuable to your audience. That's kind
of that lead magnet piece. The next
piece here is then conversion, okay? The
big piece with conversion, right, is
nailing your nurture sequence. When
someone goes and gets that lead magnet,
they're added to an email list, and over
9 days, they're going to get five
educational emails and five FOMO emails
driving folks to, in this case, his
Wealth OS, which is his kind of
educational program he's building around
his wealth management firm. Now, on the
sales side, the most important thing
here that I think a lot of people screw
up is really the most valuable page in
the whole sequence, which is your
version of this founder os.com/apply
page. Typically, what you have is all of
your social media, right, directing to
core lead magnets, and then you're
driving people to some sort of link. And
so, what you want to have is a page like
this, right? I call it my apply page,
and the winning page here has a bold
headline that allows people to
understand exactly what you do. In our
case at Founder OS, it's helping people
build a social media machine for them,
right? We work one-on-one with you to
install the exact systems behind my $15
personal brand and drive, you know, its
you know, growth, right? And then we
have a video sales letter here that
gives people a sense of what we do, what
it's all about, the kind of people that
we've worked with, and then allow people
to go and book their brand strategy
call. This then leads people to a brief
10-question application, and this is a
smart router that then routes the right
people to the right product. And so
we're only getting on calls with folks
that make sense for what we've got going
on, and the rest of folks will just get
sent to an offer that's right for them.
Now, the offer, right? This is one of
your most high-leverage aspects of the
whole GPS. This is obviously where we're
going to actually make money. And so
when in doubt, if you're not really
hitting your profit goals in your
business, and you're finding that, you
know, your close rate is below 20%,
chances are you probably need to take a
look at that offer and go and dial it up
a bit. From there, it's your delivery
end. Most businesses, after they've
nailed the offer, the next area that
they break is their delivery. Now,
systems then are what kind of bring it
all together, right? And here, the big
thing is that we want to make sure that
if you're building this, right? You got
time to actually build the business. You
know, I really talk about in my content
all the time the difference between
creators and CEOs, right? Creators go
and make money from just making content
off the backs of ads, but that's not
like you, and that certainly ain't me.
And so what we need to be focused on is
having the right systems around us so we
can go and, you know, hit it and quit it
with content, right? And be able to do,
you know, a bunch of videos, bunch of
content over a couple days, and then
have 2 months back to then focus on the
business. And so when it comes to your
platform strategy there, okay? The big
thing here is then going and translating
that GPS to the core platforms you're
on. So, let me show you how I think
about this for say LinkedIn. On
LinkedIn, I've grown my audience here to
over 908,000 followers, all organically
over the last few years, okay? And
across every single piece of content
here on this page, you know, we'll click
into any one of these, you'll see that
it's always a banger hook to go and stop
the scroll, okay? Which you can see
here, Steve Jobs once said, "The most
powerful person in the world is the
storyteller." Then there's long-form
value here, and you can see this is all
easily scannable. And so, we always have
these value-dense images as well on
LinkedIn. And then, making sure
everything right in terms of the CTA is
contextual to what's above. So,
obviously I'm talking about storytelling
in this post, and I'm giving people a
storytelling growth assessment. Now,
similar here on YouTube, right? The flow
here is we can pick any given post here.
You know, I just put up this one here,
which is "If I wanted to build a
personal brand in 2026, I would do
this." It's about a 17-minute video. In
minute four, roughly, and minute 12,
we're driving people down to the link in
the description to get a lead magnet to
help them go and scale their personal
brand. Okay? And so, again, the lead
magnets are always contextual to the
piece of content. And then, you can see
I'm also driving people to go and work
with me, which leads people to that core
apply page I was going over earlier.
Right? So, we're driving all traffic,
once people are nurtured, to this core
apply page, headline, VSL, and then the
application link. If you're looking at
what this looks like across my whole
business for a second, okay? This is
what, you know, Founder OS looks like in
a nutshell. Right? So, I'm driving
traffic across platforms like YouTube,
Instagram, X, and LinkedIn. I have my
email sequences, email courses, and lead
magnets like I just showed you. Now, all
of those different nurture sources then
lead people to our different
monetization opportunities. Our core
product is called Founder OS Velocity.
That's where we go and build your social
media machine for you. Over the course
of 60 days, we deliver over 50 assets to
help you with all the core
infrastructure behind building an
amazing, profitable personal brand, as
well as your company brand. Things like
your landing pages, lead magnets,
content machine, conversion assets, you
know, all the stuff that I've gone over
here is what we build for founders for
them in just 60 days. Just showing you
kind of how I look at this stuff. And so
here we can see that we've done just
that for James here, okay? We've gone
and shown, you know, LinkedIn, YouTube,
his newsletter and podcast, and then all
the different formats we're going to be
doing inside of that. When I think about
the formats that really are working best
for me right now that I think you should
look out for your own market, number one
are screen shares, right? Going into
showing behind the scenes just like I've
doing with you right now on what you
actually do. The second type is going
and showing yourself with clients
actually helping them. I've done this
with folks like Ali Abdaal, Blake Rocha,
so many others, right? On these
whiteboard sessions that I've become
known for. The last type is really just
having some fun and having like a wild
card type category, right? Not
everything needs to be, you know, so
rigid. And I've done this with things
like vlogs I've done snowboarding in
Japan to this video over here, you'd be
richer if you relax that I filmed in the
Dolomites randomly, right? And so I
think a mix of your own kind of personal
narrative, vlog, like fun stuff, some
stuff showing you with clients, and then
some screen share stuff is what's going
to really work on platforms like YouTube
these days. Now, on the newsletter side,
the best thing to do there is just make
sure you're publishing once a week. When
it comes then to the content pillars,
okay? I think too many people get caught
up in their content pillars trying to
perfect this. At the end of the day you
want to just get into the details pretty
fast. So, here for James, right? We
modeled out, you know, I'm really making
sure that he's speaking about things
like wealth, tax strategy, his own
story, and then his unique method. But I
think it's important to quickly get into
the details. And let me show you what I
mean by that. I like to use a platform
called One of Ten as an example, right?
And inside of One of Ten when I'm
thinking about my own YouTube videos,
right? I have a bunch of bookmarks in
here. I have bookmarks for my ideas, and
I have bookmarks for thumbnails. And so
if you go into my different ideas here,
I can go and sort these via, you know,
what I've gotten the most views. And
here I can see a ton of different
YouTube videos, right, around the kind
of stuff that I think these title
patterns in these is pretty interesting
for how I could package my own content.
The number one way to go and just break
from all the noise and boring in
those industries is to package your
content, your business, your brand in an
innovative way looking at the best
outliers that exist out there. And
that's exactly what platforms like One
of Ten help with. So, from there, right,
when we think about CTAs, right? Some
folks are saying like, "Well, what the
hell, we're only doing lead magnets
here? We're never actually talking about
our business." Here's the deal. I want
you to be able to build a brand online
without selling your soul. And if you're
constantly just going and telling
people, you know, "Buy my thing, buy my
thing." You just end up sounding like
some salesy piece of right? And
so, what we want to do is be insanely
generous with people. And about 60% of
the time, we want to be driving people
to these amazing lead magnets that
provide a lot of value, right, and show
a ton of goodwill. Then about 20% of the
time, right, we can go and just make
direct offers to people, right, actually
just going and selling your thing. And
then 20% of the time, it could be, you
know, driving people on Instagram as an
example to things like DM triggers,
right? So, in this case, it's things
like, you know, DM me tax and I'm going
to send you an optimization guide. From
there, inside of Instagram or LinkedIn,
when people have gone and DM'd you for
that given lead magnet, you can then
engage in a conversation with them or
have a setter on your team engaging in
conversations. And if that person seems
like they're in the market for what you
do and seem like they're in the buying
pocket, going and setting them to your
sales team to close up that deal. So,
the content waterfall. So many of you
guys come to me because you want to
learn how to go and turn your pillar
piece of content into 22 other formats.
These days, some of the best ways to do
this, right, are using your YouTube
videos, right? So, YouTube videos can
easily go and become things like YouTube
shorts just by going and cutting the
best moments. You know, inside of a
YouTube video, you typically will go
through say three to five different sort
of parts of a value structure, and any
one of those pieces could easily be cut,
right? And become a standalone video.
Now, you have all this content mapped
out, right? The big thing now is getting
your content calendar going. So, here
you can see, this is me going and
actually working with James to go and
show him exactly how I'd think about his
posting schedule going forward, okay?
Number one here is I want to make sure
that James is posting one YouTube video
a week. On LinkedIn, we want to be
posting every single day at 8:00 a.m.
EST because I've seen in the morning in
your given market being the best time to
post on the platform. From there, one
podcast is released every week, which is
really just taking that YouTube video
and then uploading it to Spotify and to
Apple Music. And then, he's got a couple
IG posts going out per week because, you
know, honestly, just being on LinkedIn
and YouTube for now is enough. We're
just doing a little bit on Instagram
with some of those content waterfall
cut- downs, keeping to a content
strategy that feels sustainable, right?
And not trying to do too much at once,
and then, you know, just having him give
up. From there, you know, I've gone and
generated a bunch of proven hooks across
all of these different content
categories, right? Now, when you're
going and coming up with hooks for your
content, the best place to come up with
hooks is by using a course survey you
can go and send to your customers,
right? Ask them, what's their biggest
goals? What are their biggest
challenges? And what do they most want
your help with? Inevitably, content,
like any product, is there to go and
serve people. And there's no better
people to serve than the folks that are
already paying you money. And so, that's
exactly what I did here. I generated
over 32 proven hooks across each of
these categories, wealth architecture,
tax strategy, the Mitchell Method, and
the Builder Story, to make sure that
James is essentially always drowning in
great content to create. There's no
reason when you're building content
online for you to be wondering what your
next content idea should be. That is the
content GPS, which is in Founder OS, one
of the core pieces that we go and
install inside of founders' businesses
for them. You know, I'm talking about
going and getting on a one-to-one call
with a founder right when they join.
From there, we go and chart out their
brand positioning, get their content
machine built. We go and get your VSL
and your conversion assets all in place.
And then from there, it's really going
and implementing this not just in your
business with you, but making sure your
entire team is leveraged as well. And
so, if that's interesting to you, you
should definitely go and check out
Founder OS. You can go and find a link
in the description here. Go and check it
out. Book a call with my team. Much
love. If you liked this video, you would
love this next video on how to go and
craft your brand positioning. I'll see
you over there. Be sure to like and
subscribe, and let's win together.