And so, here you can see I'm revisiting
my vision every month, right now.
10-year goals are things like, you know,
being madly in love with my wife and
having an amazing family, epic road
trips, simplicity, retired, just doing
art every day. Um I see myself these
days as more of an artist than an
entrepreneur. So, lots of big goals
there. We're publishing the book this
year, which is going to be dropped in a
few months. Currently here in Lofoten
and have a big little trip here to get a
home in Europe over the next couple of
months, but then heading out to Bali for
an epic founder retreat we're hosting
there, and then to Japan snowboarding
for the summer or the winter. So, it's
some big things planned there. So, over
the next 90 days, we are getting this
book published, continuing
to, you know, manifest this home base in
Europe, which is a big, big milestone. I
have plans near the end of the year to
go to India and to, yeah, basically,
it's pretty simple. Honestly, what I've
learned with success is that there is
one key concept I learned from the book
called The Slight Edge. It's that
everything is a curve. It's either an
upward curve or a downward curve. And
obviously, as a successful person, you
want to ride that upward curve. That
upward curve is the combination of every
decision that you make, every touch
point, every email, every message, every
call, every move you make. And so, you
want to make sure that you're making one
good move after the other. Ask yourself,
you know, is this one thing I'm doing
right now going to help my compounding
in life and compound me in a great way.
So, I like to ask myself things like,
you know, does this support the peace in
my life, the profit, the purpose? Is
this the one thing I should be doing
right now that will make everything else
easier or unnecessary?