The moment you make a promise in public,
you're putting your reputation on the
line. And at that point, you will do
anything [music] to actually do what you
committed to. That's not pressure to
avoid, that's pressure to leverage. So,
if you want to be consistent, set up
your accountability in three [music]
steps. Number one, publicly announce
that you're going to do the thing.
Number two, go and update those group of
people every single week. And number
three, start building an audience of
these kind of people that you've
committed to now. This is maybe the
early adopters of that product or that
initial community you're going to have
around that thing you're building. Use
this as a momentum you need to stay
after it.