This AI combo basically makes my
business run itself. Chat GBT decides
what needs to happen and pulse updates
me every morning. First off, inside of
ChatBT, I've gone and created a project
called the 10X Profit Project. I use
this project every single day to go and
help me with different ideas for Founder
OS. And I've gone and asked this to be
the ultimate business coach. It's giving
me constant advice over just the common
challenges I have. But where it gets
magical is that I've gone and hooked
this up to Pulse, which essentially goes
and gives me customized reports every
single morning based on the things that
I'm trying to accomplish right now. It's
giving me now a customized report ready
to go, as well as a weekby- week
breakdown on what I need to do as well
as my overarching strategy because
inside of the project files, I've gotten
uploaded 26 of our core documents. It
probably has more context than like 98%
of my employees. You can imagine how
much leverage you get by having this
hooked up and be able to look at these
reports every single morning. And it's
like having a head of operations
advising you on the specific things you
need to move forward that day to build
insane amounts of leverage.