What if I told you that the only thing
you need to get unstuck and make
progress faster than 99% of people is a
simple 10-minute system? This system
took me from trapped in a cycle of
burnout and procrastination to being
able to work 4 hours a day building a
portfolio of online businesses from
anywhere in the world. So, here's my
simple five-step system so you can get
unstuck and level up so fast it feels
like cheating. Step one, the 2-minute
mental cleanse. This part takes 2
minutes. The reason why this works is
because of Newton's first law, the
physics of momentum. When you're stuck,
it's because you're at rest. You're
trying to overcome this inertia. But
once you start moving, even just tiny
movements forward, that momentum starts
to pick up and move you forward. So,
here's what you're going to do. You're
going to go and write down everything
that's causing you mental static and get
it out of your head. Every unfinished
task, everything that you're just
circulating over and over in your head,
just get it down and onto paper. And
there's actual neuroscience to back
this. Your brain treats starting as the
hardest part of the task. though if you
can just get going even as tiny or
insignificant as it may seem you know
often times I'll go and just pick the
smallest part of any task you know say I
need to go and write a new newsletter I
may just go and decide on the subject
line or if I need to write an ex post it
may start by just sitting at my computer
opening up Hype Fury and just writing
that first sentence just take the
smallest action possible tiny actions
now lead to big results over the long
term in addition Addition to doing the
2-minute mental cleanse in the morning,
you can also apply this technique all
throughout your day. Stuck writing a
blog post? Start with the worst
paragraph possible, 2 minutes. If stuck
going and creating your first YouTube
video? Just sit down and turn the camera
on. The magic isn't in the 2 minutes.
It's in the pattern of breaking the
overthinking. Every morning, start the
clock. Do your brain dump onto a pen and
paper. Pick the biggest task you need to
get done that day. And then ask
yourself, what would the quickest
version in 2 minutes of this task look
like? and then just get going. Forel has
this amazing quote. The creative advice
I would give right now, all your fears,
your flaws, your insecurities, your
guilts, your pressures, look at them on
a list. Know they are all distractions.
Once you do that, you'll experience your
life uninterrupted. Action beats
anxiety. Step two, the momentum
multiplier. This part takes 2 minutes.
Jerry Seinfeld focused on one small win.
Writing one joke every single day. this
small tiny win, right, of just creating
one joke a day. Fast forward 10 years
later, 20 years later, Jerry Seinfeld is
worth over $1.1 billion and the Seinfeld
show is worth over 7.6 billion. Insane.
You go and you think about creating a $7
billion show, many people just get
paralyzed going, "Where the hell do I
start?" It starts in your daily actions.
I was talking to a founder named Pierre
last week, and I asked Pierre, you know,
Pierre, what are your five-year goals?
Now, he told me that he wanted to be
making $80 million per year. So, then I
went to him and I said, "Well, what are
you currently doing right now?" He said,
" $10,000 a month." I said, "Okay, quite
the gap." And so, what are the actions
that you're currently looking at taking?
And he told me how he was rejigging his
offer. He was launching a new e-commerce
site. He was launching a new YouTube
channel. He was going to launch a new
YouTube business channel as well as a
newsletter. And what I realized was that
because he was trying to do something so
big, you know, he thought that the
actions that he needed to take this week
were that big as well. And what this was
causing Pierre was just a lot of
analysis paralysis. The truth is to get
to that kind of number, you need to
focus on the smallest amount of actions
today that you can take to go and get
there. Here's some examples of some
small win categories. Now, on the
learning side of things, it may just
mean going and starting a new book and
reading the first 10 pages. On the
revenue side of things, it may mean just
rejigging one offer or getting your
first 10 customers. Now, creation wins
could be writing a hundred words. It
could just mean publishing that first
post. Every morning when doing this
2-minute exercise, ask yourself, "What's
one small win I can generate today?"
Write it down. Make it specific,
measurable, actionable, realistic, and
time bound. As Les Brown said, "You
don't have to be great to get started,
but you have to get started to be
great." Show up small and keep showing
up. Step three, the discomfort
challenge. This takes one minute. It's
called the 5-second rule. Now, whenever
you think of something that you need to
get done, you go simply and countdown
from 5 4 3 2 1 and then take the
smallest action possible to immediately
move forward and get that thing going.
After going and practicing this for just
one week, it completely rewired my brain
at 25 years old. Because the truth is
that even just a messy first action is
better than a perfect action in one
year. I used to run from every
uncomfortable feeling. You know, having
that hard conversation with a new hire,
I'd avoid it. Publishing a piece of
content, I'd wait till it's perfect.
Releasing that new product, I'd have to
run it by 10 people before I felt ready.
The truth was that I was getting in the
way of my own success. All this
perfectionism was causing me to be
paralyzed and to not just release
things. That's when I developed the
pain-seeking system. It started to hit
me that damn, I was really getting in
the way of my own momentum. You know, I
had become my own worst enemy. So, I
made a new pack with myself. I would
start seeking the pain and getting
through this discomfort. It was from
this discomfort that I was able to
finally go and start getting the real
results that I craved. Now, Mel Robbins
isn't the only person that has this kind
of 54 321 rule. Elon Musk is the same
way. inside of his companies. He has one
operating principle, a maniacal sense of
urgency. When someone goes and says,
"Oh, we can have that done in a year."
It's why not one month or hey, I'll get
that done to you next Friday. Why not
this Tuesday? Often times, our job as
leaders is to amp it up. To take those
longer timelines and make them shorter
and if we want to expect this of the
teams and people around us, well, we
have to expect it of ourselves. Here are
discomfort examples by level. So level
one beginner is just, you know, trying a
new type of food or just diving into
that simple task that you've been
putting off. Level two is intermediate.
This is when you're going to go and ask
for that raise you've been putting off
or maybe it's letting go of someone in
the company you started. Level three is
expert. This is when you have the
courage to go and maybe pivot a business
that's no longer working and choose a
new direction. Or maybe it's quitting
your job to go and bet on your calling
in life. No matter what stage you're at,
you know, leaning into discomfort in
life is where the real magic happens. As
Walt Disney said, the way to get started
is to quit talking and begin doing. Push
into your discomfort. Pain is the path.
And that leads us to the next step. Step
four, the ship messy protocol. This
takes 2 minutes. It's not ready yet. I
said those words 127 times before
starting Founder OS. You know, at first,
you know, I wasn't sure. Did I have the
skills and ability to go and teach
people audience growth? Sure. I had
built Herb to 14 million people and I'd
been doing this stuff for 10 years. But
there were parts of me that still
wondered if I was ready. You know, I
know that this isn't just me, right?
Thousands, if not millions of other
people also struggle with this same
limiting belief before launching
something. You know, there's this myth
in entrepreneurship that, you know, you
need to have it all figured out and then
launch it. When the truth is that you
launch it and then you figure it out.
The ship messy protocol all comes down
to launching something when it's at 70%.
You know, when it doesn't quite look
right, that's probably the time just to
get it out there. If you're not
embarrassed by your first launch of a
product, you probably launch too late.
So, here's what you're going to do.
You're going to write down what you're
overperfecting. You're going to write it
down and then you're going to go and
ship it today. You know, I shipped
Founder OS just at 70%. I had six
modules, a community built in school,
and I had the first 47 sales in one day.
From all that feedback, I was then able
to iterate, launch six more modules that
people actually wanted, launch a founder
retreat, and compound it now today of a
community of over 1,400 high growth
founders. And this doesn't just apply to
business. You know, it can apply to
learning a new skill like that first
string on a guitar or running that first
mile of a 5m race. Here's why the 70%
rule works. You know, at 40%, you should
probably hold off. You know, if you
launch this thing, you may actually
damage your reputation. At 70%, you're
still a bit embarrassed by it, but this
is the perfect time to put that thing
out there. At 90%, you've probably
waited far too long and you may have
even missed the boat. Here's some
shipping messy examples. Know you wanted
to start that community forever, just go
and launch something in school. You've
always wanted to have a newsletter, go
and publish the first one using Kit. You
want to launch a new business, just go
and launch a landing page. You know,
oftentimes these big projects start with
just shipping the first thing messy. The
ship messy protocol is what's going to
help you go and accomplish your goals.
Let's go and break it down to the five
core steps. Number one, define your
minimum viable value. Right? What's that
bit of value that you can get going and
then launch it. Two, define the 70%
rule. Once you've got 70% towards where
you're trying to really get to with it,
launch it. Number three, launch the
thing with a disclaimer. Let people know
this is just version one. Number four,
open yourself up to feedback. Tell
people to go and let you know how they
can improve the product and what they
want to see. And then go and number
five, respond to that feedback, iterate
on the product, and just keep going. You
know, your ability to go and iterate
quickly on these five cycles is what is
going to help create a loyal consumer
base. Mark Zuckerberg famously said,
"Move fast and break things." And this
is what has made him one of many Silicon
Valley billionaires. And the truth is
that when you're building something, you
just need to get it out there. The
market, AI, everything is moving so fast
these days. And speed is your
competitive advantage as a founder. You
will benefit by just shipping messy and
getting it out there. Step five, the one
domino decision. This part takes 3
minutes. Just 4 months ago, I was in big
su California on the coast taking some
time away from all technology to just
reflect on you know my life, my business
and you know what the core things I
could focus on to really move my life
forward as fast as possible and hit my
10-year goals in the next 6 months. And
when I went and distilled what the one
big domino would be to go and get
myself, you know, towards this big
dream, this vision, it was having 4
hours daily to work on an exceptional
piece of content every day and ship it.
You know, if you're stuck, it's often
times because you're just trying to do
way too many things all at once versus
focused on the one core thing that can
go and move things forward in your life
in a big way. Is it crafting your offer?
Is it refining your product? Is it
making one big hire? Now, why is this
called the one domino framework? Imagine
every second of your life as a domino.
Each domino is tipping the future in one
direction or another. And here's the
crazy part. If you line them up
correctly, a single domino today can
unleash unstoppable momentum, knocking
down walls you thought were impossible.
So many founders go and tell me that
they don't have enough time. But the
truth is, they just don't have their
priorities right. So, here's what you're
going to do. You're going to go and
review all your goals and take 3 minutes
and then write down the one most
important thing. your one big domino.
You may be wondering, "Well, Matt, how
did you figure out that exceptional
content creation was that one big
domino?" You know, years ago when I was
first starting my personal brand at the
age of 30, I had a mentor named Justin.
And I said, you know, Justin, I just
want to do whatever it takes to, you
know, go and achieve this mission of
inspiring 100 million founders to
accomplish their dreams through proven
systems. You know, what's that one thing
you think I should really focus on? His
next statement literally changed my
life. He said, "Matt, set your audience
on fire." It was that statement that
caused me to go on a deep dive of what
it would take to go and set my online
audience on fire. And after a lot of
analysis, it came down to just one
simple thing. Exceptional content
creation. I stopped everything. I
focused only on amazing content across
YouTube, Instagram, Tik Tok, X, and
LinkedIn. And everything changed. You
know, this content didn't just drive
leads. It created a movement. It
created, you know, an ability to go and
hire people so much easier and it built
what Founder OS is today. So, here's
some real examples. You know, you're
stuck because you're not going for
workouts. Well, your one domino maybe
just to go and walk to the gym today.
Stuck going and trying to create an
offer. Well, your one domino may be to
go and write a one pager on who you're
looking to target and how you can help
them. So, here's how you can go and use
this in your everyday life. You know,
when you go into any day, make sure that
you are clear on that one domino you can
complete that will make that day a
success. If you just get this thing
done, when you stack that up over 365
days, getting 1% better every single
day, you're 37 times better in a year,
and making massive leaps towards your
dreams. As Winston Churchill once said,
"Perfection is the enemy of progress.
Done is better than perfect." Some of
you are going to go and watch this and
do nothing. You're going to wait for
motivation and it's never going to
strike. But a small select few of you
will do this every day for the next 90
days. Tomorrow, your mind will be clear
with this 10-minute system. In 30 days,
you'll be mind blown around the things
you're able to achieve. In 90 days, your
one big domino, as well as all that 70%
rule stacked up, is going to help you go
and accomplish those goals at record
speed. And in one year, you'll be
shocked about where you're at. If you're
looking to go and join a community of
like-minded founders that are all going
and gaining momentum in their lives and
businesses, you should go and check out
Founder OS via the link in the
description. I've also gone and prepared
an unstuck playbook, which is everything
in this video listed into an insane
checklist you can go and implement today
in your life. And you can go and check
that out in the description as well.
Don't forget to hit subscribe and I'll
see you in the next