The biggest life hack isn't adding more
stuff to your life. It's actually
subtracting stuff that's broken. Imagine
trying to clean your room, but not even
taking the trash out inside of it. And
the same thing goes for your life. We
often times think that to become the
person we're looking to become or to
create the business of our dreams, we
need to keep adding things. Often times,
the best approach is radical deletion.
The system I use before I actually go
and build a system is that I ask myself,
what can I remove? The same thing goes
for your life. What are the
relationships that are no longer
supporting you? Delete them. What are
those health habits that are actually
moving you further away from your goals?
Delete that You don't need new
habits.