All right, the richest people in the
world are 75% entrepreneurs,
15% investors, 7% are athletes, and 3%
are artists.
0%
are employees. Now, before you just go
and spam the comments below and get
really angry at me, I'm just simply
saying that it's important to have
leverage, right? Leverage through media,
through equity, through code, through
people, through something that you are
building and have ownership in.
A salary for most people isn't going to
get them to their version of rich. Now,
everyone's different, everyone's got
their own approach, so it's no
one-size-fits-all.
But for most of the folks that I speak
with,
you know, they're looking to go and
build leverage through media and a
personal brand. Go and build a product
based on code or community,
a digital product, whatever, right?
Something though that they own at the
end of the day. Because
sometimes, you know, a salary just
doesn't cut it. And when we look at the
distribution of the richest people in
the world, I think there's a lot of
people
that need to figure out which one are
they trying to become. Is it an
entrepreneur? Do you see yourself as an
investor?
Or maybe you're an artist or an an
athlete.