All right, this is the psychology of how
I go and get ahead in life. So, first
things first, this
is my weekly reflection.
I go and get Claude code to go and
create a PDF document of every single
thing
I've been working on
and help even come up with, you know,
recommendations that, you know, Jensen
Huang,
Elon Musk, Jeff Bezos, or Munger,
Schwarzman, Ray Dalio, you know, a bunch
of billionaires, basically, would
recommend I
go and action.
So, I do this
every single week.
The general process is step one, get
into nature, take a break.
Step two, let the thoughts percolate.
Step three, scheme and plot.
Step four, write down
some core, you know, reflections
with clarity.
Step five, upload
to or airdrop back to my computer.
And then,
step six, [music] enter into Claude
code, uh and let it enter plan mode.
And step seven,
then start executing all those kind of
clear thinking reflections you [music]
have.
The end of day,
I think it's clear thinking that then
leads to pure magic. We're letting this
thing cook up right now.
Letting it ride.
And uh that's kind of my process.
Hope this is helpful to some of you.