George Lucas wrote three Star Wars
movies before the first one was even
released, and here's why it was genius.
>> [music]
>> When he had finally released the first
movie, he already had the next two ready
to go, and that first one ended up
hitting box office records and hitting
the number one spot in history. And so,
I think it's just the ultimate example
of betting on yourself. When you're
going and you're building your own
worlds, think about your business as big
as you can. If you need to even, go and
upload your company vision and strategy
to chat GPT, and then get it to go and
make your vision 10 times bigger. I
think just the simple exercise of going
and seeing how big your vision could be
allows you to start expanding your mind
more.