If you want to speak like the 1%, you
got to [music] break this bad habit. For
years, I tried to sound like other
entrepreneurs. I would see a speech from
Gary Vee or you see something from Tony
Robbins or Jesse Sler, and I would try
to embody their energy in what I do. But
what I realized over time is that, you
know, I'm not them. I don't view the
world the same. I don't use the same
language, and we don't even have the
same energy. What I've realized is that
my uniqueness, it's [music] me. And so,
I'm here to tell you that your unique
energy is what's going to separate you.
You don't need to be like Alex Heroszy.
Ivon Gazi, Tony Robbins, or Gary Vee.
You just need to get comfortable being
you. The reality is is that you have
your own way of speaking, your own
energy, your own tonality, and it's your
own quirks and vibes that people are
going to resonate with, and that's going
to separate you from everyone