your personal brand will either make you
money or waste hours and days of your
time the question is no longer should
you build a personal brand but instead
how do you build your personal brand so
that it makes you money it took me
nearly a decade to crack the code but
now I have two businesses that have both
10x since I intentionally started
building my personal brand so today I'm
giving you the exact seven steps I use
to make my personal brand profitable and
to maximize my freedom as a Founder
because this isn't just about going
viral or being famous it's about going
and designing a brand that works for you
and with you a brand that compounds
every single day and that pays you back
for years to come this is a
life-changing process we're about to
dive into but let me tell you creating a
profit personal brand isn't luck it's a
system and by the end of this video
you'll know exactly how to go and
leverage the system to achieve founder
freedom and control over your own brand
that lets you live on your own terms
create value and connect with Millions
let's get
started step one discovering the niche
of you the most important foundation of
your personal brand is simple
understanding you the key is to start
where most people end figuring out what
makes you different and Unforgettable
what do you want to be known for what
unique perspective or Talent do you have
that most people are drawn to
what have you been downplaying just to
fit in this isn't about faking
Perfection it's about finding the parts
of yourself that are worth sharing and
owning them your brand doesn't need to
go and be like everyone else's it just
needs to be authentic this is what will
separate you from all the noise out
there get a pen and paper out and write
down your seven core pillars once you've
completed your list the foundation for
your personal brand is set great work
you've identified those core pillars for
yourself the parts that will make your
brand Unforgettable and Uniquely
Yours step two Define your core values
and vision let's talk about your compass
I'm talking values purpose and vision if
you've ever felt lost in business or
overwhelmed this compasses why these
guide posts will help you stay aligned
as you scale ask yourself what are my
non-negotiable values what impact do I
want to make with this brand how can I
go and measure success Beyond money
write down the answers to those
questions here my non-negotiable values
love I love myself and others fully
insanely simple I remove all unnecessary
complexity leaving only Essentials and
create Clarity and power freedom I have
time financial and location abundance
I'm free to be my truest and fullest
self I have the freedom and space to
think Ponder and be creative Community I
have deep connections meaningful
relationships and a sense of belonging
creativity I impact Inspire and innovate
nature I explore go on Epic Adventures
have fun and discover new places with
people I love the clear your values the
easier it becomes to make decisions that
feel right for you and when you're
building a brand Clarity equals
confidence step three understand who
you're talking to now that you're clear
on who you are let's find out who cares
step three is all about identifying and
truly understanding your audience your
audience isn't just clients or followers
they're people whose problems you solve
here are some questions that you can ask
yourself what problems does my audience
face where do they spend their time
online what would make their life easier
knowing your audience will bring Clarity
into your strategy and decisions no
matter what state AG of the personal
branding process that you're currently
at because if you know your audience
well then you know exactly where to aim
the best and the fastest way to get
clarity around what your audience wants
is to simply just ask them here are
questions you can use in a survey to go
and interview people that are part of
your ideal audience and get to know them
a lot better what content topics would
you love to see me dive into what is the
biggest challenge in your business right
now what is your biggest goal right now
what does success look like for for you
by the end of this year the goal of your
personal brand is to be a guide that
leads your audience to their biggest
goals and helps them overcome their
deepest
challenges step four creating your brand
identity map and defining your unique
voice and style on step four we're going
to go and take all this inner work and
transform it into an external and
Visually unique brand identity that
represents your own Mission Vision and
values this is your unique voice look
and feel and it's what's going to make
your brand recognizable at an instant
glance translate everything you've
learned about yourself and your audience
into a brand identity that's
unmistakenly you this is what gives your
brand a soul before I show you my own
brand guide here's the mindset you need
to adopt when creating your own think
about how you show up is your brand
playful or serious formal or laid-back
for me Clarity and freedom are key when
I chose those elements for my brand it
wasn't just because they look good it
was because they match what I stand for
here's the deal your voice and style
should be consistent across every single
touch point where your brand exists it's
not just about looking good here's a
sneak peak of my brand identity here are
my core colors here are the common
elements that we go and sprinkle in
across my videos here's how I like to
style my short form videos and here's
the style of font that we use across all
of the different platforms I exist on
these small elements all add up to
create my unique brand identity we also
have nine core brand Commandments that
guide everything we do around my brand
here they are original we are unlike any
other we are unique storytelling we
create stories that travel stories
Define our brand artist touch stop
seeing it as marketing start seeing it
as taking up space as an artist
impeccable design tiny details Stack Up
copy words are power powerful we write
like we speak luxury experience Elevate
Inspire and overd deliver at Key moments
taste we Flex our creativity we are
creative Geniuses make art not content
dreamy Beauty matters we paint a picture
of the dream life magic we create Magic
for Founders if you are disciplined in
implementing your visual brand your
audience is going to be able to
recognize you without even knowing what
profile posted it but it was yours to
create a deck with all the details that
you just saw in mind here's the process
grab a pen and paper we're going to go
and write down the core aspects of your
brand identity starting with your voice
Define your voice what's the vibe of
your brand playful serious inspiring
bold how do you want people to feel when
they hear your message write three to
five words that describe the tone you
want to be known for visual elements
what are your Brand's core colors pick
two to four colors that reflect the vibe
you're going for font style style is it
modern classic handwritten choose one or
two that match your personality and
brand logos and symbols do you have a
signature logo or symbol that people can
easily recognize what icon or shape
represents your Brand's core values
brand identity Commandments think of
these as guiding principles that your
brand lives by here are some questions
to help guide you what's the unique
promise you're making to your audience
how do you go and stand out visually and
stylistically from others in your space
think of this as designing the DNA of
your brand each choice you make here
adds up to a recognizable powerful
identity that your audience will
remember and instantly
recognize step five positioning your
brand story and building trust you need
to build trust and that trust starts
with a story that only you can tell
trust is currency without it you're just
another voice in The Noise with it
you're someone people come back to again
and again establish your brand direction
or how you're positioning yourself as an
authority people need to trust you
before they'll invest in you and the way
that they build trust through constant
consumption of your style in
storytelling when people know why you do
what you do they're more likely to trust
you here's the truth people don't
connect with Brands they connect with
people they want to know why you do what
you do they want to feel the heartbeat
behind your your
work step six your content Pathways
laying out your content
GPS step six is all about your content
content is the life blood of any
personal brand this is how you attract
and engage your audience daily if your
personal brand is an engine content is
the fuel the power of social media is
too large to ignore in a founder-led
business and yes creating content for
your personal brand can be intimidating
here's how I go and approach creating
content to take the edge off the process
you want clear lanes for your ideas
videos posts articles whatever it is
your goal is to create a system that
brings you visibility without taking
over your life figure out where you want
to show up then ask what kind of content
am I best at creating what can I post
consistently without burning out then
implement the single most necessary
system to this entire personal branding
equation that will tie your personal
brand back to Serious Financial returns
for your business the content GPS your
content GPS is a strategic map that
guides what you post where you post and
how often this isn't about being
everywhere all the time it's about
showing up intentionally in the places
that matter most there's no one size
fits all my advice choose three main
themes or pillars that represent your
brand then build content around those
themes consistently this makes your
content creation process automatic
scalable and stress-free take a
screenshot pause this video or download
this in the description below but this
is the founder content machine that goes
and kickstarts the content creation
process for my entire personal brand
each time here's how it works step one
start by selecting three categories you
want to be known for these are the lanes
for your brand the areas you're going to
dominate so whether it's sharing
audience growth tips Community Building
strategies or scalable systems and
different Secrets choose your categories
and be specific step two pick your
approach are you the expert who knows
this topic cold or are you the curator
Gathering insights and learning
alongside your audience both work just
choose the one that feels authentic to
you step three and now it's time to go
and fill out your content machine Let's
generate 30 ideas in 30 minutes I'm
serious set a timer pull up a blank
document and let's go to town use these
categories helpful deep dive reflection
and
vulnerable step seven tools allies and
support assembling your team imagine
this you've crafted your content your
brand is gaining momentum but you're
trying to keep all the wheels turning
just by yourself it's like trying to
steer a ship solo through a storm so so
what's missing the people the tools and
the support that makes it all
sustainable I'm going to go and cover
all of those elements in detail right
now having the right support means you
don't have to do everything all alone
get clear on the tools that you need
whether it's project management software
a good camera or a supportive team
member the goal is to ensure your brand
runs like a machine with or without you
and when I say team I don't just mean
people who work for you think of allies
mentors or even legends that go and
inspire you this journey is easier when
you're surrounded by the right people as
you scale here's the initial critical
team that you're going to want in place
to build a profitable personal brand a
social manager to go and grow your
profitable media Empire a video editor
to go and create inspiring videos and a
designer to help you go and build your
brand with imagery as well as a tech
lead to ensure the machine is going and
running smoothly and here are the tools
I use to build my profitable personal
brand
pype Fury to schedule X content Athena
for elite executive assistants to manage
my calendar and emails so I can remove
myself from operations tweet Hunter X to
find inspiration for Content HubSpot for
sales school for the founder OS
Community stripe for payments webflow
for our website testimonial. to collect
testimonials notion for a company Wiki
Google Drive for photos videos and
b-roll Google docs to document all of
our systems zapier for automations figma
for designs loom for screen recording
and reduce meetings type form for a
foundos application and to get feedback
from Founders and then a sauna for
project management building this brand
isn't just about money or fame it's
about freedom freedom to create on your
own terms to choose what matters and to
connect deeply with the people who
resonate with you when you build a brand
that truly represents you it becomes a
beacon a signal to others that you're
here you're real and you're ready to
make an impact if youve made it this far
you're ready for the journey this isn't
just a week-long process it's a
lifechanging commitment to creating a
brand that works for you and builds the
future that you want