This is a leadership blueprint and it is
a six-part document that I use as a
blueprint to help founders build a team
that runs without them. And to give you
a true under-the-hood look at the
system, this is the exact document we
built for Lauren Mitchell. Lauren runs a
financial consulting firm doing $4
million a year, eight team members, 40
active [music] clients. She was spending
around 25 hours a week in meetings
because she was [music] the org chart.
Every decision, every escalation, every
senior client relationship, all running
through one person. Let's see how this
leadership blueprint transforms this
from a business that runs the founder
into the ground into a business that
runs itself. This is what we go and help
founders with. When founders don't have
a clear structure in place, right, for
their company, typically what you see is
these structures where all 20 people in
a company are all going and constantly
bugging the founder. And here you can
see as an example with Lauren, she had
roughly, you know, six people all going
and reporting to her, meaning that in
any given moment it was a mess. Right?
After this we can see that we've put in
the right sort of org chart in place so
that she's got just three direct reports
and those people are adequately going
and managing the folks underneath them,
right? Going from eight direct reports
to three, right? This also creates
greater, you know, lines of authority
inside of a company and then freeing her
up to be more of a CEO, right? Working
on the business versus constantly being
stuck in the weeds of the business. Now,
that's not enough though, right? While
this looks sexy and all, there's a
greater level of granularity needed,
right? So that people know which people
inside of your company they should go to
for different kinds of problems or
decisions or the kind of decisions that
you just want to empower them to make.
So one thing I like to do here is have
clear decision authority across the
business. And one of the great
frameworks to do that is something
called RACI, right? It stands for who's
responsible, accountable, consulted and
informed. When you take something like,
you know, revenue targets in my company,
right? I'm ultimately responsible for
those revenue targets as the CEO. That's
exactly what I've gone and done here for
Lauren's business, right? We've gone and
mapped out for all the strategic
decisions, things like new service
offerings, hiring decisions, partnership
agreements, right? Who's accountable?
Who needs to be consulted, responsible,
and who is informed? What this starts to
do is make sure that people across the
company actually know what falls under
their area. And when you go and you roll
this out on a leadership meeting, you
start to see people's like eyes perk up,
right? Because finally, they understand
what you, the CEO, are requiring of
them. What your expectations are.
Because so many times there's just these
unwritten agreements, right? We think
that someone should know what they're
supposed to do, but we haven't made it
explicit. RACI helps you get over that
by just being transparent as to your
expectations and transparent about who
ultimately owns the given things across
your business. And so it's great to do
this across client delivery, operations,
right? Finance, really like who's owning
proposals, budget allocations, right? In
the details is where it matters, right?
So we're just detailing out those
responsibilities so there's a lot more
clarity across the team. And this allows
you to move a lot faster, right? Now,
when it comes to role scorecards, okay?
This is where we go again, a layer even
deeper. Going and drawing up what these
people are actually accountable for,
right? So there's no ambiguity. We don't
want people wondering, right? What the
mission of the company is, what the kind
of key results they're responsible for,
really the kind of decisions they're set
to be making. Here I've gone and mapped
out for Lauren her key results and
decision authority, right? Closing
clients, delivering keynotes, big
figurehead type stuff, right? But
stopping things like just answering
non-critical requests, tool purchases
under $500, attending every weekly
stand-up, right? We're trying to get her
out of the weeds. It's not just Lauren
though that I want to go and map this
out for because in order for her to be
able to remove herself from more of the
operations, right? We need to make sure
that those core leaders on our team,
folks like Rachel, our, you know, head
of delivery, our COO, our CFO, they're
also clear on what they're responsible
for then, right? So, in this case, the
head of delivery needs to be delivering
an incredible net promoter score, zero
deliverables shipped without QA reviews,
and onboarding 100% of new clients
within 5 days. And so, we do the same
thing across every core person in our
company. Even in my businesses, right?
Every about 90 days, I go and draw up my
company, the different stages of it, and
what I need people to now be responsible
for across my whole business. And so, I
often times think of it something that
you're not just like setting it and
forgetting it, right? It's something
that's good to revisit. You know, here
you can see I was kind of drawing up my
business, the flywheel and stages behind
it, on paper at first. Then I went and
had some of my team in a room with a
whiteboard, and we went and started
drawing this all up. And this is kind of
what it looked like, right? We were
really trying to go and remove chaos and
complexity wherever it existed, because
even in my businesses, right? Just like
every business, they all default to
chaos. It's important that we're always
pulling it back to driving systems, you
know? If I'm being honest, I don't
really like making systems. The truth is
that I make systems so that I can have
freedom, right? And so, I'm making these
systems out of necessity, right? Not out
of some hobby I enjoy doing. The thing
is, every time I go and map out my
business like this right here, and I go
and see the kind of core systems we need
across awareness, inquiries, sales,
onboarding, delivery, collections, and
renewal. You know, after this process, I
feel such a sense of relief, right?
Because from there, we've mapped out
each of the systems that we need to have
an impeccable client delivery from start
to finish. I'm able to go and empower
the leaders around me to own different
parts of the process. And, you know,
sure enough, 2 weeks, 4 weeks, 2 months
after exercises like this, you know, I'm
able to go and remove myself from little
pieces that sometimes just creep in,
right, and start taking up my time. This
is the kind of exercise that I love
going and leading founders through
because often times they've never done
this. And so, this kind of process
starts to clean up all the gunk in your
business, all the kind of BS that's
finding its way to you, and allows you
to run a much more clean company. We've
gone and we've done that, right? We've
even identified a new hire that Lauren
needs to make. And then, this is where
it comes down to then the meeting
rhythm, okay? And so, I told you in my
business, I run this level 10 meeting on
Monday every single week with my core
leadership team. Every one of my
departments then runs a level 10 meeting
as well. So, my content team has one,
marketing team, sales team. What I go
and do here for founders is really
helping them understand their own
meeting rhythm as well. When are they
having leadership meetings, operations
stand-ups, growth stand-ups. In this
case, something like an all-hands
meeting every month to bring the whole
company together to keep on track. And
then, making sure that every single
quarter you're going and mapping out the
goals for the next quarter for the
company as well as every individual.
Now, that's exactly where we get into
then that side of it, right? If what
you're seeing right now is what you want
for your business, well, this is the
system that we go and install inside a
Founder OS. Your assessment is
identified, your decision authority is
then defined, your role scorecards are
all mapped out across the core roles
inside of your business. And I'm not
talking templates here, right? These are
custom-built around your team, right?
Your leadership and really your specific
decision loops. You can go and check it
out via the first link in the
description. Apply to Founder OS.
There's only 15 spots a month. Founders
doing 30K to a million dollars a month
or more. Now, let's get into the OKRs.
So, OKRs come from Google. It's the way
that they'd gone and planned out their
business from the get-go, right? Every
person is getting a clear objective and
then measurable key results. And so,
typically businesses have goals that are
vague, right? And what we want to make
sure is that everything is smart, right?
Specific, measurable, actionable,
realistic, and time-bound. And so, it
should be easy after 90 days to
determine did that thing actually get
done or not? And it's a mix of judging
folks based on their OKRs and the
completion of them, as well as their
adherence to your company values. That
is how you're going to judge and grade
the kind of folks that are working with
you. Okay? And so, this is kind of what
that looks like here, going and really
standardizing those goals, making sure
everyone's clear on them. And this is
the kind of stuff that you're reviewing
every single week on your leadership
meetings. From there, it's really then
going and mapping out road maps, right?
So, that we're getting some traction. In
Lauren's business, she needs to make
some key hires. And so, we're mapping
out the kind of hires that she needs to
make in what order, drawing up those job
descriptions they can go live and she
can start recruiting those people ASAP.
Now, that last pillar I had said, right,
were dashboards. And oftentimes founders
overcomplicate this. We just want to
have one spot where we can see all the
core metrics across your business. And
for most businesses, you know, there's
typically like 10 to 15 core metrics
that go all the way from things like
client health to revenue to operations
and marketing. These dashboards can be
built as simply as in Google Sheets. You
know, in this case, I'm going and
building this using a tool called Vercel
as well then cloud code for this
founder. And so, this is just one core
step and phase inside a Founderless
where we go and help systematize
founders businesses, remove them from
the operations, allow them to be more of
the owner and architect of their
business versus just the operator and
engine of it. And along the way, build a
powerful social media machine. That's
interesting to you, you like what I just
showed here in this video, you want to
check it out, you should go and apply to
Founderless via the link in the
description. Thanks so much for
watching. If you want more of a
breakdown as to how I go and remove
myself in the operations of my
businesses, go and check out this next
video. Thanks for watching and let's win
together.