What if you could achieve your 10ear
goals in just 6 months? This is how you
can do it with AI. Every single month, I
have something called the personal board
meeting, which is something I do with
myself to go and basically understand my
30-day business goals, my personal
goals, and how these ladder up to my 1
year, 3year, and 10-year vision. Now,
the cool thing is when I've gone and
charted out this plan for the month, I
can simply go and download the Google
slide deck, go and then upload that to
chat. Now, what I'm able to go and do is
go and prompt CatchBT, "All right, you
have my November board meeting inside of
the project files. I want you to go and
look at that whole document and then go
and synthesize the top 20 projects
ranked from best and most important to
the ones that's least important that I
should be focused on to finish 2025
strong." And then the beautiful thing
here is it's taking that board meeting
as well as all the other core documents
that I have here inside of this project
and it's able to synthesize that to let
me know, you know, the core projects
that I should be most focused by