Uh rule number one in business is don't
lose money.
Rule number two
is don't forget number one. It's a quote
from
Warren Buffett.
And too many founders I speak to,
they don't know the freaking numbers.
You ask them what their profit margin
is, they're not really sure.
You ask them what their year-over-year
cash collected is,
they don't have a clue.
And I'm all about being an artist here,
right? That's definitely my core. But I
also know that in life, as I became more
aware of the numbers,
you know, everything just got a lot
easier and honestly just had a lot more
peace of mind while I was building. So,
if you're trying to get a hold of your
numbers, my number one tip
is make sure that you get a CFO or
fractional CFO in your business. And the
second thing is, get that person to send
you a scorecard every Friday of your
core metrics. Cash collected, revenue,
close rate, show rate, and anything else
you may be curious about so you get a
handle on this