You're using AI completely wrong. Most
founders treat it like some shiny
assistant. Type in an answer, prompt it,
and move on. But when you leverage AI as
the second brain of your company, every
person, every project, every process
gets smarter. In this video, I'll show
you the exact AI workflow that powers
the core departments of my company. And
the wild part is, if you unlock an extra
40% of productivity at each step, you
will mathematically 10x the productivity
of your team. Let's get into it. Step
one, the prompt stock. When you're
looking to go and build AI leverage
across your entire company, you need one
core document that hosts all of the core
prompts. So, it's easily sharable across
every team member. And so, inside of
this prompt stock, you can see I've got
prompts for things like Instagram reels,
YouTube scripts, Instagram carousels,
you name it, right? Basically, every
core content format across my entire
personal media company has a prompt
associated with it. We're not talking
basic ass prompts here. You need to take
pride in your prompts because the more
powerful your prompt, the more powerful
the output. Everyone gets obsessed with
prompts. They think it's like the end
product, but really it's the starting
point. It sets that initial amount of
context that you can really go and
transform the output of your team.
Here's an example of an Instagram
carousels prompt. Okay. What I'm doing
is really establishing, you know, the
kind of tone as to what I'm looking for
here, right? I want it to be, you know,
the best copywriter and designer of
viral Instagram carousels. And I wanted
to make sure that you know it's creating
carousels at the level of like David
Oggovie, Claude Hopkins, Gary Halpert,
Eugene Schwarz, some of the best
copywriters to ever have existed. Then
I'm giving it the criteria by which, you
know, we're looking to attract this
level of founder to founder West. The
kind of founder that's doing over 100K
per month, that's looking to remove
themselves from operations, get more of
their time back, and scale their own
media company with organic content. From
there, I've gone and referenced the core
pieces that I'm going to go and show you
that are inserted into the project
knowledge of the given projects. Okay,
basically every core content format gets
its own unique project knowledge and its
own unique prompt as you're seeing here.
You want to go and probably create
prompts for all the different content
formats. Well, definitely go to the link
in the description, go and download that
so you get a quick cheat sheet to get
started. Step two, organize your
systems. You know, you want to get the
maximum amount of power out of AI. Well,
AI eats systems. This is where I see so
many founders fall short. And so, what I
want to show you here is the elite level
of getting your systems organized
because after all, that's what we do
here, right? So, what I've got here is
the founder brand positioning. Inside of
this, I synthesize the core messaging
behind everything that we do at Founder
OS. So, you can see the best way to
build an online business is a personal
brand. If you want to build a personal
brand, you want it to be, you know,
beautiful, systemized, and hyper
profitable. And the best way to do that
is with a content GPS system. And so I
get into then all the details behind the
content GPS. And this is super useful
because in a lot of our content we talk
about obviously our brand and what we're
all about as well as our core mechanism
which is the content GPS which is the
most powerful system I've ever created
to go and drive conversions from
content. So then we have you know things
like our different offers. In this case,
our edge offer as an example, which is
this kind of private advisory that I
have for founders, helping them onetoone
on calls every other week, as well as
giving them the ability to text me
anytime they want and giving seven core
team members on their team access to all
of our systems and over 50 live sessions
a month where me as well as my entire
media company team are all able to go
and help them. Not only that, right, but
I go and have detailed marketing plans
that I feed as well as things like our
entire strategy for Founder OS Studios.
I'm giving it the highle strategy, the
detailed branding, all the core
mechanisms and systems that we have as
well as who is responsible across my
entire team for the different aspects of
our content. Right? So here you can see
the different pieces of our systems,
right? All the way from awareness
through to renewal and giving it a sense
of okay, these are the different people
on my team in charge of this. If you
know, for whatever reason, not only do
we need to create content, but then I
need to delegate it to someone, it can
go and advise who I need to delegate it
to and it understands my overall content
strategy as well as company kind of
reporting structure. Lastly, what I see
a lot of founders needing to have is a
synthesized customer avatar because at
the end of the day, you're making
content for a specific kind of person.
So, in here, you can see I've kind of
synthesized this core avatar. someone
named Jack who's making over 200k per
month, wants more of their time back,
wants to be successful and to design,
you know, the life of their dreams and
wants a company that really ultimately
grows when they're offline, right? And
so I've synthesized the core aspects of
this avatar and I feed this to Claude as
well. It's because I have all of these
systems organized that I'm able to go
and tool up, you know, the given project
at the maximum capacity possible. So it
has all the context it needs to then
work its magic. You don't just need AI.
You need systems for AI to actually plug
into. Now, here's the real inflection
point, right? These systems aren't just
for the CEO. The goal here is that we
have these systems all documented and
we're able to level up the entire team.
And this is exactly how we think about
things in Founder OS with the thousands
of founders that we're serving every
single week. We're not just going and
helping the core founder. Really, we're
trying to make the founder the most
useless person in the entire business by
leveraging and leveling up the seven
core team members on their team. And the
way to do that is by giving them the
systems, the prompts, the projects, and
the right AI tools so that they can go
and become leveraged and remove the
founder from most the operations. Step
three, building your project knowledge.
This is one project we use all the time
across my team. It's called the voice of
customer. You can see in the project
knowledge here, we've put in our core
offers. And then I've also gone and put
in some core survey responses that we've
received across of the different surveys
we've done of our dream customers across
Found Velocity, Found Edge, which are
some of our highlevel offers or founders
doing over 30K per month looking to go
and remove themselves from operations
and set up their own founder brands.
I've gone and surveyed hundreds of
founders and understand their goals,
their challenges, what they most want or
help with, and the parts that they found
most valuable from working with us. What
I'm able to then do is take the real
words that they've given us and then use
this project now to go and give me
different ideas for how we can evolve
founder OS and the kind of content we
can put out even on this YouTube channel
that's going to go and attract more
founders just like this. And so going
and onboarding AI is very similar to
going onboarding a new employee, right?
You don't just onboard someone and give
them no information, right? You got to
show them the ropes. And the same thing
goes when you're tooling up a claude
project. your project knowledge, just
like the prompt, is something that you
got to take your time with. You know,
I've got a ton of different projects set
up for different needs. I have my market
researcher project here, different
projects for ads, for lead magnets, for
Instagram reels, for workshops, for the
culture at Found for email courses,
YouTube scripts, a CRO, and Instagram
carousels. Right? So, I'd like to set up
projects for individual use cases
because the prompts are going to be
different depending on the use case and
so will the project knowledges. To give
you a quick example here, let's get into
the Instagram carousels prompt here.
Okay, so inside this project, you can
see I've loaded up the prompt inside of
the instructions here. It's all
detailed, ready to go. I like to load it
up in the instructions so that you don't
need to put the prompt in ever again.
It's just there. It's locked. It's
loaded. And my team can go and use this
and rip it. And keep in mind, this kind
of copy that we generated from this has
probably generated over 180 million
organic views over the last year. Now,
inside of the project here, you can see
I've got the dream client avatar, our
different offers. I've got a bunch of
examples of my best content ever. I've
got a bunch of transcripts of me doing
coaching calls, a million words for my
upcoming book, our brand positioning,
our manifesto, you know. So, the key
thing here too is again that product
knowledge alone probably has about 2
million words in it, right? So, you
don't need to have this at the gate, but
you know, from gradually systemizing
more of your business and ideally you
steal a bunch of the systems that we
give you inside of Founder OS, you're
able to leverage this to go and move up
the learning curve super fast. So, let
me show you how I use this. I typically
go and insert my kind of instructions
inside of Claude using Whisper Flow. So,
here we go. I need you to go and create
a Instagram carousel around strategic
laziness that shows people that when
they have the right systems in place
across content, operations, finance, and
audience growth that they're able to be
more strategically lazy as a founder and
let their team do the rest. We'll just
let it go and work its magic here. Here
you can see we've got our strategic
laziness carousel here. So slide one,
the art of strategic laziness. Why the
best founders work less and earn more.
Even that title, it's taking that from
one of my best YouTube videos ever. As
you can see here, then it's indicating
every single slide and the copy that
needs to go on it. I'm not necessarily
taking this one to one and just using
this for the carousel, but it certainly
serves as a lot of inspiration that
we'll use. And the cool thing that I've
noticed with this as well is that in the
case of carousels, it's actually allowed
my designer on my team, Yan, to become
one hell of a copywriter as well. So
that I'm no longer the bottleneck having
to make all this stuff. He's able to be
empowered with my copy, with my projects
and prompts to go and create legendary
carousels that founders love. All right,
so I know that sounds like a lot of
stuff, but the cool thing is I went and
synthesized all of the stuff I just
showed you into my project knowledge
template that you can go and find via
the link in the description. So go and
download that so this doesn't look
nearly as intimidating as it maybe is
coming across right now and can allow
you to get up the learning curve at
record speed. So, now that we've gone
and turned this generic AI into an AI
that actually understands me, let's move
on to the next part here. Step four,
project instructions and memory. I don't
want my team to have to constantly go
back to that prompt stock and update it
every time. Ideally, I just lock and
load the instructions of a given project
with a prompt and it's good to go. So,
here you can see as an example in the
Instagram carousels project, I've got an
entire detailed prompt all set up here.
Okay? And so, you know, I've noticed
already, you know, my social media
manager, my designer, they're like 80%
more productive because of projects like
this. Now, the memory, I think, is
something that doesn't get talked enough
about inside of Claude. Okay,
essentially Claude regenerates memory
every evening from your past chats in
this project. And the cool thing, too,
is that I can go and tool up the memory
to actually be able to go and see what's
going on in other projects. So, as an
example, if I have amazing copy being
written for X and an awesome email
course project, I can go and tool up the
memory to actually be going and taking a
lot of the good sauce I'm building in
those projects and feeding that memory
into this project as well. Project
instructions ensure that you're giving
AI your standards, not just generic
instructions. When we go and dive into
this, right, you can see as an example
inside of the Instagram carousels
instructions, I'm setting this standard,
right, that I want the outputs to be
like the best copywriters that have ever
existed. I'm also establishing a
standard by which I want it to go and
attract the kind of founders that would
even join Founder OS in the first place,
right? So, targeting founders that are
ideally doing over 30K and beyond per
month. Now, when it comes then to the
kind of carousels I wanted to create,
the big thing that I do with each format
is I've learned these different hacks
that I often share with founders inside
of Founder OS. Part of the inside sauce
as an example with carousels is that you
want every single slide of a carousel to
be able to be shared on stories unto
itself. And so, I go and feed that into
the instructions so that I'm setting
that standard for everything that it
creates. From there also I'll get into
the kind of pain points I want it to hit
and the dreams I want to encapsulate as
well as the emotional resonance I want
to have because my goal with things like
content right is that I basically want
to read the minds and the subconscious
of the kind of customer that I'm looking
to attract. So, let's go and look at the
strategic laziness carousel that we
outputed, right? And I'll show you the
ways that it's going and pulling some of
the instructions that I've given it. As
we go and look at this, right, it's
pulling unique stories and backgrounds.
You know, it knows that, you know, I
wanted to use my own unique experience.
This doesn't just sound like some AI
goblygook. I have a lot of different
documentation I've given it that's
around those 16-hour work days that I
used to have in my first business. And
so, it's pulling that knowledge into
this piece of copy. In addition to that,
right, you can see that a lot of what
it's trying to do is writing in the same
rhythm that I write in, right? Short
sentences, oftentimes having things
like, you know, it needs better system,
systems for content, system operations,
systems for hiring, systems for growth.
This is the kind of words that I use on
a lot of my coaching calls and stuff
I've even said in a lot of my content.
The other thing that it's doing based on
the instructions is it's actually
pulling a bunch of copy from my best
tweets ever. These are just a few
examples just showing you the power of
setting up the right instructions, the
right project knowledge to go and get
outputs that authentically have your
voice. Step five, create projects for
every format. So, let me give you a
sense of the different projects that
I've set up across my team to go and
level everyone up and make them at least
40% more productive. We have projects
for Instagram carousels, for viral X
tweets, for Instagram stories, YouTube
scripts, lead magnets, you know, we have
them for email courses, for my
operations, so it runs like clockwork.
We have it for upsells and for you know
our customer success department. I have
it to help me go and create the
different run of shows for the different
experiences you run whether it's in
Austin, the Doommites, Sedona, Bali, you
name it. Every single format across all
the different departments has
essentially an AI project which is
almost like an AI strategist that can
help them go and move forward. So let me
peel behind the scenes here and show you
how this all works, right? So voice of
customer, right? I may go and use this
specific project and my team will use
this to help us go and come up with say
content ideas that are based on the
surveys that we've gotten from founders.
And so give me the top 20 content ideas
ranked from best to worst that will
cause founders that are doing over
$100,000 per month wanting to come work
with me and the team to go and remove
themselves from operations and build
their founder brands. And so we'll give
that to the voice of customer project
and boom, right? This thing is going to
go and leverage the insane amount of
context as well as the project knowledge
there to go and come up with content
ideas that we can then leverage for
platforms like Instagram, YouTube, you
name it. Here you can see it, right?
It's coming up with a bunch of
highquality ranked ideas, right? Things
like you built a 300k per month business
with $0 systems or the content hamster
wheel is killing your business. You
check Slack before brushing your teeth.
I can't take a vacation without the
business stopping, you know, and it's
coming up with a bunch of other
highlever content ideas. Now, I'm not
saying that AI handles everything, but
it handles the 80% that it can just do,
leaving your team to do the 20% that's
your team's competitive edge. Your team
stops being order takers and are able to
evolve into being strategic operators.
One infrastructure for every format, all
in your voice. Imagine the power of
having this set up across your personal
media company. This is how you build
leverage. Step six, team integration. A
big piece of this now that you have this
all toolled up is to actually train your
team on this. It's not going to be
immediately obvious to each person how
they can go and use this. And so the
typical process here is that I've gone
and I've toled up a given project. I've
used it myself for at least a couple
weeks, right? And gone it to the stage
where I'm like, "Okay, this is ready to
ship to the rest of my squad." And then
from there on a given meeting, I'm going
to go and show them some of the ways I'm
using them. Then from there, it's all
documented. There's the now the AI
project inside Claude that people
leverage. And then there's a Loom video
typically of me actually using the given
thing. And then from there, I'm
empowering my team to take it the
distance. Here's the reality. I think
while most people are focused on using
AI to replace their team, the real magic
is integrating your existing team into
AI. So, you're getting basically a 30
person team out of those five core team
members you have. When you start
injecting AI into your team like this,
your team stops feeling overwhelmed and
starts to feel empowered. When I'm
working directly with founders inside of
Founder OS, I'm not just trying to level
up the founder. It's much more important
to me that I'm leveling up at least
seven core team members so that ideally
I can just make the founder the least
important person in that business. If
you're watching this and you're
thinking, damn, you know, I'm ready for
my company to have this level of
infrastructure. Well, that's exactly
what we do in Founder OS. We're not just
going to level up you, but we'll level
up your entire team and give you the
leverage necessary to go and compete
over the next 3 years. It's the systems
plus AI plus the right team trained up
that allow you to go and take advantage
of this next wave. Step seven, weekly
improvement. AI is not just some set it
and forget it thing. Okay, I see AI
almost like its own software product.
And inside of my portfolio of companies,
we're constantly going and iterating on
the prompts, the projects because the
truth is things like the content
platforms change, your team changes,
right? The best practices in your
company will change and your core
documentation will change. You know what
are the things that need to be updated?
The given prompts need to be updated as
you go and learn different insights and
your brand evolves. The project
knowledges need to evolve as you know
the different kind of documentation
across your company changes and you're
obviously going to want to make new and
different projects as you expand to new
and different projects as well as
different platforms. It's important to
see this as something that you want to
get to a certain level out the gate
which is exactly what we help install
with people inside of founder less so
that out the gate you're not trying to
get from 10% to 20% to 30%. We can get
you from like 0 to 80% in a matter of
weeks. But from there, it's this mindset
of continuous improvement, making each
project 10% better every week. You know,
in a year, your company's leveling up
like 400x. So, here's the question. Are
you ready to stop managing chaos and
start compounding clarity? If you're
doing 30K, 100K, or even 300K a month,
the magic is going to come from having
the right systems and AI set up across
your entire team. If you've been
watching this video, you've got a taste
of what's possible. But the next logical
step is to go and join founder us where
we go and give you all these systems and
not just you as the founder but give it
to your entire team and help level them
up. This isn't some course or any
like that, right? This is
actually going and installing this
entire AI first operating system in your
business. You know, not just me and my
team, right? But you'll have access to
text me anytime you need me as well as
scheduled one-on-one calls every other
week with me directly, right? So that I
can go and help you through all of this
wave, right? and get these systems,
these projects, these prompts installed
across your team and then help go and
make sure it's as efficiently scaling as
possible. The future belongs to founders
who understand leverage. It's AI plus
systems plus leveling up your entire
team. If you're interested in learning
more about how I actually use AI inside
of my companies, go and check out this
next video. I'll see you over there. Be
sure to like and subscribe and welcome
to the founder freedom movement.