The six books that changed how I run my
business. So, first off, 100 million
money models by Mr. Hormozi. Legendary
book. Um, really helped me think about
the overall money model behind Founder
OS, make some changes, skyrocket the
business. Next one is Meditations by
Marcus Aurelius. Think it's really
helped me stay calm amidst all the chaos
and really lean into a level of just
staying chill, basically, when things
out there get a little bit nutty.
Uh, next one is How to Make a Few More
Billion Dollars by Brad Jacobs. Um, I
was really surprised by this book. I
thought that it would get into a lot
more money stuff. Um, but it actually
focused a lot on meditation. Um, and I
learned a few different, uh, techniques
that I now, uh, use daily.
The Comfort Crisis by Michael Easter.
Uh, I read this book about eight months
ago and it really encouraged me just to
enjoy the discomfort of life.
Um, and, uh, it actually helped me a lot
with my own health routine, um, and
embracing new challenges. And I ended up
taking up Muay Thai, um, after reading
this book. And then, um, Wisdom
Untethered by Michael Singer. Um, same
author as Untethered Soul. Um, it really
just teaches you a lot to be, um, you
know, less attached to outcomes, uh, and
just really love the process of
building, of life, um, and all that good
stuff. And then, lastly, Ogilvy on
Advertising David Ogilvy, legendary
copywriter. I think copywriting is the
key to making amazing content and would
highly recommend that book. And