If I was in my 20s just starting a
business, this is what I wish someone
would have told me. We want to build the
best and biggest community of
highquality filmmakers that through
creating truly unique work can achieve
financial time and location for you. I
had a chance to sit down with a couple
founders here in Changangu, Bali, and it
really made me think of some of the
things that I used to struggle with 14
years ago when I was just getting
started. Trust me, like every single
thing you're trying to do here will
probably happen. It may take a little
longer than you thought. Also,
everything you've put on here is aing
can of worms. I'm not even saying this
to just say it, but it feels like
there's a way to get off of my chest a
lot. So much lighter. There's so many
ways to go. I got to manage myself. I
got to manage different partnerships,
team members, customers, and all of this
feeling like it was just this cloud. Do
you guys want to like go hard as hell?
Just build Yeah, maybe it's some insane
that's really big, but like it's going
to take your freaking every morsel of
your being. And lastly, just a lack of
clarity and a feeling of overwhelm.
Would you guys say you're getting a
little overwhelmed? Yeah, sure. Yeah.
Would that be an okay year 1 revenue?
That would be pretty decent. I think if
you're just doing what you know you can
do and you just focus on this, that's
probably not just going to double year
over year, like it might triple. We're
eternally grateful for you taking the
time to do this and really just needing
some mentorship. So, that's exactly what
I provided these two guys with was an
opportunity to sit down with me for a
few hours, get a whiteboard out, and
start just drawing up their challenges,
their objectives, and then bringing a
bit of clarity to their business model.
We ready for this? Yes. Let's do it.
Here we go. Let's go. Maybe it probably
just be good just for you guys to
introduce yourselves and your business,
maybe just to start with. My name's Rain
and Joey. H I'm 23 years old. Over the
past 10 years now, I've basically
focused on on the journey of becoming a
filmmaker. I've shot for brands all the
way from Sony to Emirates to Apple Music
and a bunch of of others. I only
recently made the switch to building up
my own personal brand on on YouTube. A
while ago, I was kind of looking for a
for a way to build this into into a
system that I can help many more
creators with. Instead of just giving a
behind the scenes look, actually guiding
creators to help them bring their their
take their works from a certain level to
an amazing level where they can not only
work with with their dream clients, but
they can also achieve financial time and
location freedom. So my name is Mo.
Started entrepreneurship seven or 6
years ago when I was 16. Basically
because I didn't like the path that was
shown to me. I was very rebellious.
Started to get the hang of uh digital
marketing pretty quickly. eventually
found my success in e-commerce but I
always had a huge passion for cameras.
So I kind of quit all the standard
business to run around with a camera for
a while. So I did that the last 2 years
but then it did felt kind of
counterintuitive to not use all the
business skills that I had. Railin had
this huge master plan and then I was
like this is a perfect mix between uh
creation creative work but also
utilizing those business skills. as kind
of small introduction and small uh story
of how everything started. Cool. So
here, let's kind of like map this out
for a sec just cuz I'm sure as we get
going like it's going to be key that we
get this right. So why don't we go
through kind of the offer or offers talk
about a bit of like your guys objects
objectives for like the you know year
and then maybe any sort of challenges
you guys currently have take it from
there and see where that brings us.
Sound good? Yeah. Great. All right. you
have this like high-end agency. You want
to just speak to it for a sec because I
think it's really impressive some of the
brands you guys have worked with. About
three years ago, I I signed with an
agency like a bigger advertising agency
in in the Netherlands. I did a bunch of
productions with them together which
were quite quite big productions. The
money that they were spending on these
productions was so not proportional to
the output that they were creating. They
were just wasting money on enormous
teams. And I did that for for about a
year with him and then decided okay I I
really uh don't want to be a part of
this. From that moment on I started
doing things by myself and actually
that's also the point where I started
attracting these uh higherend clients
because the the unique selling point
that I could offer was okay I can
produce a commercial for for a high-end
brand that they would normally have to
pay hundreds of thousands of of dollars
for. I can produce that in a faster more
efficient way that's also cheaper. So
that was kind of the the initial value
offering and I ended up doing
productions for Ferrari, we did one for
Emirates last year, Apple Music, we will
make a course/case study for every
production and you will have one for
like pre-planning and pitching. Then you
have one module for editing, then you
have one module um like you have all
these different modules and at first we
wanted to sell those modules separately,
but then you were like this is way too
complicated. um like you're going to
have all these little offers and yes
just not going to to be efficient and
and simplistic in this way. Kind of
started to rethink the the initial core
offering. Hence we've we've arrived
here. We've now decided to focus on a on
a mid-tier product basically one offer
that will give people access to the the
behind the scenes material to the the
five modules per case study that we plan
to do. They can purchase access to that
for a certain amount of months. Yeah.
Plus they get access to the community
where we do weekly calls and we give
feedback. What do you guys call it?
Club. We call it outline club. Outline
club. Yes. That's the community part.
And like you get access to the club when
you buy uh the course. I guess we have
the high-end agency and then the second
thing is outline club, right? Yeah. The
main uh other offering is of course that
we we plan to take these community
members. we kind of take them with us on
the productions because that's kind of
the main thing that most of these
courses uh in the film making space are
missing is that real world experience on
set. And then another thing that we're
still thinking about is like a chance to
work with the agency. But then this is
like a huge thing we're still tripping
over is like how much uh time are we
going to spend in the agency and like
attracting different types of clients
versus just focusing on doing the major
productions and focusing on the info
info products. So that's definitely
something we're still uh cool. So how
would you characterize that like
challenge? Um yeah. Yeah. Focus. It
feels like there are already so many
routes we take. There are already a lot
of moving parts with the agency, then
with creating the whole behind the
scenes videos on the YouTube channel,
then creating the case studies of the
productions, you know, it's it's a lot
of work and it keeps us up at night
figuring out like where should the focus
focus really be? What do you feel like
is like the real challenge for you there
is choosing the the right path for this
business right now? We feel like we've
got proof of concept cuz I've been doing
this for a while. Uh we've got an
audience that wants to to to consume the
content considering all of the the value
that we want to provide and also the
connections that we have. We're not sure
which actionable path we should we
should
take. Now, I had to be told 14 years ago
that the specific business that these
guys are trying to create, it kind of
does feel like you're spinning three
plates. It's not all that crazy if you
feel a bit overwhelmed at first. Now,
these plates are natural, right? We all
deal with them. No matter what business
model we're creating, there's always a
bit of chaos. Now, my belief is that if
you're not careful and if you're not
systemizing your business, they by
nature will default to entropy, to
chaos. Things like mentors, guidance,
support, and systems are the anecdotes
to that entropy. Would you guys say like
you're getting a little overwhelmed?
Yeah, sure. Yeah, absolutely. Cuz that's
kind of what this kind of points to in a
way, right? like you're just trying to
like choose like we go this way, this
way, this way. We want to offer, what's
the price? How does this fit with the
brand? How do we isolate these people?
It's just a lot of stuff. And at some
points, it's like I just want to know
what do I like what do we want to do?
And then let's rip it, you know, versus
these like existential sort of things.
And I'm not saying it's all, you know,
you've got a lot figured out, but
there's also an aspect where there is
some rather big questions here, right?
Yeah. And there are like a thousand
things to do. So how do we figure out
which to do? We we give priority, you
know. Yeah. These businesses when you're
starting them at your stage, it is like
spinning plates. So there's an element
where you just got to accept it's going
to be a good amount of work. If it was
easy, obviously everyone would do it.
And you guys like you guys have like big
ambitions, not just on the things you're
trying to build, on like the quality and
the brand. You're not just trying to
like make a quick buck. Obviously,
you're trying to build something
beautiful, something that stands the
test of time, something you can work on
for the next 50 years and be proud of
it, doing cool [\h__\h] with cool people.
There are three plates, I think, that
are useful to think about like that
you're spinning, which means like you're
trying to balance these things as you're
starting, right? And it's like, oh my
god, oh my god, over here. And then, oh,
this one almost crashes. Like, you're
just kind of you're getting them to a
point where it's like they're all kind
of like a one out of 10 and then they're
at a two out of 10. And sure enough,
like you just keep spinning them and
then you kind of get used to spinning
one and then you're like spinning these
two and they feel like sometimes they're
going to crash, but you keep kind of
raising the bar to a point where it's
like one's at a seven, one's at a nine,
one's at an eight. It's like, okay, here
we go. Now we got used to like both
spinning these and also like the
interreation between these three plates.
Okay, the three plates are
audience,
product, and community.
And I think that's a really useful frame
to think about when you're just starting
something. It's like you can have all
these ideas, but like out the gate, if
we can just reduce the surface area for
like what you're trying to do, then you
can go deep and really make that stuff
amazing. I love it. And then gradually
just like let it kind of that's the
kernel of the start of this thing. And
then let it kind of gradually like root
and blossom a bit and grow like a tree
or like nature does. And you just kind
of keep watering it and listening to the
community and what they're saying and it
gradually just kind of grows. And some
of the ways it grows, you're like, "Oh,
knew it was going to grow like that."
Yeah. And other ways you're like, "Wow,
I had no idea it was going to morph into
this random thing." So, what you really
need to focus on is just like the
minimum viable seed. And if you can just
plant something that you're like, I'm
proud of what we're planting here. It's
humble and yeah, it's not this and not
that and not that yet, but it's
something and it's it's going to be
awesome, but like it's going to take a
sec. It allows you then to go and go,
"Okay, this is manageable. Like, we can
[\h__\h] do this." And you can finally
have that energy and focus it into
something that's like specific and
narrow and like [\h__\h] nail it versus
feeling like, "Oh man, I'm waking up
today and we got to [\h__\h] do this
thing and that thing and who the [\h__\h]
are we hiring? And what path are we
going? Are we doing this thing and that
and when are we going to the next
shoot?" It's like it's just too much and
you're not going to be able to use your
potential correctly. So, what I would
encourage us to do is like let's just
map out these three plates. Mhm. And
just keep in mind like it actually is
winning if it feels uncomfortably
narrow. On the audience side, what do
you guys think is like this part of our
audience must exist? What platforms, I
guess, is what I'm saying. YouTube.
Yeah, YouTube for sure. And the cool
thing is that it already exists, you
know. Yeah. We got the main channel,
right, of 100K? Yep. And then we got the
new channel, you're thinking, right?
Yeah. We'll call YouTube main and then
we'll call behind the scenes BTS. Maybe
just building in public. Yeah, building
in public because VIP the the behind the
scenes are made on the main channel. So
that can get confusing and that is then
already a question. Do we really like we
love the building in public? It really
fires us and we love looking at all the
stuff that we shot already. We love the
vision, but do we need it? I'd say that
the the main YouTube video videos that
we post of the productions, they're such
a highpaced format of giving value and
the the building in public is much more
of a raw authentic look into into it. It
doesn't need to be overedited. It can be
just very raw kind of building community
focused video. Mhm. Okay. We'll put a
dog here because like maybe it's
something to look at, but maybe not.
Maybe it's fine. So, is Instagram?
Instagram. Yeah. On my personal brand uh
IG. Anything else? I'd say those are the
three main focuses. Email list. I I have
almost 10k people in my email list,
which are people that either bought my
digital products or people that signed
up to be a part of the next productions
or people that are interested in what
we're going to to offer. We'll put the
email here. Okay. So, we got the email
list on the product side. Why is that?
Why did you put it on the product side?
Because this is kind of like your rented
audience on platforms. In a sense, I
think this is something that like you
own it. you don't own these platforms,
you know, Zuck, Musk, whoever may own
these things, but you own your email
list and that is an asset. So, we can
put it here. It also makes it easy to
because you funnel traffic from these to
this. So, it's easier to kind of easier
to map it. Yeah. We'll just put that
there. What else do you have product
wise? So, yeah, it's it's it's basically
just it's a course, right? Yeah. Okay.
We we call it case studies because we're
basically doing these productions
through the agency in which we teach the
the different techniques and from
acquiring the client to the
pre-production to the filming to the
post-production. We teach all of those
methods within that case study. Cool.
So, it's a product and community in a
way, right? Like we're talking outline
club. It's kind of both. Yeah. Right.
So, we'll just put it here
and it is, you know, the main
product and the main community. Now
let's talk about then okay so within
this like cuz that yeah that's basically
it right what is the minimum viable that
needs to be in this to launch it it's
the first case study first production
yeah is that done no we're doing that's
the Japan okay sure okay we'll call it
Japan case study anything else
like obviously uh building out the
community even deciding which which
platform we want to go Do you know which
one yet? We we kind of decided on going
for for Circle as that that being the
main main platform. Let's just let's
just assume that for now. And we need to
build like the the back end like
obviously the website uh where are
people going to check out? Do we have a
sales uh behind it? Okay. So there needs
to be some sort of
checkout. And then what's the weekly
group coaching that's with you initially
with me? Yes. And as soon as it scales
to a bigger community, we have a bunch
of connections in the film making space.
So we would invite guest speakers to to
host those sessions for months or yeah
divide the workload that way. Like one
observation as an example, right? When
you think about this and this piece I
would only do what's necessary to serve
this. Do you need to do six productions
in a year? The thing is like the YouTube
is is the main thing that fuels
everything. We want the like the videos
on the YouTube to be the behind
thescenes videos of the productions. But
if we're going to do less than six
productions, that means less than six
YouTube videos per year. And in our
head, that just sounds too little. Yes.
and and the style of content that that
works well that that is b basically a
proven concept on my YouTube channel is
this behind the scenes value which just
takes a lot of time to to bring to life
to process all of this footage that we
have from one of those productions into
a YouTube video. It's it's difficult to
do that uh within one or two weeks. It
usually takes a month to 5 weeks. Okay.
So, we have the agency shoots then as
part of this. It it it's kind of the
same as the Japan case study like the
agency productions they turn into the
case studies. Okay. So Japan is one of
the Yeah. Yeah. Cool.
One thing that I really noticed when I
was talking with them that I remember I
used to struggle with a lot and I still
struggle with sometimes today is you
know I'll get a deal from a brand where
they want to pay me say 120 grand for
the year to go and promote their
product, their brand to an audience I've
created. And at first I'm like, damn,
$120,000, I can only imagine what I
could do with that. But when I go and I
sit and reflect, maybe go for a cold
bath or a sauna, I think, there's an
opportunity cost to that. There's an
opportunity cost between investing my
energy into that brand versus actually
building my own brand. And often times
it's tricky as humans, as founders to
contextualize that opportunity cost. You
know, we see a big ticket, a big 120k
deal, and we instantly just want to
grasp at it, right? and think about,
okay, how could I maybe push this aside,
maybe make this more efficient in my
business, and then just double down in
this new shiny toy I see. But little do
we know that each time we do that, we
slowly sacrifice our dreams, sacrifice
our own progress in the hopes of
satisfying someone else's dream. And my
belief is that more often than not, it's
a mistake. One core lesson that I gave
to these gentlemen that I have to remind
myself of daily, and it's a constant
struggle, is default to know. One thing
that we are still thinking about is like
that whole personal branding offer and
like we have a client now that is ready
to pay us like a serious retainer which
would obviously help especially with
bandwidth. It's it's a thing that
completely requires our focus. So should
we do it or no? That that is what do you
think based on what what we've been
saying? No. But based on like the
retainer it is the the bandwidth it will
give us it should be a yes. So what's
what's the retainer out of curiosity
like back and napkin? The 20 to 25k per
month. You get paid for the productions
you do, right? Yeah. You can't get paid
maybe a little bit more on an extra
production. Not right now. Not right
now. Yeah. No. Since there are a lot of
production costs and flying the the
people to from the community to to
assist us. Plus, you know, the offer
that we got now for this retainer client
is basically based on the fact that we
will supply them with one of our
community members that we've trained. We
give the frameworks to that community
member to build a personal brand for the
client and then we, you know, do weekly
check-ins to see how how it's going and
then that filmmaker that we've attached
to them just films for them and we do it
on like a 3 to 6 month basis. That was
the only my own experience which just
speaking from I can just speak from what
has happened to me before, right? It's
hard sometimes to discern these things,
right? Like, is it actually something
that's accelerating your vision and
going to get you the cash you need and
be this proof point of what you're
building and and be that or is it a
distraction and it's actually going to
require you then to like be super
hands-on with this guy's personal brand
and coaching this guy up when you should
really be like building the case studies
and launching the platform and getting
the checkout live and launching it to
your email list and to your YouTube and
like just building your thing. How do
you decide based on experience? One of
that is like the criteria of like a hell
yes or a no. Like does this feel like
it's like a definite hell yes. Oh yeah,
like this is definitely going to help
us. This moves us forward. Like this is
in line with what we're doing. Or does
it like feel somewhat murky and it's
like the money's good and this part's
like cool guy or whatever, but [\h__\h] I
can't totally see how it accelerates it.
And like keeping in mind too that
there's an investment there. Like there
is time. you know, you're going to be on
calls with this guy to talk about his
brand and then to train up this other
guy. And some like some of that maybe is
stuff that you're doing, but maybe some
of it's just like it's just new stuff
and it's it's a personal brand thing
maybe and maybe determining like we're
serving filmmakers. We're not serving
like the core thing is not this thing.
This is a different thing. Yes. True.
And I also think the important thing is
to have a frame of abundance. Like
you're not saying no and then you're
screwed and you lost it on 20,000 and
like [\h__\h] like we lost money. It's like,
no, you've actually built space now for
like a bigger thing to come in. Now
you're just like, oh no, we're just
saying hell yes to like our vision. Like
it's bigger than this $20,000
check right now, hypothetically. Yeah.
You know, just to be okay with slowing
down, working at a natural pace. And the
key thing is saying no more often,
saying no to new opportunities, saying
no to people that are like, "Oh, I'll
work for you for free." It was funny cuz
in the conversation I even noticed at
the end of it I kind of said, "Hey, this
is the basket of stuff that I think you
should be focused on." This is plenty.
If you're trying to actually make this
stuff absolutely amazing, it's going to
take everything you got and then some.
We're talking maybe even like 60 70 hour
weeks at some points because they're
looking to launch this thing in like 6
weeks. Even there, you can still see
this tendency, this inclination, this
bug to basically go say yes or what
about this or what if we did that? And
you can easily drown in a sea of
whatifs. You know, Paul Graham, founder
of Y Combinator, says most startups die
of indigestion, not starvation. You
know, indigestion from so many
opportunities, so many things you could
do that you end up just drowning in
that. You end up choking on it because
you're not just focused on the one main
thing that will set your business apart.
And I think as founders, there's a bit
of a disease of this going on. A disease
of just yes, yes, yes. And I think most
of us should be in a season of no. And I
share this with you because I'm no
different than you. This disease of yes
um is something that we all are guilty
of in our lives and it's just that
reminder that you know we're likely
doing enough. We likely have everything
that we need at our fingertips. We don't
need more. We need to do less but
better. I'd say another challenge which
I've run into a bunch of times.
Initially the the reason why I started
to shift focus onto the club/course
community offering was because I spent
five or six years as a filmmaker trying
to make it without having any help from
the outside without getting any courses
and I I had to jump over so many
different hurdles and if there was a
place where I could kind of access all
of the right tools that I needed with a
little bit of a blueprint of how to
build my own personal brand at the same
time that would save me so much money
and time Since that was the initial
focus, the offering that we're going to
release on the uh for the course, I kind
of wanted to make that accessible. I
wanted to be like, hey, if you're a
driven creative, I want to give you the
tools you need, not for a for a $10,000
offer, but something that you can invest
into and if you have the drive and the
will and you can just take action, you
can make something work. The challenge
is how do we create an offer that
doesn't feel like we're impeding on on
goodwill? Yeah. giving giving even
creators that don't have a lot of money
or capital to invest to give them a
chance to to shine. It's kind of similar
figuring out like the intersection of
like the offer, the price, and like the
brand and like something that feels like
it threads the needle between like good
pricing fits the brand and the kind of
values of the brand which is like
accessible and helping the creator that
was you 3 years ago or 5 years ago while
also allowing you to build a great
business and and invest in like other
cool stuff that you have down the road
which is only possible with profits but
also not doing profits in a way that
feel dirty to the existing people. like
how do you kind of Yeah. bridge that.
Yeah. One other thing that comes to
mind. Okay. So, when I like first
started building businesses, I did it
really like half-hazardly at 21. I was
running like a technology boot camp
because I was like smoking some weed in
an apartment with other people that like
they were building some [\h__\h] and I was
interested in that and we got talking
and we were high. We're like, "Oh, that
sounds like a good [\h__\h] idea." You
know? And so we were like, "Oh, [\h__\h]
it." And we just started building this
thing. And so there we were all baked in
[\h__\h] building this technology school at
like 21. Uh one thing led to another
over the last next few years we built
something pretty significant but I hated
it. Like I had no real interest in like
technology and it was a good thing that
we were doing and it was a good learning
experience but like it wasn't fun. I had
no freedom of location which I know is
big to you guys and big to all of us
now. I wasn't very intentional about
what I was really building. I just was
building something cuz at least I was a
founder. So what I then had to learn the
hard way, entrepreneurs were investors,
right? Investors of our time, like
investors of our money, investors of our
energy, right? And just like an investor
like say Warren Buffett has like
criteria by which he invests in
businesses, right? Those businesses need
to be cash flowing, there needs to be a
great founder, a formidable motive
around the business, a recognizable
brand. It really is smart of us as
founders to view ourselves as investors
and have a kind of criteria by which
like we're going to kind of have these
criteria that determine the kind of
business we're going to build and
ruthlessly grade especially at the stage
you guys are at. This thing is like a
piece of play-doh or clay, you know,
like you can make this whatever the hell
you want. So why not get clear on your
criteria for a sec so that as you're
making different decisions, you can go
back to the criteria and go is this
achieving that? So like examples of
criteria that I've now created in my own
life with what I create is like I need
to love the customer. I need to love the
problem. I need to have distribution day
one and the ability to build like
something that I know could be shared a
lot. Mhm. I need to be able to have it
cash flowing within 90 days. It needs to
feel obvious like it needs to be obvious
that I do this like not a technology
boot camp. And it needs to be a hell
yes. So like the pieces of it, the team
I'm building around me, the partners,
the offer, all of it, I need to be like
[\h__\h] yes. And if it's not that, I'm
like, no. Long-winded way of just
saying, I think what's useful for a
second here, you have some goals, you
have some challenges, and a lot of it is
around like choosing the past, figuring
out these things, really making just a
lot of decisions around what do you want
this thing to be? And I feel like when
we have a criteria for a sec, just like
the examples I gave you, we can just
make sure that as we're making these
decisions, we're making them with like
some north star in mind. Is there any
criteria you guys made that come to mind
as when you guys think of what you're
building like this must exist? Location
freedom like that we can run it from
anywhere where we want promotes travel
in some way. And that's absolutely what
it does with the productions that we're
doing because the productions are all
just going to be that we pick the places
that we want to shoot in. I'd say that
for me at least my big passion and where
all of this started is is coming up with
an idea and going out there and making
it, bringing it to life. That that spark
of of having a vision and figuring out a
way even though the vision is very big,
how can we film this? How can we use
gear in a creative way to to to leverage
the the idea or to to create an amazing
result? That kind of process of
creativity is for me the most exciting
part. Mhm. So, how would you
characterize that as a criteria? It's
like a razor. Yep. It's going to either
determine like okay, we can do this or
no, if you can't imagine doing yourself,
we're going to say no. As an example,
how many hours do you want to spend on
the thing? Like, do you guys want to be
spending 70 hours a week working or is
it ma does it matter you that it's like
manageable a bit? Like as you guys have
all these ideas, it's like, okay, do you
guys want to like go hard as hell and
like just build like yeah, maybe it's
some insane [\h__\h] that's really big, but
like it's going to take your freaking
every morsel of your being, you know,
and you still might not pull it off. You
know, these are common struggles. If
this sounds like you, you're certainly
not alone. I see founders like this
10,000 plus a year. This is one of the
most popular struggles founders have.
that gap between potential and proven
product and like time is also just a
challenge. Time. Yeah. So many times
always a challenge. Tell me something I
don't know.
There's only so many hours in today,
Matt. We have 24 hours. Can we make it
27, 28? What can we do here? Yeah, we'll
be amazing.
Nothing works. No. Okay. So, time. time
in a sense that that we're becoming our
own bottlenecks in a way that you know
we want to do so many different things
and have got so many different ideas. It
feels like we can only kind of grow at
the rate that we can output work right
now. The hiring process is also
something that we're starting to think
about. At what point do we start
thinking about adding members to the
team? I really admire Mo and Railen for
going for it for just getting started.
No, I think that's the thing that most
people struggle with, right? Is they
just don't even start. They don't make
that bet on themselves. And you got to
admire people that take the bull by the
horns, you know, take life into their
hands and just get after it. Many of you
here are still on the fence. And this
may be your friendly reminder. Just
start the damn thing whatever way you
can. Even if it's small, even if it's
super embarrassing, hey, that's how we
all started. Now, if you're not
embarrassed by your first product,
you're doing something wrong. You're
probably taking too long to launch it.
Well, here's the thing that I think
we're all not talking about. Okay. So,
let's get into this part, which is the
math. Yeah. Okay. Think about what I
just went, right? The the kind of
determinant whether it is too little or
it's too much or it's not enough is like
off of that, which is your output.
That's your assembly line, let's say.
I'm sure I butchered it to some extent,
but I'm sure it's like not crazy off. A
12 week cycle more or less that output.
I can do that. th those four YouTube
videos or those five or whatever like
that I can do in that kind of general
cycle. The question is how many leads
and customers can that drive to you? And
is that in fact not enough? Mhm. Cuz
maybe it's actually enough, right? Maybe
it it is all you need for a sec. Yeah.
Right. At least year one. And maybe we
don't need to cross this bridge of like
I got to build a team and I got to do
this and I got to delegate all that.
Like maybe not. Maybe you just need to
like do that and you need to just build
your area and and maybe you're not
actually crazy for just like just
sticking to your guns and just sticking
to what you know works for a second. So,
do you guys know how many leads that
drives? Yeah, I I launched a $100 low
ticket product last year with some some
LS, some some presets, some other
effects, and uh like a mini 4hour color
grading course. The first YouTube video
that I posted about that converted into
about 15K profit overnight. The second
video I posted about that was about 10k
profit overnight and within 6 months
it's almost done six figures. So that at
least gives me a little bit of an idea
of okay in those 6 months I put out two
videos about the product. Okay. And we
did about 85k USD in in profit. So how
many of them did you sell back in
Afghan? About 900.
Okay. She made around like let's say it
was 90,000 just for shits and giggles,
right? Just to kind of give us some
numbers to work with
here. Okay. And that was two videos plus
uh two posts on my Instagram. Okay. So
two YouTube and two
IG. So let's say like for a second here,
just assuming no added talent, you'll
get to six YouTube. I mean 10 10 IG.
Sure. 10 IG with cut downs and Sure.
So, what are you guys thinking you're
going to sell this thing at? Still also
completely uh Do we want to use maybe
$1,000 from now then? Sure.
When you did two of these, right, you
sold 900. Mhm. Let's just say because of
the increased price, but there is a lot
more value. You're going to have some
insane email list going on around this
thing where it's like there's a wait
list, there's a drip campaign. when they
get in, they get like, you know, all
these warm-up emails around the offer,
like, you know, it's super well done.
Let's just say, so for per two videos,
you sell 400, so less than half. Yeah.
Right. But you're doing six, so it's
three times more output. So again, back
in napkin, again, these numbers are
going to be off, but just to assume some
things. So $1,000 times 1.2 million 400.
Yeah, you probably already got it. There
we go, my guy. All
right. Would that be an okay year one
revenue?
That would be pretty decent. I think I
think it would be awesome. Like I think
that would be amazing first year. Like
especially if you had all the
infrastructure and everything built,
right? And like you you've proven these
things out and you had the community
going and like people were happy and
like there's still so much upward
mobility with this. There's still so
many other products you could launch.
Yeah. Like we we didn't even raise the
price in this. Yeah, we are going to do
this, but this is worth six YouTube
videos and it is a question if we're
going to be able to
do six. But let's just assume that what
he's saying like you pull it off and
especially I think the thing to consider
is like you let's say you did the next
batch, right? And by then the thing's
launched and you sell 300 on the first
go. Well, you're going to go [\h__\h] I'm
just going to bring on some talent and
just just shadow me on this one. I'm
still going to go in the cave, but just
sit your ass in a chair beside me and
watch. Maybe you become more comfortable
with like giving someone a piece of
something or maybe you're like sit down
for the next one too. Just sit though
and just watch and like sure enough you
start to be able to have that confidence
like relinquish a little bit or give up
a little bit more control or like maybe
it's not the editing part or the cave
part but there's just other and so [\h__\h]
in your life you can get off you like
maybe you just need an EA to like answer
your emails and [\h__\h] Maybe it's not
editing time that we need as much help
with. It's just other time like there's
just other dumb [\h__\h] you're spending
your time with. M this is where you know
when I talk to founders I kind of have
this belief that as founders a lot of us
like we never wanted to be employees
right we never wanted to work for the
man we wanted to go and be able to take
life into our own hands that said in our
own way we also crave structure in some
senses we actually kind of need someone
to manage us I know in my own career
without having mentorship guidance
people around me advisers people like
the founder of Shopify number eight
number 20 at Facebook Ryan Begelman my
executive coach who I meet with every
other week Antela
the founder of Complex. The list goes
on. These are people that have shown me
the way when it comes to strategy,
hiring, firing, building a team, holding
proper meetings, building an audience,
creating content, building a brand. The
best way to learn is from other people
that have been where you're trying to
go. This is by far the ultimate shortcut
as a founder. But I think so many
founders when it comes to mentorship,
when it comes to guidance, either they
don't even bother trying to find a
mentor, or number two, maybe they're too
arrogant or they just don't know and
they don't even give it a shot. Maybe
they're too scared to reach out to
someone. I can tell you that mentorship
guidance is probably about 80% of my
success. And what I try to do here for
Railen and for Mo is to give them the
mentorship that I wish I had 15 years
ago when I was getting started. help
focusing on what the right move should
be. Help focusing on what I should say
no to and help mostly focusing on the
three major parts of my business model
that I should focus on and double down
on. And the other parts that were really
simply just distractions that I should
just throw in the backlog, lock up,
throw out the key, and never look at
them again. It's mostly you guys, right?
Like it it's solid. Like it it is how I
would do this. Yeah. And this is more
than enough. Yeah. Yeah. No, and I'm
glad you're saying that, too. Like it
really is like like I've done the things
a lot of the things you're saying. I
don't know like some of this stuff like
I've done this, I've done this, I've
done this, I've done this, I've done
this in my own way, not nearly your way
and this I've done. But I do know that
if the stuff that you know that is crazy
creative, if you just can focus on that
stuff, y and then you have the space and
the ownership to focus on this stuff and
you guys can start building trust
together and having say daily standups
where you can start to just get in this
like it's like a drum beat of what
you're building, you know, every like 10
a.m. every day like you come prepared.
It's like, I got them this yesterday.
I'm doing this today. I'm blocked on
this. This is a creative decision I'm
making. I want to do this. What do you
think? Hey, wouldn't do that. I like
this. Can you send me what they sent
you? Cool. I'm going to review the fake
mom. I'm going to review the frame. No,
I don't like that. I want this. I want
that. I want that. Are we clear? Cool.
Agree. And commit. Move. Like, go and
build. You know, you go back to the
cave, you go back to launching this kind
of [\h__\h] building funnel, building the
infrastructure, all that. Boom. Next
day, same deal. What'd you get done?
Whatever. And just running these
sprints. Like, I'm I'm not even joking.
Like I'm not even saying this to just
say it, but it feels like there's a
weight on off of my chest amount. So
much lighter. So I think we have this
like would you agree like maybe for like
at least like the next few months? Yeah.
Right. I do think that the superpower
will be you guys saying no and staying
focused. That's where I see a lot of
people most people screw up. Most people
have such like I think it just takes you
kind of just both mutually keeping each
other honest about this like defaulting
to no. Don't default to yes or I got
this other idea. like be careful of that
stuff. I think what I'm getting to too
is that I think too fast sometimes
founders look to build something that's
scalable. Some of the best businesses in
the world were built from the start in
an unscalable way. Famous examples like
Brian Chesky from Airbnb like he slept
in Airbnbs. Every three nights he
changed an Airbnb for 365 days the first
year and just lived with the Airbnb
hosts and learned how they interacted
with the website and how they enjoyed it
and what they didn't like about the
experience. and he was an actual
customer himself in a way and from that
experience like learned the ins and outs
and built you know what's now like a you
know I think a $70 billion company right
what you guys are doing in a sense is
like you're just doing all this stuff
like you're in the mix you're in the mix
like that's okay initially to just do
things that don't scale so that the way
that the initial product and service and
kind of brand and creative are all
formed it's like so like maniacally
where it needs to be we've gone over so
many things that were things that were
difficult or seemed like obstacles and
and I'm sure there's other things that
will come up, but for now we're
eternally grateful for you taking the
time to do this. I think a lot of this
stuff too is like in the DNA of what
you've built too, right? Like when you
look at your YouTube channel, I you
know, you don't generally see that like
maybe maybe it's even less than what Mr.
Beast puts out there, right? Like you're
Yeah. Again, you're doing like your It's
like I think two videos technically
every two months, but kind of like back
to back every two months. So it's you've
used a lot of restraint there to say I'm
not going to just do more. I'm going to
do less but takes a hell of a lot of
discipline especially as a young founder
and creator. Like that's not easy. Like
that's something that people often times
don't learn for like 20 years in their
career. And just stick to that magic
there. It's not that you have to get
some new skill. It's actually just that
you have to stay true to what you are.
It's not new that you're trying to do
this. It's actually what you always are.
You just started to kind of think that
you had to do more and you just and it's
just natural that when you're starting
something new, you guys are younger
guys. Like it's totally all the things
you're going through. It's all natural.
Like I've gone through this stuff. Like
I I had to have someone show me how to
do this. But that there's always that
filter when you're making decision like
do we need to do this? I think brands
get built from a lot of the time just
like staying true to it and doing less
and just like staying so true to the DNA
of it versus like thinking you just got
to like slap this on and slap that and
oh we got to do this that like that's
everything else that just gets it just
gets watered down where it's like Yeah.
Just stay true to like the core of it.
Yeah.
Boom. Amazing, bro. Let's Let's get this
off the ground.
There we go. Thanks, man. Yeah, of
course. Really appreciate it. Yeah, of
course. Of course. Of course. That's
good hanging. Honestly, incredible. Of
course. So, I believe that there's never
been a better time to be a founder. You
know, the future belongs to founders,
creators, builders, people that are
honestly just fed up with the status
quo, fed up with their current life
situation and want to take it into their
own hands to build, to create, to
manifest something that they know in
their heart, their soul that they're
capable of. With all that amazing
opportunity that we all have at our
fingertips, and especially you guys in
your 20s, right? There's just so much
opportunity, right? You can build AI
products, AI apps now, just by talking
into a piece of software. There are so
many builders, so many people building
things, so many people creating things.
So, if you're in your 20s, you got some
advantages and you got some
disadvantages. Let's talk about the good
news first, the advantages. Okay, on
this side, you got a hell of a lot of
opportunities. You got a hell of a lot
of energy. You've got so much runway and
so much appetite for risk. You got no
kids. You got no family. I'm hope you
don't have a mortgage yet. Now, you're
free and you got so much going for you
there. On the disadvantages side, maybe
you lack experience. Maybe you lack a
network right now. You may lack some
resources. You know, because of your own
immaturity, you're maybe still dealing
with a level of just even getting to
know yourself, right? Your own awareness
around your strengths, your weaknesses.
And that all comes with time. I think
what you want to do is channel the best
of your advantages and find ways to
buffer your disadvantages. channeling
that energy into a clear direction with
an amazing mentor that helps you cover
your downside, your blindsides, and
allow you to have some direction into
the one to two core things you should
focus on. I think it's also surrounding
yourself with other successful builders,
right? An amazing community, people that
have been maybe even just a couple steps
further than where you are now. The more
that you can surround yourself with
others that have been on similar paths,
you're going to be able to learn from
their mistakes versus making common
mistakes that you really just don't need
to make. You know, I remind myself when
I'm building that most of the things
that I'm creating, this isn't rocket
science. You know, this is not SpaceX.
This is not Tesla. These are rather
simple businesses that other people have
built similar models to me, and I should
not be guessing. There's no point
reinventing the wheel. And this is
something that I wish I had awareness of
when I was first getting started. And so
what I'd say to you is take that energy,
take that potential, and before you get
moving too fast, draw up what are you
building? What are the two to three
things that you need to focus on to be
the best in that given space? You know,
when Steve Jobs was inventing the
iPhone, he really tripled it down to
being this amazing communications
device, a music player, a amazing way to
call people. Three things. Take the rule
of three from Steve Jobs and then apply
that to what you're doing. What are the
three things that you need to focus on
being the best in the world at with your
business? And channel every morsel of
your energy into those things and say no
to the rest.