If you want to achieve your goals, you
need to have 365
perfect days. And that's easier than it
sounds. When I was 28, I was smoking 11
joints a day, drinking, and anxious as
[\h__\h] This [music] whole substance stuff
was screwing me up, and I needed to go
and get my blood work done. It turned
out that based on that blood work, that
my DHEA was being blocked by the
substances. And DHEA is a core chemical
that converts into testosterone, which
is the chemical in humans that makes
effort feel good. I realized I couldn't
willpower my way out of this. I had to
architect a completely different life.
So, I downloaded an app called Streaks
and added six daily habits. Lift daily,
stretch daily, no smoking, [music] no
drinking, no sugar, and write daily. But
the real shift wasn't just the habits.
[music]
It was deciding, I'm the kind of person
who designs my life intentionally, not
[music] someone who just reacts to
whatever comes at me. Here's what I
learned. You know, discipline starts
with identity, [music]
not motivation. You're not trying to be
more disciplined. You're becoming an
architect. is [music] most people are
just operators. They wake up and ask,
"What's urgent today? Who needs [music]
me? What fire do I need to go and put
out?" Architects wake up and ask, "What
did I design last night? What's my one
big domino today?" They've already
decided, and that's how they create the
perfect day. Do this every day, and you
win.