The first and most important principle
of building an iconic personal brand is
delusional self-belief. And no one
proves this better than Michael Jordan.
Now, you may know Michael Jordan as the
superstar he became and the founder of
what's now a $6 billion brand empire,
but he was cut from his high school
basketball team. Cut. You can imagine
the heartbreak there. Michael Jordan had
an insatiable competitiveness. He used
the fuel of other competitors going and
chirping him or telling him he couldn't
do it. And he took that personally.
>> It became personal with me.
>> He didn't take it personally and just
let it go and demotivate him. He
actually used that as fuel to come back
10 times stronger. It was this
delusional self-belief that allowed him
to go to the Bulls, which was the worst
NBA team at the time, and have the
belief to go, you know what? I can turn
this thing around. He going to win no
matter how you look at