the greatest power in the universe is
human conviction it's built Empires
toppled governments and created mass
movements you'll only ever pursue
something to the degree that you believe
you can succeed so the person who
believes fully in what they're doing
pursues it to their maximum ability if
you're not motivated it's because you
lack conviction you lack faith in either
yourself or your goals here's a solution
pursue something you're actually excited
to achieve hang out with people who've
achieved it to prove to yourself that
it's possible map out your own path to
success and diligently track your
progress and stop listening to people
who say you can't because you can