Here's a controversial take. Doing
nothing is the most productive thing you
do. Neuroscience shows that your brain
has two major modes. One is that take
[music] action mode when you're getting
things done, getting after it, and
really just building something
impactful. But, the truth is that
[music] part of your brain can run dry,
which leads to the second mode, your
default mode. This is when you're at
rest, you're chilled out, and this is
what allows you to overall recharge and
make sure that you're not just running
yourself into the ground. We've all been
there, you know, at the end of a busy
day, you go take a break, and you go for
a nice shower.
>> [music]
>> The warm water hits you, and all of a
sudden you have some epiphany idea. That
big breakthrough that you were waiting
for all day. Well, why did that happen?
It's because you finally gave yourself
some stillness to let your nervous
system down regulate. Strategic
stillness is the only solution to
burnout that actually works.