You know, most people
won't be able to get to the end of this
video.
When you think about one of the most
difficult questions as a founder,
it's
is this business increasing my aliveness
or is it slowly draining me?
Now, then thinking about this and
journaling around this, the difference
between,
you know, a magnetic business
and a business that drains you.
What I've come up with, you know, is
ideally, you want to have that business,
right, where you get paid
to just be the best version of yourself,
not paid to become something that you're
not.
You know, where you are able to focus on
what you love
versus being surrounded by people and
things and tasks that just suck the life
out of you.
You know, it's
going and being able to,
you know, take a week, take 10 days, and
disappear in the nature like I have
today.
And have a team that can run things
without you.
It's, I think, inevitably
being able to lean in to daily flow,
right, and
be able to get lost in the kind of
things you're doing because you think
that you're
really contributing to the world at the
highest degree possible versus feeling
tension all day long. And so, ask
yourself this question. Is your business
increasing your aliveness or just
draining you?