Most people overestimate what they can
get done in a week and underestimate
what they can get done in a year. And
that's exactly what this video is about.
How to [music] design the next 365 days
of your life. If you give me the next 30
minutes, I'll give you the complete
detailed blueprint for your success this
year. And it starts with rethinking how
you plan [music] entirely. So, instead
of writing another list of things that I
hope to do, I built this system to
design my year for me. And I put the
exact template below so you can go and
fill it out with me as we go. By the
end, you'll have a full 365day plan
built and ready to execute. Let's
[music] dive in. First off, we're going
to start with the vision map. You know,
there's this quote from Abraham Lincoln
that I think about, which is that if you
gave me six hours to cut down a tree,
I'd spend four hours sharpening the axe.
[music] And so, that's what the vision
map is all about, right? It's getting
clear on where are we really looking to
go here, right? If you have a clear
vision in mind, then you can kind of
reverse engineer that throughout the
rest of your 365day plan. And so, who
are you becoming this year? Well, you
know, in here I'm going to put, you
know, an entrepreneur,
you know, with a successful,
you know, calm
and systemized
empire.
All right. So, when it comes down to
this, let's go and write out our
non-negotiables now to go get there. So
when I think about, you know, what what
I really need to be and what I need to
do this year to ladder [music] up to
this, you know, big vision, right, it
comes down to number one, founder flow
every single morning
from 8:00 a.m. to 12:00 p.m. Number one.
Number two, non-negotiable, you know, a
players only. Okay? Obviously, if we're
going to build this amazing, common,
systemized company, it comes down to
having unbelievable people on the team.
And so, we got to be super conscious as
to who we're bringing on, making sure
that they really embody the values of
the company, which leads me to
non-negotiable number three, which is
keep things [music]
insanely simple.
So when in doubt, you know, if something
feels overly complex, delete it. So that
what we're left with is just the
simplest possible company. Um, and you
know, really just keeping things easy so
that it's calm, you know, it's
systemized, and it's beautiful. All
right, so now we're going to get into
the northstar words, right? These are
the the two to three core words that
will help me go and hit this vision. So
number one is we're going to do, you
know, insanely simple. Um, I think is a
great theme to have. I'm going to go and
do obsess over quality
because at the end of the day, you know,
you got to lean into quality to make
things happen. And lastly is elevated
design in everything that I do. So,
we've got that nailed down. And in terms
of why this matters, life is short,
right? You only live once. And so, for
me, my big mission is to unlock my
creative potential, right? and help 100
million other founders unlock their
creative potential as well. And so in
order to ladder up to this big vision,
right, I need [music] to be disciplined
about these non-negotiables and live
within these themes to help 100 million
founders
hit their dreams. The next piece here is
[music] your energy season. So when I
think about, you know, a given year, I
like to break it down into the core
seasons of life, right? And generally a
season for me lasts around 90 days. So
we can think of it kind of like you know
Q1, Q2, Q3 and Q4 the different themes
for the year. And so we can kind of go
and write out now what's going to be the
core focus for each of these four
quadrants. So when I think about Q1 I'm
really focused on setting my audience on
fire. [music]
Okay. And so I'm going to put that as
the core theme there. You know for me
this looks like really blowing up our
newsletter. We've got two YouTube videos
going out which we hope in the next
decade to go and get that to streaming
platforms like Netflix and I've got a
book on the way. So this audience we're
going to blow that up. Now in Q2 we're
going to continue to kind of double down
on the infrastructure behind everything,
[music] right? I've been removed from
operations of the company. But like
anything, right, you just need to keep
putting those reps in with the team to
make sure that we have the right
systems, the right documentation, and
that everyone's running their given
playbook. And so Q2 will be about taking
that to the next level because we've got
big ambitions which means we need big
level infrastructure. Now when it comes
to Q3 it's going to be all about
community right at the end of the day
over the last four years building
Founder S I've grown a community of
around 14,000 founders. You know we
really want to go and lean into
community. How do we kind of bring
people together not just online but
offline as well? We've been running
these epic retreats every 6 months and
I'd love to see those start to move to
every 3 months and by 2027 start doing
different sorts of retreats every single
month lading up to a few years from now
being able to have an epic retreat
center in the Doommites you know epic
experience with founders snowboarding in
the winter downhill mountain biking in
the summer and just bringing amazing
people together. Now, when it comes to
Q4, it's all really about, you know,
celebration to be honest because it's
going to be a hell of a year and
expansion. So, we got audience,
infrastructure, community, and then
expansion and celebration. [music] So,
let's get into the Q1 focus and kind of
break down how I think about actually
going and scaling up my audience and
making this the core focus across
Founder OS in Q1. So the core system
here really well it comes down to the
content GPS which is by far the most
powerful system I've ever created in my
life. Now the key metric when I think
about what really matters the most is
probably profit
per piece of content. The reality is is
that when I think about blowing up an
audience, it's not just to grow a bunch
of followers, right? We want to make
sure we're doing it in a profitable way.
we're actually driving conversions with
a big vision like we've got here. We're
not just growing vanity metrics here. We
want to make sure that our content is
actually hitting the bottom line. And so
when it comes to environment, then the
one thing that makes this easier. Well,
for my own personal environment, again,
it's really just the founder flow every
single day, right? I know that if from
8:00 a.m. to 12:00 p.m. daily, I'm going
and spending the time I need to recruit
the best people, make sure they're being
systemized, make sure that, you know,
things like my book get done or, you
know, if I got to film a YouTube video
like this, it gets filmed. That founder
flow time is my creative time to do the
things that only I can do. by the end of
this season, right, we've got our
audience
at, you know, five million people and at
the end of the day, we've gone and hit
1 million per month in cash [music]
collected. The combination of both the
audience growth as well as the actual
cash collection goal for Founder OS
would, you know, be the onetwo punch
that the content GPS at this stage is
really ripping. And it's not just me
doing everything right. This is really
my team executing at a really high
level. Um, and then utilizing just the
magic of the content GPS to go and build
a massive amount of leverage around this
personal media company that we've
collectively set up. All right, so let's
move on to Q2. Right. The focus of Q2 is
infrastructure. [music]
And so, you know, one core system I
think about inside of Founder OS is
really the upsell and retention system
inside of the business.
When you're operating a business like
Founder OS, really any business, right?
It's all good to think about, you know,
new people that you need to bring into a
community, but way more important than
that is actually making sure that people
love it so much that they just keep
coming back. Now, thankfully, we've got
a great retention system at Founder
Rest. So, like any system, you want to
be continually improving it. And so, the
key metric here is going to be getting
the upsell
rate [music] to 70%.
This is the amount of people that come
into Founder OS and either renew in the
existing [music] thing they're doing or
go and ascend to the next level. Because
we have three different offerings when
it comes to Founder S. We have founder
OS for people doing six figures. Founder
OS velocity for people doing multiple
seven figures and then Founderos
Mastermind for folks that are doing
eight figures and beyond. And we want to
be helping people go and ascend to each
of these levels and ensure that we're
creating the greatest founder community
and experience of the 21st century. So
when it comes to the environment trigger
to go and get this going, one thing that
I'm really big on is doing a quarterly
offsite with [music] my team. So what's
likely to happen here is that in Q2, you
know, my whole team, which is really all
around the world, we get together. We're
going to jam around how we can go and
make the community, the experience even
that much better and [music] then split
and do our individual parts to create
this badass entrepreneur community. What
I really want to see happen is that
[music] we've implemented 100%
of the tasks from that company offsite.
So the focus of Q3 is all around
community. In order to go and actually
build a community, you can't just be
focused on audience growth, right? X,
LinkedIn, YouTube, Instagram, these are
great for building your audience, but at
some point you actually got to own these
people in your newsletter. The core
system that's going to be required is
our newsletter system, okay? And really
putting that on steroids. Now thankfully
right now you know we have a newsletter
about quarter million subscribers there.
The key metric I want to do though is
get our newsletter
um and the subs over there to 1 million
which would mean that we're doing a good
job of putting out amazing content
translating people from that content to
lead magnets getting their emails and
then nurturing folks inside of an
amazing newsletter. Now, the environment
trigger that's going to be needed here
is really making sure that you know one
time a week newsletter sprint meetings.
One really important thing is to make
sure that you know if you're looking to
accelerate an area, you can often times
just tighten the feedback loops. And so
by the end of this season, you know,
we're going to have um you [music] know,
a million subscribers
and we will also have you know, likely
three different
highlevel kind of welcome series built
out
that inspire founders to build [music]
their operating system with our help.
And so let's move along to Q4. It's all
about celebration and expansion. So
[music] the core system here, well, when
I really think about, you know, an
amazing year at this point now, I'm
going to [music] really kind of focus
honestly on my soul trip system. What I
find is that personally as a founder,
you know, if you're just building all
the time and you're shipping things,
you're seeing results, but you don't
take time to celebrate and then rest,
that's exactly what leads to burnout.
What I want to do here is make sure that
I'm actually focusing on, you know, 2026
and there's some epic life, you know,
experiences that are going to fill up my
cup. And so the key metric here, it's
probably going to sound ridiculous, but
I need to go to India. Mark Zuckerberg
trying to go and scale up Facebook and
not sure what to do. And so he went and
emailed his mentor at the time, Steve
Jobs, and was like, "Hey, we're scaling
this up. It's becoming more complex than
I thought. Like, what do I do?" And
Steve Jobs responded to Mark Zuckerberg
with just go to India. I mean honestly
there's not much I have to do here other
than you know just go for it. Uh so the
good news is the business is systemized
you know I can remove myself from it and
just take time just to actually rip it.
So by the end of the season I will have
you know I mean kind of simple you know
gone to India on that side too. Uh
making sure that I think also the team
is rewarded for a great year. So a big
thing here too is like making sure
people are being incentivized right
team's feeling good. We're all winning
together which is kind of like the
spirit of Founder OS. Our team as well
as the community is that we all want to
win together have ambitious dreams but
also know along the way celebrate and
have a good time. All right. So now
we've established a system that will
help you go and accomplish the different
seasons that will ladder up to this big
vision you have. But now it's all about
engineering momentum. When we think
about momentum, I think of it like
different energy blocks, right? When
you're going and building a business,
you really can't underestimate your own
energy and the importance of, you know,
using your energy at key parts of the
day for the tasks that are best for that
area. So, for me, deep work is in the
morning every single morning. This is my
time to, you know, write my book. If I
need to film, I'll get the filming done
right then when I'm fresh. this could
also be time to go and if I need to hire
anyone, I'm kind of like making sure I'm
all caught up on the hiring front. When
I think of different creative work, I
mean, there's a lot of different
creative tasks that I can be involved
in, but you know, creative work for me
may include things like, you know, going
and filming YouTube videos once a month,
right? So typically what I do there is
let's just say creative work YouTube
I'll batch that and we'll do say um a
Thursday
and Friday of the last week of a month.
So on the admin work side of things
honestly at the stage [music] I'm at I
shouldn't be doing any admin work. And
so the big thing here is making sure
that I have the chief of staff system
all up to date and I'm working closely
with uh Claire, my chief of staff as
well as my sister and making sure that
everything's really just delegated and
off my plate that's anything admin
related. So in terms of moment of my
day, uh there's none of that. Now, for
you guys, if you're thinking about the
different admin side, I typically like
to get to that after I've done all of my
deep work and creative work so that I'm
not going and getting lost in the soup
of emails first thing and then a day
ends and you haven't even got to
publishing that newsletter or creating
that new curriculum or bigger task that
is really going to move the needle in
your life and business. All right, so
now we're moving on to the keystone
habits. These are really the three to
five daily actions that you need to take
so you can ladder up to this amazing
vision that you've charted out over the
next 365 days. So habit number one for
me [music] is making sure that I get a 6
a.m. workout every day. Non-negotiable.
Habit number two then comes [music] down
to daily founder flow. Right? Without
founder flow, you know, I am nothing.
Right? The number one habit if you do
anything and get anything out of this
video, it's making sure that you're
going and dedicating ideally four hours
a day to making your vision come true
because you know your dreams don't work
unless you do. Habit number three has
got to come down to reading before bed.
Okay? Uh you know I have been guilty uh
for many years of my life of watching
[music] Netflix, HBO, you name it before
bed. And I think that, you know, screens
[music]
in bed are more destructive um than we
really realize, right? So, so no blue
light, no actually just going and
reading a little bit of a book every
single night and then falling asleep.
Habit number four is blocking social
media during the day. So making sure
that throughout my day, you know, I have
my phone is typically bricked [music] so
that I can't get access to any social
platform, which then again just locks me
into the big goals I have and eliminates
unnecessary distractions. [music] And
then the last one here is just getting
my 10k steps a day. Just being able to
walk around any city I'm in just gives
me the chance to kind of let my mind
wander a little bit, allows me to think,
be creative, and kind of recharge. And
so typically after my founder flow, I'll
go get my steps in, maybe go get a nice
smoothie, go for a walk, get out into
nature, and allow myself to kind of
reset my system for the afternoon.
[music] And then obviously, you know,
feel tired enough to get a good sleep.
Now you know what you need to get done
each day to be again that best version
of yourself that's capable of
accomplishing this [music] motivating
365day vision that you've charted out
for yourself. The key thing here is you
should just print this out, put it on
your wall wherever you want or put it in
your bathroom mirror, you name it.
Somewhere you're going to be able to use
this every day. Could be at your desk.
[music] And you're going to want to just
go and fill out that you get and hit all
of your keystone habits every single day
for the entire year. And so you can use
this to kind of be that reminder and
fill this out because what I would be
trying to do if I was you is hit all of
your three to five keystone habits every
single day and don't break the chain.
James Clear has this amazing quote which
is you don't rise to the level of your
goals, you follow to the level of your
systems. And so this whole deck, right,
and what we're going through here is all
about creating systems over goals. And
so let's stop creating to-do lists here
and let's get into the four quadrants of
life, right? which are your lifestyle,
your business, relationships, and
health. You know, at Founder OS, you
know, I'm really about helping founders
live like well-rounded lives. So, what
we want to do is make sure that we're
going and architecting the right systems
in place to live a vibrant life and also
to have a sense of regret minimization.
So, let's get into the business [music]
side of things. The leverage for this
project name, okay, is all going to be
around ecosystem
expansion, right? And so [music] when I
think about what needs to happen on the
business side [music] as I think about
really expanding our audience and our
community, well the input there is going
to be, you know, our 4x newsletters per
week and it's going to be the 2x YouTube
videos that we have. Okay. Now the
process that comes into place really is
our content waterfall system. Okay.
which allows us to take one pillar piece
of content and then turn that into 32
other pieces of content across all
platforms, which allows us to get the
most bang for our buck from our best
ideas and those deep pillar pieces of
content that we create. Now, on the
output side, what that causes is that we
get 32 pieces [music]
of content from the core pieces of
content we create. And the leverage
result is that across the brand, we're
growing the audience and hitting that
sort of 5 million target [music] that
we've got in terms of the audience size
and then also going and getting the
business [music] to a million plus per
month. The reality is there's three
other quadrants to life. And now when
you're really looking to go and live
that abundant life, well, you can't have
abundance without your health. My
project name here is going to be my
longevity protocol. Right now, longevity
means a lot of different things to a lot
of different people. For me, it's not
just about living a long time, but it's
also about, you know, living to my
fullest potential and enjoying the
journey. And [music] so, the input for
me is making sure that I am essentially
getting my HIT workout in every single
day and that I'm meditating every day.
And so the process here, right? Well,
honestly, I don't really like to think
about these workouts too much as an
example. Okay? And so the trigger there
is that these days, honestly, every
morning, I just go to berries, right? I
don't need to go and think about the
workout I'm going to put together,
right? I just wake up, go to berries,
and it's all taken care of for me,
right? And so the output there, well, I
mean, I feel amazing. Um, and uh, you
know, I'm as productive as I need to be.
um and feeling awesome. And the leverage
result is that well, I'm hitting all,
you know, my health goals. That's the
health protocol. That's the longevity
protocol. It's really that simple. And I
wanted to put this in this 365day plan
because honestly, healthy founders build
healthy businesses. So, we've got our
health gone and mapped out. Let's talk
about, you know, the relationship side
of things. So, for the purposes here,
I'm going to talk about, you know, the
relationships inside of our community at
Founder OS. um and building these
awesome amazing relationships with high
growth founders because to me that's
really my calling in life. And so I'm
going to call the project name here
founder [music] community. The input is
going to be you know two times per day
um calls with founders. And so some days
these calls are around audience growth,
other days is around helping people with
their offer. Sometimes it's just having
a good time and jamming together. But,
you know, me and my team typically are
having over 50 calls every single month
with founders, making sure that founders
feel supported, they have someone along
their side. And so, the key process
[music] here internally at Founder OS is
our calendar system, right? Making sure
that all of us have enough space in our
calendar to really go and give founders
the support that they deserve. Now the
output here is that this really
contributes to that 70% upsell rate I
was talking about because if founders
feel really supported inside of founder
us they stick with us for a long time
which is exactly what we see and then
the leverage result here is that we're
able to go and invest back in founder
success right and make sure that you
know we're going and investing in things
like amazing founder retreats the epic
founder hikes that we go and create we
can go and staff up our team with even
more advisers and mentors for founders
and really go and create this
unbelievable experience. Let's get into
the lifestyle, right? And so the project
name here, let's call Freedom
Architecture.
All right, this is really, you know, how
I'm going to go and just, you know, take
things to that next level of abundance,
you know. So, you got this, you know,
big dream as an example of going to
India. 2026 is the year. And so, the
input here, right? Well, first off,
[music] it's really just time freedom,
right, which I already have. But the
input is really then just to keep on
working closely with my chief of staff
to just continue to dial in, you know,
my overall calendar, you know, making
sure that all tasks are removed from my
plate [music] and making sure that, you
know, basically leading up to that trip,
everything's gone so I can just do my
month off the grid and enjoy myself. On
the process side of things, I think the
key thing that I like to think about is
doing a time audit every three months.
So going and looking at the different
things that I'm spending my time on and
then making sure that I'm marking down
what stuff I can delegate, automate or
eliminate. And I think this is a good
exercise for founders to do no matter
your stage every few months because you
know any business kind of defaults to
chaos, right? And so it's important that
as a founder you're constantly
reflecting on the things that you should
actually be doing and making an effort
to constantly be delegating things so
you can elevate yourself to new heights.
And so the output here is that you know
obviously you're removed from operations
and then you know the leverage result is
that you know you're off to India. One
hell of a reward. And really I think the
biggest bottleneck here is just me just
sending it quite honestly. So you know
maybe sooner maybe sooner. All right. So
you've built a system now you have the
plan. Now, it comes down to the personal
board meeting. Now, of all the systems
I've ever created, I think this is the
one I've been using the longest,
probably for the last 15 years of my
life. And the reason it's so powerful,
right, is because it's this monthly
system that allows you to go and
actually revisit your 365day plan. It
allows you to then reflect on what's
going well, what's not going well, and
then make sure that you're planning out
the next month. Because, [music] you
know, so much of success in life is
about correction. You know, we all know
those people. Maybe you've been that
person, right, that sets out, you know,
these big ambitious visions for your
life or makes those New Year's
resolutions only for it to be January
15th and you've completely forgotten
about it. The personal board meeting
makes sure that you know these dreams
actually come true. The approach is
essentially that you're going and
reflecting on the previous month. You're
then iterating and doubling down on the
stuff that's working and then you're
just staying consistent [music] with the
personal board meeting. Now, let's move
on to the zoomed out destination here.
Okay, this is kind of like the onepage
vision. So, I'm going to go and fill
this out for you um right here. But what
you probably can go and do is if you've
gone and followed me so far through this
365day plan, you've probably charted out
a lot of your values, your goals, or
you've even thought through some of
these things. And so, what you can do is
just kind of take all the stuff you
filled out so far and go and backfill it
into this vision board. Okay? So when I
think about my values, it's things like
love, it's nature, it's things like
community, which is the whole impetus
behind Founder OS. It's simplicity.
Um I'm really into design and, you know,
think that if you're going to build
anything, you might as well uh make it
super beautiful. And then um connection
because [music] I think in this day and
age, you know, we don't really get that
deep level connection with as many
people um as we should. And so, you
know, between nature, community,
connection, I can make sure that I'm
balancing all the business pursuits in
my life with also, you know, making sure
that [music] I'm really, you know,
filling up my cup and being a
well-rounded human being. When we then
dive into the 10ear goals, that's the
next area I like to do. So for here, you
know, this is like getting this all done
by say 2035. [music]
And my 10-year goals include things
like, you know, getting a show onto
Netflix, um having an amazing family, um
going and setting up two homes
throughout the world. [music] So on the
three-year goal side, that would be 3
years from now, which is 2028. [music]
And the three-year goals include things,
well, number one, having a systemized
empire, right? And just continue to kind
of scale what we have going here across
the portfolio of companies I'm running,
going and getting that portfolio to over
$30 million a year in revenue. And then
in terms of the different kind of
pursuits in my own life, again, I think,
if I'm being ambitious here, I think we
can have a family in 3 years. I think
it's possible. Let's move on to the
90-day side of things. Okay. When it
comes to the vision, right, I'm looking
to go and impact a 100red million
founders with what we have going with
Founder OS and ultimately really looking
to unlock my full creative potential. My
mission is to really go and inspire
people and help them live a life of
freedom. And then the niche that Founder
OS operates in is really founder
operating systems. My belief is that
every founder needs an operating system.
You know, just like your MacBook needs
an OS. Well, you're a founder and you
need an OS. Now, on the personal side, I
see my personal niche as soulful
entrepreneurship, right? Just this idea
that, you know, you can build businesses
differently, right? I think for too long
in my career, I thought it was all
about, you know, raising money and
burning the midnight oil and building
things as big as you could. These days
though, I want to build things as
peaceful, as calm, as impactful as I can
and make sure that I'm living a more
balanced life. being able to have a
business that runs itself, have a team
that I'm really proud of that, you know,
we're all doing our life's work, and
just have that like well-rounded,
[music] you know, abundant life. And so,
on the system side, the core target of
folks that I'm going and serving are
folks just like you, right? Really
intentional people [music]
um that are looking to go and have um
you know, as much kind of like time
freedom in their lives as possible.
Okay. Now the uniques that I think I go
and offer to people, simplicity
plus systems
plus support
and then an amazing community um inside
of Founder OS. And so those are like the
four uniques that make us different.
Now, the core process that kind of
brings this all together is the content
GPS, which is the most powerful system
for going and scaling a personal media
company, allowing you to actually grow a
big audience, have the right team in
place, the right org chart set up, so
you can go and scale in a smooth,
peaceful way. Now, the guarantee, well,
what I'm really looking to make sure
that behind all this is that founders
and high performers get as much clarity
as possible. This is something that I
like to revisit every single month and
make sure that what I'm working on in a
given month is lading up to this vision
that candidly seriously fires me up. And
I think that if you're looking at your
zoomed out destination and you're not
excited, well, you're doing something
wrong. What this may involve is like
really thinking big, right? What does
the most abundant version of your life
look like? All right, so we put this
whole plan in place, right? But how will
this feel when you get it done?
oftentimes, I think, this is important
because when you're trying to like
manifest something or make something
happen, right, you want to make sure
that you can feel, right, what it's
going to feel like. If I was to sum this
up, you know, for me, I'm going to feel
really like fully alive, right? I can
just imagine a world where, you know,
I've set [music] up this epic founder
retreat center in the Doommites.
Founders are coming out. They're like
mind blown by this setting that they're
in that we've actually been able to
architect this and make it happen. I
often times like to reflect on like what
would like the 20-year-old yourself or
like the 12year-old self, you know,
think of where you are now at 36, right?
And honestly, I'd be proud of
myself. This kind of feeling of being
fully alive, I feel is something that,
you know, I can live every day of my
life. And as I continue to cultivate
that feeling, I'm able to show up and be
the best brother, the best CEO, the best
friend, family member, all that good
stuff, um, to the people around me. And
so that's the feeling I'm trying to
cultivate. So, what's the feeling that
you're looking to cultivate in your own
life? Go and write that down here. Most
people will just go and drift through
the year, but not you, right? Because
now you have the system to go and design
your life. So, grab the template below
in the description and start building
today. And if you need help with the
systems part, well, that's exactly what
me and my team can help you with inside
of Founder OS. If you're looking for
systems, the support, the guidance, and
direct access to me, well, you can go
and check that out via the link in the
description. And if you want to go
deeper in building out your personal
board meeting, go and check out this
next video where I go and give you a
behind the scenes of how I go and build
this out for myself.