One, two, three, four.
[Music]
So,
I'm out here at a Bali Villa, gone and
flown in three members of my team, our
head of content, head of sales, and
chief staff. We have an ambitious 10
days ahead of us. It's a good chance
when we're all in person to scrub things
like our newsletter strategy, YouTube
strategy, Instagram strategy. So, what
we like to do is just go into the
details, right? Figure out what's
working best. A lot of people, you know,
will give you all these different
productivity hacks, but the reality is
an old school checklist just works its
magic. I like to go and just dump all of
my to-dos into something like Apple
Notes. The note is titled Bali. I
started at the top just reminding myself
I am an athlete. No small boy [\h__\h] What
would make the better story? Abundance,
community, and fun. These are just a
couple things when I read them, I'm
like, "All right, let's [\h__\h] go." A
key aspect here that I think gets lost
is that I'm still involved in the
details. I'm just involved in the right
details. I think there's this
misconception, you know, that's really
existed in companies for the last 5
years, which is this concept of
micromanagement. I think it's made a lot
of founders and CEOs scared to actually
just get in the details, to get in the
mix, to know what's going on in your
business. I think of myself as the chief
detail officer of Founder OS and of
Herb. You know, there is no detail of
the business that's too small for me to
have an understanding of. I get it
right. Sometimes it's so overwhelming
all of the details in a business. So,
here's a simple way to think about those
details. Three useful frameworks to look
at. The first one is you likely want to
look at things that are high impact,
loweffort. These are the things that you
can do pretty easily that are instantly
going to move the needle forward in your
business. Number two is you want to
probably look at the tasks that are
going to have the biggest financial
impact. What are the things that are
going to be most cash driving? Cuz
inevitably you're probably not going to
look back on completing that thing and
regret it. You know it actually move the
needle forward. Lastly, and sometimes
this is most important is just what
excites you on the list. You know, maybe
just kind of follow that energy. go and
get that thing done while it feels
spicy, it feels fun, it feels enjoyable.
One thing I think that also gets
overlooked along the way is that we as
humans believe that we shape our
environment, but it's equally as true
that our environment shapes us. I'm here
in Bali. You know, we've got the gym set
up, the cold bath, the sauna, the right
people, the right nature. We've got
everything that we need to make this a
high performing environment and then get
all these details hammered out. Chief
Detail Officer, you know, start viewing
yourself like that. Welcome to the club.
Got a message from ex named Lewis Crook
and Lewis runs form Bali. They do blood
work. Again, you think that the benefits
are just, you know, recruiting and
getting leads or whatever, but you know,
personal brands also lead to blood
draws.
more I take care of my health, the more
just like everything in my life
transforms, including my business. I was
just on a call this morning for about an
hour with my health coach, Satie, and
she was saying how, you know, she almost
thinks of these sort of metrics. You
know, when you're like a CEO, she'll
almost be as important and almost
included with like the rest of your
company metrics, your revenue growth in
a month and your profit growth in a
month and your team size and your cost
and your profit margin. All these things
are important, but equally if not I mean
way more important is stuff like your
testosterone levels, vitamin levels
across your body. Like as an example, I
found through much more optimized
mineral levels of all things, you know,
it's given me a much greater ability to
deal with stress, also be a lot less
reactive. And then you can imagine how
that translates into management and into
being a leader. Someone does something
that kind of annoys you instead of just
being the first to react to it. Maybe it
just gives you that like six second gap
now to slow down, take a breath, pause,
and then respond to it away or even ask
a question that then leads to a
completely different outcome because
you're feeling good versus the person
that isn't taking care of themselves is
highly reactive and just kind of bites
back uh when someone maybe on the team
makes a mistake. you kind of compound
that sort of decision-m and as CEOs we
make, you know, 10,000 big and small and
tiny decisions a day. The compounding
effect of that over months, years, I've
seen is insane. Healthy founders build
healthy businesses.
[Music]
Do you mind if I do just a simp? I'm
here to do selfies. Why? Do you mind?
Take a picture. One, two, three.
Honestly, well, the only guy who makes
simple, complex, complex shapes like
really and the way I use your voice also
helps me a lot. I was like, one day I
meet you, I need to say thank you. Yeah,
thanks. Appreciate, man. Thank you guys.
Here we go. Your perfect tummy. Good.
Was it Casey? Nice that just wait
walking around just waiting for someone
to say again. Hey nice
never know if love will be made
just and just in general in my life like
I have a health coach that I sync with
like often just like to manage my energy
better like just like it's not about
[\h__\h] driving so hard like that is
always my default. She was like, "It
sounds like you need to do a better job
at parenting yourself." Like you're kind
of acting like a kid that just like is
not there no supervision. It's like,
"All right, I'm going to do this. I'm
going to do that. I'm going to do that."
He's like, "Manage yourself, you know?"
So, even like today a bit or whatever.
It's like I can feel myself when I'm
like, "Okay, whoa." Like, it's like,
"Okay, just slow her down. Slow her
down." He was sustainable. He was
sustain. Good news is is that's what
you're telling everybody to do too in
all the videos. Yeah. We're supposed to
live this [\h__\h]
[Music]
So, we've got like 152 slides we're
ripping here. I thought it was yeah,
really important. It's one thing just to
say we're going to do something. It's
another thing just to show it. So, I
spent about 4 hours. I put this thing
together. I guess like the science and
the art behind scaling this so that
quality if anything grows over time. As
we scroll through this, I'll skip a
bunch of the intro because we already
know this [\h__\h] This is more for the
rest of the team if they need to be
onboarded to it. as we're kind of making
an effort now is like really nailing
down these brand principles, right? So,
I think some key ones that we've been
focused on really recently is obsessive
craftsmanship, the aesthetics, which
we'll get into here in a second, keeping
things insanely simple along the way,
and then hitting them with some of the
aesthetics just to flex our taste.
Looking at this deck, I can show you how
I've already organized the brand
principles in terms of the organic
content, and I could just show you.
Taking the brand themes from here, I
think one of the biggest things is
people don't know how to communicate
brand in organic lifestyle content
because they think that their life is
just organically their brand, but that's
not strategic. So, in this there's three
tabs here. There's like kind of a video
context. It's a lot of words, but this
is just like everything that we can feed
into Claude or ChatgPT
um to make anything. But here's like the
core themes, topics, and storylines that
are taken directly from that last brand
principles page. Kind of inception, but
make art not content. That's exactly
like what this scene shows you. The
other themes in this v video being you
being a chief detail officer, so within
the business, and then a return on
brand, like the philosophy of personal
brand's impact on business one step
further so that we make sure that we get
the organic material out of your mouth.
questions that are designed to prompt
you to engage with the audience,
entertain the audience, inspire, and
impress the viewers. This is just to
show you the detail that I've taken from
your articulation of what brand
principles and our through lines are
into like a video by video kind of
structure. That's how I plan on on
taking that into action. I think it
makes a lot of sense. I mean, for all
these, yeah, the key thing is decks are
nice and all, but making sure that the
deck actually translates to the plans
that we got on the ground floor. Decks
and Docs. Decks and Docs, baby.
Inevitably, like our vision with the
community at Founder OS is to help
founders unleash their creative
potential. And so, we want to live that
vision like we do with everything else.
And we've been talking to a lot about
that like interesting balance like on
the one side you have like the artistic
prowess of someone like a Gauss and then
on the other side you have like like the
off-the- cuff value per second of like a
hormosi. And in a way, we kind of want
like a piece of both those worlds.
Obviously though, keep like organically
us. On the system side, I think we have
like a bunch of different ways we can be
showcasing systems to keep it
entertaining. There's the one aspect of
using sort of screen flow just behind
the scenes like actually sharing my
screen. There's another one which is
like the more aesthetic approach whether
that's just like showing me writing it
on paper or whatever it may be. I think
the thing that we can improve here is
showing like the actual system being
implemented live with the team. I don't
think a lot of people realize that like
I run a sales team of eight people. I
run a customer success team of six
people. I'm working with you
collaboratively on the creative team of
like nine people there. I think if
people can see like the details and the
systems actually coming to life with a
group of people, it's like, oh [\h__\h]
that's how that works. I think what's
cool is we have like our super valued
dense formats on videos where you walk
people through the content GPS or like
your organic content strategy for each
social platform and then starting to
incorporate like more lifestyle content
where like people see this isn't just a
script that we whipped up to like give
people value that we think they need.
It's the actual stuff that you get value
out of within your business. So, it's
like when you're telling people create a
Pinterest board and then you're like
showing me 152page deck of what you
want. It's not like this BS that we're
putting people like on a wild goose
chase. For sure. Well, I think that's
okay. Lit.
So, I know a lot of you are watching
this right now and you're going, "Matt,
one sec. Can you share this deck with
me?" The answer is probably no. I think
this is internal company IP and I ain't
sharing this. So, you're going to have
to stick around, watch every week
because we're going to be rolling this
out slowly. That said, what does this
deck consist of? Well, you can just see
that I've taken down every single core
detail of what makes a brand and I found
references, and I've written down what
my expectations are for each of those
aspects. Lighting, contrast, copy, you
know, the different shots we want, the
moments we want, the dialogue, the
branding, the consistency, the
cinematography, the references, the
creators, how to actually do it, the
systems. I mean, the list goes on. As
you can see, the key thing that I want
you to remember, right, is that you have
a vision. You know what you want if
you're being honest. You don't have to
go and do things the way Matt does it,
Hormosi does it, Gary Vee does it,
Bartlett does it. Name the person. I
think in fact, when you have that
feeling like, "Oh, I don't want to be
like this thing." Cool. That's probably
actually a sign that you do have a
vision for what you do want to be then.
So document it, write it down, detail it
out, find the references of those things
and share it. I don't care whether it's
Pinterest, a deck, Google Slides,
Keynotes, Photoshop, Figma. [\h__\h] the
tools. You need to go and document it.
You have the ability to translate
whatever the hell's in your brain to
some sort of board or deck or something.
Put it down so that you can share it
with others. You know, the key leverage
point that I want to make sure you
remember from this, right, is that when
you finally take all that creativity
that's been circling in your brain,
that's been keeping you up at night,
that you've been dreaming about, and you
translate that to something that others
can see. What then happens is you
mobilize people. You mobilize an
audience. You mobilize your team because
finally they can see, okay, [\h__\h] that's
what you mean. And that's where the real
magic happens because then you're not
the only one staying up at night
dreaming about that vision. you've now
enabled other folks around you to dream
that same vision as you. So hopey this
has inspired you. I mean, just talking
about this fires me up. We got a lot of
big [\h__\h] under the way. You're going to
want to stay tuned. So be sure to like
and subscribe and welcome to the Founder
Freedom Movement.
11 p.m. leadership meeting. Good
evening. Hey guys. What's up everybody?
There's the legend himself. Doing well
y'all. Doing well. How we doing? Cool.
Let's get right into it. I think the big
things is like we are in a year where
like I think the themes are like founder
success and the other theme is like
recruiting the best of the best. Like
these roles come open and they're really
an opportunity for us to go okay like
how I internalize it is hey those were
some great team members. This is like a
sign that we can actually like it's time
to level up. I think one aspect though
that could always be increased is like
finding some down [\h__\h] that are
just obsessed constantly around what
we're doing. Hey, we do a deck and
they're like, "Oh, can I help with that
system?" "Oh, I noticed this YouTube
video you put out. You put that design
there. Like, can I help with that? Oh,
the event's coming up. What can I help
with it there?" Like, they're just in
it. It's like someone that's just like,
"But what about this and this and this
and this?" And you're like, "Wow, this
person's just producing." And the kind
of people I think that we need to have
going forward are also people that like
aren't so precious that it's like I
heard this story of like Evan Spiegel
from Snapchat. He would get like 20
things around the product, maybe say yes
to one every now and then. It's not
garbage though. the fact that you didn't
push those other 19 product designs.
That's just like part of though building
a great brand is just saying no no no
experimenting and I'm like yeah you
pushed some stuff. We're we're standing
on such like good ground that you know
now we can just go so high and really
push the envelope with it. So I'm
excited. Overall I think things are
going well. January is like been solid.
It sets the tone for like okay can we
build a really formidable founder
experience and keep compounding there?
Also keeping in mind obviously we're the
leaders. So can we make sure that the
people around us are like really
elevating right and constantly pushing
the needle which is like the main
leverage we can provide right and when
we talk about building the greatest
founder community of the 21st century I
think this is like a step in the right
direction these are often times some of
our best months of the whole year so now
is really the time to hit it you know
now's the time to put our foot on the
gas all right let's do this y'all
appreciate you guys all much love there
we are so that was the four leaders at
Founder OS all what I like to call down
[\h__\h] The best thing about
being surrounded with people like that
in your company is that it's just an
incredibly smooth transition from the
vision that you have as a founder to
then translating it to these people that
don't just nod their heads, agree on
things, and then not get them done. No,
I know these are the kind of people that
are going to instantly action the stuff
that we commit to and get after it.
These are the kind of people that, you
know, I got to pinch myself many days to
be like, damn, I'm so lucky to get to
work with such talented people that
care, that show up, that take extreme
ownership, that are obsessed with the
founder experience. A lot of founders
get caught up in wondering, you know,
how do I find the perfect leadership
team? I think first things first in
life, you get what you tolerate. If you
want to have an amazing leadership team,
you need to make sure that you have a
standard within your company, within
your brand, that is something
aspirational, inspirational, that is
attractive to someone that is an A
player, a brand that stands for
something that you have a compelling
vision for where you're trying to go
with your company that an individual's
vision can fit under that umbrella. That
at the end of the day, I think that
you're just building a product that
people love. I think when you have that
bar, when you have that standard, it
really translates, right? People can
feel my passion for what I'm doing. They
can feel the love, the obsessiveness,
the craftsmanship, the artistry, the
taste, the time, the love that goes into
every pixel, every email, every piece of
content, every YouTube video, every
detail. When you translate that to
someone, whether that's some hiring post
I put out on Instagram, the right people
I find, are attracted to that sort of
messaging, that energy, that vision. If
you genuinely believe in what you're
doing, put yourself out there. Put the
message out there because people
gravitate to founders that have a vision
and are passionate about what they do.
And this is why I'm so passionate about
founder brands because beyond marketing
and all this other stuff people may use
brands for. I think they're one hell of
a recruitment weapon. You know, it's
January 2025. You know, we got a big
year ahead of us here. And it's going to
be these weapons on the leadership team
that are going to be really critical in
making this all happen. So yeah, that's
my spiel.
All right. So, I talk a lot about being
a chief detail officer as the founder
and CEO of your empire. And so, this is
how to be a chief detail officer. 111
scaling details that you need to know
about. So, details kill companies, okay?
You need to know the ins and outs,
right, of how your content system works.
You need to know your cash system in
your business from going from, you know,
someone that's aware of what you do
through to that person actually going
and joining as a customer, right? You
need to understand that entire flow.
Now, details can kill you, right? Or
they can help scale your company. But
most founders, they miss 90% of what
actually matters because they don't
understand the ins and outs of their
business, which is super important. So,
it's time for you to become a chief
detail officer. So, what I've done here
is I've summarized 111 of the core
details that as you scale from nothing
to 8 figures and beyond, the details
that you need to have sorted out in your
business. It doesn't mean that you need
to do all of these things yourself,
right? Systemizing and delegating are
key, but you do need to be aware of
these things. You do need to have these
things documented so that as you scale,
you build a calm company. A company
where you can leave for a month and come
back and that business is stronger than
when you left. It's not sucking your
soul. You know, the last thing you want
to be doing is running a business that's
just running you into the ground. And I
know because I've been there. You know,
my first business, BitMaker, it nearly
ruined me. I felt every day like I was
depressed. I was down and out. And from
the outside, things look successful, but
inside I felt rotten. And so what I want
to do here is detail out the sort of
systems and details that you need to
have sorted in your business to help you
scale peacefully, which is really what
it's all about, right? So these are 111
insane details that will change
everything for you. Let's get into it.
So first off, on the content side,
right? Let's talk about some of the
details you need there. You know, I
think first off, you need a content GPS
in your business, right? which is the
way that I've gone and grown my
audience. I scale those people through
to newsletter subscribers and then drive
them to the different portfolio
companies that I go and I operate. You
want to make sure that each platform you
have different guidelines for your brand
voice is documented. You have a quality
control checklist across your product,
across your content to make sure that
things are dialed in without mistakes.
You want to have an amazing distribution
strategy, right? Ideally picking two
platforms to start. If you're video
first, that may be Instagram and
YouTube. If you're more writing first,
you may choose a platform like X and
LinkedIn. And as a founder, you need to
be building your brand, right? The
future of brands are founderled and
people follow people, then they follow
companies. So, you want to make sure as
a founder that you're putting your face
out there, you're putting your message
out there, and building a movement. In
addition to that, you want to make sure
you're tracking analytics, the
performance, doubling down on what's
working every month, and then reducing
the things that just ain't working. When
I go and think about my own content,
right, I go and try to create 50% of
content that's growth content to grow
more eyeballs to my business, to my
audience and grow the followers. And
then 50% of the content is more niche
content and that's more specific content
speaking exactly to founders that are
doing seven figures and beyond and
helping them with the specific stuff
that they need. So growth content may be
something like a deep work piece of
content I put out there that's
applicable to everyone. Whereas niche
content may be about how to build a
organic content funnel. So something
much more specific, much more niche to
what I do in you know my systems focus
of my content. So this is the content
GPS. And if there was any system that
has been most responsible to my success
over the last 14 years building multiple
seven and eight figureure companies, it
is this system. So growing a personal
media company around myself with an
amazing team and systems in place to
grow on platforms like Instagram,
YouTube, Tik Tok, X and LinkedIn. Then I
drive these people to my owned audience
in my newsletter through different CTAs
and really high converting content. And
then driving people through to
customers, onboarding them correctly,
making sure they have a remarkable
amazing experience, ensuring that they
then want to tell all their friends
about it. And then this creates a profit
flywheel because you bring in a
customer, you dazzle them, they go tell
their friends, and then boom, you just
have this organic growth engine in your
business. Inevitably, when you're
growing, the best growth hack is just an
amazing product.
Now, another thing that you want to make
sure you have set up in the details end
of things is your content calendar.
Remember, the best content strategy is
the one that you can stick with. And so
here's an example of what my content
distribution looks like across every
platform. I'm not saying you need to do
what I'm doing here, but I do think you
need to know the details of when your
content is coming out on specific times
of day on specific platforms you're live
on. If you're just getting started, you
know, again, maybe you're just doing a
few posts a week on X or a few LinkedIn
posts a week, but eventually you want to
kind of, you know, grow that to a more,
you know, omniresent distribution
schedule like the one I'm showing you
here.
Now on the operations excellence side,
you need to make sure that you have
things like a daily dashboard in your
company so that your team can go and
understand the metrics and the health of
the business across every single
department. You want to make sure that
your project management is dialed in so
you're increasing the shipping velocity
in your company and you're getting the
right things done on time. You want to
make sure that you have things like all
your systems backed up, your reporting
structures, your security protocols to
protect your website, protect your IP,
and make sure that all of your tool
stack is documented as well. A key part
of why you want to document all these
things is so that when you have a new
hire go and join your team, they're not
meandering around for 3 months wondering
where is everything? How does this
company even work? When you have things
documented, you have processes in place,
you have the systems in the right spot
for the right people in a company wiki,
maybe in notion or maybe in a Google
workspace, you just make it way easier
for your company to navigate, to manage,
to scale. And the benefit there is that
when you bring on new people or even for
your existing team, they can move fast.
And that is the ultimate advantage of
any small business. While big businesses
are archaic and slow, small startups win
because of speed. So these systems help
you optimize for speed. This is an
example of me going and documenting the
operations workflow for our videos,
right? So we go and we have ideiation
which own which is owned by me. We have
a calendar that we create like you just
saw. From there, we're planning out our
videos because packaging comes first. So
title, thumbnail, and the concept. We're
then going and recording these videos.
They then go to editing distribution and
then we go and we monitor performance.
So at every step of the flow here,
there's a core owner, a core system. And
this helps us go and ramp up the
distribution, ramp up the quality
because everything is documented very
clearly with specific owners. So this is
just an example of the kind of systems
you want to have in place. Now customer
success, my belief is that it is the
most powerful form of marketing. So, you
want to make sure that you're having NPS
surveys that go out, you know, net
promoter scores so you can understand,
you know, how likely are your customers
to recommend your business to a friend.
You want to make sure that you have
success metrics in place, understanding
things like, you know, how retained are
your customers, how likely are they to
refer you to other people, you know, are
they leaving reviews on your product,
are they recommending you, are they, you
know, being a real advocate for your
brand? Inevitably, you don't just want
customers, right? You want these
ambassadors that they go, they
experience your product or service and
they can't help but go and tell five
friends about you. That is what success
looks like for me. So, on the success
metric side, you may look at things like
the amount of Trust Pilot reviews you
get, your client wins, you can look at
different call notes, a sauna task
completion, which is the project
management tool we use internally at
Founder OS and my portfolio of
companies. In addition to that, you
know, I like to make sure that given
people on my team are sending end of day
and end of week reports so that we have
a tight communication in our company
because as a company scales, you know,
communication is probably the biggest
strain on a company. And so the more
people are staying in the loop, sending
detailed reports end of week on what
they accomplished, what they're getting
done next week, any bottlenecks or
challenges they're experiencing, the
more that we can just continually dial
things in as a squad. Now, brand is
everything. The thing that I enjoy most
as I'm building a business is the brand.
You know, setting up things like brand
guidelines, brand identity, the
community guidelines, the way that our
brand shows up, the different voice, the
tone, the copy, the visual identity,
making sure that at any single touch
point, you know, whether it's an email,
a newsletter, a social post, you know,
anywhere, that all of that stuff is
consistent. I think that great brands
should feel like they are all coming
from one person. So even if it's a whole
team working on a brand, I want to feel
like every single touch point I
experience feels like, oh, this just all
feels so tight, so cohesive, so
consistent no matter where I'm viewing
this brand. That is something I am
obsessed with. So this is an example of
really then documenting say brand
positioning in your company, right? So
that not just you but your team, your
sales, your customer success, they all
know how to speak about your brand. So
this is an example for founder OS,
right? Number one, the best way to build
an online business is a personal brand.
That's really our thesis on the future.
The next aspect here is that you need to
be creating content that's beautiful,
systemized, and scalable to build an
amazing personal brand. And lastly, the
best way to build an impactful personal
brand is a content GPS system with
Founder OS, which again is the most
powerful system I've ever invented.
Now the next aspect here is finance,
right? And you know cash flow is the
lifeblood of your business. So you want
to make sure your forecasting is dialed.
You have your profit margin dialed
across all your different products.
You're tracking expenses. Where's the
revenue attribution coming per channel
that you're distributing your content
on? You have things like your financial
reporting dialed in, tax planning,
investments. You know, all of these core
items are key. So I'll show you here
too. This is my delegation example,
right? You want to make sure that when
you're going and delegating to folks
that you're bringing on people that when
you look at the math, it just makes
sense. This person really quick is going
to be a 3 4x ROI based on what you're
paying them. And if you can keep making
good bets, right, which you know,
bringing on people to your company is
essentially a bet. The better you are at
that, the better and more smoothly
you're going to be able to scale. And
more importantly, you're going to be
able to build a product that people love
and a culture that you are having fun
with and excited to wake up wake up to
every single day. And so marketing
precision is another core aspect you
want to be thinking about. So every
single part of the customer journey
needs to be mapped out, right? You need
to have your email marketing flows, your
brand guidelines, your marketing
counter, conversion optimization,
community management, and the ROI of
these activities all across the board.
This is an example of my marketing
calendar over the next 12 months. So,
I've indicated every single month what's
a core activity that we're doing on the
marketing side to build a level of FOMO,
to build hype, to build excitement, to
constantly have great things that we're
releasing to keep things jazzy, you
know, to keep people juiced up in our
audience because there's just always
good stuff coming down the pipe. In
addition to that, right, you need to
make sure that you have a badass
distribution strategy. So focusing on
nailing two platforms to start and then
scaling out from there. You know, I
originally started on X and LinkedIn
when I was going. I then six months
later took my best content to Instagram,
to YouTube, to Tik Tok in short form
videos. And then when I felt more
comfortable, I started bringing things
to the big stage here on YouTube. And so
what you want to be doing is the same
thing, right? Pick two platforms to
start. If you like being on video, go
YouTube and Instagram. If you like
writing, then maybe X in LinkedIn.
Either way, you should have a newsletter
as well and get ripping. Just get
started. Get 10% better every week, and
before you know it, you'll be a maestro.
I like to have things like purchase
flywheels baked in, too. This is an
example here. When someone joins one of
my products, they then are prompted to
go and share that they joined on X on
LinkedIn, which creates this flywheel
essentially in my businesses. Sales,
right? Sales is something that I think
you should be intimately involved in the
details there as a founder because sales
create revenue create cash flow and
again cash flow is the lifeblood of your
business. So knowing all the different
pipeline stages making sure you have
your hiring of new sales people dialed
in you making sure you have the right
setters and sales development reps going
and driving you leads making sure that
your pitch script your CRM are all
dialed in for growth. Every single one
of these details the more smooth they
are the more scalable your business will
be. So, at Founder OS, as an example, in
all of my companies, we use HubSpot as
our CRM. In here, we have different
dashboard views that allow us to go and
essentially track everyone from the
different stages that they're in, from a
lead to a sales combo to someone that
we've pitched, someone that we're
waiting to hear back from all the way
through to then our whole customer
success pipeline as well. So, we have
probably around 30 different stages that
go from someone being aware of us all
the way through to someone going and
referring someone to us. and we have all
of those details sused out so that it's
a smooth and scalable process. It's
delightful for customers and it's fun
for us to deliver on. On the growth
side, you need to make sure that you
have things like AB testing going and
dialed in long term, making sure that
you have, you know, a good market
analysis, understanding what other
options are that people have in your
market and really inevitably what makes
you different. You know, you really need
to understand how you're positioning
yourself. At Founder OS, we have
dashboards, right, that we go and track.
I have my HubSpot ones, but I also have
manual dashboards in Google Sheets. The
purpose of that is because at the end of
the day, when you have a manual
dashboard, it's being filled out exactly
how you want. You don't have any issues
with data integrity. And I find it
useful so that there's never this excuse
of, oh, this piece of tech isn't working
right, or I don't know if that's hooked
in quite right. It's like, if it's
updated by a human, we have a VA on our
team that does all this. It just makes
it that much easier, to be honest. So we
have a bunch of metrics that are being
tracked with a key owner and every
single week we're monitoring that and
then I get reports every Friday based on
our performance on the team excellence
side right having your org chart dialed
in compensation frameworks career
planning and making sure you're
documenting your culture you know if
someone joins any of my companies day
one we go through our culture and values
deck to make sure that they are crystal
clear on how we operate and what's
important to us so they can get kind of
integrated into that culture and they're
working how we like to work, right? We
build sports teams here and we want to
make sure that we're bringing on people
that are essentially athletes and bring
that kind of peak performance mentality.
So this is an example of me going and
documenting my org chart, right? Getting
clear on every single role across every
single company and then the core metric,
you know, one core metric that each of
these people are responsible for. Then
obviously your systems, right? Strong
systems build strong businesses. So
everything from your data integrity,
your systems access controls, backup
procedures, different protocols, air
handling, recovery plans, you know, you
want all that stuff documented. On the
tech side, as an example, you know, I've
gone and kind of outlined here some tech
you probably want to consider across
different areas of your business. You
know, he hype fury as an example. If
you're looking to schedule content on X
on the funnel optimization side, right,
you want to make sure that you have your
analytics and an understanding of every
single stage. What's the current
bottleneck in your funnel? what's the
piece of the funnel that people are
getting caught up in that they're maybe
getting stuck in. And then when you can
unlock that piece of the business, boom,
you just get that many more leads, that
much more revenue. In addition, things
like your nurture sequences, your
automated emails across each part of
your funnel. You want to know, you know,
when someone joins as a lead, what do
they get triggered in terms of your
email flows? When they go and abandon an
application, what kind of abandon
application email do they get? when they
abandon a sales call, what abandoned
sales call email they get. So, you want
to map this all out. I personally love
to use Fig Jam, which is a Figma
product, to go and map out that whole
flow. So, it's super seamless,
beautiful, and we're thinking about all
the different permutations of ways that
people could go through it and also drop
off of it so we can recover those people
and bring them back in.
This is an example of what our Fig Jam
would look like. So anything from social
media, joining the newsletter, applying,
getting on a sales call, and then if
they abandon these different stages,
what sort of email sequences they get
put into and if they qualify for one
product or another, we have different
sequences and different flows that they
would go through. Lastly, on the legal
side, I know, you know, last thing we
want to be talking about is legal, but
it's important that you have all this
stuff documented as well. everything
from contracts, terms of services to
your insurance, you know, data, all this
good stuff. You know, you want to make
sure that's taken care of by a reputable
person. You know, this is an example on
the CEO scorecard side. I get an update
from my CFO every single Friday at 5:00
p.m. EST, giving me my weekly revenue,
our profit, and the three key priorities
that I need to focus on on the next week
to continue to get the business 10%
better every single week.
So, when you're going and building your
business, if you have a finance manager
or a director of finance, I would
recommend that you go and you take these
metrics I have here, adapt them to your
business, and get that person to either
send you a Slack message andor a text
message every single Friday so you can
always understand the health of your
business, and then keep those feedback
loops between what you're doing in your
business and the cash flow side of
things super tight so you can continue
to make sure that you're building a
healthy empire. So, these are the
details that really matter as you're
scaling your business. If you want more
proven systems to level up, you should
go and apply to Founder S via the link
in the description. Much love. Welcome
to the founder freedom movement. Like
and subscribe and let's win