You're not broke because you don't have
followers. You're [music] broke because
you're missing the middle layer that
converts attention into money. The
Content GPS has three layers: rented
[music] audience, owned audience, and
monetized audience. Here we've got our
rented audience. So, what we want to
make sure is here is that as we're
[music] growing our rented audience
across these platforms, first off, that
you're diversifying the amount of
channels you're [music] on, right? Cuz
if you're just reliant on one platform,
well, you've got a lot of platform risk.
And the other way then to conquer
[music] that platform risk is then to go
and own your audience. So, what you want
to be doing is having the right call to
actions in your content. Those CTAs or
call to actions essentially go and catch
the sea of attention that you have out
out online and then drive those people
to your newsletter. So, the core thing
here is that email list is likely the
most valuable asset in [music] your
business. Let's now get into the
monetized audience side of things. The
key thing here is that you want to make
sure that you're driving people then
from your email list, right? To actually
going and driving them to your product
or service. You need to move people from
rented to owned first [music] and then
onto monetization.