This quote changed my life. Slow is
smooth and smooth is fast. This is what
for me has really defined my calm
company method. Building businesses that
are beautiful, that are peaceful, that
feel like play. I focus on one core
message, one core offer. Doing less but
better. You know, often times I look at
founders businesses and they've got like
10 offers going on, 10 different content
categories. The reality is you just need
one offer likely to get to the goals
that you're after. You don't need a team
of 40 people. You just need a team of
five core weapons. Slim it down. Have a
more profitable, lean, mean, calm
machine. And this is what I learned from
slow is smooth and smooth is