Everyone's abandoning Instagram for
LinkedIn and X, but I'm quietly stacking
up 5,000 emails every single month from
Instagram alone. Here's [music] how.
Instagram is not just a mood board for
your brand. I think it's quietly the
most powerful platform for conversions.
The power of Instagram is that you can
go and drive an enormous amount [music]
of business through DMs because people
actually check them. Now, with many chat
combined there, too, you don't need to
do all the handtohand combat in the DMs
[music] yourself. So, let's get into
that. Everything for me starts with an
Instagram carousel, which based on our
data is the number one way to go and
drive all of these emails. And so, what
I have here is a carousel on how to make
your business run [music] itself in 6
months. And on the last slide here, this
is where the real sauce is. They can go
and comment blue. And what happens is
when they comment, it triggers the Many
Chat automation which is now going to go
and send them an entire robust blueprint
[music] for free for getting their email
in exchange.