What if the best discipline isn't
forcing yourself to do hard things, but
it's making the good choices automatic?
After meeting tons of multi-millionaire
entrepreneurs and becoming one myself,
I've learned that automatic discipline
is the true foundation of success. In
this video, I'm breaking down the exact
[music] three-level automatic discipline
system I use every single day to
accomplish my biggest [music] goals. You
know, if you actually do this for just
the next 30 days, 2026 will be your best
year yet. As you're watching this, don't
think about discipline as effort. Think
about what your ideal day would look
like if discipline was solved by design.
At the end of the video, I'll give you a
way to map that day and see exactly why
it's not your current reality. Let's get
into it. Level one is to architect your
discipline. You see, most people just
react to their lives. But high
performers, they architect it. And it
all starts with architecting the perfect
day. When I was 28, I was smoking 11
joints a day, drinking, and anxious as
[\h__\h] this whole substance stuff was
screwing me up and I needed to go and
get my blood work done. It turned out
that based on that blood work that my
DHEA was being blocked by the substances
and DHA is a core chemical that converts
into testosterone which is the chemical
in humans that makes [music] effort feel
good. I realized I couldn't willpower my
way out of this. I had to architect a
completely different life. So I
downloaded an app called Streaks and
added six daily habits. lift daily,
stretch daily, no smoking, no drinking,
no sugar, and write [music] daily. But
the real shift wasn't just the habits.
It was deciding. I'm the kind of person
who designs my life intentionally, not
someone who just reacts to whatever
comes at me. Here's what I learned. You
know, discipline starts with identity,
not motivation. You're not trying to be
more disciplined. You're becoming an
architect. The issue is most people are
just operators. They wake up and ask,
"What's urgent today? Who needs me? What
fire do I need to go and put out?
Operators are exhausted because they're
just trying to keep up. Architects wake
up and ask, "What did I design last
night? What's my one big domino today?"
They've already decided, and that's how
they create the perfect day. Do this
every day and you win. But here's the
thing. You can't architect your perfect
day if you don't know what you're
architecting towards. Most people are
just going through the motions. They
have no vision and no target. They're
busy, but they're not building towards
anything specific. That's why the first
step is creating your vision board. What
I do is over here um I'll go and take
time um each year, right? About a week
to meticulously go and plan out exactly
where I'm trying to go with my life and
with my business. You know, I've gone
and mapped out over 10 years, you know,
I want to have seven bestselling books
over the next seven [music] years, get
this YouTube channel to over 30 million
YouTube subs, hit 5 million newsletter
subscribers, [music]
and go and have a retreat center in the
Doommites. I actually then go and I
print out this vision. What I do is 3
days a week, so basically every other
day, I go and I mark up this vision with
new thoughts and ideas. is and I take
about an hour to just with blue pen go
and look at different aspects of it and
[music] figure out, you know, what
little micro adjustments or tasks I need
to get done to ladder up to what I'm
trying to do here. So, take action
tonight. [music] Create your vision
board. It doesn't have to be fancy. It
can just be a Pinterest board. It can be
a physical board with magazine cutouts
or even just a Google doc with different
images and goals you have. Put it
somewhere you're going to see it every
single morning. Remember, an architect
designs [music] systems. An architect
does not rely on mood. But how do you
actually then go and design a system?
That's where the second part of
architecting your discipline comes in,
the power list. Every single night, I
sit down with a pen and paper and I
write down my power list for the [music]
next day. Then I rank them from 1
through 7 in order of importance. Next
to each item, I write down the potential
long-term cash flow or impact of [music]
each task. Just seeing the cumulative
potential, you know, $5 million if I
nail all seven tasks fires me up. And
above all, this removes [music] decision
fatigue for the next day. Let me just go
and show you an example of what this
looks like in real life. Okay, what you
can see here is a list. This is [music]
January 15th. It included everything
from, you know, approving some upcoming
creative that we're putting out to going
and coming up with a filming checklist
[music] to things like a hundred million
dollar action plan that I've put
together and, you know, writing 2,000
words of my book. So, [music] I'll go
and write down all of these core things
that I think I need to get done. So,
from there, I then take [music] a step
back and I look at it and I go, "Okay,
I'm going to go and rank these things."
Okay, typically around 1 to 7, [music]
right? one being that it's the most
important thing, seven being like it's
the least important. And this typically
indicates the order by which I'm going
to go and accomplish those things the
[music] next morning when I wake up and
get into my founder flow. Here I've gone
and indicated which of these tasks, you
know, adds up to how much money. And so,
you know, here you can see the $100
million action plan. I put a million
there a year. Um getting this video
implemented was a $500,000 task. Um
getting the creative approved was about
a million. And so [music] I add this all
up and you know getting these things
done equals like a $3.5 million day.
This transforms a boring to-do list
[music] into a high stakes road map. So
tonight before you go to bed, write your
seven tasks. Rank them. Write the
long-term value next to each one and
[music] then put it somewhere where
you're going to see it first thing in
the morning. Do this every single night
for the next 90 days [music] and just
watch what happens. But here's the
thing. You can architect the perfect day
on paper, but if you don't have the
execution [music] system to back it up,
it's just another plan that dies in your
notes app. But most people fail right
there. [music]
And that's why level two is all about
execution. Part one of execution is
making discipline automatic. And you do
this by following a schedule that
removes choice. Every morning, [music] I
start my day with what I call my
momentum hour. This is from 6:00 a.m. to
7:00 [music] a.m. I drink water, take
vitamins, get sunlight in my eye for 30
minutes, [music] and then go for a walk,
and maybe go and complete my first task.
But I'm not checking my phone. I'm not
in Slack. I'm just priming my body and
my mind. So then from 7:00 a.m. to 11:00
a.m., I am locking in because it's time
for founder flow. This is my deep work
time, right? No phone, no distractions.
I use a brick device to go and
completely lock all social media off my
phone. The only thing that exists is me
and the work that I've got to do. Those
seven powerless tasks. I'm writing. I'm
building systems, creating content,
designing strategies, [music] the stuff
that's really in my zone of genius. The
stuff that for me moves mountains in my
life and in my business. [music] And
that's how I go and achieve my 10x
progress. But most people's calendars
look like an absolute Tetris board.
meetings stacked on meetings every
[music] 30 minutes getting someone
else's brain picked and just honestly
just leading to information overload. By
the end of the day, you've been
productive for everyone but yourself.
Founder flow is different, right? It's
protected. It's sacred. It's the time
when you actually build your future
instead of just maintaining your
present. [music] So, tomorrow morning, a
couple of hours before you work on your
calendar, turn off your phone or use a
brick device. Work only on tasks that
are in your zone of genius. Do this for
30 days straight and watch your output
explode. All right, so here's the deal,
right? When you think about going and
actually executing, one thing I think
you need to make sure that's the focus
of it is one word, fun, right? If you're
having fun, great things are going to
happen. And the thing I'm kind of
reminding myself of as I go through
[music] these things is I don't need to
go fast, right? because I have a core
list of [music] just a few things in
front of me that I need to get done. I
remind myself that slow is smooth and
smooth is fast. So, I [music] can just
slow down, be a real craftsman, right?
And make sure that [music] I do what I'm
innately capable of, right? to go and
get these things done, not at a decent
level, but try to actually pour in my
inner genius [music] into these things,
to do them at such a caliber that it's
too good to ignore. [music] If this is
clicking, you're probably realizing
something. Your current day is the
output of your systems, not your
discipline. That's why I built a short
perfect day architecture exercise.
[music]
It forces you to design your ideal day
and exposes the one system gap,
delegation, automation, calendar
control, or decision fatigue that's
breaking it. If you want this, you go
stop for one second here and go and get
the exercise right in the link in the
description. Okay, let's get back to it.
Part two of execution is about building
confidence. You see, discipline has
everything to do with confidence, but
most people can't see why, and they
don't even understand how to leverage
it. I used to think confidence was just
something you know you were born with.
Some people just have it. But then I
realized confidence [music] is just
proof. When I started writing every
morning, I wasn't confident that I was a
writer. I just showed up 30 minutes
every day. And after 30 days, voila. I
had 30 pieces of evidence. After 90
days, I started believing it. And after
a year, it was undeniable. Every single
day that you do what you said you were
going to do, you build a little bit of
evidence. evidence that you can use
[music] to then build more trust in
yourself. Evidence that your word
actually means something. That's
confidence. Discipline equals
confidence. Most people try [music] to
think their way into confidence and they
fall flat on their face. Every time
[music] you skip the workout, your brain
files that away. Every time you say you
post and then you [music] don't, your
brain logs it. You're training yourself
not to trust yourself. The opposite is
also true, though. [music] Every small
win builds momentum. Every kept promise
is a deposit in your [music] confidence
account. So, pick one small promise
you're going to keep to yourself every
day for the next 90 days. Right now, I'm
focused on writing every single day. I'm
wrapping up my first book. It's going to
[music] be released very soon. Track it
and watch your audience grow. Now, most
people think that this is where the
story ends. You architect your day. You
execute with precision and done. But
here's what nobody talks about. You're
going to [music] slip. You're going to
have a bad week. You're going to wake up
one day and feel like the system doesn't
work anymore. And that's exactly when
most people quit. So level three is
about how you sustain everything you
created until now. And for that, you
need an automatic comeback protocol. The
difference between people who win and
people who don't isn't perfection. It's
the bounceback. Take the moon mission
example, right? And about 90% of the
time they were off track. Just like the
moon mission, you know, to your own
career. 97% of the time, you're going to
also be off track. Success, it's all
about correction, not perfection. Sure,
you can have a bad day, 2 days, a bad
week, but don't give yourself much more
time than that, right? You got to go and
bounce back fast. You know, I was about
6 months into sobriety, and then I went
and had a drink, and I remember going
and talking to a mentor, and I was like,
"Oh man, it feels like it's just all
gone." And you know, I was doing so well
with sobriety and I just fell off. And
what he had told me is like, "Matt,
you're still sober. You just made, you
know, a slip up." That made all the
difference, right? It wasn't that I had
suddenly now not been sober and needed
to start all over again. It was a slip
up. Just get back on the horse and keep
going, right? And it was that small
mental shift that made all the
difference for my own identity as being
a sober person. Here's my rule, right?
Never miss twice. If I miss a morning
workout, I don't let myself miss the
next day. If I skip writing one day, I'm
damn sure not missing writing the next
day. The biggest trap is this all orno
thinking, right? You miss one day and
your brain says, "See, you're not
disciplined. You failed and you might as
well quit." That's how people waste
years. They have one bad week and then
throw away [music] 6 months. So, when
you slip, and trust me, you will because
you're human, immediately return to the
smallest version of that habit the next
day. So, [music] you missed your
workout, do 10 push-ups. You skip
writing, write an intro paragraph. You
don't have to do an hour, just do 10
minutes, do five. [music]
Just break the spiral. Just something to
say, I'm still in this game. Trust me,
this is one of the biggest hacks you can
do so that you don't fall off the wagon
and you also make it enjoyable to do the
things that your brain is trying to tell
you are really hard. Now, if you're
watching this and thinking, Matt, I get
it. I just want the systems, though. I
don't want to figure this out all alone.
Well, that's exactly what Found exists
for. This is where serious founders come
to design their days, their businesses,
their lives, all with leverage. So, if
you want to see how this actually works
behind the scenes, there's a link below
you can go check out and book a call
with my team. And [music] if you're not
sure, well, just quit the guesswork,
right? Get on a call and we're there to
help you. Use the perfect day
architecture exercise link below. Design
the day you actually want and it'll show
you the single system constraint [music]
that's blocking it. Then bring the
exercise into the short call with me and
the team and we'll go and help you out
and make sure that you get unstuck. So,
go and book that for free below. That's
how this goes from insight to systems to
a life that actually runs the way you
want it to. All right, so now that
you've got the discipline in place, now
it's about going and getting the right
annual [music] planning systems just to
make success inevitable. So go and check
out this video on how to actually go and
plan your year and I'll see you over
there. Much love and let's win together.