All right, years ago, I was high on my
own supply. I'm sharing this for those
of you that maybe need a little kick in
the ass, a little reminder that
sobriety, it's a beautiful thing. Now,
building my second business, Herb, I was
smoking 15 joints a day, giving Snoop
Dogg a run for his money, right? I told
myself, you know, this is all good, you
know, it's making me creative and come
on, it's just weed. But, it was numbing
me and having a major effect too on my
testosterone, which, you know, little
known fact, cannabis breaks the chain
between DHEA being converted into
testosterone and I had grandpa balls,
let me tell you. And testosterone is
important because it's a chemical in
humans that makes effort feel good and
as a founder, you need that that juice,
you need that mojo, right? And so, what
I realized is that I needed to sober up,
right? I had reached out to Andrew
Huberman in a DM, he had told me about
some of the science behind how cannabis
was affecting me. I went and had some
blood work done and that blood work led
me to then going and gamifying my
sobriety, making an effort to just stay
sober as long as possible to start
seeing the impact in my blood markers.
So, what did I learn along the way?
Well, I was able to replace all the
substances with journaling. That was
something that worked for me and yoga
and running and I gradually started to
feel my vitality come back and I can
tell you, I wouldn't have been able to
build the businesses I built today
without this dedication to my health.
Hopefully, this helps you.