This is the one-page operating system
behind my $12 million a year business,
okay? So, I learned this from Marc
Benioff, the founder and CEO of
Salesforce. Early on, he had a one-pager
just like this, and I stole this from
the book that I read on him called Into
the Cloud. And so, first off, we want to
have our mission statement. Talking one
sentence, for me, it's helping 100
million founders accomplish their dreams
through proven systems. You then want to
have your avatar, right? One core person
that you're looking to help. Not a
demographic, right? We're talking about
an actual person that then all of your
content is directed at that one core
avatar. Your offer, okay? What is it?
One transformation, you should be able
to explain it really clearly. For
Founder OS Velocity, we're helping
founders go and build their social media
machine for them. We do it all.
Now, the next aspect here is your
channel. What's the one platform you're
getting started with and getting going
on? My biggest channel right now is
YouTube, second biggest is LinkedIn.
We're omnipresent across all channels,
but getting going at first, I was
actually most focused on Twitter at the
time.
Now, the metric. What is the one number
you must be most focused on? For most of
you, it's probably something like cash
collected.
The ritual, right? What is the meeting
that you have each week that sets the
tone? It's like the heartbeat of your
company. For me, it's our Level 10
Meeting, is a concept I learned from the
book Traction. I've been using it for
over 19 years now. We start off with
wins, move over to a scoreboard, then
get into any issues, opportunities, we
solve problems together, and then go
through the checklist of things that we
got to get done that week, and then
Cloud Code through some automations
keeps folks accountable so that by
Friday, all of those things are checked
off. Then the system, right? Having one
core dashboard that shows all of your
metrics all the way from top of funnel
to bottom of funnel, so you can spot the
constraint and solve it. And then, the
rule, right? If it's not on this page,
probably ain't a priority. So, that's
your one-page operating system. Let's
get busy.