So many founders that I talk to are
paralyzed by doubt, right? When you need
and what I think we crave often times is
just clarity, right?
Clarity for me comes from being in
nature, comes from slowing down, comes
from journaling, right? And realizing
in any given decision I'm about to make,
am I making this out of fear, right? Or
am I making this out of a point of
clarity, right? Is my body feeling tense
and thereby maybe this is not something
I should be moving forward with, or do I
feel a sense of flow, a sense of levity
and lightness, right? So, often times
what I see helpful here is to kind of
scan, you know, my mind, my body, my
soul, my kind of heart.
How are all of these areas feeling,
right? And what I'm looking for is a
whole body yes.
Decisions that come from my mind saying,
"Hell, yes." My heart saying, "Hell,
yes." My soul, like the pit of my
stomach being like, "Let's go."
So,
sometimes what I find useful here is
having like a mentor, an advisor, a peer
that I can kind of talk to to see where
a given decision's coming from. I like
to journal on things
and kind of understand what's at the
root of certain decisions I'm making cuz
at the end of the day, you know, you can
slow down, right? Slow is smooth and
smooth is fast.