Every piece of content has a pulse, and
if you don't know why yours exists,
[music] it flatlines fast. I've always
been obsessed with content. Now, I feel
like content is this amazing vehicle for
expressing [music] my own creativity.
Deep down, I knew that at some point,
you know, I would want to evolve past
just promoting logos and actually
putting, [music] you know, my own voice,
my own message out there. This small
change in thinking had a really profound
impact on how I approach business. And I
think the warning to you is as you're
putting your own brand out there,
[music]
you know, take the time to step back and
think about what's the stuff that you
really love to do, right? What do you
think the world really needs to hear
from you, and how does [music] that tie
in with your businesses? Cuz at the
intersection there lives your zone of
brilliance.