Five habits that make success
inevitable. Number one, treating your
body like hardware for your goals,
right? Sleep, food, movement. These are
things that you must prioritize. Number
two, planning your day before it starts.
Before you go to bed, go and write down
the seven core things that you need to
get done the next day that are going to
make the most impact in your life and
business. Number three, [music] doing
the boring high impact task first. Even
when every cell in your body wants you
[music] to check your phone, you just
got to go and do the that other
people are not willing to do. And when
you compound that long enough, great
things happen. Number four, say no to
99% of fake urgency. You need to go and
say no to most things in life to say
hell yes to the stuff that's actually
going to move the needle for you over
the next decade. Number five, asking
what did I do to create this instead of
why is this happening to me? You got to
shed that victim mindset, right? it's
never going to help you. The mindset
that [music] helps is taking ownership
of your circumstances. And when you go
and you develop high agency over where
you're at now and then are able to
gradually make those shifts, your world
changes.