[Music]
have you ever wanted to run a oneperson
business around your dreams your goals
your desires but yet you find yourself
running a business that's just running
you into the
ground look around you what the hell are
you waiting for look around you the one
person business model is the future of
Entrepreneurship it's entrepreneurship
multiplied and I don't mean it's only
you running the business it's you your
systems and a remote team of Specialists
helping you scale your business and your
legacy it could be like this super
relaxing peaceful living a life of calm
of ease running a calm company where you
love the people you love the customers
you love the community you're building
it doesn't need to be that
stressful the problem most Founders run
into when they're running their business
is they struggle to find high-paying
clients or just clients in general they
have an inability to drive attention to
their business and drive Revenue what's
the solution you need to use organic
content to multiply your audience and
what's the best system to multiply your
audience the content waterfall system
this system allows you to take One X
thread or any long form piece of written
content and turn it into 26 pieces of
content as an example three Instagram
reels three YouTube shorts three Tik Tok
videos three x videos
10 tweets one newsletter one instagram
Carousel one LinkedIn long form post and
one long form YouTube video here's an
example of turning this x thread into 22
other pieces of
content all right so let's give you a
behind the scenes look at how the
content waterfall system works in action
so here we have one long form piece of
content an X thread which is essentially
just a long form piece of content on a
in this case 13 life lessons at 33 that
I wish I knew at 23 and so this is
composed of all these different sub
tweets here like remove negative people
learn aggressively storytelling is a
vehicle for transformation a lot of the
same copy in this original X thread then
goes and becomes another tweet which in
this case are three principles I live by
and so very similarly again I'm taking a
lot of those core ideas and it becomes
another tweet right in this case how to
start a business from nothing and I also
go and accompany it with a handwritten
image from there it becomes other one
around seven marketing metrics How I
build teams how I read online you know
being unfocused and then going for runs
to try and get over that and then other
principles I live by as well as things
like the 8020 Rule and if you want
freedom build systems now we have it
we've basically taken that Core X thread
and we've now turned it into a hell of a
lot more content Downstream in addition
to that we're also going to have this
and use it as the script for for things
like short form videos like this one
right here so now we're going and
turning the same copy that was in that
pillar piece of content into a voice
over inside of this animated video that
we create we have another video here
right this one around attention is the
new oil which if you remember this was
one of the sub tweets and that original
pillar thread we're just really
multiplying our effort here and allowing
us to get off the content hamster wheel
and be able to kind of produce a ton of
content from One Core banger idea as you
keep going here we have more animations
so at this point you're kind of getting
the program right we just we like we
like animations it also becomes a part
of a script of this long form video and
so this is my story going from 15K in
debt to $8.7 million a year in this
video I take some of those sub points
and some of the copy I used in that
original post I showed you on X and I
leverage it to then put a really
beautiful cohesive script together for
YouTube we're almost done so just bear
with me for like one second this is my
convertkit newsletter it's really
important that you're driving people
from your audience across the platforms
and then actually owning your audience
in your newsletter and so here I've
basically just taken that same X thread
and one to1 it right into a newsletter
that came out about a month later I also
go and make a LinkedIn Carousel with the
same thing got over 738 likes and
hundreds of comments and then same thing
we put this onto an Instagram Carousel
where the cool thing is it's basically
get the same Post in a carousel form and
then we're driving people here to a call
to action which drives people to my
newsletter and this is a core way that
I've driven over 120,000 newsletter
subscribers in just the last 18 months
last one here I promise our team gets
really creative with things and in this
case this is what we call the b-roll
videos and so I'm shooting b-roll all
over the world where I am currently in
bogat and along my travels whether in
medine or Tokyo you know all through the
US and all over I'm always shooting
different b-roll and then what we'll do
is we'll just take individual pieces of
those points in that original thread and
we'll just splice it over this b-roll
and so this is the content waterfall
system I know that was a lot but trust
me this is how you multiply your
audience and multiply your impact to
help you take immediate action I've
given you my proven content waterfall
blueprint and the link in the
description for free so go click that
link go get the waterfall system and
implement this in your business right
away this is going to help you take your
distribution to the next level and make
it your competitive Advantage the next
problem you encounter on your goal of
achieving a scalable oneperson business
is a lack of clarity around your
direction goals and vision you dream of
the day when you have an open calendar a
day when you can leave normal society
live on a beach or way up in the
mountains totally Off the Grid
cultivating your dream lifestyle getting
paid to have fun making a massive impact
on the world going on daily Adventures
you know you want to run a business that
is fun and it's easy not all onep person
businesses are built in a dark room
alone behind some boring desk I much
prefer to go and build them outside in
adventure and exploring the world so the
next problem that you encounter on your
journey of building a scalable oneperson
business is your lack of clarity around
your direction your goals and your
vision of what you're trying to go all
of us have a dream of having a schedule
with no to-dos and no meetings and being
able to live a life in nature and
Adventure I think many people just get
stuck running a business that runs them
into the ground and before you know it
you meant to build a business but you
end up building your own prison I think
the solution is connecting with your why
you know why did you really get into
business in the first place for some
people it's because they wanted to make
a million dollars for other people they
wanted to live their dreams or make a
big impact on people you know you really
need to connect with your story your
story really feeds everything else that
you do in business your story is how you
hire people it's how you sell people and
it's one of the most powerful aspects
you can do to multiply your impact
you're probably wondering well then now
how do I come up with my story I think
you want to go and think about you know
your vision of what you're trying to do
in your business right and then use that
story to craft your origin story which
then incorporates things like your
mission your values your vision those
core stories they translate to a lot of
other pieces of your business that may
not at first seem that obvious things
like onboarding new team members your
brand strategy new employee onboarding
um you know your YouTube scripts
newsletters your X and Linkedin content
those stories become the backbone of how
your brand multiplies um across all the
different platforms that you exist on
first things first go and find your
story because you have a big mission in
life you know I know my mission is to
inspire 100 million Founders to
accomplish their dreams through proven
systems and I can only do that if I can
build a real Rich connection with you
the viewer the founders Clarity around
your story is going to give you Clarity
around your direction
you are your biggest asset but far too
many Founders neglect their health in
order to grow their business and I know
because I've been there I drank I smoked
I had a lot of super unhealthy habits
for a long time and it cost me dearly
you know I ended up burnt out totally
lost confused and in my first business
bit maker I nearly gave up I ended up
learning the hard way that to be build a
healthy business you need to be a
healthy founder on my journey I met a
guy named Robbie bent the founder and
CEO of other ship Robbie had been sober
for a number of years and opened my eyes
up to how clear thinking you are when
you ditch all these substances and
really take care of your health I ended
up going to the doctor and asking you
know what exactly do I do here you know
I feel lost confused I'm not sure of
what to do next in life to my surprise
the doctor recommended that I go get a
coach and I was like a coach like you I
was expecting something different from a
doctor Co Bryant had a coach Serena
Williams has a coach you know Michael
Jordan had a coach you need a coach and
so to multiply your energy and all that
amazing Gusto you have to build your
dreams sometimes it can be misdirected
or you're not sure where to go so sure
enough I ended up going and trying a
couple different coaches one of them
being Ryan begelman now Ryan is an
absolute Legend I mean he's become
almost an older brother to me he helped
me with different systems to grow my
business but more importantly the
importance of just showing up
authentically and not being afraid to be
just my sober self there's anything you
can learn from this too I think is the
importance to make sure that you're
surrounding yourself with a great
Community with great mentors and you're
just taking care of yourself along your
journey because a big part of being
successful is the fact that it's a
long-term game and so prioritizing
sustainability is almost more important
than anything you know there's a myth as
a solopreneur as a oneperson business
that you need to do it all by yourself
and I've learned that could not be f
further from the truth it takes a
community to raise a company and it
takes mentors and friends and family to
raise a Founder on your journey don't
feel like it needs to just be you you
want to make sure that you got coaches
around you mentors a community
accountability one of the big things I'm
big on is you know winning together you
know this idea of surrounding yourself
with other Founders they understand the
valleys they've been in the mountains
they know the difficulty the loneliness
the confusion that's just completely
normal on the journey sometimes issue
that I see Founders get into where
they're stuck for a month for 2 months
and they have no idea how to get out and
the issue is that feedback loop is way
too long you need to shorten that right
if you feel stuck you want to almost
instantly be able to go and call someone
up or hit up a friend or a mentor and
get out of that rut because the quicker
you get out of there the more you can
get back to your momentum moving and
start you know exponentially multiplying
your
energy okay so the last part of
multiplied entrepreneurship is
multiplying your output and the best way
to do that is with weapons and I'm not
talking about Firearms here I'm talking
about a players I don't know what the
heck I'm doing here but we're going to
bike around one of the highest altitude
cities in the world Bogota Columbia and
deliver this last one for you because
well why not what is a weapon a weapon
is an a player that you bring on board
to help you scale your company to the
next level and this is someone who takes
complete ownership of a given area and
helps you scale things out how do you go
and find weapons well you know similar
fish swim together and weapons hang out
with weapons and so if you're going and
hiring different rules go and reach out
to other folks you know that are a
players and see if they have any friends
that'd be down to work with you so
instead of just going and telling you
how to do things let me just show you
exactly how I did things at founder OS
this is my orc chart today that said I'd
be lying to you if that's how it all
began it began with just me in a dark
room on my laptop building this thing
out in New Zealand phase one was
ideation I came up with the idea of
something called Soulful entrepreneur
this belief that the better you are
inside the more your business and your
external world world grows I started a
course and a cohort all by myself with
30 other Founders helping them scale up
their businesses using the proven
systems I had learned over the last 15
years building four profitable companies
the more woo woo Soulful part of it less
people resonated with but people loved
the system side of it and so I decided
to Rebrand the company from Soulful
entrepreneur to founder OS and then
enter stage two validation so at this
stage I'm making over 30k per month
we're scaling things up past 50 and I
went and hired a few weapons to take
care of the worst parts of the business
I went and hired someone for funnels
copyrighting finance and Tech all those
areas now were taken care of and I was
able to focus on the founder experience
strategy content and audience growth at
this phase it can feel a lot like you're
spinning a bunch of plates and I totally
get it it's a bit overwhelming it's a
bit tricky you're doing your best to
scale things out with a lean team and
really that's what it's all about from
here we're building out the systems
we've got a simple Tech stack using
things like you know School kajabi Zoom
nothing overly sophisticated to just get
this company off the ground and get it
scaling past 100K per month phase three
is then monetization I've now gone and
sold the first 100 customers myself we
have a proven sales script and customer
success motion and we're R to scale and
so I'm hiring a bunch of sales weapons
customer success weapons and then a
bunch of people on the creative side to
take our brand guidelines and execute on
the brand identity across all platforms
we're on phase 4 is now all about
scaling now we're going and getting past
a quar million dollars of Revenue per
month and it's all about going and
empowering the weapons around me to take
complete ownership of their area hiring
more weapons around them and helping us
scale this business to a million and
Beyond per month so phase five is
Mastery and this is the phase that we're
currently on at founder OS scaling
Beyond a million dollars a month with
some just Legends around me that I'm
also grateful to call my friends here
you know it's all about really creating
the greatest founder community of the
21st Century help me make the founder
Journey more joyful and across all the
different areas of the business sales
marketing content Finance we've got some
Legends on board and I get to more now
sit back and focus on continually
passing the one Monon test which is the
ability to leave the business for one
month and come back to a business that's
stronger than when I left at this phase
it's all just about being a great leader
motivating folks making sure they have
the tools the training the motivation to
scale themselves in their teams having
fun and just making sure that we're
being as Mission driven as
possible all right well that's it those
are the four pillars of multiplied
entrepreneurship and now it's time for
you to take Massive Action
[Music]