Let me just kind of give you a bit of
how I see the old model versus the
founder-led flywheel. The old model, you
would just go and outsource all of your
marketing. But, I see this all the time.
Founders have no idea how to market
their product, and then they're just
outsourcing what I believe is the most
important part to just some agency that
hardly even knows what they're doing,
and they just start blowing money.
First-time founders focus on tech,
second-time founders focus on
distribution. And if you don't know how
to market your product, you are missing
out. The future here is that you
actually are using organic content and
building a founder-led brand that's
built around your values. My values are
things like insanely simple, being
founder first, being obsessed with
quality. When you really build a
founder-led brand like this, it will
change your life. The old model focused
on products and ads, transactional sales
funnels. The founder is just hidden
behind a brand, and I know because I did
that for years at Herb, and it was a big
mistake. Hence, now in my career, and
for the rest of my career, I am super
focused on building my personal brand
from 3 million this year, which is where
I'm at now, to over 10 million people,
and just compounding that year over
year, honestly, for the rest of my life.