You're hitting the nail right on the
head. Super powerful. There's enough
work here for a year already. I got a
message from my buddy Alex Icon, the
founder and CEO of Five Minutee Journal.
Company's doing over $15 million in
revenue a year, but he needs to figure
out how to crack the code on building
his personal brand. I went over to his
offices here in London, England, and I
broke down two core systems and asked
one key question that is imperative if
you want to go and scale a personal
brand and have a lot of fun along the
journey. I'm going to bring you into the
room where I was helping him. Let's get
into it. We're here in London. We're not
in the Dolommites anymore. Yeah. Do you
want to get into just like the context
in terms of what you're kind of
currently working on, how you're kind of
trying to link that to the personal
brand and maybe some of the gaps you're
currently experiencing or just things
you want some clarity on?
>> Yeah, for sure. I think the most
important part is really I built
intelligent change without me being the
face of the products or the brand and
has done tremendously well. You know, we
sold over 4 million products around the
world. The five-minute journal being the
bestseller product I've created now over
a decade ago. Now I feel even though in
my previous business I did use that
strategy of being a founder, not myself
included, but using that strategy my
co-founder being doing YouTube videos,
creating content, being consistent,
being authentic and then that's what
really helped us grow that business a
lot. And I feel now we're not doing that
for intelligent change. And that's why I
feel now's the time to be able to put
myself in front of camera, start
creating content, and most importantly,
delivering value to people, educating
them on, you know, the benefits that our
products can help in their lives in a
way I've been hiding.
>> Yeah. Yeah. All right. Well, we got to
get you, you know, out of the shadows.
It's time. All right. The first part
here is the founder identity
infrastructure. You know, I see so many
founders going and they've built a
company brand and they're not sure how
to go and fit in their profitable
personal brand into the overall
architecture of what they're building.
This is where the founder identity
infrastructure comes in. being able to
seamlessly link the core identity of
what makes you special as a founder and
then link that with your personal brand
and your company brand so they all feel
like they're part of one seamless voice,
one brand and one kind of common
emotional resonance. We can kind of
think of in the center some things that
you'd say are kind of core to like your
own identity as it kind of pertains to
some of the stuff we're talking about.
>> Mhm. And then we can get into like how
then the you know sort of personal brand
plays in. And then if we got enough room
on this uh white party enough and then
kind of like the themes around like your
uh company brand you know at founder OS
as an example my own personal identity
is around travel freedom you know giving
people clarity. When there's that degree
of synchronicity across these three core
areas, you create a brand, a personal
brand, a company brand that deeply
resonates with people and that people
kind of just gravitate to. So, where I
like to start at with this exercise is
at the core. It's your founder identity.
And so, that's exactly where I start
here with Alex to help bring him some
clarity. Inevitably, like I think for
any business, right, but especially like
for what you're building, you said like
for years like people really gravitate
towards like your lifestyle. Inevitably,
it's like that founder energy, right?
that's really different. So, it's nice
to start from like, okay, at the center
here, like what's the core like energy
you want to be putting out there? What's
like the core themes that are like true
to you that inevitably as you start
building your personal brand, it just
feels super authentic, right? It doesn't
feel like effort or you have to put on
some face or you have to like
manufacture some content. It's kind of
like this is just who I am and is real.
And that's I think also, you know, we
think about five minute journal
productivity planner and like the whole
suite of products you've built. I think
that's like one of the things probably
that's something I resonate with it,
right? It's like it's authentic. It's
it's kind of organic. It's natural. Like
it's not overly forced. It's just
helping you kind of design a more
intentional life.
>> Yeah. For me, identity, it all started
even with the five-minute journal with
gratitude, appreciation, like
positivity. And that was the the thing
that drove into creating that product
was how do I you know this one simple
habit cuz I started practicing gratitude
as a practice like on my come up cuz I
come from very you know I was poor
growing up and on welfare just you know
then my father died just had a lot of
happen really
>> and was living this dark era of my life
and what helped me come out of that was
actually starting to be and practice
gratitude. And you may think like that's
how like people usually say, well, it's
easy for me to be grateful now, right?
The life that I have of freedom, of
lifestyle, of money and luxury. However,
it actually started when I was starting
to be grateful when I had nothing and
and all the bad things were happening
and learning to pause and okay, what can
I appreciate in this moment and starting
seeing opportunity when I feel feel like
there's none. That's why my identity
even now, you know, like it's really
based on just gratitude and
appreciation.
>> Cool. And so when you think about other
aspects of like your kind of like
character, your identity, the general
energy you're putting out there, like
you know,
>> positivity. Cool. Just really positive
and seeing the good in yourself and
others in the world.
>> I think there's also an aspect of like
lifestyle design.
>> Oh, pure lifestyle.
>> Yeah. Yeah. like really being able to
take and create the life that you've
always dreamed of, especially as like
maybe it pertains like when you think
about and there's going to be a lot of
people that are aware of like things
like the five-minute journal. They're
going to become aware of you throughout
this journey as it keeps on compounding.
Like what do you hope are some of the
things that like they really gravitate
towards when they're like, "Oh I
didn't know this was the guy behind
5-minute journal." Like fascinating. Is
there anything that comes to mind there
is to like
>> I I think what comes up is like
overcoming obstacles, challenges and to
keep challenging yourself, you know, so
in a way,
>> right? The journey of it.
>> Yeah, the journey of it.
>> Cool. Then when you start to think about
maybe like the personal brand, when you
think about some like the subjects you
want to be putting out there, like
different formats you're thinking about
like how are you currently kind of
thinking about that world of things?
Well, I one of the things that we've
talked to you about is obviously
lifestyle as ties into a lot of the
personal brand and in terms of I do
believe that even my own life I've used
the products I've created to help me
achieve that lifestyle freedom, you
know, in general. Not sure how to kind
of communicate that or it's okay,
>> but it's expanding on that lifestyle
design. Yeah. like the freedom aspect of
being able to, as you said this week, go
to Rwanda and see the gorillas cuz I
want to and I can, you know. So, I've
been doing this stuff for over a decade
now
>> and I just do it cuz it's innately me. I
believe that life is here to be lived
and both, you know, me and you have this
opportunity of like being a real playing
characters like we're not just
>> we're in the game. You're in the arena.
>> Yeah, we're in the arena. we're we're in
it and we're also able to use this world
as seeing not just my city or country.
We have the whole world as our
playground and getting to play with it.
I think that's a big part of the the
brand and the personal brand. When you
think about things like your best year
guide or productivity planner or
five-minute journal like would you
consider those like different systems or
frameworks cuz there's definitely
something going on there too.
>> Oh purely I So how do you
>> So do you see that as systems or
frameworks or what do you call them?
>> Uh frameworks. frameworks because I
think another misunderstood thing is
people think that I am super organized
without these frameworks. For example,
if I don't use the productivity planner
myself, I'm just a disaster. There's
also like these like whether it's like
these rhythms that you have in your
year, in your week, right? Or like
different rituals or different, you
know, habits, which I think is like
largely like what your brand is supposed
to be incorporated in. Like you wake up,
you use the five-minute journal. You end
your day, you use five-minute journal.
Every end of year, you use your best
year guide. You know, like these are
like there's a rhythm to using your
products, but they're based on the
rhythm that you have in your own life.
>> Oh, for sure.
>> Right. So, in a sense, it's like you
have this like lifestyle. You like have
always relied on this like rhythm that
is like based on certain frameworks. And
when you do that, right, it feeds this
lifestyle.
>> Yeah.
>> And it's kind of like that's like this
kind of I don't know system for how you
live with like you know incorporating
gratitude in the morning and evening,
keeping things positive, being
intentional about how you design it. Um
so then as you start to think about then
the company brand like what's sort of
some of like the pillars there that you
guys have used to kind of establish you
know yourselves and create like a
emotional resonance with really creating
the life that you've always dreamed of
right so kind of intentional living
>> also at the core is really one of the
main pillars of inspirations for
intelligent change is Maso's hierarchy
of needs and self-actualization. So for
us as a company, we're a
self-actualization company. You know,
helping people realize their full
potential that they're here here to
live. And so with a company brand,
that's like what we help you achieve is
to self-actualize as a human. The next
step here is the content GPS. Now
listen, most founders, they want to go
and build an amazing personal brand, but
you know what's essential if you're
going to do it long term? Profits. The
reality is excitement, motivation can
only get you so far. But when you
actually want to go and scale something
meaningful, it takes the right systems,
the right product, the right content,
and the right people. And guess what?
Some of those things cost money. All
right, so we got the pieces of it.
Audience, we're going to think about the
formats. Then we got to own this
audience so that we actually control it
versus just on platform. And then we
need to monetize it. So obviously like
the more efficient you are at this, you
know, the quicker you're able to then go
and convert someone from say a follower
on Instagram or subscriber on YouTube to
actually going and purchasing. There's
that saying that's like the person that
wins any category is the one that can
spend the most per customer. If we're
able to effectively monetize all those
eyeballs, you're going to have great
systems. You're going to be able to
afford really good people. You're not
gonna b at like, oh like we got to
bring on this like insane Instagram
manager and have someone just manage
YouTube and have you're gonna be like,
hey, listen, as long as they can drive a
lot of audience growth, I know that the
rest of the system's super efficient and
I can afford to do this.
>> So the way to think about this, let's
start with like where your audience is
going to be. So what are the platforms
you're focused on? YouTube, Instagram,
uh, LinkedIn. So yeah, so we've got the
audience across YouTube, Instagram,
LinkedIn, and then yeah, I think it's
just about being intentional, like
you're building an intentional brand. We
kind of mapped out like the general like
emotion you're trying to tap into, the
identity of it. Now, we want to be as
intentional about the science of driving
people from awareness through to
transaction. So you're going to be on
YouTube, Instagram, LinkedIn to start.
Obviously, yeah, the goal of any founder
is like to be omniresent, right? You
want to be across all these places,
everywhere to everyone, right? But it
generally starts with just being super
intentional about two, three max, right?
So you don't spread yourself too thin
and you can go way deeper on those
platforms versus just spreading yourself
across a bunch on YouTube. Have you
figured out the formats that work best
for you on these or do you need some
help there? Currently we've launched the
podcast, so the intelligent change
podcast with myself that we've launched.
However, we're going to be launching
like a separate channel just for like
more vlogs and more just talking sit
down video styles. When you look through
the five-minute journal, you look
through the productivity planner, best
year guide, like these all there's like
10 YouTube videos around the system in
each one.
>> Like my morning gratitude practice, my
evening routine, my annual planning
guide, my way of reflecting on 2025, how
to go and plan 2026, how I approach a
new month, how I reflect on an old
month. Like there's tons of habits and
systems and rhythms and routines that
you've built your own life going from
like nothing to something, you know,
your come up and that's what then
manifested itself in the physical
product of these things. And I think
because you're so far along your
journey, like I'm guilty of this all the
time, by the way, you forget like all
that intentionality that went into all
these things. And each one of those
thoughts, right, is like a 10-minute
little like framework that you could
describe that framework, the why the way
it is, right? Like the best year guide
is based off of EOS. EOS has like the
how do you use these for your meetings?
How do you get your team onboarded to
this? How do you go and plan out your
year on this? How do you do the
quarterly planning on it? How do you run
a quarterly team retreat? How do you
incorporate the best your guide into
your team? There's like so many
frameworks
>> on all of those, right? One thing that's
useful is to think about, okay, how does
the content format tightly couple with
the product? So as an example, we could
go and make some interview where we
interview some Buddhist monk and that
Buddhist monk talks about gratitude
being important. I would say on a scale
of like 0 to 10, that being incorporated
say with like the gratitude practice and
five-minute journal, we give it like a
six. Like yes, he's talking about how
gratitude is important in this podcast.
Like oh yes, and the five-minute journal
helps you with gratitude. Okay. Like
there's a tie in there, but it's not
like bam versus you create a YouTube
video around the 5-minute practice that
changed my life. It's like and it's
literally just going through the
5-minute journal overhead cam, you doing
the thing, showing like you and how you
used it throughout your day, telling the
story behind it, how you created this.
The whole video is around this practice
that's changed your life. And the
five-minute journal almost becomes like
the hero to the story. And then like in
a video like that, that's like a 10 out
of 10 in terms of the tiein from like
the format to monetization because
everyone's going to be watching this
thing and instantly be like, "What is
this thing? Where can I get this? This
looks insane. I want to have the same
sort of come up and the same sort of
success and fulfillment that Alex has
and the examples he's given me
throughout the video as well. Like I
need to get this thing." And it's like
cool link in the description. So what
would you call then in terms of format?
So I would just say intentional
frameworks. I would have a Google sheet
I would make if I were you. So I would
map out framework, product, idea, title
and then have you posted it on all the
platforms
>> because then you know you have okay this
is the framework that I go over. This is
the product that comes from which is
going to be the hero of the video. This
is the idea. Oh, we're going to walk
through it in a how-to. We're going to
show a day in the life. We're going to
show the behind thes scenes process of
this whatever. And then here's the title
of that video. Okay, let's just make
this thing now.
>> Exactly. So I feel like this like if you
have this intelligent change pod that's
kind of like your that's like your
lifestyle character development which I
think is important. Now we need like as
an example you to get into like more of
like the intentional frameworks like the
science behind this more. You're hitting
the nail right on the head for a long
time. I have a fairly large audience.
However, I've just been, you know,
showing off my lifestyle and travel, but
it doesn't really convert to the actual
product because I'm not demonstrating,
as you said, the frameworks, the
products, and how it actually benefits
and delivers value to people people's
lives. When I think about the best
entrepreneurs I know, they're some of
the best investors that I know. They are
amazing capital allocators. So, what we
want to make sure of here is that we're
building a profitable personal brand,
not just a personal brand. And the
number one system I've ever invented in
order to do that is the content GPS
system. What I do here in this next clip
with Alex is go and break down his
content GPS all the way from his
audience to the formats to the owned
audience inside of his newsletter and
then his monetization. So, let's get
into it. And when I think about how
generous you could be with all this,
he's like, you've made the vehicle,
which is all these journals and guides
and planners. Now, show people how to
genuinely actually use these things by
showing the what and the how to do them
so that they can go and achieve the same
success that you've achieved. That would
be the most inenerous thing that you
could do for your audience. From there,
your pillar piece of content would
probably be on YouTube. A lot of your
Instagram content can just be the best
pieces of this long form stuff. And I
could see you also making some like
howto and how I type content for just
Instagram shorts as well. as an example,
like you could have like short videos
that come out like one every other day
and it's you talking about the
framework. So in a sense like your
morning ritual and then on the top part
of the reel, so like the bottom top part
is maybe you talking about the thing,
the bottom part is then an overhead cam
of you actually filling it out. You feel
me?
>> Yeah.
>> The thing that LinkedIn and people there
are going to want to see. It's a
professional network. People are less
inclined to really gravitate towards
like just like lifestyle stuff. I think
it's the same sort of educational type
stuff that just needs to be translated
into long form posts, you know, with
like, you know, it could be like things
like listicles or how-tos. All this
stuff needs to have CTAs. The one should
go to like any product that's featured
in it. And then the second is to your
newsletter. And we want to actually own
this attention for like the next 5 10
years, right? be able to communicate
them into oneonone kind of rich format
which is email, phone numbers even and
then be able to convert them to your
brand not just next week, next month but
like over the next like 5 years.
>> Yeah, for sure.
>> Then when we think about the owned
audience, right, this is like likely
just like a newsletter. I think the
secret to this is it's like probably a
weekly newsletter. Let's just say every
Tuesday, every Saturday, it doesn't
matter the day of the week, but keep it
the same day of the week, an episodic
and like each week sharing like maybe a
story and a core framework that's like
changed your life and then helping
others like implement it. How do you
feel about let's say on a newsletter
just featuring the new content that goes
out, let's say on the how-to, hey,
here's the how I changed my life. Yeah.
5 minutes and just feeding that to the
newsletter. Yeah, that's a good I would
say that's a great like V1 is just like
sharing like you know share the newest
YouTube video like on the newsletter. So
one of the magic things I would consider
doing here too I would have lead magnets
that you're driving people to on these
platforms. I watch a YouTube video
around this five minute process that's
going to change my life and then the
lead magnet, let's say, is just like a
one-pager on like the practice, right?
So, it's kind of like this onepage
gratitude practice. So, then everyone
cuz it's free, just like goes and gets
the PDF inside of the PDF or the Google
doc or whatever, there's then links to
go buy the five-minute journal,
different lead magnets that they're
given and those probably map to the
frameworks. So over time, like in two
years, like I wouldn't be surprised if
you had like 20 lead magnets. They get
then a fiveday welcome sequence, okay?
And then a fiveday what I call like a
FOMO sequence, which is like a fear of
missing out, okay? So someone is on
YouTube, they see this 5-minute journal
thing, they go get the lead magnet, they
get this like one pager, they see that,
they're like, "Shit, I want to get this
5-minute journal thing." They buy it.
They join now your newsletter. in there.
They're put into like say your weekly
Saturday newsletter list, but because
they're a new subscriber, right? They're
going to get five days of like, you
know, say the YouTube videos on Tuesday,
on Wednesday, Thursday, Friday,
Saturday, Sunday. They're going to be
indoctrinated to your brand, the
mission, what it's about, the stories of
people you've impacted, how Tim Ferrris
uses this, all that good stuff.
>> So, by the end of those 5 days, they're
like, "This brand's legit. I
didn't know it was this legit."
>> And then showing them like the best of
the best you've got. Then after
those initial 5 days, there's four or 5
days of these FOMO emails, which is now
you're going to more directly sell
people on the product. And so now what
we're doing is we're like pushing people
through the funnel fast, right? They've
watched the YouTube video, they
downloaded the thing within those first
10 days. Ideally, we're already
monetizing these folks, which then is
like, you know, an immediate like 30-day
return on that YouTube video you made.
>> These are all going to be UTM, right? So
you can track all these sales, too. and
pull them back to like what YouTube
video they came from. And so what you
may learn over time is like no one cares
about this five minute practice on
social as much. But damn, we make a lot
of money when we talk about productivity
stuff. We should just go way deeper in
there. Especially if we're looking to
really crank the engine of our media
company on the monetized side then,
right? We have the key thing here is
like obviously yeah your whole suite of
products which speak for themselves. The
right thing to have here too is like
having lead magnets in the description
of YouTube videos, driving people to the
email list. So, you're going to need the
right CTAs obviously set up on, you
know, YouTube, on IG, and on LinkedIn.
They're all slightly nuanced, but I
would just do is look at my content on
each platform and just copy the way I do
it. In YouTube, a link to the newsletter
at the top or the free thing. Second
link maybe to directly purchase the
thing that you featured in it. On IG,
you'd have probably Many Chat set up. Do
you guys use many currently?
>> Yeah. So really getting that ripping. So
now like in a short video, it's a how-to
video. It features fiveminute journal.
They can go and message you five in the
comments. Boom. You're like, "Well,
what's your email?" You're going to ask
for their email. They're going to give
you their email. Then you're going to go
send them the onepage free gratitude
guide.
>> Mhm.
>> And then now they're in your welcome
sequence and they're going to get
nurtured over time and probably purchase
if they're really looking to build an
intentional life. And then LinkedIn,
same sort of deal. I think like the big
infrastructure for you just to get going
is like one, you know, two getting the
lead magnet and land pages going and
then getting the welcome sequence and
FOMO built. That's like infrastructure
that's missing behind the attention
you're getting going. That's how I would
think about it.
>> Yeah. Perfect. Yeah. Now you've
understood a little bit more about the
art, the science, right? You get your
identity right and then you get the
infrastructure right with the content
GPS. You know, you're making content
that's growing your audience. you're
monetizing all that attention with your
content GPS. This is all good, right?
But the core thing that people need to
be aware of as they're going and
building a founder brand is as follows.
You got to make it fun. In any given
decision that you have in your business,
you have an abundance of ways you can go
and approach it. You have an abundance
of ways you can build a team. You have
an abundance of ways you can go and
offer a different product. You have an
abundance of ways that you can go and
structure your days, your weeks, your
years. And so why not choose the thing
that is the most fun that fires you up?
We only live once. And so what I get
into here with Alex in this next clip is
what I believe is the most important
question in business. What would this
look like if it were fun? Last thing I
would share with you is like I think
it's possible like within reason with
businesses like we've built, right? like
where we've like really intentionally
designed these things to make any of
these things fun
>> if you give yourself space to take a
step back for a sec now that we've like
mapped out the strategy and go like
screw how you did that with hair
extensions like I mean that's blah you
know what I mean like how could you
actually you can make this fun yeah I
think that's the most important
questions I ask something that I always
remind people in regards to even
business cuz many times people believe
that business is super hard you have to
hustle and actually one of the things
that I'm stepping in now is also telling
like people, you know, I've the way I've
built my life and businesses, I've had
fun. I've actually lived an incredible
life on this whole journey doesn't have
to be that you're just stuck in a
fluorescent room all day grinding it out
and not, you know, sleeping on the
weekends or whatever. I believe that
similar to you, what you've shown is
that ability to live your life, travel,
and still build substantial businesses.
So, what how would this look like if it
was easier and something built around
your lifestyle? So, thank you for also
showing the reality of that, the
possibility.
>> Oh, thanks for uh having us over here.
It's been good. Thanks, dude. Appreciate
you.
>> Thank you. Thanks so much.
>> So, there we go. We've gone and broken
down how to go and build an amazing
brand identity, then how to go and drive
attention through to revenue, and then
the core question if you want to go and
scale a personal brand while having a
ton of fun. Now, if you want to go and
get all the systems that I presented
here in this video, you should
definitely go and download the founder
infrastructure guide via the link in the
description. You can go and fill out
your content GPS, create your founder
identity and company identity, and make
sure that all along the way you're
having a ton of fun. So, go and download
that guide via the link in the
description. If you love this video, you
would love this video of me going and
helping out my good buddy Blake. Thanks
for watching. Like and subscribe and
welcome to the founder freedom movement.