if you're finding it hard to sell your
offers it's not you or your product it's
your wording here are seven fundamental
laws to write amazing copy every time
know your audience the power of your
copy is measured by your readers Target
emotions people buy an emotion then
justify with logic tell stories don't
tell readers what your product does show
them with stories Clarity is King use
the Hemingway app write at a fourth
grader level cut out everything that
doesn't make sense use social proof the
easiest story to tell is someone else's
use testimonials case studies
endorsements show how your product
changed someone else's life use urgency
deadlines limited offers and bonuses
everyone procrastinates unless you push
them to take action test and optimize
experimentation beats Perfection test
multiple versions go head-to-head with
yourself learn through trial and Air