Your personal brand is costing you
millions and you don't even realize it.
You're doing everything they tell you to
do, posting consistently, being
authentic, showing up every day, but
you're not getting the leverage other
founders at your level seem to attract
effortlessly. Meanwhile, founders with
worse products, less experience, smaller
audiences are getting opportunities
you're not even hearing about. The
difference [music] isn't effort, it's
five mechanisms that engineer trust at
scale. I built Founder's working with
hundreds of founders at scale and I kept
seeing the same pattern over and over
again. The ones scaling fastest weren't
posting more, they were engineering
trust differently. I reverse engineered
five mechanisms hidden in plain sight
amongst the world's most iconic brands.
And by the end of this video, you'll see
exactly where your personal brand is
leaking trust and how to fix it. Let's
get into it. Brand one, McDonald's and
predictability. When Ray Kroc partnered
with the McDonald brothers in the 1950s,
he wasn't impressed by the burgers.
Everyone told them the food was average
at best, but Kroc wasn't looking at the
food. He was obsessed with something
else entirely. He started documenting
every piece of the [music] process, how
the fries were made, how the burgers
were assembled. He broke it all down,
exactly how those kitchens were laid
out, even how employees moved their
bodies during rush hour. Attention to
detail here on steroids. He was breaking
down this entire operating [music]
system. He wanted to someone to walk
into McDonald's on the other side of the
world and already know what the brand
was all about and be able to [music]
taste that same consistent burger. Not
because it was amazing, but because it
was exactly the same. McDonald's scaled
faster than every other high-quality
competitor. Why? [music] Because you
don't choose McDonald's, your brain
does. Kroc figured out predictability
reduces cognitive load. First, pick
[music] a predictable format, something
that you can just consistently publish.
You know, for me, that's things like
these how-to videos, deep dives on
systems and, you know, this whiteboard
format over here. This is different
types [music] of content that people can
know and love me for. But the magic is
behind the background. My team's able to
systematize exactly how we nail these
every single [music] time. We've got it
down to a science. You know, the camera,
the lighting, the sets, how we go and
format these and structure these, the
animations in some of them, so it's the
same structure, [music] the same cadence
and the same style. Now, I publish the
same way, same day, every week. [music]
Not because I like creativity, but
because predictability compounds trust
faster than variety ever will. So,
second, [music] make your worldview
obvious. Okay, an inconsistent point of
view forces people to reassess you every
time. My point of view is that the
future of entrepreneurship is going to
be dominated by founders building their
personal brands. You know, people follow
people, then they follow brands. And if
you're looking to go and compete in the
future, you need to have a personal
brand that's systematized, beautiful
[music] and profitable. And so, that's
exactly what we do here at Founder's OS.
Third, make sure people can explain what
you do in one sentence. [music] When you
think about McDonald's, you know, they
generate $23 billion in revenue. Boring
[music] scales. But here's the thing,
predictability alone isn't enough
because even if people know what you do,
they won't trust you unless you prove
you can make them capable. And that's
where the next brand mechanism [music]
comes in. Brand two, LEGO and
capability. For many of us, LEGOs
weren't just a toy, they were the first
tools that taught us how to create
something of our own. But the business
behind that nostalgia almost never
survived. [music]
In the early 2000s, LEGO was dying. They
were losing millions every month.
[music] So, the executives did what
every failing company does, they
diversified. They launched [music]
clothing lines, video games, theme
parks, movies. They thought, we need to
be everywhere. [music]
But sales kept dropping. The company was
weeks from bankruptcy. Then Jørgen Vig
Knudstorp, [music] a new CEO, came in
and asked one question. What are we
actually even selling? Everyone said
toys, [music] but he disagreed. He said,
we're not a toy company, we're a system
company. We don't sell products, we
[music] sell capability. He killed
everything that wasn't about the brick.
Shut down the clothing line, sold the
million-dollar theme parks, canceled the
expansions and refocused everything on
one thing, making sure that every LEGO
brick across every set, across decades,
still fit together. The company turned
around in just 18 [music] months. Why?
Because LEGO survived by remembering one
thing. The brand disappears so the user
feels powerful. So, here's how this
applies to your personal brand. Ask
yourself, if you stop posting tomorrow,
would your audience still know how to
execute on what you've taught them? Or
are they just dependent on showing up
live, you know, having you explaining
things constantly? If it's dependency,
you don't really have a brand, you just
have a support system. And support
systems don't scale. Here's what to do.
First, stop just giving advice. Start
going deeper and giving people real
frameworks. What are frameworks that
create capability and make people more
likely to then take the next step with
you. So, second, [music]
make your content modular. Every piece
should work stand-alone, but then also
fit together into a broader framework
essentially, just like LEGO bricks.
Third, you're going to want to test
this. Can someone explain your
methodology to someone else after
consuming your content? If they can't,
you're inspiring but not empowering.
Quote from Leonardo da Vinci always
sticks with me, right? That is
simplicity is the ultimate
sophistication. We want to make things
so simple that it's easy for people to
go and translate what you do to more
people, thereby driving you more demand.
Brand three, Hermès, access and
boundaries. Let me tell you what happens
when you try to buy a Birkin bag. You
walk into Hermès, you've got the money,
20K, 50K, you know, whatever it costs,
you're ready to buy. You point out the
bag and you're like, I'll take it. And
they say to you, no. They tell you that
you need to build a relationship with
the brand first. You need to come back,
buy other things, show history, prove
that you're serious. Most brands would
never do this. Most [music] brands think
if someone has the money and wants to
buy, just sell them the But Hermès
does the opposite. They intentionally
leave demand [music] unmet. And here's
what's crazy, it works. The more they
withhold access, the [music] more
valuable the brand becomes because
people want Birkin bags specifically
because other people can't have them.
Withholding access until someone proves
they're ready for it. Once your time
becomes the most expensive input in your
business, availability stops being
generosity and starts [music] being a
liability. So, here's what to do. First,
create a process for access. [music]
Not everyone is able to get on your
calendar, right? There's got to be a
filter here, okay? There's a [music]
system, make people qualify themselves
before they get to you. Second, stop
responding to everything. I know it
feels rude, but it's not. When you think
about who you're really looking to
target, you got to be available for the
right kind of people, not just for
everyone. Your availability is really
the signal. If you respond to everyone
instantly, you're just signaling that
your time isn't that valuable. Third,
build systems that do the qualifying for
you. Before I had boundaries, every
opportunity required my involvement.
After I finally went and built systems
around access, the brand does the
qualifying before I ever show up. If
everyone can access you instantly,
right? Boundaries aren't friction,
right? They're also massive signals.
Now, you're predictable, you're
empowering, you've created boundaries,
but there's still something missing.
Because if you don't stand for anything
specific, you're just another voice in
the noise. Brand four, Patagonia and
values. Black Friday, 2011, every brand
on Earth is screaming, buy my product
now. There's discounts everywhere, you
know, it's max American consumption
mode. And Patagonia runs a full-page ad
in the New York Times and they say,
don't buy this jacket. They detailed the
environmental cost of producing it, the
water used, the carbon emitted, the
waste created, and they urged customers
to only buy what they actually needed.
Their marketing team thought they were
insane. We're telling people not to buy
on the biggest shopping day of the year,
we're going to destroy sales. Well,
sales went up 30%. Why? Because
Patagonia did something almost no brand
has the courage to do. They removed
ethical hesitation. Customers no longer
had to wonder, am I supporting something
misaligned with my values? The brand
made the decision for them. Patagonia
didn't just sell jackets, they sold
moral clarity. Here's what happened. The
people who cared about the environment
became fanatics. The people who didn't
care just left
>> [music]
>> and Patagonia was fine with that. Clear
values remove friction. You know, when
people know what you stand for and what
you don't stand for, trust accelerates.
Now, here's the truth most founders
don't want to hear. If you're trying to
appeal to everyone, you're resonating
with no [music] one. You avoid taking a
stand because you don't want to alienate
potential clients. I had to learn this
early on, right? I tried to make content
that worked for everyone. And because I
was trying to serve everyone, I was all
over the place, right? The moment that I
said, this is our founders who are
really running amazing businesses with
real revenue, who want to build systems,
not [music] hacks, and actually leverage
a personal brand. Yeah, sure, I lost
followers, right? But the ones who
stayed became, you know, the real rabid
fans and believers. Here's what to do.
First, pick your [music] beliefs. What
do you refuse to optimize for? What will
you say no to? What kind of people are
you not going to attract? Write it down,
[music] make it clear. Second, if a
topic forces me to stay neutral, I'm not
even going to talk about it. My content
only covers things that I have a clear
belief in. And that filter alone cuts
around, you know, 60% of content ideas
that could come up, but it triples the
alignment and that emotional resonance
that people have with what I'm putting
out there. Third, be willing to repel
people. This is the part that scares
founders. They think that being
polarizing is dangerous and that people
will leave, but the truth is the people
that leave probably weren't even meant
for you anyway. Clear beliefs are going
to attract the right people faster.
Vague positioning just creates
hesitation and you're kind of just
working backwards. I believe that taste
[music] is your ultimate competitive
advantage. Taste is what's going to make
you inevitable. And that's what most
founders completely miss. So, before we
get to that though, right? Let me just
quickly tell you who this is actually
for. Founder's OS is something that I
created five years ago. Over the last
five years, we've helped over 18,000
founders. If you're doing real revenue,
50K, 100K, 500K a month, and you've
already realized that your personal
brand is now probably becoming your
bottleneck, you know, this is for you.
It's not just some course or community,
it's an entire ecosystem and operating
system for serious founders. When you're
inside, okay, immediately you're going
to get a one-to-one onboarding call with
my chief product officer. We're then
going to go and engineer predictability,
a clear roadmap that's customized and
just for you, so you can dial in the
taste, your operating system, your
personal brand, the systems that turn
your expertise into inbound deals
without you really having to sell. The
operating cadence as well to make your
personal brand compound without you
having to constantly have your hand on
the wheel. And we turn your brand into a
leverage machine that attracts [music]
opportunities and isn't just some
distraction for you or your team. So,
let's talk about taste because this is
the mechanism most founders completely
miss. Brand five, A24 and taste,
Everything Everywhere All at Once, Mardi
[music] Supreme, Uncut Gems, Midsommar,
The Lighthouse. Even if you don't know
the brand behind these films,
>> [music]
>> you definitely know their work. There's
a film studio that I absolutely love
called A24. They barely market their
films, no massive ad campaigns, no
celebrity press tours, minimal trailers,
and yet when A24 announces a new film, a
cult [music] following shows up. They
don't ask what it's about, right? They
don't check reviews. They just go
because it's [music] A24. That name is
behind it. And because that logo itself
is the ultimate signal. A24 trained
their audience to outsource their
judgment. Fans trust that if it's A24,
it's worth their [music] time. A24
releases films across genres like
horror, drama, sci-fi, comedy, but
there's a consistency in the aesthetic
and the taste, right? That's
unmistakable. You can feel it. A24 does
not have to convince their audiences.
[music] They just curate it. And
curation is their leverage. Here's what
A24 figured out. Authority comes when
people trust your judgment [music]
before hearing your opinion. Most
creators over-explain their work. A24
does the [music] opposite. They let the
work speak. The consistency of taste
creates trust. People outsource judgment
[music] to curators. I think taste
really is the ultimate moat you can
have. Here's the question that matters.
Do people trust your judgment before
they hear your opinion? Or do they need
you to explain, justify, and prove
yourself first? If it's the second, you
don't have authority yet. You just have
opinions, and opinions are cheap. Here's
what to do. First, every piece of
content I create has to pass through
three different filters. Does it
transfer capability? Does it qualify
access? And does it filter beliefs? If
it doesn't do at least one of those
three things, it doesn't ship. That's
how curation becomes authority. Second,
be known for what you don't talk about.
You know, I don't talk about growth
hacks. I'm not here to talk about
shortcuts. I don't talk about hustle
culture cuz it's important to really
discern the universe of stuff that you
should be known for. Third, trust your
audience to keep up. You don't need to
explain everything. You don't need to
over-deliver context. Just curate. Let
your consistency speak. If your taste
[music] isn't obvious, no one will
follow your lead. So, let's bring this
together. Ray Kroc taught us that
predictability compounds trust faster
than brilliance. Lego taught us that
empowerment beats dependency. [music]
Hermès taught us that boundaries signal
value. Patagonia taught us that clear
beliefs filter faster than broad appeal.
A24 taught us that taste is delegated
authority. But, here's the epiphany that
all five of them shine a light on.
Personal branding isn't a marketing
tactic. [music] It's your operating
system. These five mechanisms,
predictability, capability, access,
values, and taste, are the code your
business runs on. And right now, most
founders are running on broken code. In
2026, [music] the founder is the
business. Your personal brand doesn't
support your company, it is your
company. So, here's what I built. It's
called the personal brand scorecard.
Takes about eight minutes. You score
yourself across predictability,
capability, access, [music] values, and
taste. At the end, it forces you to
identify your single primary trust
constraint. Some founders realize
they're fine. Others who have given this
to realize their growth felt heavier
than it really should. Okay? So, if
you're doing 50K plus a month and
serious about building this
intentionally, complete the scorecard
and then go and book a strategy call,
which you'll see linked below this
video. If you enjoyed this video, be
sure to like and subscribe. Welcome to
the Founder Freedom Movement. And go and
watch this next video on the psychology
of building a personal brand, and I'll
see you in the next one.