Today we're talking about creating
content, the single most powerful growth
tool for growing your business today.
But here's the problem. Most people are
doing it all wrong. They're posting
randomly, chasing trends, and hoping
something sticks. The truth, most people
are making it way harder than it needs
to be. But when you really understand
content, you realize it's actually super
simple. I'm going to show you the three
exact stages I use to create all of my
content, from collecting ideas to
turning them into posts that build my
brand and drive real revenue. By the
end, you'll never look at content the
same way again. Let's dive in. Step one,
base ideation. This is where we're going
to go and use references as well as my
own channel to come up with some banger
YouTube title ideas. Step two, the
pillar. This is your big idea. We're
about to go and leverage the content
waterfall system, but the most important
part of that whole system is your pillar
piece of content. Step three, the
content waterfall. This is one of the
most powerful systems I've ever created,
allowing you to go and turn one pillar
piece of content into 20 other pieces of
content. All of the resources that I'm
about to go and share in this video,
including the exact board, as well as
all the prompts, are shared in a
resource via the link in the
description. I'm going to be showing you
this entire system using Poppy AI. It's
going to make all of this so much easier
because not only can we add references,
but we can actually go and hook those up
into AI chats. This video is sponsored
by Poppy. I've been using them for the
last year. I love them and I show
founders all the time that are looking
to go and multiply their effort way
faster how to go and use this. And so if
you're interested in going and getting
this board and being able to leverage it
the way I'm showing you in this video,
check out Poppy AI. Trust me, you won't
regret it. First off here, we're going
to go and build the base. Here we go.
Starting fresh. Along the left side
here, you can see a lot of cool
functionality that I'm going to show
you. One of the biggest differentiators
of this tool is that it actually has an
AI chat that you can pull into the
board. Thereby, as you're pulling in
different inspo across YouTube,
Instagram, X, LinkedIn, it's going to be
able to go and transcribe that content
automatically and then use it so that
you can prompt Poppy and it's going to
pull in the content, you know, inside of
those platforms. What we're going to do
here is start going and fetching some
inspiring content. So, I'm going to go
to folks like, you know, Callaway here,
who I've been loving. Uh, Caleb Rston,
who was actually at the last founder
retreat that we ran inside of Austin.
I'm going to go and take over this
outlier that I saw the other day, how to
go and create a dumb content strategy
that makes millions and another video
from Callaway as inspiration. Now, what
I then do is go and create a group,
which allows me to pull in all of these
different content inspirations and be
able to then prompt them all in one go.
So, I pull them all into this content
inspiration group. And then what we're
then going to do is go and wire up the
content inspiration group and plug it in
to the AI chat over here. And so what
this allows us to start doing is then be
able to pull in that content, use it
with the AI chat to then start flushing
out things like script ideas, outlines,
titles, packaging, all that good stuff.
So now I'm going to go over to my
YouTube and I'm going to go and take
some recent videos that I put out and
I'm going to start pulling those into a
group that I've titled here my recent
YouTube videos. Okay? And so again, the
cool thing here is that I can go and
copy and paste each one of these videos
into that group. And now when I go and
work inside of the AI chat box here, I
can go and ask it to, you know, use the
content inspiration that I found as well
as to go and look at my recent YouTube
videos and be able to leverage this to
create amazing outlines and really to be
able to use this tool to be like a
YouTube strategist. I have a YouTube
strategist on my team, Diego. I know a
lot of you guys, you don't have a budget
yet for a YouTube strategist. And so
what this can allow you to do is get a
ton of the benefit that you'd get from a
much larger team by just leveraging a
smart tool like Poppy AI. When you're
using AI, there are two variables that
you need to control. The first variable
is your prompt, and then the second
aspect is the knowledge base that you
give the AI. Most people screw both of
these aspects up. They have prompts that
are far too short and they have a
product knowledge that's way too skinny.
We need to make that thing fat. And the
good news is is that I've given you all
of the prompts inside of this video in
the link in the description. We're going
to go and ask the AI chat here, what do
you see in the knowledge base? Okay. And
so what this allows us to do is just
make sure that the Poppy AI brain is
full and has all of the context, right?
So, it's pulling in all of my content,
all of the references, and the knowledge
base to make sure that it's ready to
start coming up with ideas and getting
the things done that we're about to go
and use it for. Now, what we're going to
do is then go and give it a specific
prompt, keyword specific. The prompt
that we're going to go and give it is
using the videos I've given inside of
the group content inspiration and then
following my brand and my style based on
the group my recent YouTube videos and
also following the ultimate YouTube
title writing framework inside the group
YouTube frameworks. Let's come up with
10 solid and banger YouTube video ideas
for my YouTube channel based off of the
inspirations and on point to my brand.
So, we're being super specific and we've
given it an insane amount of context
here. This is what it looks like to go
and 10x your channel and bring real
strategy to it. We're going to go and
copy and paste that into the text field
here. Here we can see it's coming up
with some video ideas. I spent $400K
testing these the $47 million content
strategy that 99% of creators ignore.
You know, copy my $20 million content
system. I'm giving it away for free. The
content mistake that's costing you
millions. Fix this today. I really like
that one. It's got high stakes. It's got
urgency. It's got the immediate action.
I analyzed 10,000 viral videos. Here's
what actually works. The highest
leverage spot that you can go and focus
on when you're looking to go and scale
your YouTube channel is on the ideation
phase. And this is where too many people
breeze over. And so what we're seeing
here is that it's pumping out a lot of
highquality ideas. Now, I'm not just
going to go and make all of these,
right? The cool thing is is that I can
go and take the best one or two ideas,
then go and workshop that with my team,
see if we can make them even better than
what we're being prompted here, and then
bring those over to production. But what
I wanted to now do is come up with some
better ideas here, right? And so I'm
going to say come up with a few
different ideas around the content
waterfall because I really want to
highlight that in my next video. It's
now coming up with some content
waterfall specific ideas. How I turned
one YouTube video into 36 pieces of
content content waterfall system. The
content waterfall mistake that's killing
your reach. I lost $50,000 learning this
sort of mid. Uh but we'll keep searching
here, right? The depth is needed and you
still got to be using your intuition.
And don't be afraid to like prompt
something like four or five times,
right? Go deep. Don't be afraid to arm
wrestle with AI. You know, truthfully,
it doesn't care, right? So, keep pushing
it, right? until you get what you need.
The idea that I liked the most that I
saw was the 7minute content system that
built my $10 million per year empire.
Okay, we're just going to use that as an
example here. Okay, and so what we're
going to do is flush this out just kind
of showing that the content waterfall
system has been a key aspect of me
scaling my own personal brand. Okay, and
so what I've gone and kind of put in
here now is another group. I created an
hourong video on how to build a
profitable personal brand. I filmed that
all throughout Lafeton, Norway, hiking
three different mountains. And inside of
that, I also gave an insane resource,
which is like a personal brand workbook,
all for free. And so, I'm going to use
those as the references for this video
because I made over an hour of content
there. So, surely this could help me go
and flush out a 12 minute and 30 second
video around my content system. We're
going to hook up the references as well
as the video idea framework. Um, and all
of the different YouTube video intro and
script writing frameworks that I gave
away in my previous video around making
killer YouTube videos. And we're going
to hook up the YouTube frameworks into
the chat as well. What we're now doing
is being able to go and create the
script for this title. Typically, what I
do because I'm writing all the time is
I'm actually writing my own stuff. But
when I'm working with founders inside of
Founder OS, often times founders feel
overwhelmed. They're spinning the plates
of audience growth, content creation,
community building, all while trying to
actually make money to their offer. And
so often times when you're just
starting, tools like Poppy can be super
effective to help you go and be able to
create scripts much faster. And then
what I like to do is I just riff off of
these general outlines. People really
want to connect with you, the human
behind it, your authentic voice. And
truthfully, AI can't replicate that. So,
I'm not reading off a teleprompter. I'm
just using these things as outlines. And
then I'm just layering in my own
personality, my own stories, my own way
of doing things, right? So, what we want
to do here too, right, is that we're
going to go over to the recent YouTube
videos that I made and we're also going
to hook that up to this AI chat as well
because we want to make sure that the
script that it makes really sounds like
my voice. I'm now going to go and prompt
it. And I've given you all of these
prompts again via the link in the
description. You know, I need your help
putting together a script for the video
titled The Sevenminute Content System
That Built My $10 Million Per Empire.
This video idea is based on my previous
video, which I did, which is inside the
group references titled How to Build a
Profitable Personal Brand. Now, this new
video's angle is focused on a 7-minute
quick video emphasizing speed,
efficiency, rather than being detailed
and system focused. What I need you to
do is take those references and then
using the YouTube frameworks on writing
a banger intro and a banger script, put
together a script for this new YouTube
video idea to actually just create an
outline for me. Because again, we're not
going top to bottom through a script.
We're typically just going to go and
reference little parts of it to make
sure that a video flows. I add all of
that prompt into Poppy and it's flushing
it out. It's giving me a hook in the
first 30 seconds, adding credibility,
giving people an initial question to
kind of get them sucked into the video.
The question is, what if I told you that
the entire content system that built my
empire can be broken down in just 7
minutes of daily work? I would edit that
for sure, but it's a good start. Okay.
Now, it's going to again get into
credibility. It's going to go over the
promise and plan that people can expect
in the next 10 minutes of the video.
It's going to raise the stakes, right,
which is going to help increase the
retention of the video. We're always
aiming for a 70% one minute retention.
And then it's going to go and get into
the value ladder of the video, which
means that typically a video on YouTube
will have like seven core steps or five
core stages. And inside of this video
script, you can see it's following that
general approach. This is the kind of
stuff that you typically go and have to
pay maybe a script writer $1,500 for,
pay a YouTube strategist 10,000 bucks to
do this kind of stuff for you. And for
many of you, right, that's just not in
the budget yet. And so using a tool like
Poppyai allows you to get a lot of the
magic from those more expensive hires
and be able to do it in a way that's
much more efficient and accessible so
you can get, you know, that highowered
strategy that you see on the biggest
channels and be able to get it for your
channel when you're just getting going.
What I now want to do is go and also add
that script, okay, which I've copied and
pasted into another text box here. I'm
going to label that my video script
draft. Okay, and now what we can do is
be able to go and reference that draft.
Okay, so the key thing here, right, is
that this basically just is all being
hooked up based on groups, references,
and different frameworks that are all
plugged into the different AI chats. And
so I'm going to go and title step one
here um the base, okay, which is really
like the ideation phase. We're going to
call this step two the pillar, okay,
which is your big idea. When we're
thinking about building a content
waterfall, it really starts with the
pillar piece of content. The reason why
we want to use something like a YouTube
video as the pillar is because it's
long- form content that we can then use
and distribute into things like LinkedIn
posts, different Instagram carousels,
Instagram reels, YouTube shorts, Tik Tok
videos. I can use it as a subject matter
for a newsletter in two weeks. I can use
it for things like my ex post. And so
this is how I'm able to go and turn one
long form idea into over 20 strategic
pieces of content here. You know, I've
gone and given you an image of exactly
what my content waterfall looks like.
Okay? And what I'm going to help you now
do is go and actually go and tool this
up for things like your X content,
LinkedIn, and Instagram. What we're
going to have here is our pillar content
and put that into the first group here.
you know, my most recent video, we're
going to go and put that into the pillar
content group. So, what I've done here
is I've also gone and added a note below
here, just saying that this is the video
that we're going to use to repurpose as
my pillar content. This is useful cuz
then the AI can go and see that, and it
just has the instructions needed to get
going. So, now I'm going to go over to
my LinkedIn page. We're going to go and
copy and paste some of my most recent
posts. So, this one looks great. Let's
go copy that one over here. We'll go and
paste it into Poppy. We'll go to another
post here. This one looks really good.
Okay, cool. Let's go and copy this post.
And cool thing is again, I'm just like
copying and pasting the links in and
Poppy's able to work its magic and
understand all of the content. You can't
do that with ChatBT. You can't do that
with Claude. That's I think one of the
most magical aspects of Poppy that I
haven't found anywhere else. All right.
So now we've gone and hooked up all
these LinkedIn posts into a group. We
are going to go and add in the AI chat.
We're then going to go and wire up the
pillar content as well as the LinkedIn
carousels. The cool thing is is that
I've also gone and created a content
framework here. And I've put that
framework in here. And again, you can go
and get this entire Poppy board I've
created in this video via the link in
the description. I want to give you the
systems, the frameworks that I wish I
had 8 years ago when I was much earlier
on in my content journey. We have hooked
up the chat. We're always going to go
and check it just to make sure it's
seeing everything in the knowledge base.
Beautiful. It sees LinkedIn content
strategy. It's able to see all my
LinkedIn posts. Like, how magical is
that, right? I can't get this in chat
GBT. It's got all of my content that's
ready to now be repurposed. Now, what
we're going to go do is wire up the next
hyperspecific prompt. So, now you have
an understanding of what we're trying to
do here. I've given you the pillar
content, and then we're going to go and
repurpose that into multiple LinkedIn
posts. I've given you three LinkedIn
carousels that I published in my profile
in the past that was based off of other
videos I've done. And then I've given
you a very comprehensive LinkedIn viral
content framework. What I need you to do
is then based on these resources, come
up with five solid LinkedIn post ideas.
I want two of them to be carousel posts
um that can be taken from the pillar
content video and then three other posts
and I want them all to direct to a CTA.
So, we're going to go and put that into
Poppy AI. Just triple check it as we do
with everything. And then we're going to
let it rip. Keep in mind, right, I'm
always reviewing this stuff. I would
triple check it. AI is not perfect.
Point is that this is kind of like your
content researcher, right? It's doing a
lot of that heavy lifting for you to get
you ripping. It's gone and come up with
a bunch of different carousel posts and
we've got all of these amazing hooks and
content structures in terms of formats,
hook, um the angle, um to really get
going here. The beautiful thing, right,
is that you can really just keep on
prompting AI just to give you more. So,
if you're not happy with the first few
outputs, just keep it working. Don't
feel like you got to take the first
output from this. Just like, you know,
often times with a teammate, they're
going to bring you something and you're
going to kind of ask for more, you
should be using the AI the same way.
Now, I'm going to go and give it another
prompt here. love these ideas. Let's put
together the comprehensive details of
each post. Starting with the carousel
post, how many slides each post should
be, what should be there in each of the
slides. It could be, you know, a table
of carousels, and then for the other
one, since it's just text, you can give
me the text. Make sure you follow the
same style and language that I use in my
LinkedIn carousel and the YouTube video
so it sounds exactly like me and not
somebody else. Okay? And I'm going to go
and put that as well into that prompt
dock. So, you got all of that um and can
just steal all this stuff. copy and
paste it and use it for yourself. So,
look at this, right? Like, come on,
right? So, carousel one, it's gone and
flushed out the five steps to get
unstuck, my 10-minute system. Okay? So,
it's giving each slide of this carousel,
right? Step one, step two, step three,
and so forth, right? Including my own
unique brand language, which is like
kind of insane, right? So, it's putting
things like my ship messy protocol, the
one domino decision, and it's using all
of my stuff and just repurposing it to
this format. What I see a lot of people
get worried about with AI is like, "Oh
my gosh, it's going to generate a lot of
stuff that isn't even me." But the
difference here is that it is you.
Because what we're doing is we're taking
all of your transcripts and we're simply
just fitting them into this format. This
is a way to use AI to actually make sure
that you sound legit. Um, we don't want
to be sounding like robots online,
obviously, right? We want to sound like
humans and make sure that we're actually
developing that emotional resonance,
which is likely why people are going and
following you. And that's how you're
going to go and build a cult following
around your brand online. Now, like
anything, guys, you got to scrub this
stuff. But you get it, right? We're now
moving a lot faster and helping you guys
scale up. Let's now move on to Instagram
reels. So, I'm going to start with going
and titling a group here, Instagram
reels. We're going to go over to my
Instagram page. over there. You can see
I've got over 957,000 followers. We able
to grow that all organically. You know,
some videos here have gotten over 12
million views, 9 million views. Um, and
so what I'm going to do is go and take
some of our Instagram reels and I'm
going to go and copy and paste them into
this Instagram reels group. Now, it's
going and transcribing those reels.
Okay? Okay. So, it's looking at the way
that I talk, the way I speak, my own
kind of verbiage, my own kind of
content, intellectual property, and it's
leveraging all of those different little
hints and ins and outs, and then going
to be able to come up with amazing copy
because at this point, we've probably
given Poppy AI like 50,000 words in my
voice. And so, it sees how I talk. We're
not worried now that, oh man, this AI
just sounds like some robot. I mean,
it's pretty hard when you've gone and
given it that much context as well as
the specific prompts that we're giving
it here. It's going to be able to work
some serious magic. What I love about
this, right, is that we're not going and
reinventing the wheel. This is the
beauty of the content waterfall is that
we've made a pillar piece of content,
just go and fit it into this new format.
And it's going to take the Instagram
reels examples here I've put in the
references, combine that with the
ultimate short form video script writing
framework, which I've gone and given you
guys here. And then we're going to hook
up the group as well as the text
framework. We're going to connect it all
to this AI chat. Also going to give it
the pillar piece of content, which is
essential. And all of that is in this AI
chat. And now we're going to really do
this thing. We've hooked this thing up
like a Ferrari. We can see that it's got
my Steve Jobs framework, my 4,000 weeks
perspective. We're going to be making
things like Casey Neistat with that
consistency. We've got the YouTube
pillar content. So, we're ready to go.
What I now want to do is prompt it and
say, "Okay, so I've given you the pillar
content video, which is the one I want
to repurpose into multiple short form
videos. And I've given you six Instagram
reels that I've published in my profile
in the past that was based off of other
videos I've done. And then I've given
you a very comprehensive short form
video script writing framework. And what
I need you to do now is based on all of
these resources, come up with five solid
viral video ideas based off of the
pillar content video. Each idea needs to
have three varying solid hooks. And the
script could be a clip from the pillar
content video or it could be a fresh
script that I need to record but based
off the original. Here we go. We've got
video idea number one, the 2minute
mental cleanse. Okay, let's look at the
hook here. This 2-minute morning ritual
is going to completely change how fast
you accomplish your goals. It's just
it's insane, right? Inside of that
pillar video, I talk about Jerry
Seinfeld and how he was able to write
one joke a day and build a 7 billion
empire around Seinfeld and then his own
net worth has skyrocketed to over 1.1
billion. So, the crazy thing is Poppy AI
because it's transcribing that video is
able to actually pull that out and then
come up with a short form concept based
on that. Here's the hook as an example.
Jerry Seinfeld wrote one joke every day
and it made him worth 1.1 billion.
Here's the math. We've got Instagram
hooked up, but let's do this for one
more platform here. Why don't we move
over to X. I know a lot of you guys are
looking to scale on there and you guys
want to be omniresent. So, we go over to
X and we are going over to my profile
there. And you're getting the pattern
now, right? We're going to the profile.
We're catching some references, putting
them in there, and then we're ripping.
I'm going to take in some of my posts. I
can just go and copy and paste the link
into here. I've got seven posts in here.
And then um what I'm going to give you
guys too is a text field here which is
my whole kind of Twitter content
framework. Okay. And so now we've got
the Twitter content framework hooking
that up into the AI chat. The tweet
references into the AI chat and you
guessed it that pillar piece of content
into the AI chat as well. All right. So
now I'm going to prompt it here. Great.
I've given you the pillar content video
which is the one I want to repurpose
into multiple Twitter posts. I've given
you seven tweets that I've published in
my profile in the past that was based
off of other videos I've done. And then
I've given you a very comprehensive
Twitter content framework. And then make
sure it's based off of my actual words,
content I've talked about in the pillar
content video. For me, I'm writing my
own tweets, right? But for a lot of you
guys, you guys are determined. You want
to be on all platforms, but you just
don't have the time in your day. That's
where tools like this can really help
you guys out. I get it, right? You're
obsessed. You want to have some good
That's what I'm here to help you
with. And so here we can see tweet one.
I went from burnout and procrastination
to working 4 hours a day building
multiple online businesses. Here's the
10-minute system that got me unstuck
faster than 99% of people. And so, you
know, in seconds here we are flushing
out multiple tweet structures. This is
just honestly pure magic. Now, I've
added all of that framework and that
prompt as well to the prompt stock. Get
that in the link in description. You get
it, guys. You know, we're trying to be
as insanely generous in these videos as
possible. Now, as you're watching this
video, right, honestly, this is a
fraction of what we do inside of Founder
OS. And it's all good to have all of
this knowledge, but if you don't have
the right support, you don't have the
right community and mentorship around
you, honestly, it's kind of all for
nothing. Because truthfully, this is
just one piece of the overall puzzle.
Once you go and install these kind of
content systems in your business, what
you're going to quickly find is that
you're going to want some people to chat
with, some people to help you along the
way. And that's exactly why I built
Founder OS. So, if you want to get more
help from me and my team and go and be
able to use other breakthrough AI tools,
go and check out the link in the
description and go apply right now. So,
we've got seven oneliner posts. We've
got different threads. Honestly, this is
content multiplied. You've been able to
take that one pillar piece of content
and turn that into over 20 other pieces
of content. This is what's possible when
you nail your content waterfall system.
All of this template, all of these
prompts are shared with you via the link
in the description. So, go and steal my
prompts. Go and steal this board. I
can't wait to see what you create. If
you follow these three stages, you're
going to have an unfair advantage when
it comes to creating content. Now, you
have the systems, you have the guide,
and you have the support. Welcome to the
founder freedom movement and let's win