Every brand needs to have proper brand
positioning, but the issue is so many
founders that I speak with, they're
putting themselves out there, but it's
all over the place. And the issue is
when you have that, people don't know
what you stand for, they don't
understand your point of view, and
everything just feels sporadic.
Everything that I do at Founder OS is
really helping founders build beautiful
personal brands, right? And powerful
social media machines, and do it in an
insanely simple way. And so, what I'm
going to show you here is a brand
positioning for Chris Robinson.
in mind everything inside of Founder OS
we keep confidential, but I've gone and
mocked up an example founder here based
on someone I was just helping 2 days
ago. So, Chris Robinson here goes and
runs a growth consultancy, right? A lot
of the founders that we help inside of
Founder OS are people that are financial
service providers, home services,
lawyers, accountants, dentists, you name
it. First things first here inside of
this brand positioning, right? Is this a
strategic overview in terms of how we're
going to go and think about driving
revenue to this business that's looking
to get to over $20 million this year, up
from 7.2 million. Revenue's been
plateauing there, it's just been driven
off of referrals, nothing seems to be
working because, you know, in this case
Chris's brand is really lacking that
infrastructure. And so, before we just
go and start building a bunch of email
sequences, before we go and start
building the whole content GPS and
organic content for Chris, we want to
make sure that we got a succinct brand
in place. And so, let me go and show you
how we go and do this for founders,
okay? First thing is really nailing the
creative psychology. This is probably
one of my favorite parts of building
brands is the creative tasteful aspect
behind it, right? Helping founders
really tap into their inner artistry as
well. And so, these are some principles
that I think are really important when
you're building a brand. Things like the
architect effect, not just building
Chris into the engine behind his whole
brand, we want him to be the architect
of it and have AI systems, his team all
running and being able to operate
without him being involved in every
single detail. In addition to that,
right? We want to go and we want to use
the data that he has. He's helped
hundreds and hundreds of clients. He
helps them drive insane 3x ROIs based on
his 12 years of pattern recognition. And
so, this is what Chris has over every
other person in his space, right? And
why companies choose to work with him in
Australia. And so, we want to go and
make that data front and center. Okay?
And then we have things too like the
specificity bias, right? So many
founders when they're getting going
building their brand, it's so pithy and
vague. And what we want to get into are
the details, right? The what, the how to
go and do things because it's in those
specifics, right? That we go and
showcase some of Chris's proprietary
intellectual property. Which when I
think about going and creating great
content, you kind of want 50% of it to
be, you know, you going and presenting,
but just like this video right here,
it's also the IP that's kind of the, you
know, hero inside of those videos. So
that you're showing it and telling it
and convincing people that you're legit.
And thereby, they watch the video, they
kind of see what you're all about, and
it's a beautiful slippery slope for them
going and joining and monetizing with
you.
So if you're wondering how your brand
measures up to these standards, you can
go and check out my brand scorecard in
the link in the description. Go and get
an immediate score and results on how
you stand. It's a free assessment where
you can go and get your score and then
understand if your brand is ready for a
system like this. And so, the brand
foundation, right? This is a strategic
core of really how every piece of
content and offer really then ladders
back to conversion. We like to go and
dive into the why, the how, and the
what, right? I've learned this from
Simon Sinek, right? Inevitably, everyone
is going to go and resonate with you
because of your big why. For me, that's
going and helping 100 million founders
go and unlock their full creative
potential and own their distribution.
Because I believe in this new AI
frontier that your distribution is the
final moat. And so, in this case, we're
mapping out exactly how he's going to
achieve his big why, which is helping
every SaaS founder build a growth system
that compounds and not just doing it as
some consultant that just leaves them
hanging. And so, how he does that is
with his growth arc method, and this is
kind of his proprietary approach to
going and helping them go and achieve
the growth. And then, what it is is a
growth consulting firm. He's got his Arc
OS SaaS part of his business, and then
group program. So, one part consulting,
one part SaaS, one part education. And I
talked to a lot of founders that are
doing, you know, multiple different
business models, because these days,
when you're looking to scale from 20 to
30 to 50 million dollars a year,
oftentimes you have a tech component,
you may have a consulting component and
maybe some education, right? Founders
all the time have
troubles going and basically making all
of these elements in their business all
go and become simple and build a
flywheel around them. I was just helping
a founder yesterday go and figure this
out and showing him how when he goes and
builds his construction business, you
know, it helps him go and build his
authority that will drive people to his
education business, that helps him then
go and drive more talent back to his
construction business. And oftentimes
people come to us at FounderUs to help
them go and tighten up their brand and
then amplify it. And so, the 10-year
vision here, right, is this succinct
look between the business getting to 20
million dollars plus, going and building
out the brand on LinkedIn, which for me
personally drives about 40% of the leads
to my portfolio of online companies that
are now doing over 14 million dollars a
year. He wants to make a massive impact
and scale and help a thousand founders.
And in his own personal life, right,
wants to be able to have four-day work
weeks, have a team of 40 running the
operation, and wants to be able to
control really the four Ws in life,
right? Be able to work where he wants,
when he wants, on what he wants, with
whoever he wants, okay? And so,
it all comes down to then, how do you
build a niche of one? Most people, when
they're going and building their
founder-led brand, I think have the
opportunity to build their own
psychographic. Go and attract people
that are into the things that you're
into. And so, in Chris's situation here,
he's really all about this kind of
systems-driven growth. He really loves
to help SaaS founders go and scale out
their businesses, and then he's able to
use his 12 years of proprietary data to
go and indicate exactly the different
moves they can make to scale up from 10
to 20 to 30 million dollars. He's built
this amazing revenue architecture over
those decades of experience that the
intersection of those four quadrants,
right, are what make Chris unique. So
many founders, right, struggle in this
area because I think it's sometimes hard
to find your niche of one when it's just
you alone in your room, or, you know,
you've never done this kind of stuff
before. Often times, you need someone to
kind of work through with it, right? And
this is why, you know, in Founderless,
with founders one-on-one, helping them
really nail that intersection so they
can find a niche that's exciting to
them, that they're great at, and it's
bound to make them a lot of money. And
it's the intersection of those three
areas that I think makes great brand
positioning when you're building a
founder-led brand, okay? So, let's go
down now to the audience architecture.
When we go and think about building an
audience, I often times like to think
about building it around one core
person. When we go and think about Chris
Robbins's business here, right, we've
kind of gone and synchronized a
high-value client checklist, right? The
kind of traits that really define his
core ideal avatar. It's SaaS founders
who have done a series A to series C,
annual revenue between 2 million and 20
million, you know, they're relying on
paid ads, they believe in systems over
hustle, and they're willing to invest
$25,000 as long as there's a measurable
ROI. When we've gone and then been able
to take some of the data that Chris has
had from different sales calls, we've
piped that data into this brand
positioning, right? So, we can see some
of the core quotes from those client
interviews, right? Things like, you
know, I have the product, but I don't
have the pipeline. Or we grew to $5
million on referrals, but then it all
stopped. Now, where this becomes
interesting, right, is that when we're
building content, we want our content to
be a salesperson that never sleeps. And
the way to do that is to make sure that
we're using like the actual words that
our customers are speaking. Oftentimes,
your best content ideas, your best
positioning statements for your brand
will come from the real words that your
customers have spoken on things like
customer success calls or sales calls.
And so, we've gone and taken all of that
data and then piped it into this brand
positioning so that as we're coming up
with content ideas, we can continue to
build this amazing infrastructure that's
going to make his customers feel like
they're reading their mind, okay? And
so,
with all of this,
Chris now owns a category of one, right?
He's the only B2B growth strategist who
has personally architected revenue
systems for 200 plus SaaS companies and
now teaches the exact methodology
through a productized framework founders
can run themselves. So, from there,
we're able to look at how he's
differentiating himself in his
competitive landscape, really being more
of a founder-led brand and leaning into
his methodology. You know, this is where
I see so many founders really leaving
money on the table is not going in
growing and taking their founder-led
brands seriously. You know, in
old-school industries, right, like home
services, financial services, you know,
insurance, we're helping founders in
these spaces day in day out go and use
these more new-school marketing tactics
in those old-school industries to stand
out, right? And so, I think, you know,
the opportunity here for Chris is to do
just that, right? And lean in to that
founder-led brand, which is things like,
you know, HubSpot or generic agencies or
even McKinsey aren't doing. From here,
right, we want to make sure that, you
know, every word from Chris is
deliberate. We've gone and charted out
based on some conversations we've had
with Chris, and then we use that to
inform things like the brand strategy
and the content that we make for him.
We've noticed that Chris is direct,
right, he's systems-driven, so we can
see he uses language that's also
data-anchored. You know, we don't want
him to sound like, you know, I feel like
our growth has been slowing down lately.
Everything has to be grounded in being
kind of precise, data-driven, right, and
utilizing all of that proprietary data
and methodology that he has to go and
stand out online. Out the gate, so many
experts sound like a bunch of corporate
jargon. And when we're talking online,
we want to make things clear, not
clever. We want to make them simple, not
complex, right. And we're going to stop
the scroll and be most convincing when
we're not using a bunch of vague
corporate and instead are just
speaking to people like normal humans.
And that's exactly what we helped Chris
with here. The kind of words that make
sense for Chris and his market are
things like revenue per impression, his
conversion architecture, revenue
constraints, things like this architect
mindset, his distribution mode, right,
the kind of stuff that is some
proprietary content intellectual
property, right. These are the sort of
words that when Chris uses these in his
market will cause people to perk up,
learn more, and
it's the kind of language then that all
lead back to him as the founder and for
people working with him in his business.
When it comes then to actually mapping
out your brand, right, where a lot of
founders get confused is they have a
bunch of disparate offers that are not
connected. And so, what we wanted to do
here was go and connect the four tiers
that Chris has all with one system,
right, so that every founder finds the
right entry point for them. So far,
what's useful here, right, is that Chris
kind of came in and he had a software
over here, he had no lead magnets going
on, and no way of bringing people from
his audience to his offer. And so,
because of that, you know, it was
confusing to customers, right? It's like
this spider web of different ways they
can go, and there's no understanding of
what product was right for which person.
And so, now with the right growth
diagnostic up front, he's able to have
people go through the calculator,
determine
which piece is best for them, and then
find themselves in the right product.
And so, when you think about your
platform strategy, where I see most
founders screw up is they try to be
omnipresent day one. And when you're
just getting going with content, the
issue is it's just too much at once,
right? The best content strategy is the
one that you can stick with. And so,
what we focused on here was right
message, right channel, right frequency.
So, doing five times a week on LinkedIn,
and he wanted to do two times a week on
YouTube. When we think about LinkedIn,
right? It's going to be using 60% of
content around his proprietary
frameworks, 25% on case studies, right?
Because at the end of the day, people
really trust folks when you're telling
the stories of your core customers,
right? People don't buy what you sell,
they buy what other people want to buy.
And then 15% just more on his own point
of view, right? So, people get to know
Chris as a human, because after all,
right? Personal brands need to be
personal. On the YouTube side, what
we're trying to do there is 50%
tutorials, right? Where we're screen
sharing different systems and IP that
he's made, which is going to help
attract more customers like the ones
he's got. And then 30% different
breakdowns of how he's helped different
customers, and then 20% interviews with
successful customers, right? So, that
people have more and more proof that
Chris is legit. And then we have a
newsletter, right? Which is the middle
layer where we're going to nurture
people between, you know, great
generating audience awareness via the
content, and then monetizing them. We
want to make sure that we effectively
nurture them in the middle here, so that
we're going and owning that audience in
our email list. This is going to convert
32 times better than social media and
drive the right people then to go and
work with Chris inside his different
containers. So, when you're going and
then building your actual funnel and
monetization, the biggest thing here is
making sure that you understand that you
don't just have one offer, right? You
have multiple offers, right? And that's
the kind of thinking that's required so
that every single impression has the
highest degree likelihood of then
converting into revenue. You're
engineering every single step. And so,
when you think about your content as an
example, your different post on LinkedIn
is like an offer to get someone to click
and join your newsletter, right? Which
is why we make lead magnets. From there,
on the landing page for your lead
magnet, it's an offer then to get
someone to give you their email. From
there, inside of the lead magnet,
there's a core offer in there to get
someone to maybe book a call with you.
And then, obviously, on the call, you
have an offer then for someone to then
go and join your service or your
product. And so, it's actually
understanding that you have an offer
stack. And in this case, it's going from
content on LinkedIn, YouTube, and
newsletter to then the lead magnet that
basically serves as both a lead magnet
and an application form that smartly
routes the right people to Chris's
business. The other part is that there's
a 9-day nurture sequence, which I get
into in detail here, so you can go and
steal this. So, here is the welcome
sequence, okay? And this follows days 1
to 5 being this kind of educational
email series, okay? We're going to go
and give people the audit results. And
so, for your business, you may do some
diagnostic, a calculator, a quiz, it
doesn't matter. But that's then going to
set the frame for folks, and they're
going to understand your system and
where their gaps are. From there, on day
two here, we're then going and using
storytelling to describe the kind of
customers that you've helped. From
there, day three, right? We're going
over things like revenue constraints,
the conversion architecture breakdown,
and then day five gets deep into the
growth arc method. Now, this is where
then from days six all the way through
nine are the FOMO series, okay? And this
is where we're using emails on days six,
seven, eight, and nine to more directly
drive people to a sales call. Okay? And
so, you can imagine so many people,
maybe you watching this, right? You get
people to download a lead magnet, but
then you have no emails they get. And
so, you just get like one shot at bat.
When you have a nine email series,
right? When people sign up to your
newsletter, now you're getting nine more
tries at bat being able to go and
convert people from, you know, your
email list to now that next stage in
closing those deals. This is just one
piece of the nine core phases that we go
and do for founders inside of Founder
OS, right? The craftsmanship, the data
that we have from helping over 3,500
founders, we pour into this, right? All
the things I've learned building my own
company Herb to 14 million people,
growing my own personal brand over 3
million, is all of the data that we
infuse to help founders go and build
things like their brand positioning,
their content machine, their social
media machine, and then all of the
conversion necessary to build a
profitable personal brand. And so, if
this is interesting, you can go and
check out Founder OS via the link in the
description. If you watch this whole
thing, you probably understand why this
is not just a marketing document. This
becomes one of the strategic operating
layers of your entire social media
machine. If you want me and my team to
build this layer and all the others for
you, that's exactly why I built Founder
OS. Because most founders do not need
another course or some, you know,
personal branding expert. They need this
machine installed ASAP because they
continue to post content and see no
return. So, if you're doing between 30K
up to a million a month and your
business is working, but your personal
brand is not creating a predictable
pipeline, apply for Founder OS below.
Thanks so much for watching. If you
enjoyed this video, you'd love this next
one on go and building your brand
psychology and how to go and build your
own profitable personal brand. I'll see
you over there. Be sure to like and
subscribe and welcome to the founder
freedom movement.