I gotta say that is like a real unlock
man. Like a literal blind spots that I I
just didn't see.
[Music]
So I'm here in Lisbon, Portugal, and my
good friend Igor came to me with a
problem. His content was feeling like a
chore. I get it. You don't need to do
any more convincing. I guess I didn't
see the full picture. Okay. Dreading it.
Looking at himself in the mirror going,
"What am I doing here?" Spending nights
up until 2:00 a.m. shooting YouTube
videos. Insane. But the truth is I hear
this same struggle from hundreds if not
thousands of founders. And I went and
broke down for Eigor my three frameworks
to go from content labor to content CEO.
And I'm going to go and share with you
these three frameworks so you can go and
implement them in your own life and
business today. Let's get into it. So
maybe we can start with just like like
an overview of like what you created and
like your story a bit. I just love to
tinker. I love to build. I love to
create. Yeah. Over time that took many
forms in my adult life. It started
taking the form of first a video
production company and now tech YouTube
channel on artificial intelligence
concretely generative AI use cases that
are practical. I see myself as I'm like
the practical guy that shows you how to
apply it rather than just shows you and
reads out the blog posts for example. So
it's always a balance but at the end of
the day I'm just a creator just a
entrepreneur. The main question in my
mind was I would love to do more content
that breaks a little bit out of the
routine that I've built in terms of
content creation. It's very rigid right
now. Like we do a weekly news video, we
repurpose that into free shorts that we
post across different platforms. We do
sponsored videos where I really like our
approach cuz we pick projects that we
want to do and we pitch them to the
sponsors and if their platform and
product matches with that, we do like
this project video with the sponsor.
>> Nice. Beyond that, it doesn't really
leave much space for me to kind of just
take some time and create some space to
just do something that I would like to
create. I don't remember the last time
where I kind of like really created a
project where I just felt like creating
that.
>> Usually, it's very driven by strategy
and usually it's me sitting in a room
recording a YouTube video by myself
about this neverending list of AI
releases every single week. And I just
got to say that's sometimes that's
rather uninspiring, but out of the 15 20
releases every week, we cover 10. And I
personally maybe care about one. And
maybe and usually and honestly that's
that's a bit optimistic cuz like we just
do it on every single week. And most
people if you consume it, you spend 15
minutes with the video or 20 minutes
with the video. Our entire process
actually I did the calculation recently.
I was kind of shocked by it because we
have two researchers, we have two
editors, we have me and then we have
meetings to prepare everything. Overall,
it's 45 46 hours to create one video in
man hours.
>> But it's like turns content creation
into more of a treadmill than something
that I would want to do more of. And I
would love to create more. I would love
to create something that's a bit more
authentic to me rather than just doing
the list of news stories.
>> So the first framework is the
intentional content framework. You may
be there, right? You're creating
content, but it's not filling up your
cup or you're actually really enjoying
it, but you're making no money from it.
And the problem is is that when you
don't have these three aspects nailed
down, you have content that is
essentially broken. Let me explain. So,
the three parts of the intentional
content framework are making content
that you love, that you can be paid for,
and that you're great at. The
intersection of that is the founderled
brand sweet spot. This is when you're
making content that you know just feels
like flow. It's enjoyable. You're
putting it out there and your community
is eating it up. They're in fact paying
you to go and learn more of these
concepts from you or they're buying your
product and service cuz they're so
convinced by what you're delivering and
it actually relates to the thing that
you sell. And it's something that you're
great at, right? You have mastery over
this domain. When you get all three of
those things, I think you're really
building content inside of your calling.
And ultimately, you're kind of creating
a niche, and that niche is you. As an
example, what I see all the time is that
people are making great money from what
they're doing, and they're really great
at it, but there's like this inner
artist in them that's been lost. you
know, the days of enjoying the content,
taking pride in things like the
cinematography, the tone, the editing,
the coloring, the font, the B-roll, all
those different details has been lost.
And along with that, the heart and the
soul of their brand has washed away.
This may not matter for most people, but
for the kind of founders that I work
with, the heart and soul of a brand is
everything. And I don't think this is
just important for your own sake, but as
you look over to the next decade, with
AI taking over more and more, with
content just becoming more ubiquitous
and easier to replicate, the one piece
that AI will never be able to replicate
is your heart, your soul, and the
intentionality that you put into your
content. And so when I like look at your
current situation, right, it seems like
some of the issues lie in like when we
look at this like love area because I
feel like a lot of what you're currently
doing, it's always solo. Don't love
that.
>> Yeah, you talked about being on feeling
like you're on a bit of a treadmill.
>> Yeah. I think these are the two things.
I think you you nailed it on the head.
Like those are the two things that make
some of the videos feel like a chore.
And I do them for the audience, but
there's only so much of that you can
kind of do. So when it comes to the solo
side, right, let's just like maybe
double click into a few of these for a
sec. So we got solo. So what's like, you
know, been the main struggle on the solo
side in the videos. If I'm going through
the docket of like all the topics, I'm
not excited about every single one of
them. So I got to put on a bit of a
play. Like I can go from like mellow to
like what's up guys? In today's episode
of News You Can Use, we got to kind of
cover this and this. And then you
wouldn't believe what happened with Open
Eyes new release. they got sued again,
you know, and like and I think that sort
of is draining, right? There feels like
an element there. It's like it's a
little bit draining. Yeah, it is. It is
definitely draining and it feels like
it's also I don't want to say like
performative or you got to turn on, you
know? It's like it's like a late night
host or something, right? Like they
always have this like persona, right?
And there's like this character you kind
of got to tap into versus it feeling
like it's coming from like maybe your
heart and soul.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And then on the the
treadmill aspect, like what are some
like the major challenges there? I mean,
I'm tied to upload schedule, right? I'm
tied to a team, tied to the deadlines
that come with that. But I don't
actually dread that. I kind of I don't
mind that. I think it's really more in
like the first aspect when I look at it
like this on the board. Yeah. Like the
the solo aspect.
>> Okay. This is the major one. I think the
treadmill aspect that I do mind is the
fact that it t like I feel like if I had
like a month of not creating content I
would be creating content but other type
of content you know like sort of these
like ideas that I have would like
percolates to the top because I'm on a
treadmill and because I'm on a deadline
like when I'm done creating everything
and like the weekend comes around on
Saturday I got to do some business stuff
to catch up on and then maybe I have a
Sunday off and like the last thing I
want to do on a Sunday is spend the
whole day creating because I know Monday
is coming around and like Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And like you said too, when
you're on such like a production
schedule, whether it's like four videos
a month or 10 videos a month to come up
with like that ultimate creative content
that you actually really love to do is
just more added content ideation
formulation and that's the last thing
you're going to want to do and it's
probably the last thing that's even
healthy for you to do. I think longevity
is something that doesn't get kind of
talked about enough in a way, right?
Yeah,
>> most content strategies are all over the
place. And the next framework helps you
go and synthesize your content in a way
that's clear, concise, and honestly just
a lot of fun. The reality is is if
you're making a bunch of content all
over the place, you're not going to
enjoy it. Your team's going to be
confused around it, and it's likely not
going to perform well with your
community. And so this is where the 333
method comes in. having three clear
content categories, three clear content
formats, and three unique perspectives
that really encapsulate your point of
view in your given sort of content
strategy. For this exercise for you, I
would just focus on what do you love to
create? What is the kind of stuff you
love to talk about? we can talk about
later like the paid aspect of that or
all that aspect but kind of like let's
use that as an afterthought because I
feel like you're already really great at
figuring out how to get paid for things
but it's this like love component that
>> kind of gets ignored for a sec. So for
me as an example like just to go through
these on the you know the pillars side
we have things like organic content we
have stuff like founder systems time
freedom and then on the different
formats we just kind of keep it simple
so we have like howto type videos maybe
how I which is more like about how I do
something and then behind the scenes
type stuff on the unique perspectives
we've got kind of like the Zen CEO vibe
like how to build a calm company we've
got you know systems kind of equal
freedom sort of perspective and that the
future of brands will be founderled.
Sometimes this exercise is really
linear. Sometimes it's like a little bit
messy cuz just a content brainstorm.
What are some content pillars that like
would bring you joy that you'd love to
talk about? You have like a whole new
channel you're starting. Maybe it's like
imagine it's day one all over again.
>> Yeah.
>> So just like what I really want to talk
about the stuff that I'm passionate
about I just love kite surfing right
now. Like over the past few years I just
love that sport. It's such a niche
sport. Like even the it's a small sport
worldwide. Secondly, I feel like I've
been through an extraordinary amount of
hardship for my relative young age. I
find myself one being really helpful
when somebody's struggling with certain
life life lessons and two I find myself
enjoying that. I can tell you like from
the past year the event that I actually
enjoyed the most was a local school here
in Lisbon reaching out for me to like
speak there and it was more about like
the entrepreneurial journey rather than
like just AI. They're like this this AI
creator but all the questions they had
is like how did you start like how do
you do that? How do we do that? And just
like sharing that that was the most
inspiring thing for me like
>> that was that was amazing. And I'm like
life lessons.
>> Yeah like life lessons. Yeah, that
really and then also I think when I when
I see that I think one thing that I
thought about like many times was I
think I'm really good on systems like I
I talked to like an entrepreneur friend
of mine. We kind of like compared
systems and she was like what the hell
what like how how do you have a flow for
every process? How do you have these
like job descriptions with tasks that
are tied to like out like everything is
just it's it's really like I built this
puzzle and I think I know where that
comes from. It comes from a lot of like
unpredictability in my early years. So I
learned that like okay like if I can
build this repeatable system then yeah
there's just a reason for for my life.
But like generally I think structure to
chaos. So in terms of like format you
know just to give you a broad range like
there's like listicles there's like
system breakdowns there's guides there's
recipes
testimonials like is there certain
formats? You've seen a lot of different
stuff. I know a decent amount of what
you do currently is an example would be
like news roundups.
>> I'm curious what comes up there.
>> One thing I want to y is the how I
because like that's the thing is like
when I built a personal CRM I don't
really create a video for it on the
channel right cuz it's not like a really
AI thing but I think it's super
interesting way to kind of like approach
your social life especially if you like
live globally. How do I navigate life
lessons? How do I na build systems to
help with my social community aspect to
all that? Yeah, I think a lot of this
like at least where I see it going just
to sometimes I think it's good to
reflect it back to you. It's like we
talked about the first bit, right? Which
is like that intentional content
framework, right? The love piece was
kind of missing which means like kind of
like your heart and soul isn't
necessarily getting a lot of space in
your content strategy. Yeah.
>> And then when we kind of double click
into the 33 method, we get into like all
these awesome things that you want to be
talking about like your interesting kite
surfing, how you like to like optimize
things, create like your own personal
CRM as nerdy as these things are, right?
I got a bunch of that stuff, too. This
idea of like moving it from just like
how you can do stuff to just like, hey,
I'm just going to be open about how I do
things.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, and I think that it kind of also
leads from if people are watching this
too, it creates what I think is like
almost like character development,
right? Like you can just keep delivering
all this knowledge and all this news all
the time, like who the hell is this guy?
>> Yeah.
>> And if you think about over the next
like say 20 years of doing what you're
doing, cuz I do believe that you're the
kind of guy that will be doing this that
long at least. Like
>> always creating videos. Yeah,
>> in any space, but let's just say AI as
an example. The thing that will I think
longterm create like more of a moat
around what you're doing is sure like
there's the knowledge piece and the
packaging and the titles and the
community build around all that, but
it's also just you
>> cuz there'll be a bunch of other guys or
women delivering the news and the and
some of the things. Not saying exactly
yours, but you get it right. But it's
like, no, no, but I listen to Eigor.
Like, this guy's dope as [\h__\h] Like, he
kite surfs on weekends and does this
thing over there. He's got a badass team
that meets up like in dope spots.
>> He's like a cool guy and I like the way
he delivers it. So there's this like
they feel like they know you too.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, and it's more of like a
connection with this person online as an
actual human.
>> That makes sense.
>> Versus just this like newscaster in
terms of like the general vibe, right?
We've got like the content pillars. Like
these are just some ideas, right? V1.
This is not saying like, oh, we've
cracked the code on it all, right? But
at least started to tap into some things
that like you genuinely love and that
fire you up. So I think like where I
would personally go with something like
this, right, is now you bring in like
that packaging genius part of your
brain.
>> Yeah.
>> With with all this stuff and even could
put this into like one of your AI tools,
right? Chat GBT of like, hey, I love
these are the thing these are the kind
of content pillars I'm interested in.
This is kind of some formats I'm
thinking of. These are some unique
perspectives I have. Give it as much
detail as possible. even upload some
like amazing like titles that really
inspire you after doing research say on
like one of 10.com or whatever. Yeah.
>> And going like, "Hey, come up with some
concepts around this, whether that's for
YouTube videos or like you said, you're
starting like potentially a new
Instagram channel and then it's like,
okay, here we go." Like it should help
you with like your energy, tapping into
stuff that you actually care about. It
should also be stuff that you can
literally just film like sometimes like
maybe you're about to go kite surfing
for the day and you just like quickly in
the sand before you go just share a
quick story, you know? Or maybe it's the
story afterwards like, "Hey, a guy just
flew into that cliff over there and like
I'm gonna tell you just a quick story
about like how you make plans and life
laughs at them, you know, and people are
like, oh [\h__\h] this is like interesting,
right?" And you're enjoying it just for
the point of like opening up more and
sharing more of this like vulnerable or
real side of you. And people too that
I'm sure follow you on the other
platforms are going to be interested cuz
they're like, "Oh, this is who this guy
is."
>> Yeah, that's great. Building a team can
be one of the hardest challenges of any
founder brand. And often times what you
find is that you're only as strong as
your weakest link. Now in this case,
Igor has been doing this a long, long
time. He's been building businesses for
a decade. Hell, he even ran his own
video production company. And so the
next challenge that he runs into is
super unique. And the truth is though
that I think there is actually a
universal learning from all of this. You
know, the reality is is that often times
we have a lot of the pieces in the right
place, but sometimes it's just that one
little pebble in our shoe, as an
example, that just ends up driving us
the most pain. And it can just be that
one role in your company that you
haven't quite crack the code on yet that
ends up resulting in 95% of your
problems. Now, in this case, it's
actually a few layers deeper for Igor
because his ego and his identity are so
wrapped up in this videographer identity
he used to have when he was 21. You
know, fast forward to 31, he still
hasn't grown out of that identity. And
what we need to do is kind of move him
from just being the creator behind his
brand to the CEO so that he embodies a
new level of founder, moving from
personal brand to personal media
company. And in this next bit, I'm going
to show him how he can actually go and
structure his own personal media company
for massive leverage, enjoyment, and
scale. Let's talk a bit about the solo
vibe you're doing now. And then let's
get into the personal media company
vibe. You know, you said you're filming
tonight. What does that look like? Yeah.
So, we have a research meeting at 6 p.m.
where we get together and uh with the
video editors and the researchers and we
go through every story that happened
this week. uh we go through the research
and also the testing that they have you
know that they execute each week on the
different stories. So it's sort of like
a little like presentation towards me
and then we go through each story and
then decide which of those stories are
worth featuring how I could present them
in the video if I should live test them
if I should if it needs some more review
from me if we need some extra testing to
be done and then basically the ball is
in my side of the court and I have to
record. Okay. So, you have researcher
who does the packaging. Me and my
YouTube production manager and the video
and and the video editors together.
Okay. So, you have a researcher, you
have a production manager and then you
have a video editor.
>> Yes. And then it's sort of split. We
have two video editors and then we I
also have an assistant that is really
amazing at graphics. So, she helps too
sometimes with the packaging, visuals,
>> but it's really like she she also
researches. So, it's kind of a team
effort. That's
>> a social media manager.
>> No.
>> No. No.
>> And you're all good though because Yeah.
You've got It's just a bit of content
and the existing team can handle.
>> Yeah.
>> Cool. I'm not a videographer.
>> No.
>> Okay. No.
>> So, the one thing that just like stands
out, I'm not sure how you feel about it,
right? Is this like again like the
shooting and the actual filming of it
being just like a bit of like a
oneplayer game versus that maybe feeling
a little bit more multiplayer, right?
Like um I talked about how like you know
me and Diego shoot like all the time and
it's not even just that Diego's like
shooting obviously or doing the lighting
which obviously helps or helping with
the locations and all that. It's also
just like the feeling that it's more of
like a team game, you know? So like
we're filming something and I I'm
getting tripped up on something. It's
like having that like emotional support
partner that's like dude, hey, we don't
need to do that right now. Let's just
skip to this part here. And then we do
that part. And maybe I thought, oh [\h__\h]
I'm not looking forward to point four
and six here. I actually don't feel
these. And it's like one thing is I'm
hearing just like the solo aspect
sometimes can be like lonely or even
like a bit like rigid. And then the
second aspect,
>> it's not just lonely. It's rigid too.
And I don't like rigid and it's like
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And it's
just also like you got to go home by
yourself, turn on a light at 1:00 a.m.
There's also like no accountability to
it. So I think like I mean when I look
at yourself I think it's like it's
simple. Like I think there's a world
where like all of this system like is
working cuz you're good at that. But
it's just like you plus like a like
videographer like on the actual shoot
days if you could. But Matt, I I'm the
videographer. I always used to. That was
my job title for for a decade. That's
me.
>> You're telling me I should hire somebody
that is me?
>> But I don't think that that is you,
right? You shifted from being a
videographer to being the actual person
on camera, right? And I think there's a
recognition that you're not that you
think about what you're making. We don't
need to get into all the numbers in
terms of like
>> you know your numbers and all that [\h__\h]
>> But like just in terms of the I feel
screw the numbers. The simple pain that
you feel sometimes on Wednesdays and
Thursday nights
>> like if you could pay I don't know what
is it you need like a couple hours maybe
each night as an example.
>> You know maybe let's just say you're
paying in in a given month 3,000 bucks.
I'm just naming a number. I'm sure it's
less maybe it's more. I don't know.
Right? Like wouldn't it maybe be worth
it just to like get out of like or at
least experiment with it to get out of
this feeling of like I got to go home. I
got to do all this. Like even the
uploading of the footage and all that.
Like you could have someone do all that
[\h__\h]
>> They film it. They put the carts in,
they upload it, they turn on the
cameras, they set it up, they say
they're coming by, they bring food for
you. Like what would it look like?
There's an aspect where I think that I
think it's like the survival mode maybe
as like a kid and kind of like the
resourcefulness in that like you're
you're being a good like frugal founder,
but there's also like you're at a
different stage slightly now.
>> Yeah.
>> If you know what I mean where you don't
need to operate like that. And I just
feel like you could ask yourself again
like it's not just finding the love for
the topics. It's also like the love and
like giving yourself like kind of like
loving kindness in terms of like just
like the filming.
>> Yeah. the way that it feels sometimes
right now. Like it just doesn't need to
feel like that. Like we're filming right
now and this doesn't really even feel
like filming.
>> Hell no.
>> You know, it's just like hanging out,
chilling, kicking it. Like and when
we're done here, we're done. Like I
don't I don't have to do anything. You
don't have to do anything. We just go
and chill.
>> Um and
>> yours right now. And I know because I've
been there, right? It's like, yeah, you
got to like set it up, set up the lens,
set up the this, do a test run, this is
that. Give yourself some affirmations.
Doesn't go right. Oh [\h__\h] the autofocus
is still on. You got to make it manual.
I don't know. You got to switch that.
Maybe that [\h__\h] I'm sure you're good at
cuz you're
>> Oh, [\h__\h] I forgot to switch the scene
from the live stream I did yesterday
night and now the whole 45minute
recording is actually just looking at
the screen and and the camera is across
it. So, I got to do it again,
>> right? And it say that comes up like
once a month, right? I think it's also
it gets back I always remind myself like
what is my hourly rate? My hourly rate
is around $10,000 an hour. So, if that
thing comes up say once a month you're
wasting one or two hours. Your hourly
rate's $6,000 7 whatever the hell it is
$10,000 an hour. Simply just having
someone that saves you the upload time,
makes it more fun, does like some of the
technical aspects, helps even like, hey,
you're stuck there. Let me just ask you
a question. Talk to me. Let me just tell
you, I get it. You don't need to do any
more convincing or points there. I think
no, I get it because like the first
sentence that you said nailed it
already. Like I think being a
videographer is still like a part of my
ego. And also, I think when I was
younger and also like before I went for
therapy, I think the big topic there was
like not just being like fully
self-sufficient all the time on
everything and that it's okay to need
people and that people are not built to
just self-regulate and everything. And
it's just kind of like accepting that
like nothing about my life is the life
of videographer me from like 8 years ago
or something. So, I got to accept that
and stop acting like the videographer
cuz like I'm not cuz I'm the guy who's
presenting the AI news and in other
situations I love to love that work. I
love the equipment. Yeah. I just got to
accept that I have a new role to fill.
Yeah. And I think though if you like
reflect like the reality is like you
know how to do the research, you know
how to do the production management, you
know, you know how to do the video
editing. So I don't think this is like
some skill like outside of yourself. I
actually just see it as like maybe just
like the last rung. I think there's an
aspect of you that's just downplaying it
a bit. Like I think it's more than you
think. Like because I the thing I have
to I remind myself of a lot of time and
sometimes even remind the team of is
like simply just being a founder and a
creator. That's already two, maybe even
three jobs in terms of like the sheer
level of workload, pressure, sometimes
feeling like you really got to like,
wow, like I got to really like you're on
camera, you got to give it like even in
those days that you don't maybe have the
energy, you got to show up to then go
and add literally anything more. It's
just literally not possible.
>> I do all the finance stuff, too.
>> Yeah, of course. There's definitely more
[\h__\h] you do, right?
>> And there's Yeah, there's wear multiple
hats. Okay, that simple. got to stop
being the videographer. Like if I if I
was in your shoes like just not and I'm
not here to convince anything. I'm more
just like here to like illustrate an
example, right? I personally would like
it is very convincing.
>> I would I would have like Okay, so say
you're filming on like Wednesday and
Thursday, right? And you like to film in
the evenings typically, let's just say
that was the case. I would go and
interview some different people or maybe
you already know people. You end up
finding a person that you just genuinely
like as like a friend kind of like me
and Diego or most of the people I work
with on my team. Then you know, you have
that person like maybe they like you do
a dinner like Wednesday, Thursdays. So
you go to dinner, you have like they've
already printed out like what you're
going to review. They're bringing you
like the printed stuff hypothetically.
Over dinner, you're kind of like talking
about it, brainstorming it. So your
brain's already getting in the mode of
it, but in a fun way. It's just like
over like a nice restaurant, right? Then
you both go to your place. They're going
to go set it all up. You're going to get
your computer on, start to whatever,
whatever. But they're doing the
lighting. They're doing the thing. This
is that.
>> Yeah. And then at 9:00 you go live till
11, film the one or two things, whatever
you got to do. And that's just like the
Wednesday routine. And that's also the
Thursday routine. And each time too
afterwards, they're taking the footage,
uploading it to Google Drive or whatever
you use, sharing it with the editor. And
that's kind of your routine now. That
sounds incredible. It's just it's just
funny that like I literally did
everything that is possible to eliminate
a lot of those steps. So things like the
lighting, the file management, like I
have automations that create the folder,
that move the files. So I have
automations that notify the editors as
soon as it's done. I've minimized it,
but it's still a lot. Only the good news
there too then is like that's great. So
this person's job is even simpler. It is
like and maybe you don't even need to
pay that much at all. Like maybe just
someone like literally just just to hang
out. Yeah. I think it's just also this
shift which everyone has to go through,
right? Of moving from being just like a
personal brand, which to me is like when
you are the creator behind it all and
often times like the jack of all trades
to moving and being like the CEO of a
media company. Yeah. like you have like
this like systems, automations, AI stuff
you deliver to your community of people
and then you have a media arm to what
you're doing.
>> Yeah.
>> You shouldn't be within the media arm.
You should sit above it as the CEO,
right? And you're directing the product
and you're directing the media company
and then you also have to be the on
camera talent.
>> But nothing more than that. Okay.
>> The second you start to find yourself
like editing videos, no, shooting
videos, no. Like you got to remove
yourself from all those aspects. Also,
because I'm sure we haven't talked about
the business end of all the stuff you're
doing. I'm sure you have like massive
aspirations there of like
>> doubling the business year over year or
whatever. That's going to be where your
attention needs to be,
>> not like shooting videos. And I think a
thing too for you just to reflect on
like after whatever is also like
>> like does the next like 10 years of your
life when you're filming on say
Wednesday, Thursday as an example, do
you want it to feel the way it feels
now? Hell no. Like does it need to?
>> That's the number one thing in my life
that that is
>> Yeah. And you've talked too about like
in the previous aspect like the real
luxuries in life like having a view and
all that like I think also like a luxury
is like being able to do work that feels
like play
>> right versus like having these aspects
that like you dread and all that when
it's like you don't need to do it like
that anymore like yes you needed to do
that maybe when you were first starting
to kind of get it up and going but like
you're way
>> maybe I'm stuck at that past that now
it's just the natural stage of like
again I think it's just the final strain
to kind of go okay now I'm ready to like
let this piece go too cuz you've let all
these other ones Yeah. And it feels like
I've let all of it go, but I I guess I
didn't didn't see see the full picture.
Okay.
>> Yeah. So I I got to say that that is
like a real unlock, man. Like that is
that is is like like a literal blind
spot that I I just didn't see which
aspect that I like I I I delegated and
systemized everything except of the part
that was still a part of my identity and
that's why I kept doing it but it was
holding me back.
>> Yeah. I think it's like a common thing,
right? Like I appreciate it. The thing
is like we all I think naturally have
like we didn't necessarily start what we
started to be like the CEO or be the
manager. No, we started what we started
cuz there was like probably part of the
craft
>> that we enjoyed whether that's like
shooting videos or for me like creating
different systems or creating the
content or whatever, right? But there's
a certain point where some of that
craftsmanship that we initially started
like we have to kind of rise above
certain aspects of it
>> if we hope to scale and also like enjoy
the real luxuries in life.
>> For sure. Okay, there we go. Nailed it.
Boom. Good [\h__\h] So, what's really
important to me in all these videos is
that you're actually able to go and
implement this stuff yourself, right?
Because going and learning a bunch of
stuff is neat, but honestly, what's more
cool and more rewarding for me and for
you is when you actually take action on
this stuff. And I get to see online all
the stories of all the momentum you guys
are building. And so to get maximum
momentum out of this video you're
watching right now, I went and created a
3 I3 method and gone and synthesized all
of what I just went through in an easy
to implement deck so you can go and do
it for yourself. So I'd recommend going
and getting that via the link in the
description. Go through this deck and
fill it out slide by slide. And then I'd
recommend that you go and book a meeting
with your team to go and run through
your different categories, formats, and
what you believe your unique perspective
is. From there, you and your squad can
go and formulate your own content
strategy, get more clarity, and make
your content operation more fun, more
peaceful, and that much more impactful.
So, go check that out in the description
and let's get