One decision today can knock [music]
down every obstacle in your way. Imagine
every second of your life is a domino.
Each domino is tipping the future in one
direction or [music] another. And here's
the crazy part. If you line them up
correctly, a single domino today can
unleash unstoppable momentum. So, here's
how to find your one domino. Ask these
[music] three questions. What's the one
bottleneck that slows everything else
down? What would make the biggest
difference if it were solved? And
[music] what enables everything else to
flow? When you go into any day, make
sure that you are clear on that one
domino you can complete [music]
that will make that day a success. As
Winston Churchill once said, "Perfection
is the enemy [music] of progress. Done
is better than perfect.