Right now, one of the most dominant
content formats on Instagram is also one
of the most underused. You scroll
Instagram, you've probably noticed
carousels. They're showing up more and
more across niches and across all
different styles and brands. They seem
to [music] work no matter who posts
them. Carousels alone have driven over
10 million views, 50,000 [music]
saves, and generated tens of thousands
of new followers for my Instagram
account, which is [music] about to cross
1 million followers. And you might think
it's the design or the aesthetic or just
great taste. But what most people don't
see is the amount of structure behind
those posts.
>> [music]
>> And more importantly, what those
carousels are actually doing when you're
not online. In this video, I'm going to
walk you through exactly how we build
our Instagram carousels. Not as simple
social posts, but as leveraged assets
that tell stories to deepen our brand,
provide [music] enormous value, and flex
our eye for design. We'll start with
four carousel styles we use, then move
on to the actual design process, and
finally, [music]
I'm going to show you why these
carousels keep performing weeks and
months after we post them. And here's
the thing most people get wrong. If you
only copy how this looks, well, it's not
going to work. So, let's get into it.
Section one, the four carousel styles.
So, I'm going to walk you through the
design workflow here, okay? But first,
you need to understand that we have four
different carousel styles, and each one
serves a specific purpose. We have
long-form carousels, white and paper
carousels, lifestyle carousels, and then
we have black carousels. Long-form
carousels are our newest addition.
They're mostly reflections,
philosophical content about things like
control, bottlenecks, freedom, and
overcoming perfectionism. It's content
that inspires action and sparks
reflection, but it doesn't drive to a
CTA. No sell, just pure vibes and
intention. [music]
White and paper carousels are our most
popular and highest-performing format.
Timeless, minimal, [music] clean,
precise taxing graphics, and a clear CTA
at the end. This is something I work
really hard with with Jan, the designer
on my team, um and you know, we take a
lot of pride
>> [music]
>> um in designing carousels and designing
really things across the whole brand,
right? That feel timeless, that feel
beautiful. Lifestyle carousels are
mostly iPhone shots.
>> [music]
>> So, behind-the-scenes moments,
whiteboard sessions, retreats, postcards
from trips. The purpose here is really
to inspire the lifestyle and the freedom
movement behind everything we do. You
know, really get to know me just as a
human, right? And so, I think that
vulnerability, right, is really
important, right? Showing you guys
what's going well, what's not going
well, talking to you guys about the
current things I'm thinking about, what
I'm reading. Um it's almost like kind of
character development, right? And I
think, you know, the whole point of
building a personal brand, right, is for
it to be personal. And then, [music]
we've got this black carousel format,
okay? These are our kind of joker cards,
right? We use them once or twice a
month. Candidly, these things take some
time because there's a lot of intention
that goes behind them. And we typically
will drive people to workshops or
founder retreats from these. They're
much more clean, they're
attention-grabbing, they've got that
minimal aesthetic that we really love
and um that, you know, we just think
encapsulates how we do things at the
brand. Each style really has its own
[music] job, right? And knowing which
one to use is half the battle. This is
usually the point where most people
realize they've been using the wrong
structure without even knowing it.
That's exactly why the carousel template
system exists. It will show you which
template is right for your content idea.
And if you want to apply this to your
own content, you can go and download
that exercise and fill it out right
after this video. Section two, copy the
design workflow. Let me show you the
actual design process from start all the
way to the finish line, all right? The
most important part is
the copy. We finalize the copy in a
Google Doc with the whole social team
before we ever move it over to Figma.
This is non-negotiable, right? Copy
first and design second. Once that's
done, it's time to make the copy come
alive with design in Figma. What we do
then is copy and paste each of these
pieces of copy over to the individual
slides in Figma, and then we go and
layout the CTA. And typically, these are
around 12 frames long. We want to make
sure every single slide is built for
shareability and inspiration, as well as
obviously giving an insane amount of
value. The first frame is the hook. It's
the most important one. We keep it
slightly bigger than the rest to really
go and grab your attention, right? Um
around, you know, an 80 to 120 font size
here because we want it to really stand
out, you know, as someone's going and
scrolling their Instagram home feed, we
want that slide to immediately capture
attention. If you can't hook someone on
the first slide, you're likely not going
to get them to read the rest of it. I
like to keep things really clean, the
font small, clean. I don't put too much
text on an individual slide because we
want to convey one message on one slide
and have it be stand-alone kind of value
so that someone would be willing to even
share the third or the seventh slide on
their Instagram story. That's the main
purpose of every slide, right? It's like
to be highly shareable, right? We want
people sharing this in the DMs, in
stories, and outside of Instagram to
signal to Instagram, "Okay,
this creator, this Mac Gray guy, these
guys know what the hell they're doing,
okay?" Often times what I see work here
is that the copy from, you know, X that
I see perform really well, or maybe it's
a LinkedIn hook that we've used to
generate millions of views, we'll then
go and give that a shot on Instagram as
well. What we're going to do now is go
and create um that framework in a more
detailed way um in the resource that we
go and give away inside of a playbook.
Once I've read through all the copy, I
start with a slide that inspired me the
most. In this case, it's the one that
says, "You make 300 plus micro decisions
per day, 90% don't move the needle, 10%
build empires. This gives us a clear
idea of how we can go and design
something using minimal and clean
graphic elements like dots and lines. I
go and I draft a circle. All the dots
represent the micro decisions keeping
90% of the dots one color and then
sprinkle a subtle color for 10% that
build empires. Now that color code tells
the story. I don't need more text. I
don't need more explanations. Then I can
draft graphics like this for every
single slide and then translate them
into the final slides. The core thing
here is to keep adding details that make
people want to swipe from one slide to
the next so they can reach the end which
has the most important part, the CTA or
the call to action. We have the CTA
here, right? We're driving people in
this case to this founder infrastructure
guide, right? We've got a little bit of
copy up top and then we've got the
mock-up there which again is using our
core color and then with the right
trigger word here. That word being
guide, nice, short and sweet driving
people then to the ManyChat automation,
right? Which is going to then compel
people to enter their email, get the
resource and then now they're also part
of our email flow. We're not just
growing an Instagram to grow a bunch of
followers here, right? We're trying to
actually go and monetize so we can
reinvest in people in our product and
likely as a founder in your own
lifestyle and goals you have for your
life, right? We want to go and be
insanely generous with the resources
that we give away to people on
Instagram. And the key key thing here
too is that those resources are
contextually relevant to the carousel
that someone's viewing. The carousel is
on deep work, you may want to go and
give someone a deep work checklist at
the end. You're not going to go and give
someone, you know, some, you know, call
to action to just join your newsletter
generically at the end of a carousel
around deep work, right? You can do
better than that. It's a clear framework
you can use every day. You know, we're
offering people these little playbooks
on every slide that they can save and
use everywhere. And once this is done, I
select everything, I export it, and then
it goes into our main drive. I can then
go and schedule this in Asana for a
social manager who's going to then
publish this on Instagram. And well,
that's the whole design process from
start to finish. But, we're not done.
When someone saves your carousel, that's
not just engagement. That's a signal to
Instagram that this content has lasting
value. When someone goes and shares that
to their story, Instagram's going to see
that as social proof that the content is
worth then distributing through the
algorithm. And so, when you're going and
generating all of these DMs from the
trigger words that drive people to the
lead magnet at the end of the carousel,
it's inherently going to make that given
post that much more viral. But, here's
the part where most people miss, right?
Carousels aren't just performing in the
moment. They're performing weeks and
months later. Because every time someone
new discovers your profile, they scroll
through your feed. And if you have a
valuable carousel that's timeless and
easy to save, they're going to engage
with it even if it's 6 months old,
right? Cuz the information is timeless.
One thing here, just to kind of go one
step further in the idea of being just
insanely generous with you, is to really
show you guys six of our best carousels
ever and give you just some quick
patterns I'm seeing across the best
carousels I've ever posted or that we've
ever posted as a team. Is I'm 35, if
you're in your 30s or 40s, read this.
One pattern we see a lot is using
numbers in that first slide. So, bring
that with you to your own niche and your
own brand. You can see here now, they're
very minimal, right? That white
background, little highlights over it,
right? And keeping everything nice and
chill, simple, and on brand, right?
[music] So, this post, as you can see
here, got over 25,000
likes. Same deal here, 9.5K likes. And
the cool thing here is that as people
swipe through, it gradually tells a
story. In this case, how people can go
and really get clear on their goals and
take action towards their long-term
vision, okay? Now, at the end of this,
we drive people to a workshop that I was
running, okay? And so, the workshop is a
systematized founder workshop, and so
when they go and enter in coffee in this
specific post, they go and get driven to
a link to join that monthly workshop I
was running um and go and learn how to
build their founder-led brand without
burning out. Core thing here is that,
you know, you're going to want to drive
people to the thing that's the logical
next step from, you know, Instagram. So,
you have Instagram being your rented
audience because you don't own it,
right? That's Mr. Zuck. But, you want to
drive them typically to some sort of
thing where you can own that member now,
which typically, my recommendation is
driving them to your email list, which
is going to allow you to build a
valuable, appreciating asset over time.
Now, this next one is how to set a
company strategy you'll actually use,
okay?
Pro tip here, I see how-to hooks
crank it. And how-tos are also so great,
not just for, you know, reach, but
typically, they also indicate
educational content that's also likely
to go and convert, right? Entertaining
content, while neat and all, just serves
dopamine, whereas educational content
often times drives people to actually
take action, which is what you need if
you're eventually hoping to monetize
their attention. You know, on this one,
the best founders do one thing
brilliantly, build systems that replace
them, okay? You can see that we're also
creating a lot of intrigue and curiosity
on that first slide. Every slide is
super simple. That's a tip [music] with
whatever you do is try to get, whether
it's the slides or your videos or
whatever, down to the most important
core concept, right? Simplicity wins.
Okay, in the last example here, same
deal, right? We're using a number,
right? We've got minimal, beautiful
design, right? And, you know, just
really helping people understand the
core tools to use to get ahead with AI.
And so,
these are the examples of some of the
best of the best ones. The benefit of
carousels, just like the benefit of
YouTube videos, right? Is that they keep
working [music] for you long-term.
Here's what I want you to take away from
this. What looks effortless is
structured. [music] You're not inventing
every time, you're executing. And if you
want the carousel templates that I used
here, you can go and download them via
the carousel template system. It helps
you select the right templates and
understand where content might be
misaligned. Step two is then bringing
that output into a call with my team so
we can pressure test your choice, your
ecosystem fit, and what you should stop
doing if you want that next level of
clarity. The link is below. Thanks for
watching and see you in the next one.