You know, the paradox of success is that
the less you chase it, the closer it
gets. You know, fortune is like a flirt.
The more you want something, the more it
evades you. But the more you just, you
know, do the work, you give yourself
time, you're patient, and you kind
[music] of just let things happen. It
seems like the faster things actually
happen for you. We live in a culture
that is addicted with results. I found
in my own life when I'm too focused on
the outcome, I feel this gap between
where I am now and where I'm looking to
go. So the thing that you can think
about here is to pick the one thing,
that one metric that you're going to
move forward day after day that ladders
up to the big ambitious vision that you
have. For me, that's creating
exceptional content every day. Uh the
metric is really the profit per piece of
content. And just [music] by focusing on
that core metric, making beautiful
systemized and sustainable content with
an amazing team and be able to ladder up
to this massive vision of having a
retreat center in the Doommites, but
it's [music] just one tiny action at a
time. pre- results like the side dish,
not the main