the reason most people don't succeed is
because they see failures as obstacles
instead of opportunities no matter what
you're doing you're going to make
mistakes but those failures are not
evidence of your own inadequacy they're
evidence of growth because you're doing
something you've never done before and
so there's a lot to learn most people's
greatest fear though is to discover that
they're fundamentally inadequate to
achieve their dreams that somehow their
imagination is more capable than they
are but the only fundamental inadequacy
is believing that failures are
indications that you should quit every
failure has a lesson to teach and all
you've got to do is listen