The next billion-dollar brands will look
like creators. And this is the biggest
opportunity that most people are
sleeping on. People are more skeptical
than ever. We live in a trust [music]
recession. People follow people than
they follow brands. And when you go and
you put your own founder brand out
there, you have the opportunity to go
and build trust. But the issue is too
many founders think they should just
hide behind the logo. And it was
probably one of the biggest missed
opportunities of my 20s, [music] right?
and is surely my biggest regret is not
starting my personal brand sooner.
Personal brand builds opportunities to
you, [music] helps you hire amazing
talent, helps you go and grow a loyal
client base. The leverage that it builds
is [music] second to none. And if you're
really going and hoping to separate
yourself and build a strong, formidable,
antifragile online business in 2026,
[music]
I don't think it's optional anymore to
go and build your founder and