It's actually pretty easy to build a
profitable personal brand that gets you
ahead of 99% of people. Most people stay
stuck with zero followers and zero
dollars. But I grew from zero to 2
million followers in 18 months and
[music] then built founder west over
700K per month and coach billiondoll
founders. And I've realized the
difference between a brand that pays
[music] and one that drains you is just
a couple key things. So today I'm
breaking down the five levers to build a
profitable personal brand that can
change your life. Let's get into it. And
as you're watching, I want you to think
about how this applies to your brand. I
put together a short personal brand
snapshot exercise that you can use after
this video to see which part of your
system is actually holding you back.
First, find your zone of brilliance.
This isn't some woowoo exercise. It's
the psychological foundation of every
profitable personal brand I've seen.
When I started thinking about my
personal brand, I wasn't clear on what
to focus on. I'd built BitMaker, a
coding school, then herb, my second
company. I knew systems. I knew scaling.
I knew content. But what should I
actually talk about? What would people
care about? These three circles help me
find the answer. When we talk about zone
of brilliance, often times it's just a
lot easier to go and draw this up so I
can illustrate it and it'll be ton more
easy for you to understand. What do
these three circles mean? So, first off,
we got, you know, what feels fun, right?
When you think about, you know, creating
content online, you want to make sure
that you're actually enjoying it because
if you're enjoying it, you're going to
stick with it. And like all great things
in life, the big returns come over the
long term. And so the next aspect here
is you want to think about, well, what
makes you money, right? Because you want
to go and be able to go and build, you
know, a team. You want to be able to
invest in your product and, you know,
you're going to want to have profits
that you can actually take as the
founder of the business as well. So the
next aspect here is that we want to
actually ask ourselves what do customers
want,
right? We want to go and make sure that
we're actually creating content very
similar to the products you're creating.
You want to make something that people
actually want, right? So that they're
often times pulling it from you. And
when you go and you think about really
nailing this right at the center here,
right, you get your zone of
brilliance.
So, grab a pen and paper right now. Draw
three overlapping circles. What I love,
what makes you money, and what customers
want. Fill each circle honestly, not
what sounds impressive, but what's
actually true. Then build your entire
brand around the center where all three
overlap. Next is to define your brand
DNA. This separates you from 10,000
other people who are in your niche. Your
brand DNA equals three things:
messaging, visuals, [music] and
positioning. And I'm going to go talk
through how I did this for my brand by
giving you guys an example. Let's start
with messaging. When I was 22, I was
working 15-hour days at BitMaker,
marketing, ops, sales, product, legal,
everything. I thought that's what it
took to build something real. Then at
Herb, I was still working like a
psychopath, making money but destroying
my nervous system in the process. That's
why my entire message now is about the
opposite. I'm obsessed with helping
founders build systems that let them
actually work less while making more
because I've lived the alternative and
it almost killed me. That's the core
message every piece of content ties back
to, right? It's the promise. More money,
less time, actual freedom. Next is your
visuals. I have a unique look across
every platform. Instagram, LinkedIn, X,
YouTube, you know it's me within 3
seconds. I care about elevated design
that feels cinematic. And I want clean
[music] graphics that respect my
audience's attention and cause them to
share with 20 people in their company
Slack. I want intentional shot choices,
not just talking heads. And I like to
treat content like mini films, not
disposable posts. Then there's my
positioning. I believe the future of
online business belongs to personal
brands that are systemized, profitable,
and beautiful. [music] Not one or two. I
mean all three. For me, you don't choose
between freedom and money, creativity
and systems. Making millions and
actually living your life. That's a
false choice, and I'm here to prove it.
Strong brand DNA creates instant
recognition and trust. Weak brand DNA
makes you forgettable. The psychology
behind it is that humans buy from people
they know, like, and trust. But in 2026,
that entire process happens in about 4
seconds of scrolling. [music] If your
messaging, visuals, and positioning
aren't clear, you lose. They scroll
past. You're invisible. So this week,
write down your thesis [music] in one
sentence. Then audit your last 10 posts.
Do they all tie back to that thesis? Or
are you just posting random tips, hoping
something sticks? If it's random, you
don't have a brand. You have a content
graveyard that makes zero money. This is
usually the moment where people realize,
"Okay, okay, I get the model, but I
don't know where I break." That's
exactly why you can go and download the
personal brand snapshot exercise link
below. It forces you to map your brand
across all five levers and exposes the
one constraint that you can't see from
[music] inside your own business. If
you're serious about fixing this, grab
it after this video. fill it out and
book a call with my team so we can go
and discuss the results you find. Now,
back to the third lever, the content
GPS. This is the infrastructure that
turns followers into dollars. You're not
broke because you don't have followers.
You're broke because you're missing the
middle layer that converts attention
into money. The content GPS has three
layers: rented audience, owned audience,
and monetized audience. So, here we've
got our rented audience. The key thing
here, right, is you're not Zuck, you're
not Musk, right? you don't own these
platforms. And so when you're solely
relying on, you know, your ex audience
or LinkedIn audience, you have something
called platform risk. You know, at any
moment you can just get rugpulled by the
platform. And you've heard this before,
right? That friend that lost their
Instagram page that they were working on
for years and then suddenly it was gone
and their business vanished, right? So,
what we want to make sure is here is
that as we're growing our rented
audience across these platforms first
off that you're diversifying the amount
of channels you're on, right? Cuz if
you're just relying on one platform,
well, you've got a lot of platform risk.
But if you're omniresent, let's say
across five platforms, that risk goes
way down. And [music] the other way then
to conquer that platform risk is then to
go and own your audience. And so [music]
when you think about owning your
audience, a key piece here are your call
to actions, right? So what you want to
be doing is having the right call to
actions in your content. Whether that's
in your YouTube descriptions like you'll
see right below this YouTube video or,
you know, at the end of X posts where
you're driving people to your newsletter
landing page. It could be at the end of
Instagram carousels where you're using a
core trigger word to drive people to a
many chat DM automation. or it's at the
end of your long form LinkedIn post.
[music] Okay, so those CTAs or call to
actions essentially go and catch the sea
of attention that you have out out
online and then drive those people to
your newsletter, right? And it's
statistically proven that your
newsletter converts 27 times better than
on social media. So now you've got the
CTAs going, but you're wondering, well,
how do I really convince people though
to go and want to click there? Well, the
killer flow here is making sure that you
also are giving away free lead magnets.
When you think about creating lead
magnets, you really want to make things
that are insanely generous, things that
people can't believe that you're giving
away for free so that they can't help
but go and join your email list. So,
enough about owned audience. Now, let's
now get into the monetized audience side
of things. Okay, so you can monetize
your audience in tons of different ways,
right? The key thing here is that you
want to make sure that you're driving
people then from your email list, right,
to actually going and driving them to
your product or service. [music] So,
typically, you know, as we go and look
at my own funnel inside a founder OS,
right, we'll go and drive people from my
email list to go and apply to Founder OS
if they want to go and get help from me
and get direct access to my team and
over 50 live sessions per [music] month.
From there, they seamlessly become a
customer. We onboard them in a
one-to-one call, have them join our
community, and from there they're part
of a robust community of amazing high
growth founders, and they're also coming
out to some of the in-person events that
we have globally as well. And so, when
you do this right, you're driving
results, you're driving recommendations,
and you're driving positive reviews. So,
as an example, you can go and check out
Founder OS on Trustpilot. We've got over
100 five-star reviews in just the last
couple years, and this is exactly what
you should be aiming for as well. Why?
Well, because when you nail this, you
create a profit flywheel. What happens
is all of these people are joyful.
They've gone through this amazing
experience that they go and tell their
friends. They go and ascend to other
products that you have, and you're able
to upsell them, thereby driving
additional customer lifetime value to
your business, be able to serve people
for decades, not just years. And
honestly, just build a business that
you're [\h__\h] proud of. Most people
skip layer two, right? They go from
follow me on Instagram straight to buy
my $2,000 course and then wonder why
their conversion is just 0.2%. You need
to move people from rented to own first
[music] and then on to monetization.
Number four, choose your distribution
strategy. Here's something most people
don't realize about personal brands.
Look at Tesla, about 24.6 million
followers on X. Look at Elon, over 231
million followers. That's 10x more. Same
company, same products, but people
follow the person, not the brand. CEOs
with personal brands are three times
more trusted than the companies they
run. This isn't opinion, it's data.
Here's what you can do to figure out
your distribution strategy. I'm going to
draw this out. And just to really help
you out, I want to show you exactly what
wins on each platform. Let me run you
through the platform decision tree. Here
we have you, okay? and you're confused
as to what platform you should go and
focus on. So, let me go and clear this
up and we're going to answer the
question pen versus camera. Okay, so
over here we have pen
and over here we have camera. Okay. If
you determine that you're more
comfortable with the good old pen,
writing out your thoughts, sharing your
ideas on pen, paper, well, then you're
probably going to go and enjoy platforms
like X and LinkedIn most. On the other
side of things, if you feel more natural
in front of the camera, you like sharing
videos and that side of things, well,
you guessed it, you're probably going to
go and get started on a platform like
Instagram, YouTube, or maybe on Tik Tok.
Now, it doesn't matter what platforms
you're on, okay? The key thing here is
that inevitably though, you must own
your audience. Okay? And that's where
doesn't matter what platforms, you're
always going to come back down to a
newsletter. Okay? So, you've gone
through the decision tree and now you
understand what platform is best suited
[music] to you. Great. Now, this next
piece of knowledge most people just
gatekeep this [\h__\h] but this is the
stuff that I wish someone had shown me a
few years ago when I got going building
my personal brand. What I want to give
you is the cheat sheet for each of the
core platforms. So, let's dive in. All
right, on X right now, what I'm seeing
working, and this is fresh off the
press, is that articles are absolutely
blowing up. So, what I'd suggest is that
you're posting two articles per week
using the article feature inside of X.
Now, from there, you want to make sure
that your content every single day has
curiositydriven CTAs below it that then
drive people to, you guessed it, your
newsletter. Now, you want to make sure
that you're also engaging with the
comments, right? Because this isn't just
about building some audience online,
right? You want to make sure that people
can feel the love and feel like they're
part of something bigger, [music] right?
And so, from there, I take my top
performing content on X and you guessed
it, right? We're also going and
repurposing that to other platforms. You
know, some of my best YouTube videos
were actually tweets that I just went
and expanded on. So, let's move on to
LinkedIn. LinkedIn probably drives about
45% of the leads to Founder OS. So,
honestly, probably one of the most
powerful platforms out there. And you
key thing here is you want to make sure
that you set up your profitable profile.
Okay. In your featured section, you want
to make sure that you go and you drive
people to your newsletter there using an
effective lead magnet. Okay. From there,
right, you're engaging with your
audience similar to X, right? and making
sure that you have all of your, you
know, profile set up in a good way, that
you have your right work experience, a
good cover photo, and you have multiple
links throughout it, including at the
end of each post, driving people to that
newsletter. Okay, let's move on to Tik
Tok and Instagram. Right here on Tik
Tok, you want to be posting daily, you
know, short form videos, right? That's
kind of a no-brainer. On Instagram, I
like to do one reel a day and one
carousel. Okay? At the end of each
carousel, we go and put a call to action
that leads people to a trigger word in
ManyHat. And in exchange for getting
their email there in my DMs, we go and
give them some free resource. Okay,
ManyHat is probably one of the most
powerful tools out there. And you
definitely want to make sure if you're
using Instagram, you get this set up.
So, YouTube, the mother of all
platforms. YouTube by far is my favorite
platform because you're able to go and
drive rich relationships with people
because it's audio, it's video, um, and
I think it's the best way to convey your
ideas. So, typically here, you know,
you'll hear people say, you know, you
got to upload every week. But I would
just say the best content strategy on
YouTube is the one that you can stick
with, number one, and secondly is the
one that can allow you to achieve the
quality bar that you're really after. I
found when I first got going on YouTube,
we were doing three a week. we couldn't
get the quality right and it didn't hit.
Suddenly I went and kind of reduced my
output to once a month and we really
leaned into quality and everything just
blew up. So don't feel like you need to
just do quantity quantity quantity at
the beginning. First focus on quality.
From there you want to go and utilize
your descriptions below each video to go
and drive people the core call to
actions you have. So, you can see below
this video, I'm driving people if
they're interested to join Founder OS or
giving you the free lead magnet, which
is the personal brand workbook that you
can go and leverage and go and steal all
the things I'm going over in this video
right now. So, from there, the core
thing though to really understand is
that 80% of the battle is your title and
thumbnail or what I call your packaging,
right? So, you want to make sure that
you nail those. From there, you want to
make sure that you have an insane value
per second, making it so insanely
valuable that people can't help but go
and share the video with five friends.
Okay? And then you want to make sure
that the first 30 seconds of your video
hook people and deliver on the promise
that was in your title and thumbnail.
So, you know, that is the cheat sheet
for these core platforms. You can go and
implement these today. Can't wait see
what you create. Number five, build your
offer stack. This is how you serve your
audience at every level and actually
make money. That taught me something
critical. Validate demand before you
build. Sell it, then create it. And once
you validate, you don't just need one
offer. You need a stack. You need three
offers that ascend people through your
personal brand universe. An entry-level
offer, core offer, and high ticket
offer. The psychology behind all of this
is people need small wins with you
before they trust you to then make
bigger investments. Entry offer is your
proof of concept. You know, this
person's actually legit. Core offer is
your transformation. This drastically
changed my business is what you'll hear
from people. And then high ticket is
your intimacy in speed. Like, I need
this right now and I want to be as close
to this human as possible. If you skip
straight to high ticket without entry
and core, you cut off around 95% of
potential customers. Your market is
tiny. If you only do entry level, you
leave millions on the table cuz you're
serving beginners forever. So, here's
exactly how to build your offer stack.
Step one, validate demand. Talk to 30
people in your audience and ask, "What's
your biggest problem with, you know,
insert your topic?" Ask, "If I solve
that completely, what would it be
worth?" Listen for patterns and language
they use. Step two, design your entry
offer. Take one specific problem and
solve it completely for someone in 7 to
14 days. package it as a PDF, a mini
course, or a checklist, and then price
it under $150. The goal is to have a
quick win that proves you're legit. Step
three, build your core offer. This is
your main transformation. This might
take 90 to 180 days to complete. Maybe
it's a curriculum, community, coaching
program. You want the price based on the
value created, not the time spent. Ask
yourself, if this gets my audience to
50K in results, what's a fair price for
me? Step four, create a high ticket
offer. Ask yourself, who needs speed and
personal access? What would a onetoone
with you unlock? You want to package
this as direct access, fast results, and
custom solutions. Price should feel
expensive, but obvious to the right
people. Don't over complicate it. Just
get clear on the stack and you can
refine as you go. Now, together, these
five levers work together as a system.
Building it alone can take many people,
tons of years of expensive trial and
error. So, if you're ready to build with
700 other founders doing it right now,
you can jump on a quick call with my
team at Founder OS at the link in the
description. This 15-minute call can
actually change your life. And now that
you've seen the system, step one is
completing the personal brand snapshot
exercise link below. And then step two
is bringing your completed exercise on a
short call with me and the founder S
team to help you go and build the system
to unlock the growth of your personal
brand. If you want to see how I built
systems so my business runs without me,
you can go and watch this next video.
I'll see you over there.