You want to treat your content like an
index fund, not day trading. Index
funds, they compound slowly, they're
reliable, and they actually make you
rich. The same is true with content. The
content that sells follows the SELL
formula, which stands for stories,
[music] educate, and list. Storytelling
is the number one vehicle for going and
conveying a certain lesson to people.
People don't recognize stuff if you're
just hammering them with facts. If you
tell a compelling personal story where
you learned a given lesson, this is
what's going to make your ideas so much
more sticky. E stands for educate. We're
trying to educate people, and I think
the number one format there are how-to
or how-I videos. [music] L stands for
list. Any piece of content that you're
going and putting out there, you just
want it to be a logical flow, so it's
not all over the place, and it's more
sequential, so it's easy for people to
understand and then go and implement.