All right, these are five decisions that
took me from $3 million to $12 million a
year over the last 9 years. So,
first things first,
cutting the team.
My second business, Herb, way too
bloated, getting all of the fat gone,
and moving the margin from 19% to above
55%.
From there, when I started Founder OS,
really focused on one key offer. You
only need one offer, right? It's super
amazing and sticky to get to a million
plus. And oftentimes just doing more of
the same to get to 5 million, 10
million.
Over the years, too,
escape the city,
move to Bali,
and
have a calendar that's mostly empty,
which just gives me time to create, and
inevitably I get paid
to make amazing content, to scheme and
plot,
um and to lead the team and make core
decisions.
Along the way, too, I've had to say no
to things, right? An example here,
saying no to a business that eventually
became a $200 million company because it
didn't fit in my calling in life. You
know, what brings me joy, what I love to
do, and what I'm great at. And I don't
regret a thing. And along the way,
realizing too
that having a regular content ritual to
build organic content, magnetize the
right people to my businesses is the
highest leverage thing I can do. Lead
first, build second.