I made 3.5 million last year for my
email list and today I'm going to give
you the blueprint this is how to create
a funnel it has three parts to it the
top of the funnel is your social media
following I grew my followers on
Instagram and Linkedin by focusing on
four content categories marketing
audience growth Community Building
Systems my insights are in these
categories and nothing else it helps my
audience stay engaged the middle of the
funnel is your email subscribers social
media serves one purpose to get your
followers on your email list my list is
where I drop value bombs the emails I
send out Target specific pain points and
provide insanely actionable content the
bottom of the funnel is your monetized
audience the email lift serves one
purpose selling your email subscribers
most people forget the middle of the
funnel instead you want your subscribers
to trust you so much they'll be willing
to buy anything you're selling test your
first funnel until it works like
clockwork this will become your welcome
sequence automate it and free up your
time to start building your next funnel