There are six AI skills that you can
learn in under 60 minutes that are the
difference between you making $10,000 a
month or $500,000 a month. These skills
took me from being trapped in my
business working 12-hour days to
building systems that work for me 24/7
so I can do what I want when I want. So,
let's get into it. This first skill
takes 10 minutes. Voice to text Mastery.
So, I'm going to go and give you here a
quick demo of Whisper Flow. Essentially,
what it is is it's going to be this
voiceto text AI tool that turns your
speech into clear, polished writing
every time. Now, polish is the key word
there. This doesn't just transcribe your
writing into a massive text block. It's
actually going to go and put it into
perfect paragraphs with immaculate
spelling. So, you don't need to touch
your keyboard anymore. You simply go and
press the function key in any chat
window and you can just go and voice
[snorts] whatever it is you want to
message and boom, it's going to
transcribe it so you can send it that
much faster. Another area where this is
useful is, you know, we had just gone
over those different cla projects. Okay,
I have one that's called clockwork which
is all set up to go and help my
businesses run like clockwork. And so
let's just say I'm looking to go and
tool up my chief of staff. So, what I'm
going to go put in here into my
Clockwork project, which is toolled up
with a bunch of data on my company, as
well as all of the core systems we've
created, I'm going to put, I've just
hired a chief of staff, and I'm looking
for this person to go and save me 20
hours of my time every single week. I
need you to go and structure the role
day by day from Monday to Friday as well
as the core tasks they need to get done
so that I have them going and blocking
tackling the most important stuff that
can relieve me of my time so I can focus
on strategy the founder experience and
making exceptional content. So as you
can see here it's gone and transcribed
all that instantly. And so when I'm
thinking about even prompting AI, the
best prompts number one are detailed and
they sound human, right? They're in your
voice. And so here you can see this
clockwork project plus, you know, that
simple prompt are now going and banging
out, you know, hour by hour from Monday
all the way through to Friday. the
things that my chief of staff can be
working on to help remove me from things
like hiring and, you know, offer
management, strategic partnerships, and
allow me to focus on the stuff that only
I can do in my zone of brilliance. Skill
number two, AI assisted content
creation. This is how you build your
prompt library in under 10 minutes and
make content five times faster every
single day. Let's get into how to go and
use AI as a brainstorming partner here.
Now, to be clear, you know, I don't
recommend that you just go and publish
AI content typically, just because
number one, it doesn't perform all that
well with the different algorithms. And
number two is that, you know, people
always need that kind of human element,
right? To really gravitate to your own
authenticity and your energy, which is
your uniqueness. So, what you're seeing
here is this 286 [music]
page prompt project. Okay? I can go and
take this YouTube prompt here, right,
which is around three pages long. And
I've gone and prompted this to be, you
know, better than the best experts ever.
And so the cool thing here is that
you're essentially getting, you know, a
$20,000 expert um for free inside of
Claude. So you can go and get this
entire YouTube script writing prompt. In
the first link in the description, I've
gone and given you a 1-hour AI playbook
so you can go and leverage all of the
different skills and that I've gone over
here and be able to quickly go and tool
yourself up for maximum efficiency. I'm
now going and pasting that entire
YouTube prompt into [music] the YouTube
script writing project inside of Claude.
I'm then going and uploading into the
project files all of the different
references. Right? So, I've got my top
three YouTube scripts ever inside of
that project knowledge. I've got
different transcripts from sales calls,
transcripts from coaching calls that
I've done. I've got my entire book
uploaded here, our customer avatar,
things like, you know, our different,
you know, offers and swipe files from
platforms like X, Instagram, and
LinkedIn. Just take whatever you've got
[music] and upload that to the project
knowledge so that Claude can start
writing like you speak. And so from
[music] here, I can then go and use
Whisper Flow to help be this
brainstorming partner for an upcoming
video that we're creating all along how
to create amazing hooks for [music]
YouTube. So, I'm creating a video around
how to create killer YouTube hooks. I
need you to go and flush out the [music]
potential hooks. Give me five different
hooks as well as 12 different aspects of
the video ranked from what feels most
retentive to least using [music] the
actual language and concepts. I've used
inside of the project knowledge. And so
we transcribe that using whisper flow
and then [music] let you know this
YouTube script writing prompt and
project inside of Claude be a
brainstorming partner for me. Now again,
I'm not using this verbatim. In fact,
you know, my YouTube videos are actually
just me riffing, right? There's no
script in front of me right now. That
[music] said, you know, the Super Bowl
is one in the preseason and killer
YouTube videos are one in the
preparation. And so what I'm able to do
here is essentially use Claude as this
sparring and brainstorming partner,
helping me come up with things like, you
know, the different structures of the
video, helping me research the stuff
that would probably be most retentive,
the stuff that you guys really need, so
that I can jam-pack each video with the
highest value per second possible to
make sure I'm being as generous as
possible in every single video we put
out every Tuesday and every Friday. And
this is exactly what we help founders
with as well inside of Founder OS,
helping them go and scale up their
personal media company, leveraging the
content GPS and content waterfall system
and making sure that every stage of
their content operation is powered by
AI. If this is something that's
interesting to you, you can definitely
go and check out Founder OS via the link
in the description. [music] So here we
can see Claude goes and powers, you
know, five different YouTube hook
options. From there, we can see kind of
like 12 different aspects of the video.
I'm not going to go and use all of
these, but you know, it's going to
remind me of things like, yeah, you
know, I should go and mention the
curiosity gap. You know, I definitely
want to make sure that people learn
about the importance of pattern
interrupts. And so, this will just serve
as this jump off point where I can use
these different aspects [music] as, you
know, inspiration for what I'm actually
going to go and riff on in a given
YouTube video. So, we just went through
a lot here, right? But you may be
thinking, you know, Matt, how do I even
go and create a given project for
YouTube scripts? Well, beyond the fact
that in the AI 1hour playbook, I've
given you the actual prompt in project
files that you should be using, um, let
me go and show you live how you could
just create any project from scratch.
So, we're going into a new chat here in
Claude. I can simply open up Whisper
Flow and say, I'm creating a new project
to go and help me write banger YouTube
scripts that are highly retentive and
appeal to a core, casual, and new
audience. I want [music] each script to
have a 70% retention rate by the end of
the video. I want it to be around 12
minutes 30 seconds long, which is
approximately 3,000 words. And I need
you to go and develop a YouTube script
writing prompt that I can go and upload
to the project instructions of a new
YouTube project um and be able to write
amazing scripts that have the shot at
getting over 5 million views.
>> [music]
>> In addition to that, I need you to then
below detail out the exact documents
that you think I need to upload to the
project knowledge to make sure that the
claude project has as much context
[music] on me, my voice, so that it's
able to write authentically. So, what
you're seeing here is there's no better
way to just go and tool up a Claude
project than just [music] by asking
Claude. So, now you can see Claude's
gone and outputed an entire YouTube
script writing project instructions
[music]
for itself. And so what I can do is then
simply go and copy all of this. And I
can go and copy this into a new project.
So we'll go and create a new project
here. We'll call it YouTube script
writer and we'll create the project.
We'll go to the project instructions
over here. Go and copy and paste that
entire prompt that Claude made. We'll
give that a quick edit to make sure it's
dialed. Save those instructions. And
then it's also gone and inside the chat
given me exactly what needs to be
included in the project as well. So
we'll go and follow its instructions to
[music] upload some files that I have on
my desktop. So now we've got the project
instructions toolled up, we've got the
project knowledge toolled up, and we can
just get ripping [music] with Claude as
our brainstorming partner. Skill number
three, building AI SOPs with Lumi. This
takes 10 minutes. Start the clock. say
that I want someone on my team to be
able to evolve our offers um and help me
go and create different offer stacks for
the things that we're building. Okay.
Well, here you can see I've gone and
created this overall deck um that gives
people an understanding of how our offer
pyramid works at Founder OS having an
entry- level offer, core offer, and high
ticket offer. Um and [music] I've
detailed out exactly how we do this and
the core elements of this system. Once
I've gone and recorded this 5 minute
Loom video, I can then go to generate
and in the settings of Loom, you can go
and click SOP here. So here you can see
what I love about this is it's giving
the key [music] steps. And what it's
doing is providing an image for each as
well as a few core bullet points so that
it's very easy for someone to then go
and execute [music] this stuff. And so
now you have the ability to go and
record the different tasks that you're
completing in a day all the way to, you
know, how you go and structure your
calendar to maybe how you answer emails,
how you evolve different strategic
partnerships, you name it. And you can
just record yourself doing these things
and then have Loom take care of all the
systems around this so you can move
faster, stay organized, and build
leverage across your team. Skill number
four, sales analysis. This takes 10
minutes. So let me show you some magic
here. when you're going and building,
you know, any business, you have, you
know, technically a group of like 20% of
your customers that are going to make up
around 80% of your revenue. And so what
you want to go and do is go and pay
attention to the sales calls that you
did to go and get those clients across
the line. go and get the transcript from
Fathom AI which should hook into your
Zoom so that any Zoom call where either
you or a salesperson on your team close
someone you're able to then go and
transcribe all of that. What I'll
typically go and do then is go and copy
and paste that entire Fathom AI
transcript of those top value calls and
go and paste those into a document. In
this case, I call it my velocity paid in
full deals because here's the deal. The
best copywriting is copywriting that
writes in the words of your actual dream
customer. This is a copywriting gold
mine. So, what I can simply go and do is
take all of this documentation, go to
file, download, and download all of this
to a PDF. Now, what I'll then do is go
and move this over to Claude. I have a
project here called voice of customer.
It has an abundance of the words of my
actual customers and I can leverage this
for different copy. [music]
So as an example here I can go and ask
this what are the top 10 problems that
my dream customer has in their own
words. Give me three phrases for each
problem so that I can then go and
leverage this for a new landing page I'm
making. So here we can see Claude's gone
and analyzed all of that documentation
and it's gone and pulled out these 10
core problems. So all of these core
phrases are exactly what we help people
with in founder OS. Skill number five,
datadriven decision-making. This takes
10 minutes. The goal of this is to have
a co-pilot that's helping me as almost
like a COO alongside me. Kind of like
the Robin to my Batman. And so [music]
inside of ChatBT, I have a project that
I call 10X Profits. Okay. In this
project, we have our project
instructions. and they essentially go
over, you know, you are the world's best
business coach and growth strategist
hired to help Matt Ray scale found from
$500,000 profit per month to $2 million
profit per month. Design and
continuously refine a roadmap that
increases Found profits by 5x in the
next 12 months. You will give Matt the
exact playbook to scale revenue, expand
margins, and simplify operations without
adding chaos. And so then I get into how
exactly I want to coach me by, you know,
identifying constraints, prioritizing
leverage, defining KPIs, and really
going and simulating the different moves
that I can make and making
recommendations. And so now that we have
that entire prompt toolled up, which by
the way, I've created a template of this
inside of the 1 hour AI growth playbook
in the link in the description, you can
then go and use this to help be your
strategic partner as you're scaling up
your business. Right? This is your
co-pilot. So then what I've done is then
and asked it to go and synthesize based
on all the product files I've uploaded.
I wanted to go and look at each document
and then go let me know the top 20
projects ranked from best and most
important to least important that I
should be focused on this year to finish
it strong. And so what it's then going
and doing is outputting all of the
ranked projects [music] that it believes
I should focus on. And so if you're just
beginning your journey, right, and say
you're looking to go and start a
business, oftentimes what I recommend
founders do is they think about starting
with what actually brings them joy. And
so here's an example of my icky guy
template um and my completed icky guy.
Now icky is a Japanese term that stands
for your reason for being, right? It
sits at the intersection of what you're
great at, what you love to do, what the
world needs, and what you can be paid
for. And so what you could go and do is
create your own project [music] inside
of chat GBT. Upload things like your
icky guy as well as the criteria that
you have for your next business. Say,
you know, I'm looking to go and
structure my YouTube team to get us to a
million subscribers next year. I could
go and ask this project now. [music] I'm
looking to go and structure a whole
video department to ensure that Founder
OS is set [music] to go and scale its
YouTube presence to a million
subscribers and hit that by December
31st, 2026. I want you to go and outline
where the team needs to evolve and the
different sort of goals I should have
from Q1 all the way to Q4 of 2026. And
[music] so what it's noticing is that
the number one bottleneck right now um
is postp production inconsistency and
its dependence on me at times. And so
what it's going to then get into is that
okay, the roles required by Q2. We need
to go and have a head of YouTube that
owns the entire YouTube P&L. We need to
have a lead editor. And the list goes on
here. Okay? And so it's kind of
outlining how the team needs developed
so that we can go and really have this
next like kind of 2.0 YouTube operation.
Now, it doesn't just stop there, right?
It also gets into the entire
pre-production system, how we need to go
and come up with 10 title variations,
five thumbnail concepts for every single
video as well as the post-production
system so that you know we have zero
errors, an abundance of packaging for
each concept and the right CTA driving
to Founderiz so that we can build this
profitable media company around our
YouTube presence. The even cooler part
of this whole project is when you have
ChatGBT Pro, you can hook up a given
project to your phone. [music] And on
ChatG on your phone, there's something
called Pulse, which is going to send you
daily updates around different moves you
can make to go and help accomplish the
goals of that project. And so I'm
getting these curated ideas on my phone.
And you know, instead of being in the
back of an Uber on the way to a meeting
and scrolling Instagram, instead I'm
going and scrolling through curated
ideas that can help me go and accelerate
my growth. I think that this is what
entrepreneurship looks like when you're
completely leveraged and using AI for
its full potential. Skill number six,
prompting and workflow [music] design.
This only takes you 10 minutes, but will
save you hours of time every single day.
First thing I did here is that, you
know, when I'm looking to go and build
an AI infrastructure in any of my
companies, I like [music] to first just
use a whiteboard and pen and paper. This
details out the Founder OS machine.
Founder OS is the high growth community
that I have of over 2,000 founders all
going and leveling up, removing
themselves from operations and building
AI powered teams. And so what I want to
do here first is map out every part of
the founder OS machine from audience to
inquiry to application all the way
through to then renewing people. From
there what I like to do is then go and
map it out on a whiteboard. You know too
many founders and high growth
individuals get right into AI thinking
that it's going to work all the magic
and remove them from having to think.
But [music] what you really want to do
is take things as far as you humanly
can. Right? getting it to 90% and then
let AI take it to 500%. After I've gone
and mapped this out on a whiteboard,
what becomes clear is the overall
systems infrastructure behind Founder
OS. And typically, this is how most
businesses look, right? There are seven
core stages to the customer journey. And
then each of those stages has
approximately three systems underneath
it that when you map out those 21
systems in a business, you now have the
overall machine of it and then can go
and transfer all of that to Claude or to
Chat GBT to help go and multiply your
infrastructure. Chat GBT I use as my
core business strategist. [music]
And for Claude I use this as like our
head of content. And so each project in
Claude, as you can see here, is
organized by
>> [music]
>> um content format. You know, we can use
this to help us go and evolve our
offers, help us dial in our viral
content engine, create things like
Instagram carousels, dial in market
research, or even go and create entire
email welcome sequences. And so when
you've gone and organized it like this,
I think the power of it is is that
you've got basically different content
specialists per project and you're able
to go and scale out, you know, your
content infrastructure. And the same
thing goes across your whole company.
Implementing AI across your team can be
intimidating. That's why when you join
Founder OS, it's not just you as a
founder, it's your entire team that gets
access to all of our projects and
systems so you can level up your entire
organization. So now you've gone and
completed six AI [music] skills in 60
minutes and you are leveraged as a
founder. I give you a breakdown of each
of these AI skills inside of my 1hour AI
growth playbook [music] via the link in
the description. Now, if you want to go
and further tool up your 10x profit
project, you can go and check out this
next [music] video to go and show how
I've gone ahead and accelerated my
growth even further.