Most people don't fall behind because
they work less. They fall behind because
effort was doing all the work. So, when
they slow down, output drops, things
then pile up, and life starts moving
faster around them. That's why work
less, live more sounds good in theory,
but almost never works [music] in
practice. It's not because people don't
want it badly enough, and it's not
because they lack discipline. It's
because nothing replaced the effort
[music] that they removed. Working less
only works when something else carries
the load. In this video, I'm going to
show you a system [music] that keeps
output high even when you step back.
this the work reduction system. It's
five rules that remove the exact
pressure [music] points that make work
expand and pull you back into
overworking yourself. Let's start with
the first one, the value test. Your days
feel full, but when you look back at the
end [music] of the week, you can't
actually figure out what you even
accomplished. That's because not all
work deserves equal energy. And most of
what feels urgent doesn't actually
create value. Every task you do falls
into three categories: creating value,
maintaining value, or draining value.
means the work moves something forward.
It builds, it sells, it improves, it
connects. This is the work that's going
to compound over time. Maintaining value
means the work keeping things running.
It's necessary, but it doesn't exactly
move the needle. It's the oil change,
not the road trip. Draining value means
the work that actively pulls you
backward. It's low-impact busy work that
feels productive, but leads nowhere.
Here's the problem. Most people treat
all three categories the same. Think
about Jeff Bezos as an example. He's got
this concept of one-way door decisions
or two-way door decisions. One-way door
decisions are the kind of decisions that
you make one time, and they're really
hard to reverse. Two-way door decisions
are those kind of decisions that you can
make a decision on it, you can always
change your mind tomorrow, and it's not
that big a deal. And the issue is that
most entrepreneurs think that every
decision is a one-way door decision, and
thereby, they think they need to be
involved in everything. You see, work
must earn its place. If it doesn't
create value or maintain something
essential, it should get removed. And
here's what nobody really tells you
about this. Removing low-value work,
it's not laziness. It's not avoidance.
It's the prerequisite for sustainable
output. Because, you know, if you're
spending energy on work that drains you,
you're not only wasting your time,
you're actively just making it harder to
do the work that actually matters.
Here's where most people get stuck.
[music] They remove the low-value work,
and then they're still overwhelmed.
Because removing work is only half the
battle, which brings us to rule number
two, the replacement law. Work doesn't
just disappear when you decide to do
less of it. It's going to persist. And
the reason it persists is because too
much depends on you personally. [music]
Most people try to eliminate
responsibilities, but that's not how
freedom works. Freedom comes from
redesigning where your work lives. So,
let's look at McDonald's as an example,
right? They famously made the creation
of a burger easy enough that teenagers
could go and get jobs at McDonald's and
complete this thing. By viewing it as a
step-by-step assembly line, where each
person specializes in a given part of
it, you can have a consistent burger
made wherever you go in the world. And
your business is not all that different
than this. You need to go and kind of
McDonaldize your given business, right?
By going and thinking about the core
steps that the customer goes through
when they work with you, right? All the
way from maybe hearing about you to
going and telling their friends. And
then making sure that that stuff is
systematized, that you have a systems
designer in charge of owning that given
area, so that you can remove yourself
from it and be the person that works
above the machine versus being lost
inside [music] of it. You see, right now
work lives in one of three places, in
your head, on your calendar, or inside
infrastructure. [music] When work lives
in your head, you're the only one who
can do it. You're the bottleneck. When
work lives on your calendar, you're
still doing it, but at least now it's
scheduled. It's visible, it's contained,
but the issue is it's still dependent on
your time. When work lives inside of
infrastructure, it runs without you.
It's a system, it's a process, it's
delegated, it's automated, it's
documented, and you're not trying to do
less, you're moving from everything
being in your head to everything
requiring your time to now the
infrastructure in place so that things
can get done without you. And the shift
here changes everything for you. When
you stop asking, "How do I eliminate
this?" and start asking, "Where should
this live?" the result [music] is that
everything gets easier. The goal is to
really redesign responsibility so that
stepping back doesn't cause everything
to break. This is how you remove system
dependence and how you move from being
the hero in your business to the actual
CEO. Before we go further, if you
already suspect that stepping back would
cause things to break, that's not a
character flaw. It's structural. I put
together a work reduction system
self-audit that maps these exact rules
onto your own work so you can see where
effort is still acting like the engine.
That link is below and you're going to
want to go and use that to go understand
the rules that are currently breaking in
your business. But, even as you start
removing low-value work and migrating
responsibilities, there's still one
hidden trap that most people fall into.
And it's the reason work never actually
ends, which brings us to rule three, the
finish line rule. When was the last time
you felt done? Not tired, not out of
time, like actually done. If you can't
remember, it's because you never defined
what done even looks like. Most people
operate without some clear finish line
in mind. They work until they're
exhausted, until the day ends, and they
just [music] keep repeating the cycle.
But, the thing is they never stop
because the work is never complete, and
[music] that is not sustainable. It's
mentally exhausting because your brain's
never actually able to shut off. The
finish line rule really says this, every
task needs a defined output, a standard
for good enough, and an explicit
stopping point. Because perfectionism
isn't the problem, an undefined output
is the problem. This is proven in
Parkinson's law, right? Work will expand
to the time that you give it. I know
this, right now I'm writing my book. I
found that, you know, if I give myself
two years to complete it, you know, I'll
just gradually chip away and it's going
to take that book two years to get
written. On the other side, you know,
right now I'm giving myself, "Hey, you 2
months, Matt. You got to get this damn
thing shipped." Peter Thiel famously
said, you know, "Take your 10-year
goals, and then go and get them done in
the next 6 months, right?" And this is
just an example of Parkinson's law
working its magic. Giving yourself a
clear deadline to get something done.
When you don't know what done looks
like, you keep polishing, you keep
tweaking, you keep second-guessing, and
the work never ends. [music] But, when
you define the finish line, something
shifts, right? You get permission to
stop, and that permission is
psychological relief. Clarity gives
permission to stop, [music] and stopping
is how you reclaim your life. But,
here's the thing, even when you define
the finish line, if your calendar
doesn't match your priorities, none of
this works, which brings us to rule
four, the calendar reality check. Your
calendar doesn't lie. You can tell
yourself you're focused on the right
things, but your calendar will always
tell the truth. Most people design their
calendars around coordination, meetings
and calls, check-ins and updates. Stop
trying to squeeze all your creation into
just as much and as little time as you
can, right? Because that's kind of
backwards. The calendar reality check is
really how you go and solve this. It's
going to invert [music] your calendar.
Creation comes first, coordination
second, reaction last. Block time for
founder flow before everything else.
Time where you can just go deep on a
task. Treat this like the most important
meeting you have, because [music] it
genuinely is. And then schedule whatever
you have around that, the calls,
the check-ins, the updates. They're not
the priority. And reaction, things like
email, Slack, emergencies. Try to cut as
much of that stuff as possible. Here's
why this really, really matters, okay?
Time design beats time management. You
can manage your time perfectly, right,
and still lose, because if you're just
reacting all day, and if you're
coordinating all day, you're not
actually creating. And creation is what
moves things forward. You go from
feeling constantly behind to finally
feeling in control, from feeling
reactive all the time to feeling
intentional. Even if you go and you
invert your calendar, even if you design
your days around creation, there's one
final rule that determines whether any
of this lasts, which brings us to rule
five. Longevity is the requirement. Most
people think ambition means intensity.
They think that success requires maximum
effort, maximum output. But that's not
ambition. That is burnout in the making.
Ambition isn't about how hard you can
push, it's about how long you can last.
And so, the only way to last, though, is
to choose a pace that you can sustain
for years, not just weeks. And so,
here's the question that really changes
everything. Could you keep doing this
for five years? You know, we can look at
longevity even outside of business,
right? When you look at Olympic athletes
that are training for, you know, the
100-meter dash, they're not running all
out 100-meter dashes every single day
for four years leading up to the
Olympics. It's about timing things. They
gradually kind of move up to peaking at
the actual Olympics themselves and
making sure that they're managing energy
along the way and managing their
training so that they're able to perform
at their best. And entrepreneurs in many
senses are like athletes. It's not just
about working full tilt every day.
Things like rest, rejuvenation, relaxing
are important so that you're able to be
at your peak when you need it, and then
able to kind of just stay grounded and
in your zone when you're not required to
work at that level. Because truthfully,
you know, it's not about sprinting every
day. It's about, you know, being at a
sustainable pace for the long term. You
know, if you find that you're working
12-hour days, if you're skipping meals,
if you're sacrificing your sleep, if
you're missing the things that actually
matter to you, you're not building a
business, you're building a timer until
just everything breaks. And when it
breaks, you don't just lose momentum,
you're going to lose years of your life.
So, the fifth rule, I think, is the most
important one. Choose a pace that
protects your health, your
relationships, and the enjoyment of the
work. Because success isn't extreme,
success is repeatable. And here's what
nobody tells you about working less. We
only get around 4,000 weeks on this
planet. Most people don't think about
that because most people are so busy
working, so busy reacting, so busy
trying to keep up that they forget that
life is short. You know, work design is
more than just business, right? We're
talking about lifestyle design here. At
the end of the day, you know, humans,
founders, you know, builders, we only
get one life to live and time is by far
our most valuable asset. You know, when
you think about Bronnie Ware and her
book, you know, the five regrets of the
dying, one of the main things that
people go and regret is that they worked
so much. When we're going and building,
right, we can get so passionate and
obsessive about what we're building that
we lose track of the things that
actually make life vibrant, you know,
the relationships that we have, playing,
adventure, you know, going and getting
outside and creating memories and
experiences that we'll always remember.
You know, I just want to say this to you
as a friendly reminder, right, just to
make sure that along the process of
building you don't, you know, lose track
of what's most important, which is
living. If this video helped you see why
working less has felt impossible, the
next step isn't trying harder to apply
it. It's understanding where your system
still depends on you. That's exactly
what the work reduction system
self-audit is for. You can go and fill
that out and if you want help
redesigning what it surfaces, book a
call and bring it with you. You can go
and book that call below. We'll get on a
conversation to help make all of these
learnings become real. And listen,
building like this, it's not meant to be
a solo game. And that's why I built
Founder OS. It's a community of people
that all believe that you can have a
vibrant life and a vibrant business. The
place where ambitious founders help each
other build systems that scale freedom,
not just revenue. We're a tight-knit
group that believes that we're stronger
together and that no founder lets
another founder fail. No fluff, just
founders [music] who actually build. You
get direct access to my team, the
systems we use to run multiple
eight-figure brands, and a community of
people who really embody the values I've
gone over here. This is interesting. You
can go and check it out via the link in
the description. And if you love this
video, you'd love this next video on how
you can go and build systems to work
less instead of working harder and get
really in the nitty-gritty of how to
build the most beautiful business in the
world. So, go check out this next video
and let's win together.