The richest man in Europe bought a
company that everyone thought was
finished, [music] but he turned it into
a $200 billion empire. In the 1980s,
Dior wasn't Dior. It was this wounded
animal limping around Paris, but there
was one man that saw the potential in
it, Bernard Arnault. Arnault had this
vision that Dior could be a part of this
stable of luxury brands, and he thought
that over the next 50 years, this luxury
brand portfolio could be [music]
something incredibly special. The thing
was, everyone thought he was but sure
enough in the 1980s [music] he acquired
Dior and over the last 40 years he's
gone and acquired 50 other luxury brands
and [music] turned it into a portfolio
worth over $200 billion.
And so, this is the thing, right?
There's not much of a line in the early
days of building something between
looking absolutely [music] crazy and
having a compelling vision.