Richard Nixon once said the unhappiest
people in the world are those in Palm
Beach drinking too much talking too much
thinking too little retired no purpose
it's possible to achieve greatly without
feeling great about it here are the four
Ps every business needs to avoid the pit
of despair people love who you work with
or don't work with them they should
challenge you inspire you and be fun to
work alongside purpose exist to help and
serve the best place to draw meaning is
from helping others passion don't just
be excited be thrilled push the
boundaries Excel push the limits beyond
what everyone thinks is possible Tim far
said excitement is the more practical
synonym for happiness and it is
precisely what you should strive to
chase profit make plenty of money spend
that money on things that are meaningful
to you travel eat great food help your
friends and family money is only
meaningful when it's used in a
meaningful way