All right, nobody talks about this, but
the cost of saying yes.
You know, saying yes
to that potential hire. Saying yes to
that opportunity. Saying yes to that
person that's outreaching to you asking
to go and pick your brain.
Saying yes to that coffee with some
stranger that wants to hang with you.
Saying yes
to
little things here and there that seem
innocent in the moment. But
when you stack it up, you realize that
every yes you say to one thing, you're
saying no to potential dreams, to plans,
to strategies that you've put down for
yourself that now you slowly are seeing
wither away.
You know, we live in a day and age of
distraction, right? Social media, email,
Slack, messages, notifications
everywhere. And if you're not careful,
you find yourself in some
you know,
stream of distractions that have led you
way off course in life. And so
you think about going and scaling as a
founder and just as any human, right? I
think the scarcest resource we have is
our focus. It's important to get clear
on what really matters to you. I like to
do this by entering every single week
with the 10 things
that I know will make that week
successful and then just going and doing
those things and intentionally and
politely saying no to any