In 2017, I was depressed, anxious,
and running a company I did not
want to run.
I had
been building Herb for a few years
and realized that I'd kind of built
myself my own prison.
Fast forward,
a mental breakdown,
anxiety attack,
and a lot of inner work.
I realized that I was guilty
of what I call or thinking.
You know, maybe I should have a great
business
or a great life. You know, maybe I could
build
a great team
or
you know, have
more time for breaks.
You know, maybe
I could
you know, build
a high-growth company
or
have something
that was fitting my lifestyle.
And it's this or thinking that drives
you into the ground.
What I'm passionate about these days is
and thinking. You can have a great
business and a great life.
You can
build something super impactful
and
you can take breaks, go on solo trips,
live life.
It's that and thinking [music] that
leads you to do what you really want and
think more abundantly. That's what I
would have
Woah. It's what I wish I knew
10 years earlier.