Discipline isn't about perfection. It's
about what you do after you [\h__\h] up.
Take the moon mission example. Apollo 9,
first mission to the moon, and about 90%
of the time they were off track. Just
like the moon mission, 97% of the time
you're going to also be off track.
Success, it's all about correction, not
perfection. Sure, you can have a bad
day, 2 days, a bad week, but don't give
yourself much more time than that. You
got to go and bounce back fast. The
biggest trap is this all or nothing
thinking. So, when you slip, and trust
me, you will because you're human,
immediately return to the smallest
version of that habit the next day. You
missed your workout, do 10 push-ups. You
skipped writing, write an intro
paragraph. You don't have to do an hour,
just do 10 minutes. Do five. Just break
the spiral. Trust me, this is one of the
biggest hacks you can do so that you
don't fall off the wagon, and you also
make it enjoyable to do the things that
your brain is trying to tell you are
really hard.