if you want to master something in your
life there's only two things you need
the first thing is time it's easy to
watch an expert and think I can never be
that good but shift your perspective
look at the number of hours months and
years they've put into becoming
excellent now you start to think I can
be that good if I put the same amount of
time into it and if you're asking how to
put that time into it the answer is deep
work choose one thing to master at a
time block out 4 hours a day put in the
Reps now comes the second part your
Learning System Mastery of a skill is
really Mastery of a series of smaller
skills put together so break it down
dominate one carefully crafted skill at
a time buy courses read books pay for
coaching and mentoring obsess until you
conquer each step of the staircase move
to the next one time and systems are the
key to mastering anything you want your
only limitation is choosing when to
start