Before you hire the next person to solve
a problem, there's a question you have
to ask. Can this be automated? I was
talking to Oren Hoffman a few years ago,
and he completely rewired how I think
about teams when he said something that
[music] stopped me cold and that I
haven't been able to shake it in my mind
since. He said, "Matt, hiring is a mark
of failure." I was like, "Failure?
Really? I thought, you know, hiring
meant you were growing and, you know, it
was great that you're adding to your
team." His point was this, [music]
right? If you're creating a new role, it
means you failed to automate it first.
Now, we're at an extraordinary
inflection point right now. AI tools can
handle engineering tasks, content
production, customer service workflows,
research, scheduling, distribution, and
virtually every piece of grunt work in
your business. The tools are there
today. Most founders just haven't
reorganized their thinking around them
yet. What Elon Musk does better than
almost any other operator is his
four-step algorithm for building
companies. And I think every founder
should have this in their [music] head.
Step one, you're going to find the
limiting constraint in the operation.
Step two [music] is to eliminate
everything unnecessary around it. Step
three is to simplify what remains down
to its most essential form. [music]
Step four is to automate what you can.
Only after all four steps would you ever
go and consider making that next new
hire.