If you want to reach peak performance,
you need to understand the Goldilock
skill. The Goldilocks effect is when
your brain works best in [music] just
the right zone. Not overwhelmed, not
bored, but stretch just enough so you
have to pay attention. You know what
you're really trying to do here, right,
is find that perfect zone where you're
stretching [music] yourself just a
little bit that you're challenging
yourself and you're growing, but it's
not so insanely [music] challenging,
right, that you're procrastinating on
it, right, because it's just way too
hard. In that case, [music] you likely
want to go and take the given task and
break it into smaller bits so you can
chew through all of it in that state
[music] of flow versus getting into a
massive amount of cognitive dissonance.
On the other side of things, if [music]
you find yourself just working on stuff
that anyone else could do, it's probably
a sign you should either be removing
that stuff from your plate [music] and
delegating it, right? So, there's this
perfect zone, right? little bit
challenging, but not too much that you
want to [music] be sticking in if you're
looking to really get ahead this