I learned something recently and it's
changing everything in the way I do goal
setting if you're looking to achieve
something amazing in 2025 this is for
you it's called anti-g goals the problem
most people have with setting goals is
focusing only on the outcome you create
a road map to get there but then you
face huge challenges along the way you
get burned out you don't have enough
energy you get distracted here's where
anti-g goals come in anti-g goals are
the things you don't want to happen as
you chase your dreams here's an example
I have some huge goals planned for 2025
I want to hit a million dollar a monthly
cash flow for my online Community
founder OS I want to grow my audience to
10 million I want to help a, Founders
hit a million dollars in Revenue by
using proven systems but I don't want
this to take over my life that's where
my anti goals for 2025 are no meetings
before noon no meetings longer than 30
minutes no more accepting negative
people around me my anti goals are
almost as important as the first set of
goals and they help me not only stay
motivated but never let success become a
source of stress and anxiety in my life