Here's why 90% of creators burn out
[music] and what the 10% do differently.
When I first committed to acts 5 years
ago, I had no idea what I was doing. I
had no editors, I had no social media
manager to start with, [music] and it
was just me out there in the wild
posting some stuff. It's at this stage,
right, that you start to get on a bit of
a hamster wheel. You don't really have
any systems in place, you're new [music]
to this thing, and what's inevitably
going to happen is the creator dip. This
is all part of the journey. The things
you want to start taking note of are,
you know, in those moments where you're
feeling some cognitive dissonance, some
[music] frustration, elements that
you're like, oh, I think this could be
better. Make note of those areas. These
are going to be areas that we're going
to want to systematize. We're going to
want to get ready to go and delegate
these areas so that long-term, we're not
just building content for 3 months,
right, that we've got a sustainable
system for 3 years. [music]