Every story that makes money follows the
same five line structure. Miss one line
and you'll lose the sale. Joseph
Campbell's The Hero with a Thousand
Faces analyzed myths all over the world.
He realized they all followed the same
structure, The Hero's Journey. Star
Wars, The Matrix, Harry Potter, every
story you love follows this arc. This is
why I use a five line framework for
business stories. Step one, the mirror.
You want them thinking, "Holy this
guy is literally reading my mind."
Example, you're stuck in Slack all day.
Message after message, the day ends and
you can't help but think to yourself,
"How long can I keep going like this?"
Step [music] two, the friction. You keep
missing your kids' birthdays, your
partner asks when things will slow down
and you have no good answer. Step three,
the realization. The problem isn't your
work ethic, it's that you are the
system.
>> [music]
>> Replace yourself with systems and
everything will accelerate. Step four,
the shift. I went from 15-hour days to
4-hour days, burnt out to energized, and
trapped to free. And [music] last, the
invitation. Most understand the
framework, but you still don't
understand where your story breaks.