I sold my first company and thought I
was free. 6 months later, I was building
my second company the exact same way.
Same 80our weeks, same stress, same
feeling like everything would collapse
if I wasn't there. I remember sitting in
my office at midnight thinking, "What
the hell am I doing? Why is this
business so dependent on me? I was
gaining weight. I felt depressed like a
shell of the person I used to be. And I
realized something terrifying. I was
going to spend the next 20 years of my
life exactly like this unless something
changed. That's when I had a
conversation with my friend Robbie that
saved my life. He looked at me and said,
"Dude, you keep building the same prison
over and over again." And he was right.
I wasn't building businesses. I was
building elaborate jobs that I couldn't
quit. But that conversation led me to
discover something I call the three S's.
Three simple shifts that transform me
from being owned by my business to
actually owning it. Now I wake up to
money being made while I sleep.
Obviously, not every day is huge. Some
are smaller than others. But here's what
matters. The business runs whether I'm
there or not. In 7 minutes, I'll show
you how to break the patterns that are
keeping you trapped. Even if you feel
stuck right now, even if you think your
situation is different, the cycle ends
today. Nine years ago, I was standing in
my bathroom at 2 a.m. after another
16-hour day. I had built a successful
business, but from the outside,
everything looked perfect. But inside, I
was dying. I realized I had created the
most sophisticated prison on Earth, and
I was both the prisoner and the warden.
That night, I made myself a promise.
Either figure out how to build a
business that runs without me or sell
everything and just go become a yoga
instructor in Bali or something. What
happened next changed everything. 99% of
entrepreneurs get this completely wrong.
They think the goal is to scale revenue.
Here's the truth. The goal is to scale
freedom. Let me tell you about David
coaching business. $300,000 a month.
Sounds amazing, right? When I got on a
call with him, first thing he said is,
"Matt, I'm trapped. I haven't taken a
real vacation in three years." David had
fallen into the founders's trap. High
revenue, zero freedom. He was the
bottleneck for everything. Every
decision, every client call, every
meeting. If David stopped, the business
stopped. Here's the crazy part. David
thought this was normal. But I had news
for David. Success isn't working in your
business. Success is working on your
business until it works without you.
Most founders build fragile empires.
Look strong outside, but depends
entirely on them showing up every day.
Smart founders build antifragile
empires. The difference? Fragile empires
break when you're not there. Antifragile
empires get stronger when you're not
there. Amazon doesn't need Bezos to
fulfill orders. Netflix doesn't need
Reed Hastings to stream movies. These
are anti-fragile systems. And you can
build one, too. There are three levels
of founder evolution. Level one, the
doer. You do everything yourself. Chief,
everything officer, proud of how hard
you work. Level two, the manager. You
hire people but manage everything. Every
meeting, every decision. You think
delegation means telling people what to
do. Level three, the architect. You
design systems that run without you. You
build a machine that creates predictable
outcomes whether you're there or not.
Most founders never make it past level
two. They get stuck managing instead of
architecting. The leap from level two to
level three isn't about working harder.
It's about thinking differently. And it
comes down to the 3S system. S number
one systems. Everything needs a system.
How do you onboard clients? System.
Handle complaints system. Create content
system. Hire someone system. I have 247
documented systems. You might think that
sounds like work, but you're already
doing these things. You're just doing
them in your head every single time.
Systems mean you think once, execute
forever. Example, I used to spend 3
hours every week writing the same email
to new clients. Three years, that's 468
hours of my life. Then I created a
system, wrote the perfect email once,
created a template, and then trained my
team. Now it's automatic. Haven't
written a client email in 2 years.
That's 312 hours back from one system. S
number two, structure. Most founders
hire randomly. They need help, post a
job, and then hope for the best. But
this is completely backwards. Don't hire
people and then figure out what they do.
Design structure first and then hire
people to fill it. This is org chart
first thinking. Draw your ideal org
chart 18 months from now, right? Every
role. And then ask yourself, what roles
am I going to go and fill in this
company? And I can't just do them all
myself because that's just a recipe for
exhaustion. fill just one role in your
company, CEO. S number three, standards.
Your team will never exceed your
standards. They will meet them. Low
standards equals low results. High
standards equals high results. But you
can't have high standards without high
systems and structure. You can't expect
10 out of 10 performance with five out
of 10 systems. The 3S system works like
this. Systems equal clarity on what to
do. Structure equals clarity on who does
it. And then standards equal clarity on
how well to do it. When you have all
three, magic happens. Your business runs
itself. Remember David? He went from
working 80 hours per week to 20. Took a
3-w week vacation to Japan. Business
grew while he was gone. 2 weeks ago, he
texted me from Thailand. Day 12 of
vacation. Just check the numbers. Best
month ever. That is an anti-fragile
empire. And it isn't just David.
Michelle went from 70hour weeks to
25-hour weeks while growing her
business. Not everyone gets results like
this, but the principle works. When you
build the right systems, you get your
time back. Whether your business grows
50% or 500%. This isn't about getting
rich quick. This is about getting your
life back. Building an anti-fragile
empire isn't easy. Most founders quit
after month one because it feels slow.
They want results in 30 days. But think
about it. How long did it take to build
your current business? Years, right? So
why would you expect to transform it in
just 30 days? Founders who succeed think
in 18 months cycles, not in just 18
days. Every hour invested in systems
gives back 10 hours later. short-term
pain, long-term freedom. They do the
work most founders won't.
Close your eyes. 18 months from now, you
wake up when you want, check your phone,
and your business made money while you
slept. Team is executing flawlessly
without you. And your systems are
running like clockwork. Complete freedom
to work on what energizes you. You
travel for a month. Your business
doesn't fall apart. time with people
that you actually love and projects that
actually matter. How does that feel?
That's not fantasy. That's what's
waiting on the other side of the 3S
system. But it's not going to happen by
accident. It won't happen because you're
smart. And it's not going to happen
because you work really hard. It only
happens if you decide it will. Then
commit to the work. Most people will
close this video, feel inspired for 3
minutes, and then go back to their old
ways. Keep trading time for money. Keep
being the bottleneck. Keep building
fragile empires. But 3% will be
different. You'll take action, build
systems, design structure, raise
standards. 18 months from now,
completely different life. Which group
are you in? The 97% who stay stuck or
the 3% who break free? Remember, you
started your business to gain freedom,
not lose it? The 3S system is how you
get that freedom back. Systems,
structure, standards. Your future self
will thank you. Welcome to the founder
freedom movement. Like and subscribe. If
you want to be part of a movement of
founders that are breaking free with the
three S's and taking control of their
lives, be sure to apply to Founder OS
via the link in description and let's
win Together.