Casey Neistat proves that consistency is
more important than perfection. Casey
Neistat went and filmed a vlog for 800
days straight, filming, editing, putting
the storytelling together every single
day in the same 24 hours that you and I
have. That is insane levels of
consistency. And here's the math behind
it all. If you go and you put in a 100
reps and with each one of those reps,
you get 10% better, you're 13,800
times better by that 100th rep. I know
when I first got started building my
personal brand, I just focused on
creating writing that I was proud of
1,000 times. You know, fast forward 1872
days later, I've created a brand that
has over 3 million people around it.
This is the magic of compounding.