here are five crazy facts about human
productivity that will make you rethink
your work schedule multitasking doesn't
exist in an 8h hour workday the average
person is productive for only 2 hours
and 53 minutes if you work for yourself
spend less time at the desk and more
time actually getting stuff done limit
yourself to 4 to 5 hours of deep focus
work per day research suggests that when
you get under 5 hours of sleep you
undermine your productivity by 29% the
best way to get great sleep is to create
a schedule go to bed at the same time
every night and wake up at the same time
every morning Mondays and Tuesdays are
the most productive weekdays frontload
your most important work to the
beginning of the week you'll get more
done and output better quality you can
Master any new skill with 1 hour a day
by dedicating 1 hour a day 7 hours a
week or 365 hours a year to self-study
within 3 to 5 years you'll be a master
apply these five facts to your life and
you'll get more done in less time than
99% of people