But what I want to show you here today
is the inside look at how I've gone and
scaled a high ticket offer to 100K plus
per month. I'm going to give you the
inside scoop, each phase of the five
phases that really matter to scale a
real high ticket offer. So this is you
over here, okay? And you're probably a
founder that's looking to scale your
offering without getting stuck in
fulfillment that's just draining your
energy. You probably want to scale your
distribution of content in a way that is
time efficient so you're not spending
hours and hours of your day writing. And
you probably want to go and actually
build a business that's based on organic
content, not just the ads hamster wheel
and ideally attracting amazing customers
that effortlessly enroll and so you can
spend more time working on the business
and not in it. This is the dream you're
after. But there's likely some problems
you're facing along the way if you're
watching this video. When I talk to
founders that are scaling to 100K per
month in their offer, first off, they're
having troubles connecting their high
ticket offer messaging and getting the
right audience on board. What ends up
happening is they attract the wrong
audience and then they're enrolling
people in their offer when they're not
even the right fit. So you end up then
taking on clients that shouldn't even be
in your offer. And this just leads to a
horrible fulfillment, a horrible
reputation, and honestly, a horrible
life. And what you end up finding as a
founder is that you're in the rat race.
And you know, as a founder, you don't
even have the time to support the
founders inside of your offer. So, this
is a recipe for disaster. And many of
you watching this are experiencing just
this right now. You know, looking
yourself in the mirror at night going,
"What am I doing?" You know, how do I
get this business to the next level? and
just finding like your mind is racing.
You're overwhelmed and not sure what the
best next move is. Well, the solution
I'm going to go over with you here in
this video is that we're going to go and
show you how to optimize your offer,
right? So, you can really get that
scalable offer that you're after. From
there, it's important that you're
actually aligning your brand positioning
with the offer and then your content
underneath that so that it's driving the
right people to you. The beautiful thing
is that when you're attracting the right
customer, you're able to make sure that
your fulfillment actually delivers on
that dream outcome for the right people.
And this inevitably allows you to get
your time back and enjoy your life. So,
I'm going to go and actually show you
how to do this by using Founder OS as an
example. Let's start with some
background here. You know what sucks
about most high ticket offers? Well,
first off, a lot of high ticket offers,
I don't know about you guys, but I've
been burned in the past. I remember
going and signing up for a high ticket
offer. I thought it was going to be
amazing. I was going to learn how to
sell from stage in this particular
example. And sure enough, I got going
and I started working with the founder
and I was just getting hit with
different links all the time, different
decks. It was chaos. I had no idea what
I was actually supposed to do. It was
unorganized. It was overwhelming. I
ended up getting out of that as soon as
I got in. This is not a unique
experience. I hear founders experiencing
this all the time. And so what we want
to make sure that you're constructing is
not an offer that sucks obviously. So
first off, most offers are chaotic and
they're unclear. Often times inside of
these offers, they are just hollow
inside. The founder actually hasn't done
the work to go and systemize their
business and how to actually go and
deliver an offer that's going to drive
real results for people. In addition to
that, often times there's zero
fulfillment, zero support, and you don't
actually get access to the founder or
creator behind it, which kind of sucks.
Lastly, it starts to feel grimy. There's
no real reputation. You just see bad
taste everywhere, and you start to
wonder like, does this person even have
good judgment? And when you sign up for
an offer like that as a customer, you
know, you end up looking around and
going, oh no. And the buyer's remorse
kicks in. And so when you think about
then creating a real high ticket offer,
you know, I'll give you an example of
then founder OS and how we think about
it. So first off, everything that we do
is systemized, simple, and repeatable,
right? Giving people proven, actionable
results that are actually going to get
them to where they're looking to go with
their brand at the end of the day,
right? People are looking to build
founder-ledd brands where they have a
personal media company around them.
Everything is delegated and systemized
in their company. they have the right
team in the right seats and they're able
to achieve founder freedom having time
freedom, location freedom, um, and
financial freedom. This is really what
it's all about, right? And this is why I
started and created Founder OS in the
first place, which I'll show you some of
the details here in just a second. Now,
further that, some important parts of a
real high ticket offer are getting
access not just to you, but likely the
team behind the scenes so they can learn
from the people that are actually
surrounding you. They want to get access
to you and you need to make sure that
people are getting real accountability,
right? You don't want to have people
that are inside of your high ticket
offer and they're going through things,
but then they start to meander, they get
lost, and they're not sure how to get
back on track. You know, 99% of success
on the fulfillment side is keeping
people accountable, making sure that
they're staying on track so that they
can hit what they're really after. So,
inside of Founder OS, as you'll see, I
am actually in Founders's corner, right?
This is my mission. This is what I'm
really in this for is to really help
founders where they are accomplish what
they're really after with their founder
brands and do it in a way that is
systemized, that's beautiful, and that's
scalable. And I've really done this,
right? I'm currently operating a
portfolio of companies that do over
$13.8 million a year. And it's all while
I get to travel the world and live my
dream life. And so my belief is that the
future of branding is founderled and
people will build brands that are
beautiful, thoughtful, intentional, and
that it's the founder and their
personality, their story that will
really lead the way. And so when we kind
of go and dive into the offer side,
okay, your offer is the foundation of
your real high ticket offer. And you
need to make sure that that offer is
repeatable, it's scalable, and that
you're actually enjoying it. So, one of
the main things that we help founders
with inside of Found is getting that
offer scalable and getting it right. You
want to be asking yourselves things
like, you know, what is your offer,
right? What's that core transformation
that you're driving people towards,
right? Who is your target customer? You
need to be crystal clear on this stuff.
You know, what problem are you solving,
right? What makes your solution
different than everyone else out there?
And then how will solving this problem
for your core customer impact their
life, impact their business, right? This
is going to then influence the kind of
content that you create to attract
people to your high ticket offer. And so
in addition to that, you want to think
of things like what's the cost of not
solving this problem? What price do you
plan to charge for your offer? As this
is key, I generally recommend that
founders have no more than two high
ticket offers. You know, I see people
with thousands of offers, sometimes
hundreds, and it's just a mess, right? I
think a lot of founders on average have
about 12 offers across their company.
And what it does is it creates like
decision paralysis for their core
customer because they don't know whether
to buy a $47 product, a $100 product, a
$5,000 product, a $10,000. It's just
overwhelming. And so I recommend that
you have no more than two. You keep it
simple. You have something that's
probably more super high ticket, say
around $20,000. And then you have
something that is high ticket around 5
to 10K. And that's it. Okay. Now, it's
going to depend on the niche and
everything you're in, but this is just a
good guideline to get going. So from
there, you want to think about, well,
what does success look like in 12 months
for the people that are joining your
high ticket offer? And then making sure
that your delivery, your fulfillment,
your service, your support, your
education, the systems all help to
deliver that core transformation. The
more clear you are on exactly where
you're trying to take that customer over
the course of working with you, the more
that you can reverse engineer that in
what you're building. And so you also
want to think about what are the biggest
challenges or bottlenecks, right, that
your core customer is facing right now.
And this is exactly what you want to
speak to then in the content which we'll
get to here just in a minute. Now I want
to show you me actually rolling up my
sleeves and helping a founder so you can
get a sense of how we help founders
really differentiate their offer. So
this is me helping Bobby take his offer
to the next level by having both an
amazing high ticket offer and an
ascension model that leads to his super
high ticket longer term offer. Here it
is. I raised the prices to 15K. So I'm
here we go. We're moving. But it's more
on the limiting belief, but it can be
nerve-wracking as you as you go. You
don't want to ruin the cash cow, but
also know that you need to be making
like more for what you're doing.
Exactly. I see so many authors and it
shocks me that they don't just create
content from their book afterwards. And
you wrote their whole book and now it's
like, listen guys, we're going to take
all the best content for this and we're
going to actually like help you sell
your book too. And like ghost writing is
like say 4 to 6K a month maybe like
depending on how you want to do it,
right? So, you have your front end
that's like 15 to 20K. Your back end
that's like 48K to to 72K. That'd be
wild. I mean, that'd be amazing. I love
where we're going with this. It makes it
feel so much better than me over
complicating with podcast and speaking
engagements. when I do this stuff,
especially with the offer that you have
right now, like the reason why I think
this offer that we're just cooking up
here, Bobby, is like really, really
powerful, is because you making your
social really good, and nailing your
strategy really good, and getting your
profile, your newsletter, all that.
People are going to want that. And so,
like, that is the sales to your authors.
So, it's cool because you just get paid
to like be really creative with your own
[\h__\h] Absolutely right. Exactly. That's
why I'm like, "Oh man, I really need to
get this together." And see what
happened was when I started like
reaching out to people cold, I saw that
they were going to my LinkedIn. I didn't
even have a LinkedIn and then also my
website. I was like, I need to get my
social proof going on. Now with this
backend offer coming, I'm like, I need
to make my own LinkedIn, you know, be
good. It's good. Yeah. Know, it'll get
you excited by it and I think it'll
really give you the juice you need to
like really get ripping. Exactly. Yeah.
Know, it just inspires me even more.
Build my own LinkedIn and and just have
that sole focus. Oh, I love it. Thank
you so much. you have my number, too, so
you can message me anytime and we'll
just go from there. Bobby, thank you so
much, Matt. Really appreciate it. Now
that you've gotten a bit clear on your
actual offer, right? You should go and
actually answer these questions, pause
this video, and write this down for what
you're building. You can go and actually
go and construct your brand positioning.
For me, I look at the brand positioning
formula. This is how I've always
constructed the brand positioning for
any business that I've created over the
last 15 years, building profitable
companies. So, first off, you want to go
and nail your thesis, okay? Which I'll
show you an example here in a second.
Secondly, you want to go and outline the
two to three things that then deliver on
that thesis. And third, you want to go
and outline your core mechanism that is
the best way to actually achieve your
thesis. So, an example here with founder
OS is that our brand positioning, right,
is that the best way to build an online
business is a personal brand. Secondly,
right, you need to build a personal
brand that is beautiful and systemized.
And the only way to build a sustainable
personal brand is with a content GPS
system with founder OS. This is our
brand positioning statement. And then
this goes and influences the kind of
content uh that we create. So we'll whip
over here. So when we're going and
building content GPS's inside of
founders businesses, in summary, it
consists of these four elements, right?
We're helping them set up their organic
content waterfall, making sure that they
have the right sales process, leaning
from platforms like YouTube X, LinkedIn,
Instagram, driving people to their core
offer, oftentimes setting up a sales
page, a VSSL, and making sure they have
the right call to actions across all
platforms. This then converts people to
the core offer that we're generally
helping founders build that scalable
offer inside of Founder OS. People come
to me all the time. They've got an offer
to about 80,000. Um, but that's not the
same offer and the same structure that's
going to get them to that next stage.
And often times there's parts of it that
are not scalable. There's parts of it
that are just draining the founders's
energy. They find themselves staying up
at night stressing because they want to
grow but the offer that they're sitting
on just will not allow them to do that
and it's not working right. It is just
not working. And
so one of the solutions to this is
getting your content right to make sure
that you're attracting the right people.
So the question to ask yourself when
you're creating your content is what's
the one thing that your core customer is
doing right now that's not working in
each area that your offer delivers on.
So for me as an example I asked myself
you know what is not working right now
for a founder when they're creating
organic content. And the answer to that
is they don't have it systemized. They
don't have a clear content strategy.
They're just putting content out there
sporadically. You know what's the one
thing that's holding them back from a
proper sales process? you know, they've
got a sales process that had worked so
far. They're deeply involved in it, but
they want to go and bring on a head of
sales. They want to find a more reliable
team. They want to close more
consistently versus being on this roller
coaster ride of revenue on the
conversion side, right? They're posting
content sporadically. They don't have
the right CTA set up. They don't have it
systemized so that leads sometimes come
in and then they dry up. and they're
tired of this roller coaster same thing
on the lead side of their business. And
lastly, on their offer, they're finding
that while it scaled them to around 80k
per month, it feels like if they were
doing that same offer at 250K per month,
it would break. And they're not sure
which part of that offer to fix. And
they need some support, some guidance,
and someone to actually be there to roll
up their sleeves to support them. This
is exactly what I talk about in my
content. You know, let me show you a
couple examples here. And so on
Instagram as an example, right? I know
that people have these sorts of problems
and these are the sort of issues that
are really paining my audience, right?
So I speak to these on Instagram, right?
This is some content around the truth
about pricing your high ticket offer,
right? People are trying to hit those
200k, 300k months, but they feel like
their pricing's off. And so in content,
I'll go and address those sorts of
problems to go and help attract people
to what I'm building and get them to
share this also with other founders they
know that may be experiencing these
exact issues. Similarly over here,
right, there's a lot of founders out
there like I'd identified that aren't
even using organic content. They've been
relying on ads, building their business
solely off of cold traffic. And it gets
exhausting, right? you're not actually
building an asset that's self-
sustaining around your business.
Instead, you're just relying on pumping
out ads. And I address this in a lot of
my content, speaking to those exact pain
points and problems that founders are
experiencing, right? So, when you go and
you put this sort of content out there,
it's almost like a bat symbol you're
shining into the air and you're
attracting people that have those exact
problems. And when you can speak to the
problem, to the pain that your core
customer is going through in your
content, you're going to attract people
that want your help solving just that.
So very key there. Okay. So you may be
saying, "I don't really know how to go
and even create the content. You know,
Matt, I'm not sure even what the
problems are with my core audience."
Well, the cool thing is you can survey
your audience. You can survey your dream
customers. You can survey your existing
customers. So this is an example here of
a type form survey I've put out. Right?
So at Founder OS, right, we're trying to
create the greatest founder community of
the 21st century. And so you can go and
ask your core customers things like, you
know, what challenge in your business
right now is costing you the most money.
Then go and tally up all of those
different survey responses and look for
the patterns. You know, for me, I see
people that are struggling with ads
right now and it's cost them a ton of
money. I see people making the wrong
hire and it's costing them a ton. I see
founders that are really looking to
systemize their business but are
struggling to set up those systems and
find themselves being the chief
everything officer, not the actual CEO.
And so what we want to do is help people
run a more zen business. So all of the
content that you'll see across all of my
social platforms, whether it's LinkedIn,
you know, on YouTube, on Instagram, they
speak to these core pain points. So if
we look on YouTube here, you can look at
some of my recent videos. I've gone and
put out content that really helps folks
like the top 1% of CEOs really go and
systemize their businesses or helping
people find new ways to go and drive
their audience from organic to actual
paying customers. Similarly, I show
actual coaching sessions that I'm having
with founders like Lincoln here um who
is a founder inside of Founder S+ so
people can see a behind-the-scenes look
at what it actually looks like to work
with me in Founder OS. And so the
content and the purpose of the content
is to speak to the problems and to the
pain points of your core customer and
what they are experiencing right now and
then kind of usher them into working
with you by really showing that you have
a deep understanding of those problems.
Okay, that is the key. So as we go here,
there are core CTAs that you'll see in
all of my content. So here's an example
at the bottom of a YouTube video. you'll
see and have the opportunity to go and
apply to Founder OS or join my
newsletter. And so you'll see that
actually underneath this video as well.
If what I'm going over here sounds
interesting to you and you're interested
getting my help, my team's help in
scaling your business, go and check out
that link below. Um, we'll get on a call
with you, learn what you're really
trying to do with your brand and help
you get there. So, all of those links
lead to either my newsletter or directly
to an apply page to apply to Founder OS.
So people join my newsletter, right?
This is key because then I actually own
my audience. I'm not relying solely on
social platforms. I actually have an
email list that I own and that I
control. From there, we can drive people
in our emails to core CTAs. And those
CTAs generally go to founder
OS.com/training. This page has a VSSL on
it. And that VSSL gives people an
understanding of how it works, what we
do, and it really gives people an
impression of, you know, what Founder OS
is really all about. Now, inside of
that, there's an application. If we deem
that someone's qualified through the
automations inside of that application,
we then allow them to book a time with
me or with my team. On those calls, we
get to know them, you know, what they're
really after, and we try to assess if
it's a good fit to work with us. So when
it comes in, this is a small part, but
this is a big thing. The beauty is a lot
of founders don't have any funnels or
email automation set up. And so
depending on the different pieces of the
application, we go and grade different
folks that come through that application
and determine their fit for Founder OS.
And if you're building a real high
ticket offer, you need to make sure that
you have your email automations set up
like this. So we have things like
application pages, right, with abandon
application emails that go out if
someone abandons the application. We
have our book a call page and different
flows there that drive people to the
call. And then also if they abandon a
call or don't show, we have email
automations that go out around that. And
what these are essentially ensuring is
that your funnel is tight because if
you're running something, right, you
know that leads are valuable, right?
when you're building organic content,
when you're running ads, you want to
make sure that you're not wasting leads.
And a lot of people have a messy funnel.
It's all over the place. They can't
measure the conversion rates. They don't
know what metrics to track. They're
really confused at the breakage points
along the way. And if you don't have the
right sequences and tracking in place,
you are just going to be bleeding cash
flows and leaving so much money on the
table. And so what you can see here is
that I have inside of each of my offers
a core sequence of emails that go out to
make sure that we're not only capturing
leads over here and then ushering them
through the funnel, but also when they
are onboarded, we have a whole sequence
of emails go to make sure that they can
find their way around the systems, the
curriculum, the support that we offer
inside of Founder OS. Okay. And so we
have things like emails around their
accountability calls. We have emails
around different roadmap calls we do um
and making sure that every step of the
way um they're being notified not only
by a founder success manager that we
have on our team who's working with them
onetoone to give them the support, the
guidance um the implementation that they
need to take their brand, their content,
their personal media company to the next
level. Uh but we also have these emails
um so that you know they're being hit up
across multiple platforms by the FSM on
Zoom. They're hearing from the FSM in
onetoone in Slack and then they're also
getting emails that are automated
depending on the stage that they're at.
So this sort of email sequence funnel is
really important. Okay, it's going to
allow you to make sure that you're
getting the most from the leads and the
traffic that you're driving to your
business. Now, as we continue to
progress here, this all feeds into your
sales pitch because when you're creating
the right content that speaks to the
actual pain points that your dream
customer has right now, you're
attracting the right people. And you
don't need to force these people to work
with you, they're begging to work with
you, right? And so after you've done
your discovery, you know, on a sales
call, learning more about what their
desire is, their pain point, their
doubt, their cost, from there, you're
going to go and obviously transition
after about 20 minutes of discovery to
your actual pitch. So in our case,
right, our pitch at Founder OS is all
around helping folks with their content
GPS, getting their positioning right,
helping them with scroll stopping
content, and then setting up that
content GPS in their business. From
there, we really saw the fact that
people get access to me and a dedicated
founder success manager. Right? This is
what I've been doing for the last 15
years, growing brands solely from
organic content. My passion is really
helping other founders with just that.
Getting their content right, growing on
social platforms, getting the CTAs right
to drive people to sales calls, making
sure their positioning is right so they
can scale their business the same way
that we've scaled our business at
Founder US and that I've scaled multiple
other businesses like BitMaker as well
as Herb. And so the main goal that we're
setting up for founders and that our
content drives founders to us with is
that founders want to come to us to
build their personal media company.
Okay? And so we have the systems, we
have the support, the access to me that
helps founders go and get their writer
in place, get a social manager, really
learn how to structure their team so
they can remove themselves from the
operations and work on the business, not
inside it all the time. And this is what
I think most founders are really after.
You know, I know that I've been building
businesses all along to get freedom. You
know, I want to travel. I want to go to
Bali, Japan, Colombia. That's what it's
all about. And so for us, you know, we
set up these sort of systems. We help
embed hires into companies um so that
people can go and get that level of
peace of mind. Now, here's an example of
someone named Lisa that I've helped with
over the last year do just this and hear
what she has to say. Anything else,
y'all? But I just want to say thanks to
you, we have our ops manager. Judging by
the energy and tone of your voice, it's
you sound much more peaceful and more
relaxed doing their job. So we've had
four VAS, but I had become the ops
manager, which was just um taking me
away from
everything that I love to do. I mean,
I'm a good events manager. I'm a good
ops manager, but you know, really I just
want to be teaching and writing. And so
anyway, every day I'm like, thank God
for Matt because that the process inside
Founder OS uh of that that onboarding
process, the I mean even even just
getting really clear on what we needed
and who we needed it to be um was really
invaluable. So I just want to say that
out loud. It's made a huge difference
and um I would encourage anyone who's
teetering on that do I invest in someone
that greatly. Um I think it's yeah it
was has been a really great move for us.
All right. So we've covered a little bit
on optimizing your offer, your brand
positioning and your content. But let's
get to the real belly of the beast. It's
fulfillment which is a big piece of
things. And so your fulfillment is key.
This is where most high ticket offers
fall apart. People start marketing it,
making content for it. It's all over the
place and the fulfillment is a disaster.
And not just for your customer, but for
you as a founder, right? You are just a
sloppy mess to be honest. And so there
are four aspects to fulfillment that
most people talk about, right? It's
things like access to you as the founder
and your team. It's community and
experiences. It's the education and the
systems you have behind the scene. and
then support. But I actually like to
break this out into two separate
diamonds, which we'll get into. Here on
the left side here, you have things like
systems, experiences, access, and
support. And then over here, you have
things like your intention, your
reputation, your taste, and your
leadership. So, let's start with the
left here. Okay, the left here
represents more the hard skills and the
hard aspect of fulfillment, right? The
core things that you're going to deliver
on. And so let's get into it here. With
Founder OS as an example, we're helping
people build what I believe is the most
beautiful business model in the world.
How I classify everything that I do in
business. It really has to achieve these
17 criteria. I want it to be peaceful,
right? So I want to have a team that's
being retained for three plus years. I
don't want to have any refunds around my
business. I want it to be fun to deliver
on and have a fun team around me. I want
each part of my business to be a hell
yes. I want the entire model to be
insanely simple, right? Simplicity is
the ultimate form of sophistication. I
want it to be easy to sell, right? The
offer has to be so good that someone
can't help but buy. I want there to be
amazing longevity with what I'm
building, right? I see too many founders
that are doing something that they can't
even imagine themselves doing it two
years later because they're burning
theirel out and they just hate it, but
they're just doing it for the money
today. The truth is though, building a
business, you know, it really happens
over the long term. And you got to make
sure, in my opinion, that you're making
decisions that you can actually see
yourself doing for the next 10 years,
not just the next 10 months. In addition
to that, I like to build businesses that
generate endless referrals and endless
positive reviews. Right? You can
actually go and check out our Trust
Pilot over here, and you can see all the
amazing reviews that we're generating
every single day. you know, whether it's
via Trustpilot or via software like
Testimonial.TTO, it's important that
you're building a business that people
are raving about because people don't
buy what you sell, they buy what other
people want to buy. In addition to that,
you want to make sure that each part of
what you're doing is scalable, right?
That you're not just building something
that you can only sell 10 of. Because if
you have goals of getting to 100K plus
per month, you need to make sure that
what you're building is scalable and
repeatable. In addition to that, one
thing I'm big on is that you have a
viral loop that as you get more people
in what you're doing, they're sharing it
on social, they're telling their
friends. So, you're generating an
enormous amount of business through word
of mouth. In addition to that, I want to
be working with people I love. So, you
know, in Founder OS, we give people
access to the same people I work with,
right? And allow them to go and bring
these people onto their businesses. And
a key thing is that you don't just want
great people. You want to work with
people that you actually enjoy working
with so that your work feels like play,
you know, at the end of the day, you
want to make sure that you're loving the
customer, right? Because if you're going
to business every day and you just dread
going and serving someone, you know,
that's a horrible business to be in.
Okay? You want to build something that
you're proud of, that you can work from
anywhere, that feels easy. So, I think
when you've gone and you've achieved,
you know, these 17 criteria, you know,
you've really achieved this beautiful
business. And so these are the sort of
systems that we help people go and set
up. Helping them get the right traffic
to their business. Making sure that they
have all of their web pages optimized to
actually convert that traffic to sales
calls or directly to product sales.
Making sure they have their product
suite up and running. They have the
right content GPS system going proper.
So in our case at Founder OS, we have a
thesis video, an apply page, and then
two products that we offer. Right? This
is what I recommend for most founders.
and we help founders set up this same
sort of system in their business. You
then need to make sure that you have the
right team in place, right? The truth is
that most founders don't just want to be
building a personal brand. You want to
be building a personal media company.
And so this means that you have core
weapons across each area of your
business. So you're not doing everything
yourself, right? It's exhausting when
you're growing a business. And if you're
the chief everything officer, then sure
enough, one day you're just going to
quit. you're gonna pack it in because
you can't keep operating like that long
term. And so a key part is not just the
systems that we deliver inside of this
real high ticket offer. It's also the
talent that we help connect people with
so that they can build their beautiful
business. And so as we work through
this, this is exactly what we deliver
inside of Founder OS. So when you go and
look here inside of the Founder OS Plus
online community, we have, you know,
founders constantly sharing their wins.
You know, you can see people hitting new
revenue milestones, starting on social
platforms and scaling them at record
speed, them going and keeping each other
accountable, attending the different
experiences that we have around the
world like, you know, Bali and Mexico
City, Sedona, and really going and
supporting one another. You know, our
belief inside of the founder US
community is that we are stronger
together. And so, it's founders
supporting one another, building their
online businesses, and building founder
brands. Now, a big part of this is also
having the right systems in place. And
so inside of founder s I give people all
the core systems that I've used to scale
my empires. And so inside of this you
see you know as an example how to go and
scale your own personal media company.
So I have short videos here that
describe how I structure my team, how I
hire writers, how I hire a social media
manager, how I bring on chief of staffs
that go and manage my calendar and all
the different special projects that we
have going on. how I hire designers,
closers, setters, copywriters, and not
only do we show people how to go and
hire for these roles, we help them with
their onboarding and help them connect
with the right talent. So again, that
these founders are able to set up their
own personal media companies. A key
thing that when you're building your own
real high ticket offer, right, is that
you need to make sure that you have a
core mechanism. When you have the right
mechanism, right, that really
encapsulates what your ideal customer is
truly trying to accomplish, that
mechanism then helps you go and attract
people that are actually aligned with
what you offer. So, your messaging
becomes aligned with the right audience.
You're enrolling people who are actually
an amazing fit for what you do. You
start taking on clients that you
genuinely want to serve. You then have
fulfillment that overdelivers, right?
Because that mechanism truly helps
people with that painoint solve their
problem and achieve a solution that they
really need. And what this gives you
time to do is actually just enjoy life
and focus on the parts that you love
because you have the right people coming
to you from the right content finding
the right solution and it all just runs
peacefully. This is I think what most
founders are after and this um is really
what we help people with inside of
founder OS. So for me as an example, our
core mechanism is called the content
GPS. The content GPS is the most
powerful system I've ever discovered to
drive people from a personal media
company across platforms like X,
LinkedIn, YouTube, Instagram, Tik Tok,
and drive those people to your owned
audience. Whether that's in your email
list, text messages, right? You can go
and then drive people from those owned
platforms, your email list and text
message to then driving those people to
hot leads, going and converting them to
your offer mostly during sales calls and
then having those people become loyal
customers that then are telling their
friends and it creates this founder
flywheel in your business where you have
the right customer coming in getting
insane value from what you offer, going
and telling more people because they
were so blown away from your overd
delivery of what they were expecting.
and they go tell their friends because
they were so impressed. When you have
this flywheel in your business, you have
a real high ticket offer. And so for me,
the content GPS really works in any
niche, right? We help people that are in
coaching, courses, you know, agency
owners, ecom, SAS, consulting, it
doesn't matter. For us, our core thing
is that we're helping people again with
their founder brand, with organic
content, setting up their own personal
media company, and systemizing it along
the way so they can work on their
business and not in it. That's how we
position what we are doing. We're not
trying to do everything to everyone,
right? We really focus on that zone of
genius, this bundle of stuff that I've
really perfected of 15 years building
strictly organic audiences. And if
founders want that, we work with them.
If founders don't want that, we say no.
And that's a key aspect, right? You need
to make sure that you're clear on what
you do do and what you don't do. You
know, for me, I know that if you're just
looking for some quick get money scheme,
you know, this is not for you. I know
that if people are questioning the value
of a brand, then the content GPS is not
for them. Similarly, if they're not
looking for a proven system, they just
want to wing it on their own, then we
turn those people away. But on the other
side of things, if they're looking for a
proven system, if they're looking for
real support, if they want to make an
actual impact and stop being so stuck in
their business and have the ability to
work on their business, then the content
GPS and what we've got going on over
here at Founder OS is right for you. So,
let's get into the support side of
things. Support and every high ticket
offer will look different. I think you
want to make sure that you are actually
delivering though on the level of
accountability, the level of onetoone
interaction that people need to feel
like you really have their back. So
inside of Founder OS, we give people
access um to our founder success
managers via Slack. Um I'm there and
even giving my WhatsApp to many
founders, helping them via there and
then also on school. And so to give you
a sense, you know, this is school. You
can see all of the different messages
that I'm getting from founders every
day. Okay. And I'm in here all day, you
know, every day, um, checking this
multiple times, making sure that
founders are taken care of because we
genuinely care about helping people hit
their goals. Inside of this, people are
asking me questions about scaling their
YouTube. Here, you can actually see Olly
um is asking if I want to go and meet up
with them here in Brooklyn, so we'll go
hang with him. You know, you want to
make sure that the support that you're
offering uh really delivers on what
people are really coming to you for,
which oftentimes isn't just the
education, it's the community. It's the
access to you, the proximity to you as
the founder, the creator of the high
ticket offer. I wake up every morning, I
check the messages I've gotten from
founders. I go and make sure uh that I'm
giving founders the support that they
really need um so that they're getting
to actually interact with me as the
creator of this because I think that's
important, right? And so I'm going and
making sure that people are scaling
their YouTube right. I'll even review
people's YouTube videos to make sure
that their scripting is right, their
titles, their thumbnails. So I'm getting
my hands dirty helping founders scale
their businesses inside of Founder OS,
which I think is super important. So
when it comes to other access, right,
you want to go and think about what is
your offer really going to hang its hat
on. So for Founder OS as an example, we
go and give you direct access to me and
my team so you're never stuck, never
alone, and always supported as you build
your systemized, scalable founder brand.
This is the level of service that we
pride ourselves on in Founder OS. And so
everything that we offer inside of the
delivery side of Founder OS must deliver
on that core delivery mission statement.
Too many founders overpromise and
underdel with their high ticket offer.
And while that might be good for a
couple months, the word gets out
eventually and people get upset, right?
You need to make sure that you are overd
delivering, that you're building
something with integrity, with a great
reputation. This is what it's all about,
right? Is building something you're
actually proud of. And so inside of
Founder OS, we give people access to
mentorship sessions with me where I'm
covering things like, you know, how to
create your content calendar, how to
delegate, how to create funnel maps, how
to film yourself, how to write online.
I'm actually giving demos of exactly how
I do these things and then answering
questions multiple times a week from the
community live on these calls. Here you
can go see a couple clips of exactly
what those look like. What I try to do
is I try
to always think about like what hires
can I make that are just such a
no-brainer that at the minimum these
people are worth what I'm paying for
them. This is like this delegation math
system, right? Say I'm looking to bring
on a social media manager as an example.
Say the social media manager is going to
save me 20 hours a week initially or 80
hours a month. I put 80 hours there
because that's a time saved per month.
Then it's okay. Well, what's my hourly
rate as a CEO? Well, let's just say
early on I could get on sales calls and
say I'm Adrian, right? He's going to go,
let's just say he was selling his thing
for 5,000 bucks. The margin's 50%, the
revenue he could generate an hour is
5,000 bucks. Now, the cost of the new
hire for a social media manager, let's
say it's 8,000 bucks. And some of you
guys may say, "I get someone so much
cheaper." But let's just use 8,000 for
the example here, right? Cuz we want a
real weapon, someone insanely talented.
80 hours saved a month. He's going to
reallocate that time to being a uh to
selling these people into his program.
The cost to hire is 8,000 bucks. So, the
revenue per month of that reallocated
time, right, is those 80 hours times
5,000, which equals 400,000. Say his
profit margin was 50%. His profit on
that's like 200 grand. His profit after
the higher 200 grand minus the 8K is
192K. So his return on the $8,000 is
24x. Now let's just say Adrian's like,
"Bullshit, man. I'm not spending that
much time on sales calls." Well, let's
just say he even spent a quarter of that
on sales calls. He was on 20 hours of
sales calls in the month because he's
now free from doing social media stuff.
He still generates a 5x return on that
hire. To be clear here, guys, in this
example, all I'm filling in is the
yellow spaces. And if you know the
yellow, the rest just calculates itself.
When it comes to support, there are many
ways that you can offer support inside
of your high ticket offer fulfillment.
Oneto ones, messaging, group calls,
in-person support, or even things like
customer success managers. In our case,
we call them founder success advisors.
These are folks that are rolling up
their sleeve on onetoone calls and in
onetoone Slack support with founders,
helping them scale their own personal
media empire. Now go and check out my
good friend Sean, one of the founder
success adviserss here at founder us
actually helping a real founder with
their business system scale better the
people how can I build my marketing my
messaging everything so that if I had to
do this without a sales call like how
would I get them so convinced and that's
just a good frame of reference where
then eventually like if you think about
like that then your marketing is
covering like all of this space then
when you plug people into it so you plug
your closer. It means that your hiring
that you do going forward is you don't
actually have to rely on talent as much.
You just have to rely on like good
scripting and basically giving people
just layups like all the time. That will
scale so much better if you can kind of
think about it. Super valuable. So I
totally agree. When you're trying to
overd deliver, you want to go and think
about all of the intricacies that are
going to go and help your core customer
get to what they're really trying to do.
And so for us, a big thing that founders
are looking to do is go and scale their
own personal media company. So we go and
help them with access to people like
copywriters, uh, engineers, social
writers for X and LinkedIn, a chief of
staff so they can go and delegate more
of their operations, an executive
assistant so they can buy more of their
time back. people like long form video
editors and short form video editors to
scale on platforms like Instagram and on
YouTube, YouTube producers, YouTube
script writers as they're looking to
scale their YouTube engine and also
people like newsletter writers so that
as you're going to go and own more of
your audience, often times founders
don't want to be doing all of their
email writing themselves and so we'll
connect them with reliable talent that
way. In addition to that, right, we have
daily instructor sessions with my team.
These are the exact people that have
gone and helped me scale my own personal
media company. And so people don't only
get access to me twice per week inside
of Found OS, they also get access to my
team of legends. What I call this is
really thinking about going and
opensourcing your team. Right? You've
got a team of weapons likely in your
business that could spend part of their
time actually delivering the growth that
you're after in your company, but then
also going and providing some value by
teaching for maybe an hour, two a week
with the people that you're serving.
That way you don't need to go and scale
your headcount a bunch and can run a
lean mean empire. You know, I even have
my COO at times getting on calls with
founders to help them go and scale up
their systems. Here you can go and see a
couple clips from Dawn, the COO on my
team, helping founders and blowing some
minds. How valuable was this last hour
to you? Probably the most valuable I've
had all all of my life to be fair. I
know that this is something I've been
missing. But it's like your community or
like people that understand and how you
think and where you're you're at. That
was a big thing in my head and the
selling point for this. It was you guys
are doing it. You're where I want to be.
So you're the advice I want to be
taking. In addition to that, right, we
have the digital community side of
things inside of Found where founders
are sharing wins, supporting one
another, helping people with the
intricacies of scaling founder brands.
And then we have these epic experiences
that we run all over the world in
Austin, in Mexico City, and in Sedona.
Next one is in Bali. You're definitely
going to want to check that out. Here's
what founders are saying about our
experiences. I would highly recommend
Matt's Grace Mastermind to really any
founder of a group like this. You know
that they're going to draw individuals
that have that same passion for what
they do. It just makes you desire to be
the best at what you do, even if others
are in a completely different field. If
you come to a founder OS retreat, you're
going to leave refreshed. You're going
to have new friendships, a network of
people. I know that whenever the founder
and puts an event together, it's going
to attract really high caliber people
and they're the people I want to be
around. So, as you're going and
delivering on the fulfillment side of
your company, you want to make sure that
you've systemized your fulfillment from
front to back so that over the course of
the entire duration that someone's with
you, their mind is blown and they are
incredibly satisfied and happy that they
made the decision to work with you. So,
let me show you what this looks like. So
inside of Founder us, one of the key
people that we help is a time optimizer.
A founder that's looking to get more of
their time back so they can have more
freedom in life. So these are people
that are looking to free up their time
by installing systems that remove
themselves from daily operations. And so
oftentimes the goals of these folks are
things like freeing up 20 hours per week
by optimizing their time management.
They want to implement core systems to
remove operational bottlenecks. They
want to be able to create a 4-hour
workday structure for themselves and be
able to delegate tasks effectively to
key hires and then automate their
workflows to maintain efficiency while
they're scaling. But the challenges that
we find a lot of these folks are
experiencing is that they're constantly
overwhelmed by day-to-day tasks. They're
struggling to delegate without losing
quality and they're unclear on how to
structure a lean but efficient team.
This causes them to really get caught up
in things like reactive work instead of
the strategic growth that they really
need to be doing and they don't really
have a clear execution plan for how to
automate and scale their business. And
so the key aha moments that we help
people with is showing them that they
don't need to do everything right. Time
really isn't their problem. It's their
lack of systems that are holding them
back. And in order to delegate, they
need the right systems. They need the
right onboarding. and they need to
obviously be sourcing the right talent
that can actually relieve them of their
workload. But when they're able to do
this, they can focus on much higher
level tasks that are going to give them
more leverage and help them truly
experience the growth that they're
really after. In addition to that, you
know, scaling starts to become a thing
that they don't need to work harder,
right? They really just need to design
smarter workflows. And we help them on
the ground floor design these workflows
inside of their businesses. And so to do
this right, we help people with their
time audit system. We help them delegate
and create systems. We help them set up
their personal media company, right? So
that these folks can go and over 30, you
know, 60 and 90 days achieve the level
of delegation they're after, go and
construct their personal media company,
become an actual CEO that has a peaceful
operation around them versus being lost
and burnt out. and then helping them
achieve core wins like getting more of
their time back, running a lean, mean,
effective team, um, and reducing their
workload as well. Now, our goal with all
of this is that we're helping founders
so much that they can't help but share
their experience and tell more friends.
And so, we include exactly, you know,
the kind of result that we're looking to
drive founders to. And so, that all of
the founder success managers on my team
are effectively aiming at getting a
founder to say something like this. you
know, I just cut my work hours by 40% in
60 days thanks to the systems I
installed with Founder OS. If you're
tired of working non-stop, you need
this. So, we want to go and reverse
engineer that sort of statement from
someone inside of Founder S because
they're so satisfied with how we're
doing things. From there, we've even
mapped out the ideal testimonial that we
want people saying when they're inside
of Founder OS. You know, I learned this
from Jeff Bezos. You know, whenever they
go and launch a new product, they start
with the press release. So they're
basically starting with the end in mind
and knowing how do they want, you know,
the press to talk about this product
when it's launched and then they go and
reverse engineer that exact product, you
know, that they've written about. And so
the same thing goes here. We are writing
the testimonial before a founder has
even joined us so that we can then
reverse engineer that exact emotional
state and satisfaction uh that we're
trying to get someone to. And so inside
of this then all of our coaching, all of
the proactive consulting that we're
doing with founders um is really helping
achieve that founders's core goal. And
so we've mapped that out from front to
back. And this is what we do with things
like our time audit and helping them set
up their own personal media company. So
I can show you here, you know, this is
the time audit system. We help founders
go and audit their time, their schedule
over the past month so they can see what
they've really been dedicating their
time to. The core thing is that the
devil's in the details. And if you're
looking to gain more time freedom, you
need to look at where you're actually
spending your time. From there, we go
and fill out this time audit system so
that a founder can get clarity on, you
know, where are they spending their
meetings, who on their team is requiring
the most management, what are the areas
of their business that they should be
getting off their plate because it's
lower than their true hourly rate. So,
when you have clarity around where
you're spending your time, you're able
to delegate the stuff that you should
not be worrying about. You can eliminate
stuff that you shouldn't be doing in the
first place. and then automating pieces
of the business that some tech could do
much better than you. So, the time audit
system is just one of 180 systems that
we can help founders with inside of
Founder OS. And the cool thing is that
we're not making founders do all this
stuff. We're going to work on the right
system at the right time so it's not
overwhelming. That's why we have the
founder success advisors that are
essentially guides while a founder is
inside of Founder OS. As we go and then
think about the softer side of things, I
like to think about too when you're
building a real high ticket offer, you
need to nail, you know, what is your
true intention here? What is your
reputation that will support your high
ticket offer and the brand you're
creating? How does your taste really
exemplify and build trust with people?
And then how do you show that you're a
real leader in the space? Because I
don't think it's just about having the
hard skills. It's also about having the
brand match. When you look at the high
ticket space, I think 99% of the space
just looks sketchy, right? There's a lot
of messy brands, founders that have no
idea what they're doing, um, and, you
know, a lot of dicey things. And so, you
want to make sure first off that you
have the right reputation and that your
brand online exemplifies that. So, here
you can see, you know, a bunch of
amazing testimonials that we've gotten
around Founder OS. Um, you can check out
our trust pilot to see tons of those.
And we're really big about helping
founders really go and build their own
personal media company. And there's tons
of examples of founders going and saying
how much what we've done inside of
founder us has really changed their
life. Here's just a few examples. With
the help of my success coach, we've been
able to craft a higher ticket offer,
create it into an agency, and now our
biggest problem is we can't handle the
leads. He definitely has the business
acumen, but he also shares content
around the well-being of founders. I've
worked with other CEOs and founders and
coaches and gurus, and it's always been
so aggressive. And Matt and his team,
everybody is just so aligned, so
soulful, but everyone is creating
creating monetary results as well.
beyond your reputation, right? You
really want to be thinking too about,
you know, what's your intention and
making sure that people understand why
you actually went and built your offer
in the first place. Now, I talk a lot
online about how a number of years ago I
discovered my icky guy, that my calling
in life, why I actually exist here on
earth. And for me it was things like
building systems, helping founders with
distribution on day one, helping them
build a team of A players in their
business and really viewing
entrepreneurship as this soulful
journey. This opportunity to build, you
know, a peaceful life, a peaceful
empire, a peaceful team, have fun
building cool things um with people that
you actually enjoy. This intention is
really exemplified not just in how I
deliver the offer. It's exemplified in
all of my content in the travels that I
have and sharing my journey and giving
people behind the scenes of what I'm up
to, the good, the bad, what's working,
what's not working, the playbooks, the
systems, the stories. You know, I try to
just be an open book and open source
everything that I've learned. And from
doing this, I'm really exemplifying to
people that, you know, my intentions
here are pure. You know, I genuinely
wake up to serve founders, to help them
systemize their businesses, and to be
able to build personal media companies
that help them go and attract leads
through organic traffic, not having to
rely on paid ads or having to get lost
on some content hamster wheel. So, this
is why I actually built my offer. And
I'm curious, you know, why did you build
your offer? You want to make sure that
you're going and telling that story,
telling your mission, your vision, your
why, so you're attracting people that
are really called to work with someone
just like you. So don't lose track of
that. Your intentions matter. In
addition, something I don't think that
gets talked about enough is taste,
right? Taste, I think, is the ultimate
competitive advantage. You know, there's
a lot of people in the high ticket space
that when you look at their website, you
look at their content, it's salesy. You
know, it's kind of gross. And you have
an opportunity to really separate
yourself from the pack by creating
content that is genuinely beautiful and
that's tasteful because I think beauty
exemplifies the level of attention to
detail um and your own intentions behind
why you created something. If someone
can create a thoughtful brand, chances
are they can also probably create a
thoughtful product, a thoughtful
service, right? Your brand matters. You
know, every decision that we make at
Founder S is brand first. We will always
think about the brand reputation and the
longevity of the brand over everything
because without a brand I believe that
we are nothing. So you can see this
across all platforms whether it's like
Instagram you know the content that we
create is beautiful you know it's dialed
in. We're making sure that our content
displays the real core sentiments of the
brand that you know we stand for freedom
in creating this aspirational brand
almost like what Apple has done for
creatives what Nike has done for
athletes we're trying to do for founders
you know in addition to that I'm giving
people behind the scenes at how we do
things letting them to see behind the
scenes of different coaching sessions
with founders inside of OS plus and so
if they feel like they really resonate
with what I'm putting out there they're
going to join us and join the movement
in addition to that like I've mentioned
mentioned, I go and make sure the
content is really hitting the nail on
the head in terms of the actual problems
that my core customer is having. And I
don't just go and put this out in a way
that feels like garbage, right? We're
putting a lot of intention behind this
into the design, the copywriting, the
look and feel of it so that we're
breeding confidence in the end consumer
versus making them confused. Because the
truth is, when you put stuff out there
that's confusing or gross, you build
anxiety in the end consumer. And when
you build anxiety, they're just going to
close their wallets and they will not
have confidence in what you're building.
So, as you see here, it's not just on,
you know, Instagram, it's also in all of
my LinkedIn content, right? So, we're
going and putting out content that is
unique, that speaks directly to the end
consumer, helping them with the problems
we know they have, and helping them take
their business, their empire to the next
level. We come up with different formats
that are new, that are different because
I'm not looking to be better than other
people. I want to be different. Right?
We want to show people that our mission
is different. We want to show people
that our intentions are different, that
our design is different, that our brand
it's different. We're not like everyone
else you see out there, right? We are
actually about helping you. Um, and
about creating something that's
enduring, not just for a year from now
or two years. I want to do this until I
die. Um, and I'm passionate about
genuinely serving the founders um that
we work with. And so taste, I think, is
a big thing. It's not just about
building leadership through your
content, but it's also what people are
seeing in and around your brand. And so
I want to show you some examples of
this. Here's one clip of me actually
going and helping Ali Abdal with his
content and helping him get his business
to $5 million a year. What do you think
are the chances that this will work?
100%. Really? Yeah. Damn. 100% this
works. Like there's nothing. I need to
move to Dubai and hang out with you guys
more. If this actually works, then like
the fact that we've documented this
whole process, it will work. It's going
to be so sick. When this works, it will
be sick. It will be absolutely sick. And
over here, you're going to see another
clip of me actually having Horoszi on my
podcast to jam around the future of
personal brands. I think we live in a
totally different day and age now.
There's a lot of people out there that
just can't see the ROI to this. Like,
why am I doing this? And I lose all my
privacy. I lose all this. Like, and what
for? Right off the bat, I don't think
everyone should be famous. I don't think
everyone should build a personal brand.
I don't think everyone should anything.
You can do whatever you want. I do think
that from a money-making perspective, it
is a it is a time warp. You can just go
way faster. Mhm. And just one more
example here is I actually flew out to
Idaho recently to go and help Russell
and his team with his organic content
funnel. At a high level, um how I look
at all content is what we call like a
content waterfall. A content waterfall
is essentially like a system that you
can use to go and turn like one core
piece of content into like 32 or more
other pieces of content. At a high
level, I'm always trying to look to like
maximize the content um that I've
already put out there, leverage all that
material versus defaulting to new. These
days, I try to as much as possible
default to like what have I already said
around this, right? Cuz I'm pretty sure
I've said the things, I've done the
things. I don't want to just default to
having to do it all over again. And it's
not just what I've done, you know,
today. It's also the background of
experience that I have, you know, not
just building Founder OS, you know, I
exited my first company, Bitmaker, uh,
you know, when I was 24 years old. In
addition to that, I currently am the CEO
and founder of Herb as well, which is
the largest cannabis community in the
world, where we help brands really
transform their cannabis marketing by
getting in front of the most engaged
cannabis audience in the world. You
know, this is a business I've been
building the last 10 years. We've grown
it to over a million people on
Instagram, over 10 million people on
Facebook, all through organic content in
one of the hardest and trickiest spaces
out there. You know, cannabis is no
joke. Um it is a difficult industry and
so I've been able to build this
compliant platform with over 14 million
people. We have millions of emails we've
collected and we help people almost like
a Google for weed. You know brands can
come to us. They can get clear trackable
metrics that help them understand how
they're attracting, collecting, engaging
and converting people from our audience
to their product or their service. And
so we've been able to build this
incredible business over the last decade
that's a leader in the space working
with the best brands in that industry
and providing them with detailed
trackable and measurable results. So in
a sense what I've built with Herb is one
part you know allowing people to go and
tap into this amazing audience and then
the other side we also have this insane
analytics platform that allows people to
track from you know audience through to
conversion um and be able to measure the
return on their advertising spend with
us. This serves as a proof point that
the systems that I'm building have not
only worked in the education space or in
the tech space or in the cannabis space
that they can work for founders no
matter what industry they're in. Which
gives founders confidence that I know
what I'm doing because I've built SAS
businesses off of organic content. I've
built, you know, education businesses,
course businesses, consulting
businesses. All of these different
industries can benefit from having their
own content GPS. So this is how to go
and build a real high ticket offer in
your niche. This is all about, you know,
an amazing experience, undeniable
support, and overd delivering to people
so they go and tell all their friends.
If you want my help and my team's help
going and scaling your offer, be sure to
go and apply via the link in the
description. Thanks so much for watching
this. Like and subscribe and welcome to
the Founder Freedom Movement.