If you don't own your audience, you're
actually just throwing money down the
drain. The reality is is that the
platforms that you're on are generally
just middlemen. The real value when
you're building a business is your
actual email list, right? Those are
emails of potential customers that you
own. Not Zuck, not Musk, you. And the
truth is that most people forget that
all these social media platforms have
platform risk, meaning that at any given
moment something could change on the
platform and all of a sudden you're
screwed. the best way to go and defend
yourself against this risk is to
actually own your audience by creating
something like an email list or a
newsletter, right? Doesn't matter what
platform you use, whether it's Substack,
ConvertKit, HubSpot, the tech doesn't
matter. If you don't have an email list
over the next 10 years, you will die.