Everyone wants to make a great living
doing what they're actually good at.
But, the real challenge isn't finding
[music] your passion. It's knowing how
to package it into something people will
pay premium prices for. You know, most
people try to create a high-ticket offer
out of thin air. They guess, they wing
it, and then they burn out. But, here's
the truth. The coaches, [music]
creators, and consultants earning
serious income, they aren't inventing
offers. [music] They're choosing the
right high-ticket model that works for
their expertise [music] to drive those
end results that their customers deeply
value. So, in this video, I'm breaking
down the five high-ticket [music]
business models making coaches and
consultants anywhere from 10,000 to over
$100,000 per [music] client. I'm going
to show you how you can go and choose
the one that fits your strengths without
burning out or diluting the work that
you love. Once you finish this video,
you'll never look at monetizing your
expertise the same [music] way again.
Just a quick heads-up here as well, all
right? This video is step one [music] of
two. So, step one is that you're going
to watch this and then understand the
five models. Step two is where you then
go and figure out which one you should
build. So, I created something called
the five [music] scalable models
self-audit. It's a 15-minute diagnostic
where you're going to rate your fit for
[music] each one of these models.
Download it below and complete it after
you finish this video. Let's break down
the models. Model one is group coaching
or cohort-based courses. This is where
you [music] stop selling your time and
you start selling a transformation
system. A true cohort is going to force
progress to a structured milestones,
assignments, and deadlines. In a cohort,
[music] you're finally not the product.
The system is the product. You're not
trading your time for money like
one-on-one coaching. You're building a
structured, time-bound program where
around 25 people, give or [music] take,
are able to go through a transformation
together. Pre-built curriculum,
assignments, [music] peer
accountability, and it's live group
coaching. The calendar enforces progress
and the curriculum is going to replace
live teaching. The system teaches, and
you just calibrate. [music]
Let's get into the pros and cons. The
pros? Well, it's scalable. You record
the curriculum once, and you use it for
multiple cohorts. The community effect,
peer pressure, and accountability are
going to drive results. You can [music]
run two or even four cohorts per year
and get that recurring revenue. And you
can start with a minimal team. The cons?
It's still very time-intensive delivery.
You still need to show up for live calls
and facilitation. Managing 20 to 30
people [music] through milestones is
somewhat complex. And curriculum
creation up front requires significant
work before your first cohort. You can
only run about two to four cohorts per
year without burning out. And if the
[music] curriculum is weak, well, people
drop out and could even damage your
reputation. So, a great example here are
my good friend Dickie and Nicolas Cole
over at Ship 30 for [music] 30. They
created this amazing program to help
people with online writing. There's $350
per cohort. Over 10,000 students have
gone through it. Their promise is
essentially that you can write essays
[music] after this and be able to share
that writing online. It's about really
just building that daily writing habit.
Live sessions are all recorded, so you
can also go and check them out after.
And you're [music] able to get peer
feedback in the community. Why does this
work? Because the system teaches.
[music] Dickie and Nick just show up,
and they calibrate. And they've really
gone through this multiple times, and so
they've [music] helped scale this
million-dollar model from just
repetition. This is typically a great
model for founders that are doing
between [music] 10 to 50K per month.
Looking to scale their time. You're
probably solo, or maybe you have a small
team of one or two or three people. And
your goal is to scale from about 50K per
month to 100K [music] to 200K per month.
Here's the trap. If your curriculum is
weak, you're just running expensive Zoom
therapy. A weak curriculum means you
become [music] the teacher. The system
has to teach, you just calibrate. So, if
the system is the product, what happens
when the room becomes the product?
That's [music] model two. Model two is
high-ticket masterminds. And masterminds
aren't about just learning, you know,
they're about network arbitrage. People
join masterminds because they want the
right introductions, right? Because the
right introduction can really collapse 3
years of trial and error into just one
conversation. Masterminds are typically
an elite peer group paying premium for
just a curated network and not just
education. Now, the most important thing
here is the curation,
>> [music]
>> right? You curate the wrong group of
people and the mastermind is likely to
fail. [music] But you curate a really
high-caliber group of people and I've
seen these [music] be insanely
transformative. In fact, when I look
back to my own career, you know, a lot
of the masterminds that I've gone to
that have been insane inflection points
and allowed me to go and level up. About
5 years ago, going to a mastermind that
was run by a good friend Eric Sue and
over there, I remember meeting Hormozi,
Cody Sanchez, [music]
Sam Ovens and others. And this was a
great opportunity at that time for me to
really understand the value of building
my own founder-led brand. And it helped
really rocket ship a lot of my progress
in building Founder OS. These sort of
masterminds are amazing. [music]
It's important to find the ones that are
curated right for you. And if you're
making one, it all comes down to making
sure that the caliber of the people in
the room are elite. The pros, [music]
well, this model tends to be the highest
revenue per member. Often times charging
between 30K to 60K plus per member per
[music] year. You got insane network
effects as well, right? Members create
value for each other. And if it's really
good, they go [music] and tell their
friends. The cool thing is is it can
scale without you once you get that
critical mass. In addition that, you
have sticky [music] retention, right?
People don't leave elite rooms once
they're finding an insane amount of
value in them. If you get the right
people in the room and everyone's making
connections, opening different doors,
well, before you know it, that group of
people are just compounding. [music] So,
some things to think about here are
premium positioning, also making sure
that it's exclusive so that you drive
desirability. You You have about 20
members at 60K, which is an easy 1.2
million dollars
>> [music]
>> of revenue a year with a pretty minimal
delivery burden. The cool thing here is
that you can really structure it however
you want. The cons is that it requires a
strong personal brand. [music] You know,
you can't launch without proven track
record and authority. There's also a
high rejection rate needed, right? You
must say no to about 90% plus of
applicants to maintain a really high
standard. [music] So, you want to make
sure that each member is actually
elevating the experience. When you're
building these, you know, exclusive
retreats, members-only dinners, and
[music] you know, exclusive access to
things that people couldn't get
otherwise. Examples of this are, you
know, Russell Brunson has his inner
circle. I know [music] good friend Dan
Martell has his Elite Growth Mastermind.
Myron Golden has a different one for
Offer Mastery. So, these are all over
the place, right? The truth is, [music]
it's not just about education, right?
What you should be primarily concerned
with is curating the right room of
people, right? That's what makes these
so valuable. And so, this is exactly how
we've gone and created [music]
Founderless Mastermind. You know, it's
about $60,000 per year. It's capped at a
really small group of eight-figure
founders. [music]
Each one gets six private one-to-ones
with me every year. Weekly group calls,
exclusive retreats. Who this is for?
Well, this is for founders doing around
100 to 500K per month with a strong
personal brand, network, [music] and
then the ability to curate elite peers.
At the end of the day, you know, people
can feel, especially in groups like
this, when you really care. And I see
caring as being one of the biggest
competitive advantages when you're
building a mastermind [music] like this.
Now, models one and two require you to
show up live. But, what if [music] you
could scale without being on calls?
Well, that's model three. So, model
three is DIY program plus high-touch
mentorship. This separates information
delivery from decision support. Record
the content once and you can typically
sell it forever. Show up only for
high-leverage [music] feedback at
critical decision points along the
client journey. This is the first model
that can realistically serve 500 [music]
plus people without overwhelming you.
Information delivery is automated,
mentorship prevents costly [music]
mistakes, and members can learn from
content. They get calibration from you
at critical decision points, and you
[music] have a clear structure that's
laid out for people with pre-recorded
lessons, templates, and frameworks. And
you may even throw in things like
monthly group calls or [music] Q&A. The
catch here is that delivery is insanely
important, and it's where most people
running this model fail. [music] You
know, I know we've probably all been
there when we've purchased something and
then you get on the inside and you're
like, "What the is this thing?"
[music] Right? And what I see a lot of
people do is they see the dollar signs
on a model like this, and they fail to
understand the delivery that's required
to do it right. The reality is this,
right? You have someone coming in that's
just purchased, [music] and they have
expectations. You as the founder, maybe
you don't want to get too involved in
the delivery because maybe the price tag
isn't massive yet. So, you feel [music]
like, you know, it should be relatively
scalable and that you shouldn't be lost
in the weeds, but I think what you
really want to do here is make sure
[music] that you're mapping out all of
the core activation points when someone
joins. They typically are sold in, they
have an onboarding call of some sort,
[music] and then there's probably a
series of three to seven core milestones
that get someone from where they are now
to the kind of given [music] outcome
that they were promised on the sales
call. The important thing is that you
think strategically about how you
deliver on that transformation for
someone through a combination of the
curriculum, of the support that you
provide, and any one-to-one or
mentorship access they get as [music]
well. Typically, the curriculum and the
overall program needs to be updated over
time, right? You need to make sure that
it's fresh, it's dialed in. Inevitably,
if you're watching this, right?
>> [music]
>> You're here because you want to create
something amazing. Cuz as much as we can
talk about different content systems for
marketing, inevitably [music] the best
marketing is just a amazing
product. Having regular feedback surveys
that you send your members to
understand, [music] you know, what stuff
are they looking for help with, what
gaps are they seeing, what stuff could
you do to really delight them, and then
responding [music] to that feedback
super fast with new and updated modules
or support or Q&A. I think it's
something you can do to really provide
that delight that I believe members in
these [music] sorts of programs
genuinely deserve. It's easy to sell
this right? It's a whole other
thing to go and deliver on it, which is
why you really need to understand the
details when you're doing this. You
typically will charge here about $2,000
up to [music] about $10,000 depending on
the given program. Examples of this are
things like, you know, Ali Abdaal's
Part-Time Creator Academy, helping
first-time [music] creators go and get
their first YouTube going and starting
up their channel. I've also created
something inside Founder OS, which is
called Founder OS Flagship, giving
people access to the 180 systems that
I've used to scale multiple [music]
companies and all the things across
YouTube OS, LinkedIn OS, X OS, Instagram
OS, and helping you go and also optimize
your offer. Humans crave structure. And
so, what you need to be thinking when
you're running a business like this is
what's [music] the structure you need to
have in place where someone can come in
with little knowledge and go through a
proven framework [music]
of items, right, and move seamlessly
through a journey to be able to get to
some end state [music] which they have
insane amounts of clarity, because
that's essentially what you're selling
here is clarity.
So, model four is done-for-you services.
So, clients here aren't just looking for
your advice, they [music] want to never
think about things again. And that's why
done-for-you doesn't just sell hours,
right? It sells certainty. People
actually want the work done. So, clients
are paying to not hire, to not manage,
to not figure out the system on their
own. If you can just [music] productize
your service, you know, you have the
potential here to scale this to millions
of dollars per month. Then you and your
team actually execute the work
completely for the client. So, the
client just shows up only just review
and approve the deliverables. And so,
this can scale, but [music] it really
takes operational excellence on your
part. You need specialists who actually
know what they're doing, obviously. This
is where, you know, you having the right
SOPs, system, technology, team, that can
produce [music] outcomes repeatedly is
insanely important. You know, this is
just what I built with Herb, okay, which
is one of my businesses that helps
people in a regulated space. And what we
did was we created the first of its kind
kind of marketing system and company
that would allow people to track their
conversions all the way from awareness
through to transactions. [music]
These done-for-you businesses can be
tricky because people have high
expectations, right? And often times
what I find hardest about them is that
initially it's kind of hard to
understand what's most repeatable about
it. What you can find, if you're not
careful, is that every single client
wants a customized solution. [music]
That gets exhausting, right? You can
imagine having a hundred different
clients, they've got big expectations
cuz they're all paying you $20,000 a
month, and they all want different
and you've [music] got a team of like 25
people. You know, this is really where I
cut my teeth with systems, right? And
fast forward today, [music]
20 years later, it was all the work I
had done at Herb over those years,
really working in an insanely hard
space, building this kind of service,
that really taught me the importance of
having amazing systems for operations,
finance, [music] billing, marketing,
sales, customer success. You'll learn a
ton in a model like this. It's a hell of
a good model if [music] you just have
your dialed in. But, you know,
there's no room for sloppiness here. If
it's productized, meaning that the
service [music] is able to stay the same
and be delivered thousands of times,
then yeah, you could be looking at 70 to
85% profit margins. [music] But, if that
is broken, right, and highly
customized, I've seen people struggle
here with like 5 to 30% margins max. And
so, you got to make sure it's
productized. You also want to make sure
that you're building team-based
leverage, right? So, you can scale by
hiring amazing specialists and getting
that recurring revenue because your team
is delivering on the promises every
single month to those clients that are
coming on board. One area where I see
get hard here is if a CEO is not good at
retaining his talent, you both have
these clients with high expectations and
a revolving door of talent going through
and suddenly things just start to
collapse in on themselves, right?
Because client expectations in this
model are high. A great example of a
legend in this space is Gary Vaynerchuk
with VaynerMedia. Full service content,
social media strategy. So, this is one
of the larger done-for-you agencies out
there in his given space. He's got a
team of specialists over there that are
delivering outcomes for massive brands
at scale. If your goal is to get to say
200k to 500k to a million plus per
month, you know, you're going to need
that team leverage in place. And so, you
need to be really good at recruiting
legends and not afraid to pay up. That
reliability is everything. [music]
That's a lot of pressure, right? So, you
got to make sure you got the right
people around you. All right. So, models
one through four are powerful, right?
But, there's one model that combines all
of them into something much
>> [music]
>> bigger. And that's model number five
here.
Model five is the hybrid operating
system.
>> [music]
>> So, this isn't a course, it's not a
mastermind, it's infrastructure. This
model offers clients complete [music]
business infrastructure. SOPs,
templates, frameworks, dashboards,
tools, coaching, and community. [music]
It's not just education, it's that
entire suite of systems that run a
business. And it transforms [music]
how operations work and how the founder
thinks. This model is insanely [music]
powerful. You can think really about
like McKinsey as an example. They don't
just give advice, they [music] install
frameworks, they have proven playbooks,
they have dashboards and operating
rhythms so their clients' companies
[music] run better forever, right? And
so, a hybrid OS does this but at scale
for creators and founders. Instead of
500,000 for McKinsey consultants, you
know, you're able to pay maybe just
20,000 to 40,000 per year for all the
systems from specialized [music]
people in a given space. I think this
model is really dependent [music] on a
founder, right, that believes in being
insanely generous. [music] You're likely
not just helping them, you're actually
enabling their whole team to [music]
take all the resources that have maybe
made you successful. You're also giving
them the intimacy [music]
of the mastermind model, allowing them
to, you know, get to know one another.
You're going above and beyond and the
extra mile for them. I think it's a
beautiful model here and kind of has
[music] the best of both worlds and from
my experience is highly retentive for
the people that join it. This model can
be the most scalable [music] from my
experience, right? You can oftentimes
serve 100 to 1,000 plus members if you
have the right infrastructure, okay? And
that's key. [music] Infrastructure is
everything. And by infrastructure, what
I'm talking about here is [music] the
proven process and system for actually
delivering something like this. [music]
It's easy to sell any of these things,
right? The hard part is the delivery.
You know, it's the difference between,
you know, someone holding the door open
for someone at a restaurant and then
delivery being the whole meal, the five
courses and making sure that they've
enjoyed every bite. When [music] you do
think through the details, though, the
beautiful thing is that this can be
insanely defensible. It's hard to
replicate, as an example, hundreds of
proven [music] systems. Members come in,
they get using the suite of tools and
support and access to you and then they
start asking you for more things.
[music] Maybe it's access to a AI agent
or maybe they want to have epic retreats
somewhere in the world. You don't know,
right? But the cool thing is that the
product kind [music] of unveils itself
as you're building it. You can add
things here like, [music] you know, team
licenses, advanced tiers, different
retreats, right? Just compounding that
value. Systems
>> [music]
>> can continue to improve over time and
then just continue to increase that
perceived value and allowing you to
position this in a very premium way.
[music] Let me show you exactly what
this looks like, okay? Because this is
what I built for myself inside [music]
of Founder OS Velocity. So, we have over
180 systems that we give members, right?
They get weekly calls with me, and they
can also get access to my leadership
team. All of our AI tools, a custom AI
agent we call Arya that's trained on
over 600 of my private systems. Took us
over a year to build this tech. [music]
And the cool thing there is now founders
can just ask any question, get it to do
anything that we teach in seconds. They
can go and get their offer made, or they
can go and get a YouTube strategy made,
or a whole content [music] strategy for
2026 made for them. And we can go and
make sure that your team is
systematized, they understand how to go
and leverage organic content, they
understand how to go and evolve your
offer. We allow them to get tooled up so
that they're less reliant on you. Make
sure, inevitably, that the founder is
more free. If you're an established
founder doing between 30K [music] and
500K per month, this is the most
leveraged way to work with me and my
team. So, you can go and book a call via
the link in the description, and let's
talk about how we can help you go and
package up your expertise [music] into a
business that works without you. Now,
these five models aren't about getting
rich, right? They're about architecting
impact [music] for people at scale.
Before you go, I created the five
scalable models self-audit. This is a
15-minute [music]
exercise where you can diagnose which
model is going to fit you best, okay?
So, go and download that below, complete
it, and then go and book a call and
bring it to my team so we can go and
review your results together, right? And
then show you how to go and build it and
see if we can help. Go and check that
out, and I can't wait to see what you
create. [music] And if you want to go
and get an in-depth breakdown on how to
go and create the Hybrid OS for
yourself, well, go and check out this
next video. I break down what I believe
is the most beautiful business out
there. So, go check that [music] out,
and let's win together.