hunger drives hustle hustle fuels
momentum momentum breathes success this
is the cycle of greatness a Relentless
pursuit of Excellence it's not about
perfection it's about progression
consistent unwavering daily progression
towards your highest Ambitions through
your darkest valleys beyond your
greatest triumphs because complacency
it's the precursor to obsolescence but
Relentless Pursuit it's the Hallmark of
Legends the secret sauce of icons the
differentiator of the undenied able so
cultivate your hunger amplify your
hustle and let your Relentless Pursuit
Define you in business in life in every
waking moment this is how legacies are
forged one Relentless step at a time