Views. Views. Views do not equal cash.
Here's something [music] most people in
the space will never show you. This is
our actual YouTube performance [music]
dashboard, the live system my team runs
every week to make the right content
decisions. It [music] pulls from YouTube
analytics and HubSpot CRM
simultaneously, platform performance on
one side, applications and cash
collected on the other. I'm going to get
into how I've gone and gotten myself out
of the brainwash these platforms get you
to care about and gone and focus on the
metrics that I think
>> [music]
>> you're really supposed to care about if
you're building a great business on the
back of content. But first, [music]
movie time here, okay? Brad Pitt in
Moneyball. This is a scene in Moneyball
where the old scouts are arguing about
the right look, and Billy Beane walks in
and says, "You're not even measuring the
right thing."
>> So, using this equation to your left
over here, I'm projecting that we need
to win at least 99 games in order to
make the postseason.
We need to score at least 814 runs in
order to win those games and allow no
more than 645 runs. This is building in
all the intelligence that we have to
project players. It's about getting
things down to [music] one number. Using
stats the way we read them, we'll find
value in players that nobody else can
see. You're going to get a guy that's
been released by half the organizations
in professional baseball because he's
got non-repairable nerve damage in his
elbow. He can't throw. He can't throw
it, he can't field. But what can he do?
He gets on base. He gets on base.
>> So, he walks a lot. He gets on base a
lot. Rocco, do I care if it's a walk or
a hit? Pete?
You do not. That is exactly what is
happening in most content businesses
right now. They got the wrong data,
wrong decisions, wrong scoreboard. And
what happens is you just go in the wrong
direction. At FounderUs, we built our
own Moneyball system for YouTube, a
dashboard that pulls every video across
12 variables, views, subscribers,
applications, deal value, cash
collected, editor performance, format
ROI, so you know with precision what
content actually will convert. This is
something that my head at FounderUs
Studios, Diego, worked meticulously to
put together, integrating it with our
HubSpot. And what you can see in here
are first off, all of our videos, right?
We've gone and synchronized this to the
YouTube API, so you can see every single
video that we have here. Now, if we go
and rank these based on views, right?
You're going to see content that I put
out there like success is hard until you
build systems like this, right? But the
interesting thing here is as we scroll
over to the right, that video according
to our last touch attribution data, only
made $258.
So, why am I sharing this with you,
right? Well, views don't equal cash.
When we go and rank this list now based
on revenue, right? You see an entirely
different picture, right? Videos like
how to make a killer YouTube video or
you'd be richer if you just relaxed,
right? Are videos that have only gotten
15K and 49K views respectively, but I've
generated $69,000,
$55,000.
They definitely aren't the videos on my
channel with the most views, but there's
some patterns amongst those and that I
want to show you. There's a certain
energy that goes into these videos
that's a lot different than my typical
videos. Now, this is a video I filmed
about 8 months ago in the Italian
Dolomites all around, you know, you'd be
richer if you just relaxed. You know, I
decided to go and just go for a hike one
day and figured I would bring, you know,
a simple tripod, my camera with me and
somewhere along the hike, I felt
inspired and I just plopped down the
tripod, set up the camera and just went
for basically a rant talking about just
the importance of taking breaks, taking
like a soul trip basically every 6 weeks
to step away from the business and that
when you oftentimes are just able to
take a break away from your business, it
allows you to kind of get in touch with
what really matters in life. Weirdly
enough, I think just sharing my own
story in this video, sharing a little
bit about my own philosophy, my point of
view around business, right? The
importance of balance, the importance
of, you know, really escaping to nature
to go and come up with my most creative
ideas was something that clearly
resonated with a lot of people and
caused them to go and want to go and
eventually join Founder OS. The
commonality I've seen here is that
sometimes it's just the videos where I'm
just speaking from the heart, from the
soul about the kind of stuff that really
fires me up, nature, traveling, um being
able to build a business that fuels my
life um versus drains it. When I'm
sharing that part of myself that I find
people most want to actually work with
me. I think there's a degree of
resonance that comes from that, right?
People see, you know, this lifestyle,
they see kind of my own philosophy on
life, they see this more soulful
entrepreneurship approach to business,
they see this, you know, side of me
that, you know, you wouldn't see if it
was overly polished. This is kind of a
trend that's going on in content right
now, right? We're going back to this
sort of raw, real, rant style. People
are yap maxing right now. It's a
beautiful thing. Just sharing your
authentic self, you don't need to be
overly produced, you don't need some
fancy FX3, you don't need some crazy
sound, just you, even in an iPhone
camera, and you're good to go. Now, the
cool thing is, that's actually how I
started this whole journey. You know,
when I look back 4 years ago getting
going on YouTube,
truthfully, I had no idea what I was
doing. As I was journaling every day, I
realized that I wanted to go and share
more of this online. That then
compounded into sharing more of my
thinking on X and on LinkedIn, growing
my audience to over 600,000 folks on
those platforms in around 8 months. And
then, at some point, I was like, "Well,
you know what? Let's give this whole
video thing a whirl." Had my iPhone at
the time, a $20 Amazon little tripod,
and figured, "Screw it. And we'll just
start ripping some videos like this one
here, seven decisions to stop screwing
yourself over." There I was just
ranting, sharing myself to the camera,
and started producing more and more
videos like this. And these videos did
not get many views. We're talking like
100, 200. I think it was a breakthrough
moment when I hit my first video with a
thousand views, and that was probably 20
videos in. You know, you may see my
videos these days and you sometimes
think, you know, it started this way,
but you know, it started just in a janky
setup in the backyard of my Puerto
Escondido, Mexico spot. Somewhere along
the journey in some senses, I kind of
got a bit lost in a way. It was kind of
lost and inspired at the same time,
okay? And so, I started making, you
know, videos like this one, right?
Success is hard until you build systems
like this. Now, I'm proud of these
videos, right? We put a ton of work into
things like our B-roll, our
cinematography, the beauty behind these
things, because part of my goal has
always been to build this Apple for
founders. That said, though, these sorts
of videos started to get super polished
over time. You know, we we're caring
about every pixel, every little bit.
That's all good and all for the visuals,
right? For the beauty, but sometimes
what it led to was that I was kind of
being a bit overly perfectionist about
these videos, right? Caring about every
animation, every little color grade,
every little sound quality little quip.
Somewhere along the way, sort of losing
a little bit of the authentic voice
behind it. The videos these days when I
look back that I'm most proud of are
videos like this one here, right? You're
wasting 80% of your potential every
month. Again, another video that when I
was just in La Peñita with a friend, you
know, I decided just to go and set up a
simple camera, my laptop, and show one
of the most valuable systems I had
discovered up until this point in my
life, which is called my personal board
meeting. Something I revisit every
single month and helps me kind of stay
on track with my big aspirations on both
a personal and business side around my
life. Super simple video here. We're
talking about 25 minutes total of
filming time, just going and sharing my
screen, recording it via QuickTime,
talking to the camera, and just
genuinely sharing how useful this system
had been for me. And the crazy thing is,
again, by just sharing what felt good
for me, what fired me up, when we look
back to this YouTube dashboard, this
video is actually my fourth most
profitable video I've ever made out of
the hundreds I've put out there. And so
there's this theme that I've begun to
pick up on more and more as I start to
look at this data, especially over the
last 6 to 8 months, right? It's this
idea that there are really two kinds of
videos that I see that really perform
extremely well. One is this kind where
I'm genuinely just sharing the kind of
stuff that I'm fascinated by, right?
Maybe it's something I've learned
recently, maybe it's a core system that
I'm interested in. The second kind is
when I'm just sharing my work, right?
That could be these kind of whiteboard
sessions like the ones I've done with
Ali Abdaal and my good friend Blake, um
or it could be ones where I'm sharing,
you know, my killer YouTube system and a
little bit of behind the scenes of how
I've gone and structured things like my
packaging and titles for YouTube, like
this video here where I showed the
behind the scenes of how I'm using
Poppy. And so as we look at this
dashboard, right? The data starts to
inform us of like directionally what
content I should be creating and
thinking about, right? And so here you
can see, you know, my revenue per video,
right? It's showing me that content
around, you know, my content systems
like my YouTube systems, as well as
things like, you know, how to go and
beat the LinkedIn algorithm have been
some of my most profitable videos. Over
here, we can go and see the content
matrix as well, right? And looking at,
you know, which different formats have
provided us with the most views, the
most subs, applications, revenue, and so
forth. What we can see as well is like
different formats, okay? And see which
formats are also performing. And so as
we're looking to go and refine our
approach, right? Typically, I don't want
to be doing too many things at once,
right? We'd love to just pick a few core
categories, things like storytelling,
AI, and content, and then pick a few
core formats, things like whiteboard
formats, system screen shares, and say
talking heads, and just double down on
that format. And so, as we go down here
as well, something that's interesting is
we're able to see the applications per
different kinds of formats and
categories as well. So, here I can see
that my storytelling format, right, gets
me the most applications, right, per
10,000 views. People on this channel
want to learn how I approach
storytelling, the different systems
behind creating content. You guys are
also coming to me for things like how
I'm using AI, as well as the
behind-the-scenes content systems.
That's why we love to share, you know,
how to go and stand out on platforms
like X in this video over here, how
we've gone and achieved over 950,000
Instagram followers in this video over
here, which performed insanely well, or
this recent one on how I beat the
LinkedIn algorithm as well. And so, from
there, we can see on the format side,
it's this system screen shares that
crush it. And I think the interesting
learning for you as an executive or a
founder
or a business owner really looking to
grow on YouTube is just sharing your IP,
right? You inevitably have some systems
or frameworks or a method that is unique
to you that you've helped people with.
And there's no better way at, you know,
creating simple content that allows you
to speak authentically in your voice and
drive people to the thing you're selling
than by just showing it behind the
scenes. And I think it's a beautiful
format that converts well, performs
well, right, and is easy to create,
which I think is also super key. Because
you want to enjoy this whole process at
the end of the day. We can go and chart,
you know, different formats on things
like, you know, performance quadrants
and all this, but candidly, the things
that I think are most interesting are on
graphs like this, right, the strategic
outlier board. Looking at things like
the top revenue board here, and really
just looking at, you know, my highest
videos in terms of revenue, right?
Because I have a team around 15 core
people at Founder OS, and we want to
make sure that as we're building out our
content and media division, that it's
insanely profitable, it's lean, um and
we're making a real business impact with
the stuff that we're putting out there.
We want to go and lean into more
formats, um like the ones I've shared
here. We're not going and transforming
any given piece of content too much
because if you pursue views too
aggressively, what you're going to find
yourself doing is just creating content
for everyone, including beginners. And
if you're anything like me, the kind of
stuff I'm putting out there, right, is
more for folks that are doing, you know,
a million plus a year in their business,
right? And so, I want to make sure that
I'm speaking directly to the kind of
people that I want to speak to versus
complete beginners in my content. So,
all this data is amazing, right? But
it's only as good as the insights and
strategy you're able to drive from it.
And so, here we can also see in this
dashboard, we have a strategy tab. We're
able to go and synchronize the core
insights from all this data to inform
our next batch of content. And so,
typically when I'm filming, I'm doing
about 16 videos over about 7 days, and
we're filming in batches so that we can
go hard, film a bunch of content, and
then let that get edited, and then, you
know, 2 months, 3 months, I'm just kind
of working in the business, doing my
thing,
and then, you know, getting back to
video every 2 to 3 months. And so, it
allows us to batch the content, have a
clear plan, and great insights from this
dashboard we've just made. So, again,
we're not getting too lost in the sauce
of all these, you know, data points.
We're just able to bubble up um the
stuff that informs our action plans.
Things like, you know, AI leads on both
reach and revenue, right? So, clearly,
we can see then, it maybe makes sense
for us to double down on more AI-related
content, especially when I find myself
in Cloud Code a few hours every single
day these days. Or, you know, things to
fix, right? Like the primary funnel
constraint is deal close rate, right?
And so, showing us sometimes inside of
our organic content funnel areas that we
we can optimize.
And then, you know, things to look at,
right? Things like, you know, system
screen shares generating the most
applications for 10K views, right?
Hence, why we're making more screen
share videos like this one here right
now. So, this is how you go and turn all
this raw data into a real operator tool,
something that transforms this dashboard
from some reporting layer into a real
decision engine. If you want me and my
team to go and bring this level of
insight and sophistication into your
social media engine, that's exactly what
we build inside of Founder's OS. Because
most founders don't need another course
or some personal branding, they need
this machine installed ASAP, right?
Before they continue to post content and
see no return. Inside of Founder's OS,
we're going to start by diagnosing your
business, your offer, your audience,
your current content, and the constraint
blocking your growth. In the first 60
days, we build all of the core
infrastructure for your personal media
company and your social media machine
for you, okay? Day one, we're going to
deep dive into your brand. By day seven,
we're going to give you your full brand
positioning documented. By day 21, we're
going to deliver your entire content GPS
so you can see how your content directly
plugs into your monetization and
business. This, you know, for me is the
real difference between just posting
content and the difference then between
actually building a social media
machine, which is what you're really
after. So, if you're doing between 30K
and a million dollars a month and your
business is working, but your content
machine is not yet creating a real
predictable pipeline, well, you should
go and apply to Founder's OS via the
link below. And if you're building on
YouTube, check out this next video to
make sure that you're doing it right. Be
sure to like and subscribe and let's win
together.