Every episode of Seinfeld used the same
sets. Every episode of Friends used the
same apartment. And here's why your
content should do the same. The reason I
was able to grow to 200,000 subscribers
on YouTube, 900,000 followers on
Instagram, and 800,000 followers on
LinkedIn is that I don't wake up every
day wondering, "What should I make?" I
know exactly which format fits the idea
that I want to communicate. Let me show
you how we approach [music] formats on
YouTube. The first one are systems
breakdowns. This is where we go really
deep into the how, the what, and the
specific steps that [music] go in to a
specific, repeatable process in a
founder-led business. Next format are
real systems demos. This is when I'm
showing behind the scenes, sharing my
screen, and showing exactly what goes in
to a specific system within my
companies. The next format are founder
mentor sessions. These are whiteboard
breakdowns where I'm helping folks
either inside of Founder OS or other
large creators like Blake Roca or
[music] folks like Ali Abdaal and
helping them build their business live
by breaking down a specific challenge
they're having using the systems I've
built over the last couple decades to go
and help them overcome that challenge.
So, pick three content formats max and
[music] rotate them forever. If one gets
boring, substitute one other one in, but
don't constantly change everything.
Change the input, not the structure.
Same format, different topic. This is
how you build a sustainable content
operation that doesn't burn you out.