imagine building a multi-million dollar
business plan in just a few hours well
that's exactly what I'm here in Lisbon
to do I'm meeting with my chief of staff
and my head of marketing to go and build
some insane systems here for founder OS
our goal is to health Founders skill
their businesses to millions of dollars
using proven systems and there's a few
core things I'm going to be running
through today with my team to generate
over $3 million to my business and
you're going to be in the room where
it's all happening number one we're
going to go through the content GPS and
how we're scaling it up at founder to
capture a $1.5 million opportunity and
help fers with the most powerful system
I've ever discovered number two we have
the biggest launch ever coming out here
in just a few weeks for Black Friday
Cyber Monday and we're going to give you
an inner glimpse into how we're planning
out this entire massive launch now
number three is what I'm most excited
for we're going to be giving away yeah
giving away our entire million launch
plan this is exactly what we're doing to
generate over a million dollar over just
4 days so you're not going to want to
miss out we got a lot of cool stuff we
about to drop here over the next 10
minutes so let's get
it all right so in this next section I
break down the most powerful system I've
ever discovered it's called the content
GPS and it's responsible for driving 20
million plus to my portfolio of online
businesses over the last 4 years in this
next section I break down why it works
how it works and then how you can go and
install this in your business today
let's get into it first I want to give
you an inner glimpse of how I use the
content GPS to scale over $13 million a
year let's get into it I never wanted to
be famous you know this is me back in
high school I know a little
embarrassing I'm an introvert you know I
love spending time in nature I'm
happiest just being outside this is me
here and the dolomites and just with a
pen paper notebook maybe a good book
those are the things that bring me joy
but I did dream of a life where I could
make an impact in millions of Founders
lives just like you you know I love to
you know build systems help people grow
their communities I want to make lots of
money um and I love to be able to live
life on my own terms over the years I've
learned the importance of scaling with
systems systems give you the ability to
go and remove yourself from the stuff
you don't enjoy and have other people
help you execute those so you have a
business that runs on
autopilot and most importantly I have a
dream of being able to travel the world
control where I work when I work what I
work on and who I work with and so to be
able to live this life of freedom I need
to have systems in place because systems
give me the ability to step back from my
business and have it run without me and
so
one of the best things I've learned over
the years is to build a personal brand
you know your personal brand is an
appreciating asset that's going to help
you become a true leader in your space
and be a magnet for top talent for
opportunities community and cash flow it
is the best investment that you can make
but when you're going in building a
brand online you can get a ton of
conflicting advice it's confusing
sometimes it's hard to tell what you
should be doing because there's no clear
Playbook and so this is where the
content GPS comes in it really helps you
go and build a personal Media Company
where you dominate platforms like X
LinkedIn YouTube and Instagram funnel
those people to a newsletter that you
own through core call to actions across
each platform from there you drag people
to sales calls close them into customers
and get them to refer their friends the
content GPS is the most powerful system
I'd ever invented in the 15 years I've
been building businesses you know I've
used this to go and sell my first
business bit nagger to General Assembly
I then used it with herb to grow the
audience there to over 14 million people
and then I utilized this system at
founder OS to scale up Beyond $800,000
in Revenue per month um and help me grow
my personal brand to over 2.7 million
people now when you're looking to go and
build your personal brand the content
GPS actually helps you with things like
your brand POS positioning formula your
brand positioning is essential so that
you are unique from all the other noise
that exists out there it really comes
down to number one nailing your thesis
two determining the two to three things
that are going to allow you to deliver
on that thesis and three identify your
core mechanism that is the best way to
achieve that thesis so let me give you
an example of this with founder OS you
know our brand positioning at founder is
as follows number one the best way to
build an online business is with a
personal Brand number two you need to be
creating content that is beautiful
systemized and Hyper profitable to take
advantage of this opportunity and third
the only way to build a hyper profitable
personal brand is with a Content GPS
system with founder so these three
aspects constitute our core brand
positioning at founder Ro I now let's
move on to then your content funnel when
you're going and thinking about actually
than a Content funnel you need to make
sure that you're driving people from
your rented audience on social to your
owned audience in an email list which I
use convertkit for my newsletter and
then driving people to your monetized
audience which is the people that are
actually purchasing your product or your
service the quicker that you can drive
people from your rented audience to your
monetized audience you know the more
powerful your funnel because you're
using those cash flows to then reinvest
in your product your people and your
mission now
on the content side the key thing is
making sure that you have scroll
stopping hooks the more powerful that
first sentence the more you stop people
when they're scrolling and they're going
to go and dive further into your funnel
on the left here you can see an example
of me doing this to generate over
290,000 likes over 35 million organic
views on X and this is all without
spending a dying on ads this is the
power of your personal brand and this is
the return you get on organic content it
is second to none as you go and actually
want to stand out on these platforms you
want to think about having your own
content calendar here you can go and
steal mine go and take a screenshot of
this and you can go and use it for
yourself you can go and see my schedule
across X LinkedIn YouTube Instagram and
Tik Tok Monday through Sunday what you
want to do over time is maximize the
quantity you can put on each platform
and also maximize your quality because
at the end of the day quality is
ultimate pattern interrupt when it comes
to actually drafting your killer offer
you want to make sure that you have
incredible
differentiation have a unique mechanism
and a massive desired outcome that
you're producing for your audience now
many people think they just have one
offer but I actually believe you you
have multiple offers here is an example
of an offer stack where you have people
going from your social bio and following
you then going and joining a newsletter
maybe joining a Workshop getting a low
ticket offer moving to then a high
ticket offer your core offer to a
mastermind and continuing to kind of
evolve to the different offers that you
have you often times don't just have one
offer right again on social it's an
offer that you have in your bio to get
someone to follow you the average person
out there as an example converts about
05% of visitors of the profile to
followers in my case I convert around
20% that's 40x more people this is the
power of the offer stack now as you go
and build your personal brand you likely
want to evolve it to being more of a
personal Media Company where you have
weapons all around you executing core
systems so you can work on your business
and not in it and have true freedom in
life now when it comes to actually
creating that content you want to go and
nail your content Tech stack I use kit
for all of my newsletter needs I use
height C to schedule my X content
Hemingway to to make sure that I'm
writing at an eighth grade reading level
tweet Hunter X for all my content inspo
and figma for beautiful designs over
time you really want to nail removing
yourself from operations so to do this
you're going to map out your customer
Journey all the way from awareness to
transaction to referral you're then
going to go and identify the two to
three systems for each stage of your
business you're going to then document
each system and record it using loom
then go and save all these into a Google
drive folder so it's easy for everyone
in your company to access them and
Implement them and then you're going to
train your team on two processes per
week and aim as a team to get 5% better
every single week you do that 5% better
every single week for 52 weeks a year
and you're like 5,000 times better after
just one year now the game is always
changing and so what you're going to see
in this next clip is me and my team
going and implementing different changes
different improvements to get 5% better
every single
week is there a way to like preview any
like in the instructor calls or anything
like that where it's like oh if you like
that like I actually do this oneon-one
with like for them to like preview what
like something that they would actually
be servicing in OS plus something think
on that like I'm always big on kind of
like from doing one thing getting 10
things out of it I feel like over the
next bit because some changes we're
making I'm probably going to have to get
on some like one toone coaching calls
with some people yeah and so what if
like the one one coaching like Matt
getting on this but by the way we're
going to use we get your permission to
use this marketing so then I'm on it and
I build their content GPS for them in an
hour oh yeah we should and then we
record that and then they're like what
the like I get that kind of like
whatever he just did with her when I'm
in that like s me up you know that was
insane there's an example of someone
Samy H he joined OS in October no
product no nothing and yeah built a 30k
Mr de signal business and then yeah 6
months later exited for $600,000 because
of the connection I believe yeah C
[Music]
us starting off I think you want to
drive people to your lowest lift thing
right so we give them more uh uh content
systems for the short form for YouTube
all of our hiring Sops just keep me post
it man I'm here to help Head West onod
aom R
luck all right well another day at the
[Music]
office all right in this section I then
go get into the behind the scenes of how
we construct our Black Friday Cyber
Monday offer this offer is going to help
us make over a million dollar and
provide
insane value to the founders in our
community I'm going to break down our
exact strategy how we go and craft the
killer offer and then how we execute on
it I'm going to give you the exact
blueprint and I've never shared this
before so let's get into the next part
of the Whiteboard session so the next
aspect here Black Friday Cyber Monday
goal here is just just go for it you
know home run would be million dollars
from this and helping at least what is
that let's just say backwards math here
a million divided by say what is it like
a $199 thing yeah yeah yeah probably
yeah so selling 5,000 what do we think
there oh I think we can do it okay I
think we can do it all right but let's
uh let's B this one see how this goes um
but I do think we should have like a few
emails or Ps or something that's like
indicating to people like hey we have
something coming up that's insane
newsletter yeah we have X we have
LinkedIn we have Instagram YouTube yep
an IG text messages mhm school do we
want to share it in school cuz it is
something yeah it's something different
like they could technically F or share
with their friends or whatever I think
that we should do two ps's okay in the
newsletter right and I think that we
should do one dedicated email not a
newsletter just like a quick really
short email like hey I just want to let
you know Black Friday 7 m is cominging
up we prepare something absolutely
insane so just make sure you're keeping
an eye on like y what's coming up during
the launch I think the email strategy
for during the launch is relatively
obvious like you do you know it's like
four launch emails so we definitely want
one on the day it starts Friday we maybe
want five just for like a final urgency
one so I think then also there's like
abandoned card yeah you're right so we
definitely want an abandoned card email
sequence 100% yep good call I mean again
I think we should have like like at
least one post that's like yeah yeah
well for the launch yeah definitely one
post per day 100% so four threads maybe
four tweets and four ctas then LinkedIn
four long form post four CPAs and then
YouTube this video
yeah yeah honestly one long burun video
yep and then we'll do like one YouTube
short script IG one IG real script and
like maybe some stories templates text
one text message yeah take one text
message want to stay light on that
school maybe like two School two post
yeah two what I was thinking 36 36
assets
yep that is MIL know
launch and now for the grand finale I've
built multiple million doll plus
launches and in this section of the
video I'm going to give you behind the
scenes of exactly how we go and
construct a killer offer how we generate
Mass awareness and hype amongst our
community and then convert people to
purchase you know the devil's really in
the details when you're launching
something of this scale and I'm going to
go and give you the exact checklist and
blueprint that we're using to make sure
that our next launch is a massive
success you're going to want to go and
get your pen and paper out and take
notes here because this is some Secret
Sauce buckle up I'm going to give you my
million dooll launch formula let's get
into it I want you to get your pen and
paper handy because we are going to move
fast through some very critical stages
that you're going to want to implement
today let's go
launches are incredible opportunities to
go and drive people from your audience
to your offer and unlock true freedom in
Life Time Freedom location freedom and
Financial Freedom and so getting it
right is key and I want you to
understand something velocity is more
important than speed you know velocity
equals speed plus Direction and
Direction makes all the difference when
launching so here is my direction for
you this this is the launch OS it
consists of eight core Parts getting
your Landing paves social media
newsletter funnel mapping metrics assets
workshop and email all driving in the
same direction to make sure that you
unlock that million dooll launch so I'm
going to give you a glimpse of all of
these in the next few
slides first off when you're going and
creating a launch you want to have a
compelling Vision that really motivates
your audience and sets them on fire so
they can't help but move forward and
purchase from you so when you're going
and thinking about creating content
online and around your offer you want to
think about having 50% growth content to
drive eyeballs and 50% Niche content to
then push those people through your
funnel through to purchase so as you go
and want to drive people from your
audience to purchase the core middle
part there is your ctas and right here
are 17 core areas where you can have
called to actions across all the social
media platforms go and take a screenshot
of this and make sure that you have the
right ctas in place for your next launch
now let's get into part one your cold
audience mechanism this is how you're
going to generate attention and drive
people through to your newsletter when
you're creating content you want to
think about what are your for Content
categories at founder OS I focus on
organic content proven systems build
predictable lead engines and I give
people personal stories on exactly how
I've done this across the four
profitable businesses that I've started
over the last 14 years these categories
will become the drum beat of your
marketing around your next launch part
number two now is your warm lead
mechanism this is how you're going to go
and actually create a ton of Interest
now in your offer so inside of your
newsletter you want to make sure that
you have a well-designed opt-in page to
convert people from this page to the
newsletter and then in your newsletter
you can be going and teasing your
upcoming launch building weight list and
then driving people to your offer when
it's live to get people to actually come
to your newsletter something that I
think you should have is a desirable
lead magnet I founder OS we go and have
created a 50 system to generate a
million per month lead magnet that has
driven over
137,000 people to our newsletter you can
go and check it out at found.com s/
newsletter so along the way you want to
make sure that you're measuring every
part of your funnel what gets measured
gets managed and so here you can see an
example of all the core metrics that
we're measuring across the launches that
we have I found a OS your vssl is
another core asset you want to make sure
that you have in place the right vssl is
going to position your offer so it's
irresistible for people it's going to
set the tone introduce exactly how
you're going to help people and the next
steps that they need to take in order to
convert and drive revenue and profit to
your business workshops are something
that I've used over the last year to
generate over $1.8 million in Revenue to
my portfolio of online businesses
workshops really consist of six core
steps getting the right structure having
a simple technical setup having email
series go pre and postworkshop getting
the right promotion in place across all
your social media having practical value
so you have high value per second and
then showing you have stories that
people can't help but be captivated and
then convert to your offer at the end of
a
workshop here's the deal when you're
going and launching anything sometimes
your expectation is at just some linear
growth but from my experience you know
it comes in waves and so you know at
first it may not seem like you're making
a lot of progress but stick with it you
know nothing worth doing is going to be
easy and so here you'll see that your
expectation maybe to just get from here
to here easily well it may look a little
bit more like this but stick with it you
got this along the way you may determine
that you need some help you can go and
post in the comments below I'd love to
see you know from all of this what's the
thing that you most need help with along
the way if you want my help going and
installing the content GPS for you and
helping you with your next million--
dooll launch you can go apply to foundos
I found.com Clan