All right, here's how I'd start a social
media machine in 30 days.
Week one, nail your positioning, right?
Do you have positioning around your
brand that makes it easy for people to
tell their friends what it is that you
do, right? I hear from founders all the
time they say, "Matt, you've helped me a
lot build my social media machine and a
beautiful cash flowing business." So,
that's some easy positioning and what
allows the word to travel around what I
do. So, you want to think about what do
you want people telling their friends
about you. Week two then, pick one
platform, right? Don't overcomplicate
it. The best content strategy is the one
that you can actually stick with. I like
to get started probably posting five
times a week, but again,
if you're going on YouTube, it may even
look like just posting once a month or
once every other week. Just pick a
content strategy that works for you.
Now, week three, over time, you can
start to build your content waterfall,
right? Going and taking one pillar piece
of content and then going and
repurposing it for other platforms. So,
if you have a, say, long-form YouTube
video, you could be cutting that up
for things like Instagram reels,
Instagram stories, X videos, and so
forth. Now, from there, you want to
install the bi-weekly ritual, right? The
bi-weekly ritual, I think, is really
going and answering some core,
vulnerable, authentic questions around
what you really believe in, what makes
you different, what's your uniqueness,
and some things maybe that you've been
dealing with the last few weeks, and
then recording a voice memo,
transcribing it with Claude code, and
using that to go and be the basis of
your content for the next 2 weeks.