here's a question that thing you're
really passionate about doing the thing
you believe can have a meaningful impact
and really change your life what if you
did that thing every day for the next
decade could you fail most of us think
in terms of months or years but the
really amazing stuff happens as a result
of daily action over decades think about
it if you did that thing every day for
the next decade even with the good days
and the bad days there's virtually no
way you could fail because you'd have
done it long enough that the Universe
would simply see your persistence and
give you what you want the next time
you're feeling discouraged remember
you're in it for the long term not just
to make a quick splash