lock yourself in a room and read these
seven books on copyrighting you'll thank
me later the Bor on Letters by Gary
Halpert Gary explains Insider tactics
and Sage wisdom to his youngest son bond
cashvertising by Drew Whitman learned
how to use more than a 100 secrets of Ad
Agency psychology to make big money
selling anything to anyone the adwe
copyrighting handbook by Joseph sugar
this is The Ultimate Guide to writing
powerful advertising and marketing copy
from one of America's top copywriters
snow leopard by Nicholas Cole get the
best strategy for creating compelling
copy that creates a cult following how
to write copy that sells by Ray Edwards
the step-by-step system for more sales
more customers more often scientific
advertising by Claude Hopkins create a
winning personality for your ads
incentivize people to buy without using
sensationalism or empty rhetoric and run
tests to make smarter copy confessions
of an advertising Man by David ogy this
book revolutionized the world of
advertising and became a Bible for the
1960s ad generation