Everyone is obsessed with deep work, but
most founders are tricking themselves
and just working really hard and driving
themsel into the ground. What I'm going
to break down in this video is my deep
work routine that allows me to get more
done in 4 hours than most people get
done in 4 days. I'm going to take you
through the entire routine starting with
the night before because that's where
the real magic happens. Around 5:00
p.m., you should be wrapping up your day
and making a list of the core things
that you need to get done the next day
to be successful. Most people think, you
know, deep work is just putting on some
headphones, locking in and getting
going. But there's no sense working on
stuff if you don't have a clear
strategic direction. Take some time to
zoom out. And what I use for that is my
personal board meeting. I've gone and
charted out my vision for the next 10
years, 3 years. Things like, you know,
creating seven best-selling books over
the next next seven years. You know,
building a retreat center for founders
in the Doommites. Now from there I then
go and break it down into what I need to
get done you know in three month
increments right so each year and then
each quarter which then ladder up to the
goals that I need to go and hit in any
given month. And so as you can see here
my one big domino is establishing this
4hour deepwork system to produce one
truly exceptional high lever piece of
content every single day. Now that I'm
clear on what I need to get done that
month. The second step here is to then
go and write out what you're going to go
and get done the next day. Here I've got
things like, you know, filming a YouTube
video, going and sending the financial
controller job description to 50 people,
uh, you know, going and sending my book
and final manuscript to, uh, James
Clear's editor, who is someone I'm
considering. And so what I've done now
is I've got clarity around exactly what
I need to get done the next day. And I
think this is important because my
personal belief is that when you go and
you get clear on what you need to get
done, that list that you've actually
written out on pen and paper then kind
of circulates in your brain at night.
From there, you're good to go. 6:00 p.m.
final meal of the day, making sure that
you're giving yourself 3 hours before
bed so you can digest that food and then
get a great sleep. 10 p.m. it's time to
get lights off. No phone, no computer.
I've got my red light glasses on,
blocking out any blue light so I get as
much deep sleep as possible. The room
should be pitch black and set up to get
the best sleep of your life. 7:00 a.m.
I'm typically up ready to go. I don't
set an alarm in the morning. I'm not
looking to be that dude that's waking up
and doing cold bass and saunas.
Typically, honestly, I just wake up and
we're raring to go and it's time for my
abundance 15 minutes. 7:10 a.m. I
typically go sit down cross-legged and
meditate for around 5 to 10 minutes,
just priming my brain for what's about
to be an amazing deep work session. 8:00
a.m. I arrived at the cafe, open up my
laptop, I've got my list in front of me
of the things I need to go and get done.
And now I'm ready to lock in for my
4hour deep work session. I'm basically
blocking out all distractions. My phone
is in my bag on airplane mode. I am
locking into the task at hand.
Neurologically it's proven that right in
the morning your motivation is the
highest and so you want to get right
into that work. I go and look at my
tasks and typically I have them ranked
from like one to five. Meaning these are
the tasks that I'm going to go through
in that order so that I'm not going and
defaulting to the easiest tasks which
sometimes can be the least important.
Some other core tips here. I learned
this from Andrew Huban. A lot of people
think that when they become unfocused
that it's because of lack of hydration,
but typically what's actually going on
is that you lack salt. Salt has
electrolytes. And so, one weird thing
that I do during my deep work sessions
is if I'm feeling a little bit of brain
fog, I'll just pour a little bit of mort
salt in my hand, knock it back, and then
knock some water back just to kind of
replenish my electrolytes and just keep
me focused. Another aspect that I think
is really helpful if you're looking to
lock in is go and find a playlist that
you love. For me these days, it's
listening to George Harrison or the
Beatles. In the past, it's also been
using tools like Brain.fm, which is a
great tool that uses binaural beats to
help you neurologically lock in to the
task at hand. You could also try things
like setting different timers. Often
times, I'll gify my deepwork sessions. I
know that I have 45 minutes to lock in
and go and create a YouTube script. The
gamification of it is that I need to
complete the task and then film a Loom
video on it and pass it on to the next
person. Thereby, I've completed the task
in that amount of time and then I've
filmed my completed work and then sent
it on to the next person. So, it's now
delegated off my plate and I'm building
more leverage to the people around me
within my company. Far too often, what
founders do is they'll lock in for deep
work. They'll get all this amazing stuff
done, but meanwhile across their team,
no one has a clue as to what you're
doing. And that's a mistake because you
then don't get the leverage that you
could be getting if more people on the
team were aware of how you go and
perform different tasks. And so
something I think a lot about is going
and bringing people on my team into the
room with me. What that may mean on a
remote team is I finished a YouTube
script. Now I'm going to go and run my
team through my process and how I did
this so they can do it going forward. If
I've gone and created some Instagram
carousel copy, I'm going to go and show
my team how I went and made that, the
process by which I took and the research
I put into it so they can go and help me
going forward with that. And so when you
bring people in the room, you get the
leverage of those folks so that you can
delegate more of the tasks in your deep
work sessions and continue to go deeper
and deeper on the stuff that only you
can do. This deep work routine has
unlocked an insane amount of creativity,
progress, and momentum for me and lots
of other high growth founders inside a
founder OS. If you're looking to go and
join a community, get mentorship from
people that are all looking to go and
optimize with these kinds of systems,
you should check out Founder OS and
apply via the link in the description.
Get on a call with me or my team. We'd
love to chat, see what you're really
looking to get done this year, and help
level you up with proven systems. So,
you've locked in from around 7:00 a.m.
to 11:00 a.m. A key thing that you want
to do is protect that time. So, that
means going right now. Yes, like
literally right now. And go and block
off your calendar from 7:00 a.m. to
11:00 a.m. every single day. No
meetings, no [\h__\h] no crisises, no
emergencies. You are locked the [\h__\h] in.
This is your sacred time to work on the
stuff that's the real needle movers in
your business. You may be asking, "Well,
Matt, how do I think about the stuff
that I should be focused on in this
period of time?" Well, I think you want
to focus on the stuff that's in your
zone of brilliance. And you can think of
it like three concentric circles. You
have the stuff that you're great at, the
stuff that you love to do, and then the
stuff that you can be paid for. For me,
as an example, the stuff that I'm great
at are, you know, building audiences,
building distribution for founders,
going and helping build out, you know,
YouTube concepts that will blow up. The
things I love to do, I love to write. I
love to be creative. I love to build
teams. And then the things that can be
paid for are things like helping
founders, providing value, creating
content that helps uplevel founders. And
so the intersection of that is things
like creating exceptional content every
single day. Videos like this to go and
serve you guys. You know, the cool thing
is is that it's a highly leveraged task,
right? Creating exceptional content
isn't just me talking to one founder at
a time. You know, these videos I create
every week allow me to go and reach
millions of founders every month and get
that much more leverage for my time for
you. It leverage can come from things
like leveraging technology, building
automations, creating systems, hiring
folks, you know, investing capital in a
way that builds leverage. These are the
kind of things you want to be thinking
about if you want to become a more
systemized and leveraged founder and
scale up your business. Now, your deep
work session is done and it's time that
we move on to the afternoon. Noon, we've
wrapped up four hours of deep work and
it's time to go and reward ourselves
with an amazing meal. These days, what
I'll typically eat is some sort of
protein. So, like maybe eggs, bacon,
I'll have some Greek yogurt, and then go
for a nice walk and just enjoy the
sunshine, get outside, rewarding myself
for work well done. I'm not here to tell
you what to eat and do your stuff.
There's other people like Ronda Patrick
or Andrew Huberman that can tell you
that stuff. What I'm here to tell you is
just to be intentional. Be intentional
about where you spend your time. Be
intentional about who you surround
yourself with. Be intentional about what
you put in your body. Because the end of
the day, how you treat yourself is how
you're going to treat others. And how
intentional you are with your day is
going to dictate the intentional
business you're able to create. My
mornings are more internally focused on
the deep work routine and getting [\h__\h]
done. And then typically I'll use my
afternoons for the more external side of
things, connecting with others, building
community, and any team meetings I need
to be on. 2 p.m. We've wrapped up lunch.
It's time to go for a hike. Go and
connect with other people. Some things
to consider to make sure that you're
feeling primed and ready to go for the
next day. Is energy management. Making
sure that you're working out every day.
Making sure that you're moving your
body, getting your 10,000 steps. Go
explore. Go adventure. Go reward
yourself for work well done. You know,
get some sunshine. Go and connect with
people. And this is also a good period
to go and fit in any meetings you may
have. On the subject of meetings, you
need to be strict with your meeting
schedule as well, right? We don't want
to just be slamming meetings all
throughout our weeks. I typically like
to go and allocate Tuesdays as my
meeting day and thereby the rest of my
week is filled with time for me to
think, strategize, write, and just enjoy
life. The truth is the more healthy you
are as a founder, the healthier the
business you're going to build. And so
when I think about the kind of rhythms
in my life that help me be healthy, it's
things like mobility daily, making sure
that these, you know, hips are all
stretched out. It's lifting four times a
week. It's taking time to get my steps
and go and explore. It's taking one or
two days to be in nature every single
week. And making sure I'm getting some
yoga in every week, too, just to stay
mobile, you know, stretch this uh old
man body out. So, we've talked a lot
about what you should be focused on. I
also think it's important to have a
notto-do list. Some things that are on
my notto-do list, and these may sound a
little bit weird, no eating after 8:00
p.m., no extreme fullness. I know
sometimes when I get stressed, you know,
it's nice to just go and devour a bunch
of food, but the truth is I eat too
much. Again, I wake up the next day just
feeling like [\h__\h] and super groggy,
which affects my next morning's routine.
No computer or phone in my bedroom,
using my bedroom to just get a great
sleep, which is a key aspect obviously
to deep work. And just making sure that
overall like no energy vampires, no
people that are going to stress me out
unnecessarily. If at the end of the day
I look back on my day and there's
certain things that have just caused
unnecessary [\h__\h] you know, I'm
probably going to go and just add those
to my notto-do list and make sure I'm
more locked in, feeling good, and able
to keep on building on the success of
the day before. This can seem super
rigid, okay? But the truth is once you
get into the habit of this, I believe
that the constraints that I've just
outlined actually breed a lot of
creativity. The reality is that as
founders, our businesses are changing
all the time. There's always a thousand
things we can do. And so, it's useful to
have a schedule you can rely on. So, you
can focus and block out distractions and
do the best work of your life. 5:00 p.m.
It's time to repeat this whole process
all over again. Winding down my day,
taking my evening routine super strict
so that I'm able to get a really good
sleep that night. The biggest hack to
going and making sure that you are as
creative as possible in your deep work
session is really just making sure that
you're getting a great sleep. I'm sure
you've all been there, right? Those days
that you're just not slept very well.
It's almost like you're drunk. And the
last thing you want to be doing is
trying to create a masterpiece the next
morning drunk. The magic here comes from
not just doing this schedule one day,
one week, one month, or one year. I've
stuck to this schedule for a decade.
This is more or less how I go and embark
on every single day of my life. Those
constraints that I give myself in this
routine allow me to be super creative
because I don't need to guess at what
I'm going to do the next day. It's more
or less this routine every single day.
You know, making sure that you're taking
care of yourself. The afternoons, you're
giving yourself time to then go and
chart out your next day all over again
and just repeating this cycle. So, I
know I've just given you a lot of stuff
here in terms of my AM, PM, and evening
routine. But the good news is I've gone
and synthesized all of this information
in a deep work routine system, which you
can find in the link in the description.
I've gone and given you a checklist of
all the core aspects from this video so
you can go and implement it in your life
today. Intentional founders have an
intentional deepwork system, and we've
just covered what that looks like. Now,
it's up to you to go and implement this
so that you can build the intentional
business you're after and get more done
in four hours than most people get done
in 4 days.