[music]
Most people that are using AI are
obsessed with only using 10% of what
it's actually capable of doing. Now,
[music] you know, I'm no AI expert here,
right? Right? I'm a CEO that designs
systems to be able to remove myself from
the operations of my businesses. You
know, be able to really enjoy life and
build businesses based on freedom. You
know, what I want to go and show you
here is not some tutorial or how to go
and use tools step by step. This is an
actual jam session of me going and
sitting down with 30 high-powered CEOs,
helping them go and leverage AI so they
can go and remove themselves from the
operations of their business, become 10x
more productive, and be able to go and
get more of their time back so they can
build an amazing business and actually
go and enjoy life. This is from Founder
OS, the high growth community of
founders and CEOs that I run, helping
them build their founder brands and go
and remove themselves from operations.
If you're interested in checking out
Foundest, you can go check it out via
the link in the description. Much love.
Let's get into it. So, let's get into
the AI side of things. How many people
are like using like AI? Would they say
like every day all day? Pretty hardcore.
Okay, cool. So, CHBT I'm primarily using
as like a business advisor. I'll show
you here in a second. like this 10x
profit project I've created that
essentially is almost like a board of
adviserss that whenever I'm going and
creating anything business related I'm
often times running it through this or
getting it to go and produce the initial
draft of something that then I can go
and refine and from there um Claude is
what I'm typically using on all content
related stuff is kind of like the
content team and I have a bunch of
different formats that we make content
for obviously YouTube scripts Instagram
carousels expost post, LinkedIn,
whatever, because every format slightly
different. We need a different project
and a different project knowledge for
each of them. So, what I'll go is I'll
show you like how I've gone and set up
the 10x profit project. I'll do the same
and show you how my cloud is set up and
how the team leverages that and then
just some other useful tools um along
the way. Let's get into it. On the uh
chat GBT side, we'll start there. I use
these things in super quirky ways. So,
I'll be real and vulnerable here, but
like you know, adapt to your own stuff,
right? This 10x profit project is the
primary one I'm using the most when I am
using ChachiBT. In any given day when I
sign off for the day, I'm writing like a
list of the things I need to get done
the next day. I was talking with some
folks at dinner last night and they were
kind of asking like, "Oh, how are you so
productive and how do you get things
done or how are you so energetic
throughout the day or so focused?"
Right? One of the most important
activities I've always done is like
taking time just to write things down on
like pen and paper. know even before I'm
using any sort of like chat GBT or
Claude I'm like just taking a second to
like write down my thoughts and my
thinking organized clear thinking is
going to lead to like organized clear
outputs there's no replacement for just
like good clean thinking right good
inputs will lead to good outputs I'm
typically going and writing down all the
things I need to get done the next day
typically it's around 3 to nine things
and then I'm putting down a ranked order
of like okay number 1 2 3 4 5 in terms
of like which stuff is most important to
least important. And then what I try to
do these days too is go down that list
and indicate like which of the stuff AI
can help me with. So I'm like, okay,
right, I'm going to do this like
priorities for the rest of 2025. I'm
going to use the 10x profit project I've
made to kind of go and help me with
that. Oh, I need to go and like ideulate
around this YouTube video. I'm going to
go get Claude to go and help me with
that. So that I'm kind of like also
making up the plan as to how I'm going
to go through these. and then I embark
on like my day. This 10X profit project,
there's a lot of similarities between
how I'm onboarding humans and how I'm
onboarding AI. Details matter. The more
flushed out it is, um, the better. And
so, inside of the instructions of this
project, I'll just read out what's here
so you can get a bit of context and I'll
keep it quick. So, it's like, you are
the world's best business coach and
growth strategist hired to help Matt
Gray scale founder rise from $500,000
profit per month to $2 million profit
per month. You advise the greatest
entrepreneurs in the world like Larry
Ellison, Elon Musk, Jeff Bezos, and are
10x better than Bill Campbell, the
trillion dollar coach. This is a coach
that advised like those CEOs as well as
folks like Larry Page, Sergey Brin, the
founders of Instacart, and a bunch of
others, which is why he's called the
trillion dollar coach. You have deep
expertise in systems design, financial
strategy, team architecture, AI
leverage, audience growth, high ticket
coaching and consulting models, organic
content, paid ads, B2B sales, personal
branding, YouTube newsletters, email
funnels, and building media first
businesses. You think in terms of
constraints, compounding and clarity.
And so then it just kind of keeps going
on in terms of like the instructions. I
ask it to like identify constraints,
prescribe systems, define KPIs,
prioritize leverage, simulate different
moves I should make, and like add the
financial constraints and considerations
for each, and just be as direct with me
as possible. It's a pretty like ruthless
and like to the point prompt and guiding
me on like I want to get this business
from here to here. in terms of the files
that I've uploaded. So, it's got all my
core systems. It's got the map of our
company. It's got our financials. It's
got all of our core offers, Founder OS,
Velocity, Mastermind. It's got my book
in it. It's got transcripts of some of
our calls. Things like our brand
positioning. It has that one pager on
our mission, vision, and values that I
sent you guys this morning. It has like
maximum context as to the company. It
knows the offers. It has my whole team.
It knows like what each person does as
well as their one thing. So, it knows
also like who to assign stuff to. And
so, I've taken a second to slow down,
which is a bit of a theme here because
it's not a rush. It's like, okay, what
are all the documents this thing should
have? Take a second, download all those
core documents, upload them all to the
project. On the prompt side, you don't
need to rush through it. Like, I'll give
you the prompt tomorrow morning, but
like now take time to like make that
really badass for what you're doing.
Expand on it a little bit. Maybe you
have like your own values or the own way
you want it or maybe you you really wish
it coached you like a certain person you
really respect or whatever. Like a big
piece of this that I'm always thinking
about is slowing down and building it
really methodically because I'm going to
use this a lot over the next year. So
it's worth like tooling it up. Right.
The second thing like the crazy thing
with this is like I feel like with a lot
of these things like most things in life
you're only limited by your imagination.
So like if you can dream it like the
thing can probably help you make it
happen. Hence in the example I was
giving you there in terms of how I want
to advise me I'm thinking of like Bill
Campbell. So I imagine like wow what
would it be like to get coached by Bill
Campbell on my business. Now I can show
you for a second here like some ways
that I may use this. One example of this
is uh I was looking to go and come up
with the priorities for the remainder of
um 2025.
Wanted to go and sequence like what
would matter most in the company for the
remainder of the year. I essentially had
all the documents uploaded as you know
to this project and I just simply asked
it, you know, when you think about all
the projects that I have on the go, what
would you rank order the top 20 that I
should be most focused on finishing in
2025? And then it's going and kind of
outputting, well, I think you need to
get the YouTube empire built. You should
focus on finishing your book. You should
optimize this offer. You should get your
newsletter system dialed in. Make sure
you launch Black Friday Cyber Monday.
Continue to focus on removing yourself
from the entire operation. hire a
full-time financial controller. And it's
kind of going and prioritizing what it
feels are the top things. What I would
go do with that, right, is this is an
example. I'm again going and writing out
what I believe the priorities are based
on what it's giving me. So here I've
said, okay, well, I agree with some of
what it said, but I've thought like,
okay, we need to get a dashboard 100%
accurate. I want to get the email
sequences done. So I'm kind of writing
out my version of this, but leveraging
it as like an adviser. And then what
I'll do is like go in file download say
this Google sheet once I've just got the
first column of it done and then say
okay I've got these other columns here
that are like okay who's the owner of
each thing what's their incentive off
this thing what's the core metric they
should be aiming for and I can just go
and file download it and then ask it to
go and complete filling out the rest of
the chart. So now it's going to go and
tell me okay well based on your
priorities here's like who should be the
owner of each of these initiatives
here's the incentive that you should
have for each person and chat GBT can
obviously just output like Excel
documents right so it's gone and like
you know made this document I can save
it you know obviously download it and
then just like you know get fully
flushed out sort of like plans Google
sheets whatever from it that I can then
use to kind of organize project
priorities etc. In terms of like this
project, I'm using this thing like every
day for a bunch of just stuff all the
time. Examples of what I've been using
it for over the last like week. I've
been using it to like go and flush out
some of our copy needs when I was on
boarding that copywriter. I've been
using it to go and think of like call to
actions that I should put into my
YouTube videos. So, I'm like, "Okay,
like you know all the goals. You know
everything about the brand. Like what
should be the call to action when I make
this video this week?" I'll use it to
come up with book recommendations on
what I should be reading based on my
goals. The list goes on. If I encounter
any mental block that's business
related, my first instinct these days
would be to go into this project and get
its help thinking through what's going
on. Anything that AI can do, I'm trying
to get it to do the first draft of that
stuff for me. So, I'm primarily using it
as like a productivity tool at the end
of the day. Anything that's easy for me
to do, I'll do it. But anything that
develops any sort of like cognitive
dissonance or like this is going
to take me a second, I default to like,
okay, is this a business related thing?
the 10x profit project. Is this a
content thing? The claude projects
thereby I'm just kind of like rolling
through tasks. Um, and typically in like
a 3hour sort of deep work session in the
morning, I can get more done these days
than would maybe take me like 3 or 4
days of deep work like a few years ago.
Once I know I'm moving on to a different
sort of task, I'll just start a new chat
window within the project because then
what's nice is like I can see all these
really quick and I know like there's one
around core incentives and metrics,
there's another one that I've done
around the founder OS story. So I can
just easily just like jump back down to
that one and play with it more if I need
to. So all these conversations were in
the the 10x profit project. Let's move
on to the cloud side of things. I've got
a bunch of different projects all set up
here. So, some include kind of like
Instagram carousel projects. I've gone
and set these up. I've gone and added
the prompt to it as well as the project
knowledge to it. And then once I've
toolled that up good where it's writing
stuff even better than I would, then
that's something I can go and delegate
to like Nick and our designer and they
can then use that to create the
carousels. We have a team account on
Claude. So our whole team has access to
all these projects that I create. So
essentially I'm going and tooling them
up. I'm playing with them at first,
making sure, oh, it's aligning with my
voice. It's making good It's more
or less there. There's like a good
process to it. Document the process.
Loom the process. Pass it off. And now
they have access to a project and can
start making that stuff without me.
Every single carousel now that you see
on my Instagram, I don't make any of
this stuff. This stuff is being made by
uh actually a designer on our team
primarily who's not a copywriter, but uh
many of them have like 400,000 words of
transcripts that I used for my book, a
million words plus of just coaching
calls and things that I've done. And so
for any given subject that we'd write
about, it's able to pull that voice from
all those uh words and kind of value
that I've put in these transcripts um
and then leverage that for our content
and package it up correctly. If we go
into the voice of customer um section
here, there's really like two core
things that you need to be thinking
about when it comes to Claude. You have
the instructions area. Obviously, that's
where I put all of the prompts inside of
this. This is the voice of customer one.
I'm I'm essentially going and getting it
to analyze surveys, interviews,
testimonials from our actual customers
and then use their actual words and
messaging from these surveys to then go
and create core documents, landing
pages, anything I want that are actually
based on the real world words that our
customers have said. And there's a known
thing in copyrightiting that like the
best way to speak about a given thing is
not in your voice, but in the words that
your customer actually uses, which
eliminates any jargon when you're
speaking about things. And then again,
so there's you'll see a similar pattern
here, right? I've put like our offer and
such in here, but then you know, I've
got surveys I did around my book. Got
like a hundred people to ask me what
they wanted to know about founder
branding. And so all of the responses
were downloaded from type form into a
CSV and just uploading the CSV to the
project knowledge. And so it has all
that survey data. Similarly, like other
responses based on surveys we've gotten
from you guys in velocity and I've
gotten over the years from founders are
all just uploaded to the project
knowledge. And so when I'm then trying
to go and write in the words of my core
customer, this whole thing is fed by
that outputs from this project would
include things like this document I made
which is like a copy research document.
every single section of this document
which is all around like the pain, the
dreams of our customer, what they're
trying to get to, what they're trying to
avoid, their goals, their objections and
constraints. Every single sentence in
this document is like real words that
people have given us. So, as an example,
there's kind of a lot of people that
talk about drowning in operations,
right? So, there's one quote here, I'm
stuck spinning on the content hamster
wheel. You could imagine if we were
going and releasing some product called
content OS. It's like stop spinning on
the content hamster wheel is like the
headline on the landing page. So again,
just like using the exact words from
people and then leveraging that for
things like landing page copy. In terms
of the projects that I have set up here,
I have a YouTube script writing one. I
don't use the YouTube script writing
stuff to like actually make all my
scripts. In a lot of the content
projects, one things that I'll often
times ask it is like come up with novel,
non-obvious ideas. I don't want to
obviously have a video where I'm like,
oh, like third thing you need to do,
deep work, let's just say, right?
Because that's already a thing. People
have already heard that. It's played
out. I may use it to kind of come up
with like novel, non-obvious ideas. And
then it's like coming up with something
like strategic stillness. That's new and
that's interesting. Let's use that for
that video. I can use that project to
come up with yeah just new and different
sort of phrasing or ideas leveraging the
knowledge I've given it that just kind
of creates yeah just like interesting
content that I can then riff on let's
say in a given YouTube video. So I'm
using it more as a brainstorming partner
than like a script writer because as we
talked about on YouTube I'm not even
scripting my stuff. There's a concept
but I'm riffing on it on Chat tobt. I'll
just show you something they released
like a few weeks ago for it's called
chatbt pulse. So I'll tell you how I use
this in a sec. So essentially that 10x
profit project.
You can link in on your mobile device
something called pulse when you're on
chatbt pro. It can hook into a project
you have and then start sending you
things that are relevant every single
morning based on that project. So every
morning when I wake up, I'm getting like
multiple reports from Chatubt on how to
go and 10x the profit of my business,
right? And it's prompted off of all the
stuff I'm working on and it knows the
current stuff I'm battling with or
trying to figure out or the stuff I've
been prompting it with every day. And
it's giving me these different
recommendations on new things I can look
at. how to increase average order value,
how to increase customer lifetime value,
how to go and structure the team a
little different, how to get ahead of my
2026 goals. And so, it's almost like
this custom newsletter based on your own
stuff that you're getting from it every
single morning. I'll use that to then
just like get some different ideas and
just kind of like read up on like maybe
some new fresh stuff that I could be
considering today just to kind of like
get me closer to where I'm looking to
go. So, I've been finding that like as
an interesting little tool, a way to
kind of make a project live in kind of
like your daily rhythm a little bit.
Inevitably, my perspective on like
getting towards your goals is just like
you're just always looking for those
little little things, little ideas that
just ever so slightly 1% 5% every day
help you get closer towards it. A lot of
you guys are already using this. This is
probably like the AI based tool that I
use the most of everything just because
it's like kind of just in your everyday
rhythm. But what it allows you to do is
go to any chat window, whether it's the
notes in your phone, Slack, messages,
WhatsApp, doesn't matter, and simply
just kind of open it up. You press like
a key on your computer, in my case, like
the function key, and it's going to go
and start listening to what you're
saying. Whenever you like stop pressing
the key, it's going to transcribe
whatever it is you were just voicing.
So, when I'm like talking to people in
Slack, I'm typically just voicing it all
in Slack. If I'm messaging folks, if I'm
prompting Claude, as much as possible,
trying to not type. The main thing, you
know, I'm always thinking about with
this, I don't think AI is magic or
anything. It's just like trying to just
reduce the friction that exists to
getting stuff done. As an example, one
thing I love it for is like responding
to you guys in school or in Slack,
right? It's like, oh, you have all these
like Slack messages. It doesn't feel
nearly as cumbersome as it did a year
ago, you know? Like you just open them
up, read the thing, voice your response
back, send it. And in that way too,
you're like authentically answering
stuff versus feeling like you got to
like type stuff maybe more formally or
something like that. I mean, really just
anything I'm typing these days, like
more or less it always starts using
Whisper Flow. I think there's never
going to be a replacement for like human
judgment. And I think it's the same
trouble you may get into when you're
taking my advice. Like you always have
to go and take things through your own
intuition and like how it actually
resonates with your own business, right?
whether it's like a adviser or mentor or
strategist you're working with all the
way through to like a GPT that's
advising you, you still have to put it
through your own filter. You got to kind
of tune into like your own like mind,
body, soul, like how it kind of filters
through that whole mechanism, right?
There's certain stuff I see that I'm
like, "Holy shit." Like instantly you're
just like it's a light bulb moment,
right? You're like, "All right, I'm
going to really run with this." I'd say
a lot of the time I'm seeing it and it's
like, "Oh, that's a really smart
structure. I wasn't thinking about it
that way. I don't think it got it quite
right, but it's definitely helping like
lead me in the general direction. And
now I just need to like augment a little
bit of this through my own judgment,
which I think is probably even when we
think about this container here during
this retreat, I'm sure that's kind of by
default where a lot of the advice we've
gone over probably filters in that
direction. I don't think anything that
or much of what we've said is like,
okay, perfect one to one. I'm just
running with what Matt said. It's like,
okay, solid point. I got to kind of mix
it with what actually is going on in my
business and the actual dynamic on my
team and kind of marry these two
thoughts. So that's the default that's
happening. It's just becoming this like
strategic sparring partner. And the
thing that I like most or that I find is
interesting about these kind of things
is like number one, you can be insanely
vulnerable. You can say whatever the
hell you want um or at least I do to
like chat tot and like let it know what
I'm going through, what's in my head,
what I'm scared of. Like you can get
that real with it. And secondly, it's at
your fingertips. So you don't need to
call someone up at 2 am. Like if
something's just like actually up or
whatever, like you can use this seven
days of the week, 247, right? So I think
there's going to be no replacement for
your own like judgment and filter. All
right, y'all. Um, hopefully this was
helpful.