You can't run a 2025 business with a
2015 playbook. So many CEOs are stuck in
firefighting meetings and just dealing
with the problem of the day. But there's
a new kind of CEO that's focused on
building trust, distribution, and
leverage. I call it the content CEO. And
I want to break down the four limiting
beliefs that you need to get over to be
able to go and build your content CEO
stack. So let's talk about the old CEO
versus the content CEO. A lot of
founders out there, they're building
businesses and they're built on a house
of cards. It's all reliant on you at the
end of the day, not having the right
systems for building authority, for
building up distribution and leverage.
It feels rickety and often times you end
the day, you're looking yourself in the
mirror and you're thinking, man, I don't
know if I can go another week like this.
Now, the new CEO, which is the content
CEO, understands the importance of
building leverage around them. So, there
are four stages to becoming a content
CEO. So, let me just draw this up for
you. What we've got, we're looking to
grow brand and leverage. So, it looks
something like this. You've got brand
over here, got leverage down here. And
when you get these four playbooks in
place, you're essentially going and
gradually increasing your brand
awareness and increasing leverage in
your business. Now, most founders that I
speak with are doing it the old way,
which leaves you somewhere down here.
And where I'm trying to get you
throughout this video is grow you to
this point here where you've got each of
these four systems nailed and you've got
maximum brand resonance with not having
to do it all yourself because you've got
the right leverage in place. So the
first system now is your authority
engine. So let's go and get that built
into place. So now you're worried that
no one's going to be listening to you.
But the truth is you just need to know
the right way to go and build authority
online. You know, when I go back and
look at my own content journey, I didn't
get so caught up in how many people were
listening. I first focused on just
getting the reps in. Now, whether it was
starting my newsletter or beginning
YouTube, what I focused on was I'm going
to do this thing 100 times that I'm
proud of, 100 newsletters that I'm proud
of, 100 YouTube videos that I'm proud
of, and at the end of the day, if I do a
hundred of these things, the score will
take care of itself. Sure enough, with
my newsletter as an example, after doing
a 100 reps, I grew that newsletter to
over 182,000 people. Or on YouTube here,
after about 96 reps, you know, we've now
grown the YouTube to about 172K subs.
And so, it was this focus on the
practice, on the work at hand, and
creating something that I was genuinely
proud of that led to all the results,
not this overconerning or obsession
around, you know, subscribers,
followers, and all these vanity metrics.
When you show up and just do the thing,
you get the content out there. You start
to build some level of attention. That
attention then leads to leads. Leads
leads to cash flow. And cash flow gives
you the ability then to reinvest in your
content, your team, and make even more
exceptional content. And that flywheel,
the authority flywheel, just keeps on
ripping. You know, I've listened to my
audience and their favorite type of
content is when they just get to see me
live helping other founders. And so this
became a content idea we came up with
which we call our whiteboard sessions.
I've had the opportunity to sit down
with founders like Blake Roa, Ali Abdal
and go and chop it up and bring you the
audience into the room while I'm
actually helping these founders. Now
sure enough, people come in the room,
they see how I'm helping others and then
they want to go and join Founder OS. And
you get it. This is the authority
flywheel at work. When you go and create
this in your business, it's going to
look probably a little bit different
than mine. But what I want you to look
out for is number one, just get started
with whatever content excites you today.
Two, listen to your customers and
understand, you know, what is it that
they're really coming to you for? Ask
them even what content that you've
created is their favorite. And then from
there, number three is just double down
on a few formats that you're seeing
work. You don't need to do everything
all at once. Ideally, over time, you
triple down on just a few formats that
you love. For me, it's things like deep
systems, these whiteboard sessions, and
behind the scenes. I keep it simple.
Those three formats get the job done.
And so, you want to think about what are
the three content formats that are going
to help your authority flywheel get
ripping and then let them run. So, now
you know you're worried that you're not
even sure what to go and put online,
right? So, this is where your content
waterfall system comes into place. So,
you say you don't have enough time, but
the truth is you really just don't have
the right systems in place. So, we're
going to dive into how to actually go
and structure your content to get this
right. Every business these days is a
media company. You know, you need to
build content to build an audience to go
and build trust at scale. And this isn't
something that you can just go and
delegate out the gate. You know, you
need to deeply understand, you know, the
importance of this because content isn't
an extra part of your business. It's an
essential part of what you're building.
An example of these systems at scale are
my content waterfall system. you know,
the ability to go and take one YouTube
video and turn it into 26 other amazing
pieces of content across my business.
All right, so sometimes I'm a little bit
better at showing you than telling you.
So, let me just show you exactly how
this content waterfall system looks like
in place. So, first things first, you've
got your pillar piece of content as an
example. That may be a long form piece
of content like a YouTube video. So,
we've got that at the top. Now that one
YouTube video can become 26 plus other
pieces of content if you do this right.
So as an example on the short form video
side that YouTube video can become three
IG reels. It can become three Tik Tok
videos
and become three YouTube shorts. This is
all by taking the core moments in that
pillar piece of content and then just
cutting them up for these short form
video platforms. You can also go and
take all of that script that you had in
place for the YouTube video and turn
that into amazing content for platforms
like LinkedIn. And so one, you know,
13-minute YouTube video may become three
LinkedIn posts. It can become three X
threads. And it may also become a
newsletter a few weeks later. Now, it
doesn't end there. You also can go and
obviously take that YouTube video and
distribute it onto platforms like
Spotify and then also onto things like
Apple. Systems like this help me
maximize my time and effort. You know, I
can film this one video right now and
over the next month I have a calendar
for Instagram, Tik Tok X, and LinkedIn
filled up. That's the beauty of being
able to repurpose your effort so you're
not on some content hamster wheel. But
to do this, we probably just need to
manage our priorities different. What
I've learned over the years is that, you
know, most CEOs can get the majority of
their work done in four focused hours. I
remember hearing this from Toby Lucky,
the CEO and founder of Shopify, about a
hundred billion dollar business at this
point. Is it that most people just need
4 hours a day to get their core task
done? So, your question may be, well,
Matt, what the heck am I going to do in
those four hours? I like to break down
those four hours into four key aspects.
Number one is strategic decision-making.
two is content creation and systems.
Three is your team growth and strategy.
And then four is you have your revenue
generation period. When you think about
these four hours, right, it's being able
to then go and batch that time at the
right time of day. For me, those 4 hours
are most critical between about 7:00
a.m. and 11:00 a.m. every single day. If
I don't get that uninterrupted time
first thing in my morning, I'm probably
screwed that day. Now, with the founders
and CEOs I talk with all the time, this
is one of the first core improvements
they need to make so that they're
actually blocking off that period of
time to get these four key aspects done.
On the team side, right, this gives you
an opportunity to schedule any of those
key meetings you have. So, every week,
as an example, I have a level 10 meeting
with my core leadership team, a chance
to go over our scoreboard, go over key
metrics, and then any issues,
opportunities, challenges, or
constraints we're currently experiencing
and put our heads together to solve
them. Now, from there, we break off and
we meet again in another week. Now, on
the content side, it comes down to
things like your content waterfall
system. Being able to create one pillar
piece of content that turns into 26
other pieces of content. This is what's
going to allow you to go and get the
maximum time and effort out of what you
pour into content. Now, on the revenue
generation side, you know, revenue cash
flow is the lifeblood of your business.
and without being able to pay attention
to this aspect for about an hour a day.
You may be able to get a couple weeks
by, but sure enough, you know, something
blows up on your sales team or you have
some issue with customer success. And
so, it deserves your daily attention to
make sure that you're moving the needle
forward. When you take this approach,
you're not running on some content
hamster wheel, giving up, then getting
back on the train, then giving up, which
is what so many founders do. With this
system in place, you have, you know,
revenue being generated, the right team
in place. You have time every day to
make those key strategic decisions while
also giving yourself the space to think
about amazing content and then show up
with energy, whether it's on camera or
writing on platforms like X and
LinkedIn. So now you're going to go and
create all this content, but you're
asking, Matt, how's this even going to
go and drive me revenue? So let's get
into system number three, your content
to revenue bridge. So the content to
revenue bridge looks something like
this, right? You've got a kind of funnel
going from awareness at the top. You got
interest, you've got consideration here,
and then people inevitably making a
decision. Now, when you get each of
these four stages right, it's like a
slippery slope, right? People go from
awareness up here all the way through to
transaction. Cool thing is when you get
it right, people are like, "Damn, I
don't know how I got on this sales call,
but your process is smooth as hell." And
often times I think that when you have
this right, it's super indicative of how
great your delivery is going to be as
well. So it's worth investing in getting
that slope made in a way that's
frictionless, seamless, elegant, and
beautiful for folks. So awareness is
going to take place on platforms like
YouTube, IG, X, and LinkedIn. So on the
awareness side, right, you want to make
sure that you're creating content that
actually converts. And the best way to
do this is to understand from your
actual customers what are their main
problems, challenges, obstacles, goals,
and biggest dreams. From there, when you
survey them and understand the responses
to these questions, you can go and come
up with hundreds of content ideas that
literally go and solve that stuff. When
I go and look at my best content across
all platforms, I see that how-to videos
as an example convert the best because
I'm actually just going and educating
people and helping them with the core
problem that they brought up to me. From
there, if they want to go and work with
me in a bigger way, they can go and
convert. This is where you're just going
and capturing folks attention and
bringing them to the next stage, which
is interest to move between awareness to
consideration. Right? It takes things
like CTAs and lead magnets. Okay, this
is where you're going and say creating a
video on deep work and then people can
go and actually download a deep work
checklist via the link in the
description. Now, on the interest side,
the key thing is then making sure that
you're converting people to a newsletter
into a call. And the best way to do that
is with the right CTA system in place
under any video. As an example that I
put out, I have a core call to action
that then leads people to a lead magnet
that relates directly to what that
person has just watched in the video.
From there, I'm able to capture their
email, their phone number, and sometime
between, you know, today and 2 years
from now, most of those people will
eventually convert to the next stage,
which is consideration, where you're
building more of a rich relationship
with that consumer. And so the best way
to do this that I've seen is a
newsletter. Now don't get caught up on
what platform to create on. You could
use Beehive, Kit, HubSpot, doesn't
matter. All these platforms are great.
The most important thing is that you're
actually just consistent and get going.
Now this all leads then to decision,
right? Inevitably, you're putting that
newsletter out there. A lot of people
are like, damn, I want to work with this
person. And sure enough, they end up
either on sales calls or on a landing
page and converting to your product or
service. We want to make sure that we're
giving people all the right information,
right? We're helping make sure that they
understand exactly how we can help them.
Make sure that we're linking the content
they just watched to the product or
service that we're selling and make it
easy for them to say yes. This is why I
think it's really important as well with
your content that you're not just
chasing vanity metrics. What happens is
as a founder, if you're just chasing
likes or engagement, you just start
creating a lot of viral content. And
what is viral content? Well, it probably
has a massive total addressable market
and it's going to appeal to a lot of
beginners and just general folks, but a
lot of our businesses, right, as
founders are more niche. You know,
you're going after that person that's
making 50K plus or you're trying to
close big businesses. That kind of
content is going to look a lot
different. It's not going to have
necessarily mass appeal. It's going to
be more specific to a certain kind of
problem or obstacle. And so, the core
thing is to actually look at your profit
at the end of the day. How much cash is
your content actually driving? You know,
cash in bank or profit per month is
going to be the ultimate metric of your
content, not likes, not followers, not
engagement. Those things are important
to consider, but at the end of the day,
you want to actually look at your bottom
line. You get these four stages right,
you get your pieces of this all mapped
out, and you have a slippery content to
revenue bridge. The more seamless your
content to revenue bridge, the more
easily you're converting people from
attention all the way through to
transaction. And so a lot of founders at
this stage now are like, "Okay, well, do
I have to do everything myself? Hell
no." Right? We're going to get the team
multiplication system built into your
business to get that final piece of
leverage in place.
I want to tell you, as part of the
content CEO stack, you need a team to
multiply your impact. And so you're
probably wondering, "Well, Matt, what
team should I create?" Well, what you
want to do is think about that content
to revenue bridge and the people that
you need in place for each stage of it
long term. Most of you are like this,
right? It's just you versus the world.
Well, no more of that. That is the old
way. Let's get in to the content CEO
way. Here it comes down to your team
multiplication system. Okay. Now, when
it comes to your team, you've got really
three core elements. the creators, we
have the distributors, and then we have
the strategists. So, got creators, we've
got distribution here, and then we've
got strategy. All right? So, your
creators are going to be people like a
writer and an editor. Okay? Depending on
whether obviously you're making, you
know, post for X and LinkedIn or you're
making stuff for YouTube, IG, and Tik
Tok. So for me on my team, you know, I
have writers on my team like Niels. I
have video editors on my team like OT
and Memo. On the distribution side, the
key thing here, and I think it's one of
the most valuable players when you're
building up your own media empire, is a
social media manager. So many people
just think they can go and hire some VA
and this is just some simple role, but I
got to tell you, I think it's one of the
more complex roles in any organization.
And the reason being is that that person
as you're building up your media company
is in charge of actually going and
distributing all that content across all
of the different platforms flawlessly
and oftentimes doing it 7 days a week. I
really encourage you to go and value
your social media manager, right? This
is essentially your chief distribution
officer of the media company you're
building. Also, shout out to Nick on the
founder side for all his hard work. So
on the strategy side, this is where
folks like in my case it's me and my boy
Diego. The key aspects of strategy is
that we're looking at the data, titles,
packaging, thumbnails. We're taking into
consideration where people are
converting from, why they're converting.
We're taking into account, you know,
data that we're getting from our sales
team to understand what content should
we be creating next. In addition to
that, we're also getting into the
details of planning out shoots. You
know, right now I'm in Lisbon, Portugal.
We're shooting 10 pieces of content over
the next 7 days. No small feat, but it's
made possible because we've got the
right structure in place, the right
team, and you know, we're all owning our
given areas. So, the old way is just
you. We definitely want to scrap that
immediately. The new way is thinking
about your team in these three stages.
You get this right. You're creating
content that you're proud of, that's
converting, all the while being able to
live a calm, peaceful life. It's this
team in place that ensures that all the
content you're seeing from me is
distributed seamlessly and that we're
able to constantly raise the bar. If I
was going alone, I would be screwed. And
so, it takes a team to build a media
empire and it takes a team to be able to
stay in the game long term. If it all
comes down to you, you know, I worry
that you're not going to be able to
stick with it. And like most great
investments in life, you know, they come
over the long term. And so the key thing
is longevity and being able to stay in
the game. And that's exactly why having
the right team in place is so critical.
So yes, you're going to build the team,
but that doesn't mean that you just
totally let it all go, don't pay any
attention to it, and just ignore it
going forward. You know, for me, brand
matters. And as a founder brand, you
know, you know uniquely exactly how you
want to show up, the kind of topics you
love to talk about and the ones that you
don't want anything to do with. And so
it's important that as you start hiring
these people that you're still involved,
right? Especially on the strategy side
and the ideation side. Essentially, my
involvement on my team is I'm kind of
like the chief detail officer, right?
Making sure that as we're ideulating
different subjects, I have like the
final green light on stuff that we're
going to move forward with and the kind
of things that I don't think quite
encapsulate our brand. Because beyond
content, beyond views, beyond cash flow,
I think the most valuable thing that
we're all building are brands. Brands
inevitably are the emotional connection
that you build between yourself and your
customers. And no one's going to know
that as well as you, the founder. You
can no longer say you don't have time
because now you got the content
waterfall system. You can no longer say
that no one's going to listen to you
because you have the authority flywheel.
You can no longer say, you know, how's
this even going to make me money?
Because you've got the content to
revenue bridge. And you can no longer
say, "Oh, I'm just going to have to do
this all alone." Because you've got the
team multiplication system in place.
Now, if you want help going and actually
implementing this in your business, I
think the logical step for you to do is
go right down to the description right
now and get my content CEO playbook. Me
and my team spend around 10 hours going
and creating a whole implementation
checklist so that you can go and
implement exactly what I'm going over in
this video. It's got a deep dive on my
content strategy, the team that I've set
up, and how I've built authority with my
personal brand over the last four years.
So, go and check that out via the link
in the description. Thanks for watching
this video. I can't wait to see what you
create and let's continue to win