All right, I got a confession to make. I
am more of an artist than an
entrepreneur. I'm not actually that
obsessed with systems for systems sake.
Systems are something I create so that I
can get the freedom to get out of the
[\h__\h] that I hate and focus on the kind
of stuff I love. My inner soul, all
right, is an artist. Someone that loves
free time and space to think, to scheme,
to plot, really to build, too. I talked
to founders all too often. In their
heart of hearts, right, they're an
artist just like me. But somewhere along
the way, you know, they built an offer,
they grew a team, they're making money
now, and they're kind of larping as a
CEO.
But when they actually go and take some
time to reflect, right, they get some
space from their business, they realize
in some way, shape, or form they're kind
of losing themselves. And I think
there's so many of us, right, that at
the end of the day we just want to be
creative, right? We want to build great
products uh with customers that we
genuinely love. We want those uh
products to be sold to a, you know,
smaller group of amazing humans that
really value what we do and will pay us
great prices to do those things so that
we can run, you know, a really like
lean, beautiful, cash-flowing lifestyle
business. Yeah, live vibrant lives, make
an impact, um and have fun. These days
I've been insanely obsessed with you
know, just cranking on Cloud Code,
building dashboards across our entire
team, really going and making sure that
the whole company infrastructure layer
is,
you know, tight, going and building a
new product called Henzo, which allows
people to go and generate a really
pristine LinkedIn content based on the
exact formats and everything I've
learned growing my LinkedIn to over
900,000 followers all organically
without paid ads. Lots going on there,
right? But that all comes from an inner
artist in me. It's not that inherently,
you know, I love the business business
side of things, right? Or the operations
side of things, you know? The systems
side of me is how I feel is just like a
necessity to get out of operations,
which really I kind of hate. I think
it's this combination of being an artist
with an autonomous engine around us. By
artist, I mean someone that every day
gets paid to do the kind of [\h__\h] you
love. I think that's when you're like
really leaning into your own creativity.
My belief in any business, right, is
that, you know, there's a lot of things
that have limits. Your cash flow's maybe
limited initially, your resources maybe
limited, your people are limited. One
thing that's limitless, though, is your
creativity. You know, at any given
moment, you could make a YouTube video
that's so creative it blows up and
change the trajectory of your business.
At any given moment, you could make a
newsletter that's so powerful that it
completely transforms the trajectory of
your business. At any given moment, you
could architect a funnel, right, that's
so good that it changes the trajectory
of your business. And so, that all comes
down to you leaning into that core
artistry. When I think about building
organic content funnels around my
business, going from social to our
founder west.com/apply page, to the
video there, to then the emails that
people get, the flows they get in, all
of that to me is like a work of art. And
when I'm able to pull and push my
artistry kind of into those projects,
that's when I've gotten the greatest
returns in life. Now, that's the artist
side of it. But, the other side is this
autonomous engine. Something I'm
passionate about, right, is really going
and running a lean team, a highly cash
flowing business that's generating over
50% plus margins, making sure that my
business is strictly A players, and
really having it be this like lean mean
machine. You know, somewhere along the
way, I think in entrepreneurship, so
many folks have just been led astray,
right? Running bloated teams, you know,
getting lost in a web of confusion,
overwhelm, night after night wondering
like, "What the hell am I even doing?
How did my business end up like this?"
No, I'm just here to say like there's
definitely a better way because I was
just like that. I'll be honest like even
these days, I find at some points, you
know, I think it's kind of the default
state of where your business is always
by nature kind of pulling itself, right?
It's kind of pulling itself to chaos,
pulling itself to entropy, right? And
you constantly have to kind of be
conscious of that to make sure that it
stays on the path that's kind of your
true north. True north for people I
think that are as part of this channel,
right? Is you know, a business that's
systematized is a small lean team of
weapons. A business that actually fires
you up is, you know, working with
customers you actually love and saying
no to ones that are not a good fit. I
think true north is being able to charge
proper prices so you can have healthy
margins and be able to also build a
brand and build like, you know, your
business as this kind of work of art.
And true north I think is being able to
build amazing content around your
business so that leads are coming
organically. Um you don't need to go and
get on some ads treadmill. Um you don't
need to just rely on referrals or wonder
where your next leads are coming from.
You know, you've got a powerful organic
social media machine, owning your
distribution so that you really control
your destiny as a founder. You know,
I'll be real with you, right? I think
that every business as it grows, right?
You end up scaling up, you end up kind
of going through these stages of
expansion, building out new product
lines, right? And often times you're
going and adding new team members. And
then before you know it, there's like a
few stragglers. I know I'm speaking with
like my COO Dawn and Diego on my team
and you know, you can kind of tell on
the team the kind of people that are
like one of us, right? The kind of
people that care a lot, right? They go
above and beyond, they have an all-in
mentality, um they obsess over quality,
they really um want to pursue like
elevated design and are product
obsessed. And then, you know, every time
you know, you're maybe building a
company of like 16, 17 people, often
times here and there like one or two
folks come along and you're like oh man
not the best of hires, right? Not
someone that's actually in the game.
What I'm passionate about on that side
is overall like having a lean team of
like say 12 or so folks and then having
an autonomous engine that's built across
the company so that by default, right?
We're automating roles versus hiring new
people. More than ever right? It's you
know, kind of viewing hiring as a
failure and finding areas that you can
just automate these aspects. Having an
automated organic content funnel. Having
automated emails around your business.
Having automated follow-ups after sales
calls. Having automated ways of grading
your sales team to make sure that folks
are staying on track and if they're not
being able to remove them and having
automated hiring funnels to bring on new
folks. You know, having automated ways
of going and discovering the best kind
of content that you should make. Having
automated ways of tracking your
financials, tracking the growth across
the business, getting dashboards served
up to you so that you can, you know,
really go and double down on the
patterns across you know, finance, ops,
content, marketing that are going to
keep pushing you forward and doing less
of the stuff that's not working. You
know, versus trying to scramble in your
business and really just kind of burn
out. It's this kind of artist plus
autonomous engine that I think is the
winner. Now, when you have an autonomous
engine in place, right? This is where I
think you get the peace of mind to then,
you know, it kind of is a flywheel back
to the artistry. You're able to rely on
things. You're not dealing with a bunch
of [\h__\h] constantly. And so because
of that you're able to relax, right? And
it's from that state of relaxation, from
that state of calm that you're then able
to go and be your most creative self.
You know, I know for an example, right?
If I were to go and go and film some
videos and that morning I'm dealing with
some fire for some reason, oh my lord,
you know, my ability to go and
articulate myself in a video, I'm
screwed, right? Because my mind is just
scrambled. On the other side, you know,
when my business is, you know, running
nicely, when things are going the way
they should be going, when, you know,
pieces are automated and I'm not dealing
with some random crazy text from someone
on the team, you know, able just to lock
in, to focus, and do what I do best,
making exceptional content, going and
building the business, serving founders,
publishing the book, you name it. I
think it's those two pieces, right, that
we're all really after, right? And the
artistry comes from knowing your zone of
genius and the kind of stuff that you
should be most focused on and getting
the rest of it automated or delegated to
core weapons on your team. And the
autonomous engine comes from really
zooming out from your business for a
second and thinking about
your business as more of a machine. This
machine is there to serve you, right?
It's not there to be run by you and then
simultaneously run you into the ground.
When I go and I think about this,
oftentimes the best tactic I have for
building that autonomous engine is
honestly getting a few core people on
your team in a room, getting a
whiteboard, looking at your business
from a bit of a bird's-eye view across
sales, inquiry, onboarding, awareness,
finance, ops, renewal, and going and
thinking about the different components
in all of these areas and who needs to
own which parts, who's responsible, who
needs to be accountable, who needs to be
consulted with certain decisions, and
who just needs to be informed, who's
going to be the different systems owners
for the different pieces of your
business, and across this machine now,
which parts can you go and automate so
that it doesn't even need any human
involvement. And these days with tools
like Claude Code hooked up with, you
know, Vercel and your HubSpot or
whatever CRM you're using, you know,
you're really limitless in terms of what
you can automate. I have ambitious goals
of, you know, building this founder
infrastructure layer beyond the give,
the whole side of our business that is
automated to founders and to help them
grow their own autonomous engines
because I think this is the future. This
is what I'm most focused on helping
founders with these days. Um I think
that, you know, if this is something
that's interesting to you, this is
exactly what we help people with in
Founderwise and giving you that founder
infrastructure layer so that you can be
an artist with a beautiful autonomous
engine. And so if that's interesting to
you, you want us to go and build your
social media machine, your engine to go
and drive your content through to leads,
you go and check out Founderwise via the
link in the description. We'd love just
to book a call, see if we can help you.
When you get this right, right, you're
moving from just someone that's an
operator in your business, right?
Getting sucked into all the business
[\h__\h] to be able to be more of an
architect. You know, that was my core
theme this year inside of business,
right? It's like really architecting the
kind of business that I love, the life
that I love, and helping others do the
same. So, hopefully that resonates.
Thanks so much for watching.
Sure like and subscribe and I'll see you
in the next one.