If you're someone, you know, following
this channel, you probably follow this
for the idea that we can have it all as
founders, right? We can have a vibrant
life and a vibrant business. We can be
like zen at times and be intense
[\h__\h] We can want to build a
beautiful, calm business while also
wanting to win our category and get the
[\h__\h] after it. we can, you know, want
to, you know, be able to remove
ourselves from the business for three
weeks and come back to a business that's
stronger than when we left while also
when we're in the business and there
with the team wanting to push it, right,
and evolve and dominate. What makes
founders special, right? Is this ability
to kind of straddle two seemingly
desperate worlds, right? And uh, you
know, sometimes I think you may see that
one world of the zen, calm systems dude,
right? Um but yeah, do not be mistaken,
right? There is a crazy [\h__\h]
also behind the scenes. And I think this
is, you know, what I, you know, see, uh,
founders inside of Founder OS, you know,
getting a taste of, you know, that, uh,
that David Gogggins, um, side of things
that's, uh, you know, pushing the
needle, trying to help folks win, um,
really helping people, um, you know,
bring a new level of caliber and
expectations to how they operate and how
their team operates. And it's by setting
those high standards for myself as well
that I've been able to be, you know,
successful over the years.