I wish I had known this earlier in my
career. All right, screw co-founders.
All right, bear with me here for a sec.
You know, one of the quickest ways to
actually go and ruin your wealth is by
getting into business with partners that
don't really fit your values.
Often times founders think that they
need to have co-founders because early
on in a building a business, it's kind
of tricky. And so, it's nice to have
other folks around you.
But from my experience and from the
experience of helping thousands of
founders,
I see so often those relationships that
start really solid
3, 4 years down the line end up becoming
the bane of their existence.
In my first business, I had four other
co-founders. And
while the business ended up being a
success,
the journey was insanely hard. And I
swore to myself after that to never have
co-founders again.
Now,
there's exceptions to the rules. There's
some folks that they
were just destined, right, to have
co-founders. It just works well with
them. But I think when you go and engage
in any sort of co-founder relationship,
you got to understand that this is like
a marriage. And so, make sure that you
date for a while before getting into it.
And default
to no co-founders, right? What would it
look like for you just to build your
thing solo. And then over time, hire an
operations person, hire a tech person,
hire a finance guy.
But consider just going it alone.