I had a call last night with my wealth
advisor. Every month set up a call same
time every month to just invest on a
regular basis. Kind of a
approach that I learned from the book
Psychology of Money
by Morgan Housel, um which is a great
book, side note.
And I was talking to him
and asked him about, you know,
of the folks that are younger that you
work with that have retired, like what
have you seen there?
He's like, "Yeah, you know what?
People end up retiring and I give them 9
months.
In 9 months, they're back doing
something. Doesn't have to be for the
money, but they're doing something. And
the funny thing here, Matt, is they end
up doing stuff that they want, nothing
that they hate, and they end up making
way more money."
And it hit me, you know.
It's interesting to think just pursuing
what you want in life is likely
your most profitable business strategy.