I have created a hundred YouTube videos
and grown my channel to over 172,000
subscribers. It's taken a ton of work in
thousands of iterations. In this video,
I'm going to break down the four
systems, the story system, value system,
production system, and conversion system
to go and blow up my channel and show
you the actual tools, the team, the
systems that made this all possible.
Let's get into it. What I'm going to
show you is what I've learned along this
journey going from level one beginner
all the way through to level 25. So here
on the left you can see where we
started. This is me interviewing my good
friend Steve Gatenna, the founder and
CEO of pray.com. You know I was just
making these videos in the backyard of
my place in Porto Escandido, Mexico. It
was just me, a decent microphone and
just started recording some podcasts
with friends. I had really no idea what
I was doing. But fast forward to today,
after putting all these reps in, this is
where we are now. You know, this video,
how to work less and earn more. It's
close to 600,000 views. We've really
dialed in the artistry around our
videos, the packaging, the titles, the
thumbnails, and what I want to show you
are some of the core things that I've
learned all along this journey, putting
in thousands of reps, learning 10,000
plus little variables that all stack up
to create amazing YouTube videos. Let's
get into the story system. Number one,
you got your hook, right, which is the
first 30 seconds of the video. Two, you
got your middle section where you're
building the value. And then third, the
payoff, right? The end part of the video
that people are sticking around for and
staying retained. Your hook consists of
things like a pattern interrupt,
stopping people in their tracks in the
first 5 seconds, going and giving people
a plan and a promise for why they should
watch the video, and then a little bit
of proof as to why they should listen to
you. When it comes to a perfect hook,
there's a lot of different formulas
here, but here's a couple to inspire
you. You know, if you thought and then
saying something like a common
assumption, what if I told you insert
some pattern interrupt? Formula two here
is here's exactly how I and then getting
vulnerable into a result you've achieved
that's desirable to your audience in a
certain time frame using this unique
system. Lastly, we got the one thing
nobody tells you about insert topic that
changes everything. These are just a few
to kind of get your brain juices going.
One thing you can also do is just go and
study other successful YouTube videos
that you've enjoyed and just go and look
at their first 20 seconds. What did they
say that hooked you? And then what would
that look like in your video content? On
the building stage, you want to start
stacking the value. You know, my goal is
to create videos so valuable that people
go below them and go, I cannot believe
this is free. That's the goal with every
video we do. And we also give away a
free system with every video as well.
We're weaving the story around, you
know, five or seven pieces of value,
let's say. We're teaching these things,
getting into the what, the how, and the
specifics as to what you need to do.
trying to always go deeper with no
fluff, no BS, getting into the actual
systems I use to scale my businesses.
And then at the end, we typically will
have around two CTAs in a video. One
that will drive people to Founder OS if
they're interested in working with me,
my team, and getting more mentorship. Or
we go and drive people to a course CTA
that we have, giving away a free system
or deck that people would find useful so
they can go and implement the given
video system in their business. today
when it comes to the value system. Okay,
this is really why people are going to
keep coming back to you, right? Because
they see it as a good use of their time
to watch your videos cuz they get
something out of it. Number one is you
want to teach, you want to also make an
effort to show the real things, whether
that's mirro boards, decks, show your
team or show your process, right?
Actually show people. Don't just tell
them. And then give. Focus on insane
generosity. Every video I create, I'm
always challenging myself to give as
much as humanly possible to you, the
viewer. So, on the teaching side, that
could be things like frameworks, step by
steps, actionable tactics. You know, I
go and give away, you know, my deep work
system. I give away uh the different
tools that I use to really lock in.
These are just some examples that, you
know, if someone's able to go watch a
12minute video and get that much value,
they're likely to keep coming back. On
the show side, I love to give live
demos. There's many videos that I've
gone and actually gone and shown people
like the 36 systems that I use to run
companies like Founder OS and Herb just
really pushing the envelope with trying
to go and open source the internal
systems that we use at Founder OS so
that you can go and implement them for
yourself. And then it's really about
giving things away. We have core lead
magnets inside of each video that when
people go and enter their name, their
email, their phone number, they can go
get the systems that I go over in each
video. This is a strategy that we love
so that we can go and connect with our
audience in a deeper way inside of my
newsletter where I share one free system
every single week to help you go and
scale your business. So the production
system, this is where we have a few
stages that you need to be aware of. So
pre-production are things like your
scripting, your ideation. You need to
make sure that right there you get that
right. How do you come up with your
ideas? It comes from all over the place,
but I want to distill this into a few
core things you can go and implement on
your channel today. First thing is I see
a lot of founders and they're making
content that isn't built for conversion.
And I think that's a mistake because as
you hope to go and build not just a
personal brand, but a personal media
company, it's important that your
content actually has the ability not
just to reach an amazingly broad
audience, but also to convert a core
audience to your product or your
service. One of the best ways I've seen
to do this is to go and create a survey
that you can go and send to your dream
customers, the people that have actually
purchased your thing and ask them
questions like, "What is your biggest
challenge?" You know, "What is your
biggest goal this year? What is
currently keeping you up at night? And
if you could wave a magic wand, what
problem would you want me to solve?" The
answers to those questions go and give
you a lot of context around your dream
customers core desires, their wants,
their pain points, obstacles,
challenges, and you can download the CSV
file, upload that to ChatGpt, and then
get ChatGBT to come up with a ranked
list from 1 to 100 of the best content
ideas that would appeal to your
audience. Now, let's talk about a couple
tools that you may find useful. If
you're looking to go and find amazing
hooks in titles and packaging for your
YouTube concepts, Creator Hooks is one
great tool to check out. Inside of this,
you'll see something called a hook score
that'll go score the best concepts and
then you can use the AI within the tool
to go and come up with formulas for your
titles and then adapt them to your
niche. Another great tool that I use
pretty religiously is called
oneof10.com. inside of this tool, you
know, you can go and search any given
subject. So, let's just say I was
searching systems. I can go and find a
bunch of different systems related
videos. But what I typically will do is
then go to the filters here and I will
go and say I want to go and look at
people like videos that are 4x plus
outliers. I want views of say over
250,000
um and a video duration of say above say
6 minutes and then I'll look at the top
outlier say from the last 3 months and
so here I can see you know how to build
systems to actually achieve your goals.
This is a 6.5x outlier. So what that
means is that this video performed 6x
better than the average video on this
guy's channel, right? So it's just going
to show me the top videos from given
channels around that subject. So what
I'll typically do then is like say I
like this concept. I can go and save it
to both my ideas, which is kind of like
my titles folder, as well as my
thumbnails folder. And then you got
these awesome bookmarks you can go and
have. So here you can see inside of my
thumbnails, I've just got a ton of ideas
all gone and saved here. So I'm never
running out of ideas around what I want
to create. They're all right there. And
I I can also go and sort these by the
amount of views. So, if I'm looking to
build a video that has a massive total
addressable market and blow up on
YouTube, I can go and look at my outlier
research, my thumbnail folders, my idea
folder, and go and use these folders to
come up with banger titles and thumbs
for my channel. When I talk to different
YouTube experts, it's always that
pre-production stage that if you're not
growing at this, you know, rate you
really wanted to be growing at, that's
where you need to focus more of your
energy because a lot of people skip over
the idea. And truthfully, it's the idea,
title, and thumbnail that are where all
the magic exists. When I first started
on YouTube, I was scripting all my
content. Okay? I would focus on making
12 minute, 30 secondond videos around
2500 words long. I put that into a
Google doc, oftentimes run that Google
doc through a tool called Hemingway,
which would give my script a readability
score. Now, the goal there was to get
the readability score between a grade
five and grade eight readability,
meaning that it was easy to understand
for anyone across YouTube. I didn't want
to use a bunch of jargon or weird
terminology because I want regular
people to be able to understand what I'm
talking about. From there, we now move
forward with the scripting. You know,
I'm typically going creating in Google
Docs, but I also am leveraging Claude
for that. So, inside of Claude, I've
gone and uploaded over a million words
of everything I've created. It's got
300,000 words of my book transcript.
It's got all my course systems,
transcripts of my top YouTube videos, my
top X content, LinkedIn content,
everything. You can see though that I've
also not just uploaded a massive amount
to the Claude database here, right? But
in addition to that, we also have a very
detailed scripting prompt that we use
inside of Claude. You need to make sure
that you're giving it as much details as
possible. This specific prompt is around
nine pages long, getting into everything
from the core avatar we're looking to
target to the goals of the video to the
retention we're going for and to the
core criteria that I want every single
video to have. I can go and put in any
given video I'm looking to create like
how to sell without being salesy as an
example. Let's say that was a video I
wanted to create. Claude is going to go
and help me create a concept and a
script off that using all of the
material that I've ever created around
this specific subject. You know, again,
if you're looking to leverage Claude
properly, I would encourage you to go
and take a lot of pride in the project
knowledge you create within Claude and
also make sure that your prompt is as
detailed as possible. So, here you can
see, you know, Claude's using everything
I've put in the project knowledge here,
you know, doing the research, doing the
heavy lifting here. Lord knows I can't
remember those 1.2 million words all in
my head. So I'm really just using Claude
to be this researcher. You know, on big
teams that I've seen out there, whether
it's Hermosis or Diary of a CEO, you
know, often times these teams are
robust, like 20, 25 people. Candidly,
I'm not looking to build a team that
big. And so being able to leverage AI as
my researcher is a major hack. And so
here you can see it's able to use all
the research and words that I've put
into and bubble them up so we can
deliver it to you with an insane amount
of value here on YouTube. That's just a
quick taste of how we use Claude
production. You know, the key hack here
is to make your production as simple as
possible. You know, I highly recommend
that if you're in one location, you set
up a studio you're proud of, you know,
with your camera, your lighting, and
ideally, you just need to push one or
two buttons to record and get going,
thereby reducing the cognitive load to
record and making the process as simple
and easy as possible. And so, when it
comes then to thinking about the B-roll,
you want to make sure that you've got a
concept laid out and that you likely
have all of the B-roll mapped out as to
what you need to get to make the video
concept as rich as possible. Here you
can see, as an example, our B-roll
folder. We've got B-roll for hiking, me
playing paddle, journaling, baby photos
of me, you know, some of these even
being slightly embarrassing. The key
thing I want you to understand is that
it's important to be meticulously
organized as you're building your video
or studios department in your company.
You don't want you or your team spending
tons of time trying to navigate where
the hell is that file? Where's B-roll
for this? You are a mess and wasting
your time if that's the case. On the
post-production side, this is where it's
all about having the right editor,
content manager that you can hand things
off to. Here's the deal. Working with
editors can be tricky. You're working
with people that are a lot different
than you often times as the creator,
right? They've got their craft, you've
got yours. And so, let me give you a
behind-the-scenes look as to what frame
looks like on our side. So, here you can
see in this video all of these comments
that we've gone and left all across the
different time codes. It's myself and
Diego leaving comments for our video
editor memo. So, it's super easy then
for the editor to see that piece of
feedback and then adjust it at that
exact part. This just shows you the
level of rigor and detail that goes into
creating the art that we push out to you
on YouTube. Now, let me show you the
behind the scenes of some of the tools
we use and what we actually do on the
strategy side to make this all happen
because there is some serious sauce
here. And honestly, I've never shown
this before on Figma, which is really a
collaborative design software that we
use. You can see all the research that
goes into a given concept before we even
create it. We're using that outlier
research from oneof10.com, the titles,
the thumbnails to then go and inform the
kind of text that we have inside of a
thumbnail, the title that we're going to
create, which then informs the first 30
seconds of the video because we want to
make sure the hook of the video fulfills
the promise of the title in the
thumbnail. So from there, the legend
Diego goes and comes up with oftentimes
like 30, 40 titles for one video and
then ranks them from best to worst.
We're looking often times, as an example
with the Steve Jobs video that we
created just a month ago, you know, all
the different angles that we could take.
We want to make sure that we're
appealing to the kind of founders that
are doing say 100K plus per month while
also appealing to a broad audience on
YouTube to increase both viewership and
conversion from the video. And so here
you can see our top three picks were
titles like everything Steve Jobs can
teach you about business, how to sell
anything to anyone, Steve Jobs secret,
which actually that specific title idea
came from one of our most open
newsletters. So we're also using other
data we find across other platforms and
pulling that into our YouTube research.
Now from there you can see our top three
winners ranked. And so these are the
titles we will go through until we think
that video has a fighting chance of
being a one of 10. So from there we go
and we come up with all of our thumbnail
concepts. Here you can see we've come up
with seven unique concepts and then
where you see this firecracker emoji
that means the one that we're actually
going to go with. So we pick of the
seven we pick three. Now for each of
these different concepts we come up with
multiple variations. As I had said, we
know we're going to go live with this
one, which compares Steve Jobs in 1955,
2006, and then 2025, what would be his
advice. We have this other one we went
with, which is just Steve, you know, the
iMac. And then we have, you know, this
one with me in it. So, we're just trying
some unique concepts. They're all very
different because we want to go and test
in the AB testing area of YouTube, you
know, which of these concepts is going
to catch the most fire. Now, from there,
it's now time to go and actually publish
the video. So, you're putting that in
YouTube Studio, you're uploading it, and
now you're actually going and releasing
it. Well, we're not done there, okay?
And this is something that took me over
a year and a half to learn. There's a
whole game being played when the video
is actually published because often
times, as best as we try to pick a good
thumbnail or title, we often times have
no idea what we're doing. And that's
okay. Because of the AB testing that you
can do inside of YouTube, you can kind
of play this game where you're trying a
few thumbnails, picking a winner, trying
some variations of that, picking a
winner, playing this game of gradually
getting a video that may start at an 8
out of 10 and moving it up to a 1 out of
10. And yes, that's actually possible.
right here in our Slack. You can see in
our thumbnail forge channel, Diego is
running a bunch of different titles and
thumbnails, and we are trying our best
to get this Steve Jobs video, which
starts at a 10 of 10, gradually moves to
a 9 of 10. We then cycle some titles
because we have all these titles as
backups. We keep on then testing
different thumbnail v variations. We
then finally find a winner, thumbnail
number two. From there, we start cycling
on to our next title because it's still
not catching fire. And we land on the
title, what Steve Jobs can teach you
about business that Harvard can't. All
of a sudden, magic starts to happen.
Things start to take fire. Finally. So,
here we go. This video then moves to a 6
out of 10, moving up and up and up until
it hits a one of 10. This is the magic
of the pre-production process. We've
already got 20 titles lined up and we
are ready to test. We've got over 18
different thumbnail formats ready to go.
And we are ready to iterate. And it's
because of this pre-production and the
preparation we put in that we're
actually even able to achieve these
results in the post-production process.
That combined with a great system and an
unbelievable team make this kind of
iteration possible. You can go and nail
all your packaging, but the truth is if
you don't have a great product, you're
probably not going to go and build a
breakout brand on YouTube. And so on the
conversion side, number one, you're
going to engage people, right? Create
videos that people actually want to
watch. If they don't watch it, you're
never going to convert them. Second then
is building trust, giving value, going
over the top with being insanely
generous. And then third is you convert
people. You convert people right with
strategic CTAs. Generally, at the 1
minute mark, we'll prompt people to go
and subscribe to my channel. At around 4
minutes and 20 seconds, we then go and
drop a free resource that people can go
download via the link in the
description. And by the way, if you want
this whole YouTube deck and all of the
steps that I would take if I was just
starting my channel, well, you can go
and get that deck via the link in the
description. At the 12minute mark, we'll
generally go and have the main offer,
which can be a reminder around that CTA,
or just subtly reminding people that
they can join Founder OS if they want to
work with me directly, my team, and join
a community of high growth founders
focused on building their founder brand.
We then input the actual CTA links
inside of the description below the
video. Inside of my descriptions, you
can see that I always have one link that
leads to apply to Founder OS and another
link that goes and gives you my
newsletter and then oftentimes a third
link that allows people to go and
download the lead magnet from the video.
This is how I've done things. It's
helped me grow my newsletter to over
242,000 subscribers. Hasn't happened
overnight. It's been the culmination of
at this point, you know, 70 plus lead
magnets that me and my team have, you
know, built in, you know, hundreds of
hours. But, you know, this is the kind
of generosity we want to have on this
channel. And, you know, we want you to
have the systems so you can succeed. So,
lead magnets will look like this, right?
We typically put them in Google Docs or
Google Slide deck so it's easy for you
to go and copy them, um, share them with
your team in Slack and implement them in
your company. just try to get into as
much detail as possible and then give
you this system that you can go and take
home and use with your team. So, when it
comes to my value ladder, okay, we're
basically going from free YouTube
content, newsletter signup, giving
people an entry offer if they want to
work with me, then you can go and drop a
high ticket program if you're interested
in that. That's generally just the
simple kind of seamless approach that we
go from audience through to our
community. The truth is I can't do this
alone. uh you know my success on YouTube
um is really our success as a team
because I've had amazing people
alongside me all along this journey that
have made this all possible. Now Diego
is the head of video here at Founder
Rice. He is what we'd call a jack of all
trades. Diego can edit, he can shoot,
he'll string out videos for other
editors, he'll come up with the
packaging and the thumbnails for videos.
That's not even doing it all justice.
That's probably just 10% of what Diego
does. So the key thing here is, you
know, you don't need to have a massive
team on YouTube, but you do need to put
thought into putting the right team
together. You know, one Diego equals
five B players, right? So having the
right people in the right seats. Now,
John is an animator. We've gone and
created a whole motion graphics
guidelines that we have both in Google
Drive as well as in Behance. So that
when we're going and onboarding new
video editors, we can make sure that
there's a similar and consistent motion
graphics style pack for every single
video that we put out. We have legendary
video editors like my boy Memo. Now Memo
is responsible for videos like this one
over here around Steve Jobs. He's not
just any video editor. He's someone
that's willing to kind of go the
distance, take an original concept and
footage he gets and give it a whole new
life. Now, lastly, we got Nick, the
chief distribution officer here at
Founder OS. So, this is one of the most
important roles. Other companies would
call it a social media manager. And
Nick's in charge of making sure that all
of our content goes at the right time
with the right titles, the right
captions, the right call to actions in
the descriptions of all of our YouTube
content to make sure that we're driving
the max amount of attention on YouTube
and driving those people that are
relevant to Founder OS. I think this is
one of the most important roles in the
whole business, right? Because you can
go and create amazing content, but if
it's not distributed correctly, it's all
for nothing. And so you want someone
that's equally part, you know, with
amazing attention to detail, but also
constantly looking at the data and
leveraging the data to then make sure
that, you know, titles and descriptions
and the way that we distribute things
are highly intelligent. He's also in
charge of running our entire content
waterfall system at Found. Making sure
that each YouTube video is cut into
upwards of 12 to 15 other pieces of
content to make sure that we're getting
the maximum amount of leverage from the
time, the energy, and the investment
that we put into each YouTube video. The
game of being a founder brand is one
part founder, one part creator. And
while it's fun as hell, you also got to
be aware of that the number one reason
why people stop is burnout. And because
founders burn out and creators often
burn out, you almost double your chances
of burnout when you're building a
founder brand. And so it's important
that with every single decision you
make, you're also thinking about the
longevity of things, the people, the
systems, and the focus on actually
managing your energy is imperative. All
along the way, you know, my culmination
of using all of these tactics has
brought me an insane amount of results
over the years. And this is just my
performance. No guarantees here, right?
But the reality is it's helped me drive
over 172,000 YouTube subs, 200,000 plus
newsletter signups. Um, and from my time
and investment on the money side into
YouTube, we've gotten over a 700% ROI.
your next moves if you're looking to go
deeper on YouTube. Number one, go and
download the YouTube content GPS via the
link in the description. Go and check
out my newsletter if you're looking for
more free systems from me. And lastly,
be sure to apply to Founder OS if you
want help from me, my team, and are
looking to join an amazing community of
people that are all going and growing on
YouTube and using it to build movements,
to build their community, and grow their
businesses. Thanks so much for watching
and let's continue to win
[Music]