When you're building an amazing
founder-led brand, you're going in and
you're delivering an amazing product,
and you're generating tons of reviews.
The importance of reviews cannot be
overstated. People don't buy what you're
selling, they buy what others want to
buy. And so, as you're going and
building your personal brand, you want
to make sure that you're racking up
reviews on sites like testimonial.to,
Trustpilot, and any other reviews that
are popular sources of reviews in your
industry. And so, here you can see, you
know, people are constantly saying great
things about me, my team, and awesome
work that we're doing at Founder's OS to
really help founders with a few things.
We help founders gain massive clarity
through proven systems. We license all
of our proven systems to founders inside
of Founder's OS, over 180 systems.
Number two, we have a tight-knit
invite-only community of people that are
all there helping one another. And all
the founders are generous, good vibes,
great energy, and all supporting one
another's growth as they all are looking
to go and build personal media companies
and remove themselves from operations.
In addition to that, we have an insane
amount of support that we give founders.
You get access to me every single week,
my C-suite, as well as over 50 sessions
every single month with my team. So,
you're never more than like 12 hours
away from just being able to just hop on
a call with one of the legends from my
team and get help with building your
business and overcoming any roadblocks,
challenges, or obstacles that you may be
facing. So, it's all about really having
founders' backs.