here's how to find business ideas that
can make you $100,000 per month build
the anti something take something
popular and then create the opposite of
it Uber is anti- taxi Airbnb is anti-
Hotel Tesla is anti- gasoline look at
job descriptions search your favorite
company's job listings see what they're
willing to pay for and then build a
business around those responsibilities
turn a spreadsheet into a business if
you've got a spreadsheet of customers
growth engines or finances think about
turning it into a soft software that
people will pay for leverage your
strengths identify what you're great at
explore models like courses coaching
Consulting launch learn and iterate