I am currently getting all packed up. A
threemonth legendary trip through
Europe.
>> Prese.
>> Yeah.
Three days left in the Dmites.
[Music]
It's been a amazing trip here in
Amsterdam. I am currently getting all
packed up, ready to go. We're heading to
the Doommites.
How we doing, dog?
Speechless.
You know, I've taken trips with
different teammates probably around
every 60 to 90 days. The intention of
kind of like leveling up a different
area of the business and also just
connecting on a more human level. You
know, we operate this remote team of
amazing creatives from all over the
world. You know, we have brand
strategists in Canada, we have founder
success people in Australia, people all
over. But I think a important thing to
do is actually have that human element
to what we're doing, right? And actually
bringing people together and being able
to just connect more in person. Gives us
the chances to unlock, you know,
serendipity and other just amazing
aspects that you probably wouldn't be
able to unlock otherwise. So, here we
go. It's about to pour here. So, we're
going to uh probably have to get
running. Let's go.
[Music]
This is your year.
>> Yeah. The other thing I I wanted to
explore is like infographic video
infographic like mixing carousel with
like static stuff and then video. So
like the snippets of your YouTubes could
be also be like infographic and you know
it's like show and like show what I
didn't tell but then I can have this
infographic and then like a short video
is like I don't know like 15 seconds to
support whatever I'm trying to
>> put an image the be b-roll like music
coffee like these are like the main
parts of the brand.
>> Yeah.
>> So like it's important that like the
B-roll and the photos are like so
dialed. We have like legit like movie
level [\h__\h] You can see the good [\h__\h]
when you see it. Like it's so obvious.
It's like there we go. Like there's like
that's like a movie. Like make it look
good.
>> Mhm.
>> The brand like over time just got very
delicate, but it needs to sit at both
the intersection of delicate and really
authentic. Like it's almost got to
straddle both worlds. So it's like, oh
[\h__\h] this guy's like really
intelligent, but like oh [\h__\h] they're
just having fun and like [\h__\h] around.
And it's like missing all that right now
just for a number of reasons including I
think it is a bit of the downside like
not in a negative way but of like the
brand of me playing by myself and us
being a remote team
>> cuz then I'm just like
>> like
I am I'm making the two YouTube videos.
I'm making 35k a month. making like I'm
making content, but it's like it starts
that's where it's like, okay, I have to
get other [\h__\h] off my plate. If I'm
literally going to be like a [\h__\h]
creator like full full time and just
like videoing everything like
>> it's like at that point like you're
making like seven pieces of content a
day. I'm like a [\h__\h] content machine.
>> You just have me following you around
and like content.
It's real.
>> Real dog.
>> I wasn't expecting that. So
laughing.
What a day.
[Music]
Four days down.
Three days left slept in the Dmites
enough to Norway.
Norway on Sunday.
Not bad.
Oh, look at this guy. He just
>> All right,
let's go.
All right.
Get a coffee.
doesn't get
a bad little plan for the last day in
the doll. So sad
last day up to refugeio
[Music]
for a little creative
just going to eat as as usual.
>> The key part of retreat is eat. Rich
eats.
About 14 years ago, I went with three
other roommates. We traveled all through
21 countries all around Europe. And it
was by far the most legendary trip of my
life. All my roommates ended up going
home and then I ended up flying from
Zurich, Switzerland way to Bangkok,
Thailand, and then traveling Southeast
Asia for another 3 months. I think this
is when I got my first taste of freedom.
Really, the taste of just being in new
places, meeting new people, experiencing
new cultures. I became addicted to say
the least. Now fast forward to today, I
slow travel around the world uh living
all around different places. Really
excited for these next few months. I
think brands are built uh from also just
being expansive, right, and escaping,
getting into nature, enjoying yourself,
and then becoming inspired. And so this
is one of those trips, right, where we
can get outside, get inspired. Um, and I
like to think of these as like a soul
trip, a chance to just like reinvigorate
your creativity, take things to the next
level, you know, really just amp it up a
bit. I feel in general, the brand, the
content, all this stuff, it just takes
care of itself. It's really effortless.
Yeah. You don't think about it. Just let
it happen. Like,
>> some days you film some [\h__\h] some days
you don't feel like it. [\h__\h] it. Like as
long as you know you're generally like
doing yeah living your life
>> looking at tips
>> enjoying things doing cool [\h__\h]
>> the rest kind of takes care of itself.
You know what helps sometimes when I go
through a creative process?
It's like these moments where just do
nothing really do nothing for like let's
say extended period of time where you
journal and and then you just you just
put your attention where you want let's
say think about thumbnails then you
close your eyes and you imagine like
your perfect thumbnail not like what
every creator is doing like what would
be your favorite perfect thumbnail and
then you just like imagine it and then
you create I think that's you create
your own trend basically.
It's all the creative process behind
everything that that's what's going to
stick with founders because I think it's
like you don't even have to tell so
much. It's like just showing like the
process of it.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Founders going to be like, "Oh [\h__\h]
okay, that's how you do it."
>> That's what we get feedback on all the
time, right? It's like people just love
to learn just from how you think about
things.
>> Yeah.
I'm pretty sure we're kind of going to
miss the the quietness of this
placeholder.
>> Yeah,
>> it's going to be our peaceful reference,
right?
Just funny even like the small things,
you know, like just like like crossing a
street like actually having to like walk
both ways cars like out here. There's
just no
just walking in the middle of the road.
I just probably go for like a like a
nice hike like
>> uh there are nice beaches though like
not too far.
>> Perfect.
Okay,
last
adventure.
[Music]
Yeah, this place
is insane.
All right, tonight getting a little 8:15
dinner after wrapping up for the day and
going on the midnight hike, chasing the
sun. It never sets here. So, we're going
to see the sun kiss the ocean and then
come back up while at one of the higher
peaks in this area. So,
you know, the days don't need to end
here is the beautiful part. You know,
most days you end at like, I don't know,
6:00 p.m. and you're like, damn it,
sun's going down. Day's over. Here, nah,
that sun ain't never going down.
Sometimes, just like in life, you need a
mountain. You need the same thing
creatively. some challenge that comes
out of nowhere and just helps you tap
into those creative juices. And in this
case, it was climbing five mountains in
5 days from the Dolommites, Italy to
Lafeton, Norway. Nothing better than
going on a midnight hike and be able to
go on a 1:00 a.m. cold dip right after
something special. I think a core memory
I won't forget for the rest of my life.
Now, often times when I've thought about
myself over the years, as I've grown as
an entrepreneur, I actually see myself
as more of an artist than an
entrepreneur. Now, there's the art of
creating beautiful content, content with
taste, with style, with your tone, your
own point of view. you know, the
artistry, I think it matters because
amidst, you know, a sea of constant
noise online, there's something for it
to be said for just making things your
own. You know, we didn't have to climb
nine mountains in 9 days filming this
series. No one told us to do that. That
would be crazy. But it's for the
artistry, folks. The art
[Music]
Feel
like those people are definitely from
Canada.
[Music]
The core thing with the uh coloring
right now at least memo is just yeah we
want it to look like real and rich not
like bloomy. go and audit the video,
please, to make sure it's all dialed in.
Thank you.
>> So, that's what I did for now so far.
Nice. I think it's pretty clean. I'm not
sure if I want to go like with these
kind of colors, even though like it
grabs the attention. I like the
minimalism a bit and like I think it's
sense he did it just very delicately. I
would leave that how it is, but like I
would say almost like this is rated as
[\h__\h] Subtitles, I already laid out some
examples. Uh, Sarafont.
Um, I think it's hard to read for me.
Personally, I wouldn't do that. This one
is Helvetica bold.
>> Mhm.
>> I like it.
>> I think lower case is the knife.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Lower case because like it's just
easier to read like for the eye.
>> Yeah. We just have to like say that we
want it and we have the squad now to do
it.
>> You know, like they're there waiting.
They're like just send us exactly how
you want them.
>> You know what I mean? What they're going
to do is they're going to send us like a
one minute like sizzle of like, "Hey,
you've sent us all this [\h__\h] We
understand your brand. We understand
your shit." They're going to take some
of our footage. They're going to be
like, "This is how we're going to edit
your videos.
[Music]
Some of that Morton sea salt,
that Celtic sea salt, the real [\h__\h] in
the water.
Major hack.
Get your electrolytes, folks.
Third way through the town.
Bad news. This is going to be a [\h__\h]
This is This if we're doing it,
[Music]
that's a sight.
That's why you go to the summit, you
know, you finish what you started. You
never know what's on the other side.
Most founders, you know, they live in
spreadsheets and strategy decks. But
sometimes, sometimes you just got to
climb a mountain, five mountains,
actually. Not because it makes sense,
doesn't make business sense. Not because
there's an ROI calculation or any crazy
thinking behind it, but just because
it's what your soul is calling you to
do. It's because the mind, you know,
that solves problems in conference rooms
isn't the same mind that solves them
from 10,000 ft. This is what they don't
teach you in business school. Sometimes
the most strategic thing you can do is
the thing that makes no sense. Dragging
camera equipment up a mountain face to
film a video about personal branding.
That's not content creation. That's more
like creative rebellion. These side
quests, these deliberate departures from
logic. They're not distractions. They're
where the real work happens. Where
exhaustion strips away the performative
[\h__\h] and leaves you with just truth.
Raw footage. No retakes.
This yours?
>> Yeah, I think so. Yeah, that's mine.
>> You want it?
>> Yeah.
>> I like it.
>> This guy likes us.
>> Has a sick body
[Music]
when the grass ain't green.
Let's
[Music]
just take a
Fzande.
>> Yeah. Fand
>> and sorts like take some of our
animations that we've got, but then this
is like, do we like this? How do you
update it next? Do we like this? How do
you update it next?
>> I think life is short, right? And too
many of us live like we're just going to
live forever. And I think that when you
realize that you're going to die and you
really think about that for a second,
like internalize that, you really start
to wonder like what's the life that you
really want to live? When I've gone and
reflected on what I want to leave here
on Earth in my short time here, I'm
really here to help humanity, help you
go and unlock your full creative
potential. I think a lot of us forget we
didn't start our business to work more
than we ever have. We started them
because we wanted more life. But
somewhere along the way, the work took
over. The things that gave us energy, a
travel, movement, nature, connection,
those got pushed aside. For me, that
never made sense because what's the
point of building something successful
if you have to give up the very things
that make you feel alive? That's why I
work in places like this, the mountains
in Norway, the trails in the Doommites.
I can hike in the morning, make deals in
the afternoon, and end the day watching
the sun drop behind a ridge. It's not
about escaping the work. It's about
integrating it into the life you
actually want. Designing it so your
energy stays full and your days feel
like they're yours. Because freedom
isn't about time or money. It's about
building something that lets you live
exactly how you want while you still
can. You know, if there's one question
I'd encourage you to ask more of in your
life when you're at a crossroads, it's
this. What would make the better story?
Just go do it. You got this.