Here's how to generate a month's worth
of content in just 45 minutes. Number
one, generate 100 ideas based on
customer feedback. Use type form to
survey your customers. Understand their
core goals as well as challenges and
then use those to go and generate your
content ideas. Number two, use a media
team to produce this content. You should
be building a personal media company
around yourself. Video editors if you're
moving forward to YouTube and Instagram,
writers if you're building out your
newsletter and more of a writing first
content team. Three, turn each pillar
piece of content into 35 other pieces of
content. One YouTube video can become
three YouTube shorts, three Instagram
reels, three Tik Tok videos, two
LinkedIn posts, multiple X posts. Step
four, distribute across all platforms.
The goal here is to be omniresent. No
matter where your customer is, they're
going to find you. Step five, measure
performance and iterate. Every month,
you should be looking at your top 10% of
content and doubling down on those core
patterns and looking at the stuff that's
in your bottom 10% and stopping that
stuff. Keep on putting these reps in
month by month.