A personal brand is the highest ROI
asset you can build. And this is why. A
personal brand is not just about
aesthetics, okay? It is about getting
your message out there to the world at
scale. When you go and you're in a sales
conversation, it's just you and the
client. When you're going and building
your personal brand, you may put a real
out on Instagram or you may put a long
form YouTube out and you know, minimum
you're probably getting around a,000
views there. Now, imagine that in
person, right? Imagine at the snap of
your finger being able to go and have a
room of a thousand people around you
that are all listening to your core
message, your point of view, and how you
might be able to help them. Now, think
about that multiplied over 100 videos
and 100,000 people. You're now filling
up stadiums. And the key thing here is
that this is helping you build massive
leverage. And so what you want to be
thinking about instead of going from one
to one with the message, how could I go
one to