Every business has one defining
decision.
>> Decisions. Decisions. Decision. I mean,
one.
>> That single shift is everything in my
opinion. The thing that actually
separates founders who build empires
from the ones that just stay stuck. It's
not their idea, it's not their work
ethic. I think it's who they actually
drive their inspiration from and who
they see as like their mental mentors.
You're not going to be very successful
in business if your mind is all over the
place.
>> And so, what I'm going to do today is
break down five decisions that I've
learned from five genius founders and
apply these decisions to help impact the
trajectory of your company and your
life. I built a founder decision
scorecard that you can go and download
after this video. You're going to have
the exact framework by the end of this
video to make the same kinds of
decisions as these billionaires did in
your business. Let's get into it. Genius
decision number one, Jensen Huang,
Nvidia. People with very high
expectations have very low resilience.
At some point you have to believe
something.
There was no reason to not be committed
because we believed it. Everyone thinks
Nvidia won because of the AI boom, but
the real story starts three decades ago
with a decision Jensen Huang made that
almost nobody saw coming. So, here we
go. Picture this. Your company is
dominating in gaming graphics. That's
what pays the bills. That's what
investors understand. That's what you're
known for. And then you make a decision
that completely changes your company's
direction. Who in their right mind would
do that? Well, a genius. In the
mid-2010s, Jensen made a move that
looked from the outside completely
reckless. Nvidia wasn't going to define
itself by gaming chips. It was going all
in on AI infrastructure. And here's the
thing back then, AI wasn't a gold rush,
right? It was just some research
project. Academics were excited, but
most executives had no idea where it was
even to go. And from the outside, it
looked like he was betting the company
on some science fair. From the inside,
it was a complete redefinition of the
company's destiny. Jensen wasn't asking
how big could AI be? He was asking, once
AI becomes inevitable, who owns the
infrastructure of it? This is a
completely different way to think. This
is some titan energy here. And when the
AI boom hit years later, well, we know
how that went. It didn't just create
Nvidia's success, it actually revealed
what they had been working on for
decades. What looked like overnight
success was actually a 30-year
positioning strategy finally paying off.
Jensen once said, "The question isn't
should we take a big bet? It's what
future risks can we eliminate right now
that our competitors are ignoring." Read
that again. Eliminating future
irrelevance, not chasing upside. That
framing alone is worth more than 99% of
business advice you'll ever hear. The
mistake most founders make is copying
someone else's playbook, optimizing for
what looks smart now instead of what
will really matter later on. So, here's
the shift that you need to make. Stop
asking what's working today and start
asking what will be obvious in 10 years
and how do I position myself before it's
obvious? You know, most founders just
protect revenue streams. Genius founders
protect relevance. Invest in skills that
compound. Build assets that will still
matter if your industry evolves. Jensen
positioned himself before it was
obvious. That's the whole move. Every
single year around February, I like to
go and jam with my team on an offsite
and really just work to go and see how
we can go disrupt our own business. Just
like Steve Jobs, just like Jensen, these
titans of industry can teach us things.
And if there's one thing we can go and
get from them, it's that decision to go
and disrupt yourself before someone else
does. Genius decision number two, Steve
Jobs, Apple. Are you getting it?
I know that you can plant something in
the world and it'll grow and change the
world ever so slightly. One of Jobs'
most famous quotes is, "If you don't
cannibalize yourself, someone else
will." He didn't just say it, right? He
lived it twice. In 1997, Apple was 90
days from bankruptcy. Dozens of
products, no clear identity, and sales
were falling off a cliff. Everyone
expected him to come back, launch more,
chase more markets, add more features.
Instead, he killed 70% of the product
line. Four products, that's it. Not to
cut costs, but to create radical focus.
And just when that bet paid off, he did
it again. Jobs made the call to build
the iPhone, fully knowing that it was
going to kill the iPod. The iPod was
carrying Apple. It had dominated
portable music, was wildly profitable,
and defined the brand. Most founders
would have just gone and protected that
product at all costs. He chose to
disrupt himself rather than wait to be
disrupted. And that one decision turned
Apple into the most valuable company in
the world. When I was building Founder
OS, we had one core product for the
first two to three years. One. And we
scaled that single product to a place
where the business was genuinely,
insanely profitable, and powerful.
Meanwhile, I keep seeing founders, so
many, who are juggling 10, 12 different
offers, side products, side projects,
experiments, and none of them are even
breaking through. There's no depth, no
dominance, just a bunch of half-built
things competing with each other for
attention. And that's a real trap. You
think more products means more revenue,
but what it actually creates is just a
dilution of your time. You end up being
known for nothing instead of being known
for one thing. So, here's how you go and
apply this right now. Anywhere you see
complexity, you got to kill it. Identify
the product, the service, and the
project that is actually driving you
real results. That's the one, right?
Pour everything into it. Look for that
piece of your business that's the
easiest thing to sell, and that is the
highest percentage of your profits, and
then just double down relentlessly, even
when it feels uncomfortable, because it
probably will. You got to bring what I
call war chief energy. Eliminate the
noise, kill the complexity, and any
products that aren't contributing to
your core focus. Because the founders
who win are the ones who are still
standing in 10 years and the ones who
had the courage to say no to everything
else. Genius decision number three,
Brian Chesky, Airbnb. Airbnb could
become so much more than it is today.
The hardest thing to manage in a crisis
is your own psychology. Brian Chesky
didn't build his edge through product or
some growth strategy. He built it by
doing one thing most founders overlook,
his culture. Imagine losing 80% of your
business in a single month. Well, that's
exactly what happened to Airbnb in March
of 2020. Bookings disappeared overnight.
Investors panicked. 1900 people lost
their jobs. Morale had cratered inside
of the company and the engine that had
powered Airbnb for over a decade started
to completely stall. Culture itself was
unraveling, right? And most CEOs in that
moment would just step back. They let
the team sort it out, hire someone in
just to go and fix things, right? But
not Brian Chesky. This guy made a bold,
unconventional decision. He went and
personally stepped into every part of
the company. And so, what did he do?
Well, he shut down unnecessary
divisions, remove layers of approval,
remapped the entire operation. There's
like 90 core screens that are part of
the Airbnb product, right? And he went
and simplified that overall UI. Going
and cutting all the noise, removing a
lot of the product management,
flattening the organization, and just
helping move through key product
decisions. His rule was radical in its
simplicity. Everyone's going to work on
everything together. And if I can't
personally focus on it, we won't do it.
Now, some called it micromanaging, but
in a moment where the company survival
and soul is on the line, you got to go
and personally make the decisions to go
and save it. I had a version of this
recently. I'd gone and brought on a
copywriter to help solve a content
problem. And what was one of their first
suggestions? Matt, we need to hire a
head of marketing. And I thought, you
know what? That's the last thing we need
right now, right? The real answer was
simple, but also a lot harder. I need to
step in myself, and I need to actually
instill a level of extreme ownership in
this individual. Getting closer to the
work, understanding the problem
firsthand, and then building solutions
in place so we don't need to just add
more head count, more complexity, more
humans, right? But find a simpler
solution. Here's what this means for
you. You know, when the culture in your
company starts to kind of drift, you
can't delegate that standard, right? You
have to hold it high and embody it. The
bar that you set becomes the bar that
everyone follows. So, pick your moments
carefully. When things are breaking,
step in personally. But when the systems
are working, you can kind of let people
carry the work. That balance is how you
maintain a high-performing culture over
the long haul. You get what you
tolerate. Genius decision number four,
Edwin Land, Polaroid. Take a wallet out
of my pocket and perhaps open a wallet,
press a button, close the wallet, and
have the picture. You may not recognize
the name Edwin Land. I get it. But
here's one of the reasons I was tipped
off to him. This is Steve Jobs' ultimate
idol. Jobs himself called Land one of
his biggest inspirations, and here's
why. In 1943, Edwin Land was on a
vacation with his 3-year-old daughter.
He took a photo, and she asked him a
simple question. Why can't I see the
picture right now? That one question
from a 3-year-old changed the entire
photography industry. At the time,
getting photos developed meant sending
film away and then waiting days. Most
people would have tried to make that
process faster or cheaper. But Land
approached that from a completely
different angle, asking, "What if the
wait didn't exist at all?" After years
of secret research and hundreds of
failed experiments, he unveiled the
first Polaroid camera in 1947. Its
initial run sold out almost instantly.
Land didn't compete in photography. He
invented a version of it that nobody
else was even thinking about. He didn't
find a niche, he became the niche. I
hear this all the time from founders,
right? What's your niche? What exactly
do you do? And I always think, why are
you asking that question? Why are we
trying to fit into a niche when we could
just go and create one? Here's the
question that you need to ask yourself.
Am I trying to fit in or am I building
something that reshapes the space
entirely? What can I build that doesn't
exist yet? Something so compelling that
others naturally find their place around
it. If you want to build something
legendary, stop chasing where the market
is. Start with the vision of where it
could be and then become the standard
everyone else aligns to. That's what
Land did, that's what Jobs did, and
that's exactly what you need to do.
Genius decision number five, Brad
Jacobs, QXO. I like making money for
shareholders. As a founder, the
difference between struggling and
dominating often comes down to one edge.
An edge that most people never really
think about. Brad Jacobs has built seven
billion-dollar companies and his edge
wasn't money, it wasn't talent, it
wasn't connections. It's control over
himself, his own mindset. Brad Jacobs
built some of the largest companies in
their industries, United Rentals, XPO
Logistics and others. But at some point,
he realized that the biggest threat to
his success, it wasn't the market,
right? It's how he handled the struggle
in his own mind. So, he did something
most founders never do. He turned
inward. He studied how he operated under
pressure. He learned meditation. He
learned to separate emotion from
decision-making and he built the kind of
internal OS, right? That discipline that
let him stay clear-headed even when
things got kind of chaotic and crazy. He
stopped reacting and started responding.
The meditation led to clear thinking,
clear thinking led to stronger decisions
and scale and the ability to hire better
performers and just outperform the
market not just once but seven times. He
led high-performing teams without
getting pulled into the noise. He didn't
just build systems for his companies,
right? He built a system for himself,
and that there is what has allowed him
to go and build billion-dollar companies
over and over again. And so, here's the
exercise. Let's just say something goes
and knocks you off kilter, right? Where
suddenly now you're stressed. And we go
and imagine ourselves 50% as stressed as
we are right now. And you kind of hold
that for a minute. So, now we're
suddenly allowing things to cool down,
and then we think, "Okay, can I be 50%
less stressed than that?" What's really
happening, right, is we're gradually
practicing this mental exercise of
realizing that most of our problems are
just manufactured in the mind, and your
perception is not the reality. Jacob
started to understand even the clearest
thinking won't matter if the wrong
people are around you. So, he applies
that same discipline time after time to
his team. He has surrounded himself
exclusively with what he calls A
players. And I'm not just talking
talented people. We're talking about the
right people, and then he incentivizes
them extremely well, right? Making sure
that they're not just going to stick
around for 6 months, but these people
want to stick around him till the very
end of that journey. People who didn't
need to be managed, who took ownership,
who raised the bar for everyone around
them. And he's ruthless about this. We
all know A players attract A players,
but B players attract C players, right?
So, the importance of having absolute
weapons in your company is insanely
important. And when you look at folks
like Brad Jacobs, a seven-time unicorn
founder, these guys embody it. Because
one wrong person is a key seed that
doesn't just slow things down. It really
just drags your entire culture
backwards. It's one part mental mastery
and one part organizational
architecture. That combination, right,
is how it's allowed him to build
multiple billion-dollar companies not
once, but over and over and over again,
seven times. So, here's the question for
you. Do you have a system for how you
handle stress? Do you meditate? Do you
seek nature? Do you have some different
mindfulness exercises? Do you have a
standard for who you allow on your team?
And most importantly, who you definitely
are going to say no to. You know, when
you get intentional about building that
operating system for your mindset, your
people, and your business, that's when
you stop grinding and start building
something with real peace, real profit,
and real purpose, which is really what
it's all about. So, what do all five of
these founders have in common? Every
single one of them made a decision that
looked counterintuitive at the time.
Every one of them chose a long-term
alignment over short-term comfort. They
didn't ask "What's working right now?"
They asked "What will the future demand,
and am I building towards that thing?"
If you want to make sure that the next
decisions you make are on par with the
greats we featured in this video, I
built something practical for you. It's
called the Founder Defining Decision
Scorecard, and it's linked in the
description below. You'll score yourself
across the five decision categories that
I just walked through, focus,
positioning, future relevance, culture,
and your internal operating system, and
then it's going to go and expose the one
defining decision that you're probably
avoiding right now, which is useful
because then you can go and take that
scorecard to a strategy call with me and
my team, and we can then go and help you
kind of pressure test those decisions
and really how you're thinking about
your systems architecture to make sure
that you're supported for success and
scale. Because clarity without systems
is just going to create chaos. If you're
a serious founder building for the next
10 years, not the next 10 months,
download it below and let's build this
thing properly. The defining decision in
your business, and the one that will
matter most, it's not going to feel
safe, okay? It's going to force be
honest about who you actually are as a
founder. That's the line between
something that lasts and something that
just works for now. You've got one life
to build this thing. Don't play small,
don't play safe, make the hard call. If
you like this video, you'd definitely
like this next video on the psychology
of going and scaling a brand. Be sure to
like and subscribe, and I'll see you in
the next one.