Here's how Mr. Beast stayed obsessed for
a decade, and how it made him a
billionaire. Mr. Beast is notorious for
thinking insanely long-term about any
project he takes. Every single video
that Jimmy puts out, he bets the farm
each and every time. People think he's
nuts, a borderline addicted gambler, but
it's this level of obsession around the
craft. Not the results, not the numbers,
not the money, but the craft itself that
separates Jimmy from every other
YouTuber. You know, without this level
of obsession, there's a thousand reasons
he should have given up. Jimmy had 20
subs in 2012 and 15,000 subs in 2015.
These are humble numbers. I mean, hell,
you probably know a thousand other
YouTubers with larger followings than
that. You can just imagine how obsessed
Mr. Beast was. And that obsession, it
didn't compound linearly, it compounds
exponentially. With each rep, he's
getting 50% better, 20% better, betting
all the chips, going all in every time.