you don't need to hustle harder you need
to slow down find Clarity remember that
money is not the prize don't build a
business just to become a slave to it
don't create a lifestyle that drains you
robs you of your relationships and makes
you unhappy success without fulfillment
is not success at all it's just stress
if you're pushing out 12 and 18 hour
days to hit targets then you're playing
the wrong game entrepreneurship is not
about surviving entrepreneurship is
about thriving revenue is the fuel on
your journey of living a life you dream
about the goals life you're excited to
live everything else is unsustainable
hustle for too long and you can't hear
your heart anymore so rest meditate get
into nature find Clarity on your calling
and build a business that makes you
excited for tomorrow