what if I told you that to make $1.2
million a month you only need to work 20
hours a week you heard that
right 10 years ago when I was building
my first business through endless cycles
of burnout I would have had the same
reaction as you just did then I
discovered strategically designed
Frameworks that allow me to remove
myself from all of the chaos and live my
dream life Frameworks that let my team
run the show while I focused on the big
picture and travel the world it doesn't
involve sacrificing quality hustling
24/7 or juggling everything yourself the
key ingredient systems that scale on
this channel alone I've broken down many
of the systems that I've designed and
leveraged that have allowed me to run a
portfolio of online businesses that
pulling over $10 million a year while
only spending about 20 hours a week on
my business today I'm giving you the
five ingredients you need to design your
own set of scalable systems this isn't
just some Theory this is is the exact
recipe I used to create systems that
brought me from a life of burnout to a
life of complete Freedom over my time
most people are just one system away
from completely transforming their lives
and by the end of this video you will be
ready to unlock more freedom than you
ever thought was possible you'll have
time to travel work on what you love and
still grow a beautiful systemized and
Hyper profitable business let's dive in
the first step is documentation and I'm
not talking about creating some boring
manual that no one's going to ever read
this is about setting the foundation for
your freedom if you walked away from
your business tomorrow would someone be
able to take over seamlessly and do all
the tasks that you do most Founders
would say hell no when I was working 14
hours a day back at my first startup I
felt like I was too busy to stop being
busy people told me to work on the
business instead of in the business but
no one told me how I should have
delegated my busy work to free up time
for higher levelx ass instead I just
tried to add 4 hours of working on the
business to my already 14-hour days and
it broke
me at my second business herb I sore to
myself that I'd never make this same
mistake again today I spend 37 minutes a
month running herb my unpopular opinion
these days is real success in
entrepreneurship comes from strategic
laziness knowing when to work hard and
when to delegate I'm going to show you
the system I use to free up 20 hours a
week and 10x my income here's what I
want you to do start with a Google doc
and document every task you do one by
one write down the goals the steps and
most importantly the why behind each
task why is this task essential what's
the bigger goal that it serves building
a $10 million business starts with
awareness and solid understanding of
what consumes the time of the business
and its key operators you must start
documen men ing all tasks you work on in
any given month the key here is to get
certain tasks off your plate so you can
achieve more time freedom in your life
but why do you even need time Freedom
time freedom is important to me because
you know I have Big Dreams outside of
work you I want to travel to all 195
countries in the world I want to have
Rich relationships with my friends and
family and I want to have systems that
unlock all that freedom if you want to
travel the world build systems if you
want to sell your business one day build
systems if you want to work just 4 hours
a day build systems strong systems
create a strong business make a habit of
documenting one system every day tiny
systems daily lead to massive freedom in
the long term documenting is simple so
don't over complicate it stop being the
bottleneck start being the architect
real success means working smart not
just hard now that you've begun
documenting you need to master slow
recording here's where it get it's fun
too many Founders have no clue how to
build systems and it kills your business
you think you need to show every new
employee how to do their job in person
on meetings and you just waste a ton of
time you feel like you have to answer
every question from every client from
every employee you have to do all the
work and this is what leads to burnout
but what if you could just clone
yourself that's exactly what we do with
slow recording slow recordings are
in-depth videos that give your team the
perfect understanding of of what they
need to do to execute any given task
effectively for every key task you're
going to record a 5-minute loom video
that's going to walk them through each
step Loom is a tool that allows you to
screen record your desktop and it makes
it easy to show people exactly what to
do on any given task Loom builds
leverage you no longer need to be on
meetings constantly and repeating
yourself keep it simple speak slowly
explain at things as if you're talking
to an eighth grader this becomes your
internal team University instead of
training people live they can just watch
the recordings and learn exactly what to
do and get to work here's a bonus tip
add a bit of your personality to these
recordings you're building a culture not
just some task list your team will feel
connected inspired and clear on exactly
what they need to do there are three
possible excuses for why you don't have
systems in your business number one you
put off Building Systems because you're
lazy two you're too busy or three you
just don't know how either way you need
to stop saying to yourself someday I'll
get around to it someday is a disease
and it will kill you I live by the motto
slow as smooth and smooth as fast and
when you're looking to build a
sustainable business you need
sustainable systems so how do you ensure
your team uses the beautiful systems you
create you need a systems owner this is
where most systems fall apart you can't
just create a system and not have anyone
actually own it each major system in
your business needs a champion someone
responsible for keeping it up toate
optimizing it and ensuring in it runs
smoothly not to mention keeping your
team accountable to it this is how you
scale without just losing control here's
what this looks like your Chief of Staff
probably handles things like onboarding
team meetings and project management
systems your head of marketing owns
content distribution product launches
and social media systems a finance
manager is going to be responsible for
things like projections invoices and
cash flow a chief Revenue officer is
responsible for things like Sales
Systems HubSpot systems and your overall
pitch script your goal is to make
ownership part of your culture this
isn't just delegation it's true Freedom
your team is there so you can rely on
them they're there to make your vision
happen so you can remove yourself from
operations each system in your business
needs an owner hiring recruiting
audience growth video editing website
design sales funnels email automations
dashboards and content an example of a
Key Systems owner I have in my business
is an Athena executive assistant to
effectively clone myself it's amazing
Athena allows me to hire highquality
executive assistants for my portfolio of
companies and multiply my effort systems
and productivity my Athena EA
effectively takes care of any task
outside of my core dream task so I can
focus on my zone of Genius they do
things like coordinating meetings
booking flights managing my calendar
answering emails I have all of that
taken care of for me documentation plus
recordings plus owners equals freedom
now that you have documented tasks
recordings and owners you need to home
for it all this is your notion Company
Wiki it's like a digital operating
system where every process every system
and every resource lives in notion
you're going to create a page for each
department Marketing sales Finance
operations everything inside each page
store your top five systems from
customer onboarding to finance tracking
this way every team member knows where
to find the information they need
without needing you which is going to
save you a ton of time this will be a
breath of fresh air think of it as your
business brain everything your team
needs to know all there and one place
with this you remove friction eliminate
bottlenecks and create a smooth scalable
workflow that keeps your business
running whether you're there or not all
systems across your business should be
neatly placed into your notion Company
Wiki that way new employees can
reference it when they join and people
don't need to guess at where everything
across the company is living let's get
real for a second there's something
every single one of us has in common
whether we're making 50k a month or
aiming for that $10 million a year
Milestone your personal brand is your
biggest hidden asset most Founders see
their brand as just an online presence
but here's the kicker a well-built brand
is a magnet for opportunities clients
and growth it's a powerful machine that
works even when you're not working and
I'm not just talking about being known
I'm talking about being trusted people
don't trust corporations they trust
people they Trust trust you take any
major brand today as an example Tesla
Airbnb virgin the founders of the faces
of these Brands and they're the ones
that people connect with your personal
brand isn't just a nice to have it's the
ultimate leverage point for growth and
here's why it's different from
traditional marketing a strong brand
means clients come to you already
convinced here's something that blew my
mind when I first started building my
brand most people think they have to be
some star of the show but the truth
people don't want a hero they want a
guide they want someone who's been in
the trenches who's faced the exact same
problems as they have instead of trying
to think of yourself as a hero think of
yourself as a guide helping your dream
customer conquer their own Journey For
example talk about the times you've
struggled to find clients burned out or
failed then share how you solved it
that's What Makes You relatable it's
going to make you trustworthy and
someone worth listening to people buy
into your story and your energy long
before they buy your product here's just
a few of the tools I use to automate my
personal brand growth hype Fury helps me
with posting and automating messages tap
Leo X streamlines my research and helps
me Source viral topics chat gbd helps me
rapidly come up with 30 plus new content
ideas in just 30 seconds Athena gives me
aordable executive assistance to help
with research organization and project
management and then yesware is amazing
for automating my email follow-up
process and drive leads through my
content a powerful personal brand isn't
generic it's spefic specific it's
original and it stands out I'm not here
to promote custle culture I'm here to
show you a new way to scale your
personal brand is an appreciating asset
imagine a world where your content your
message and your brand are working 24/7
to generate leads clients in sales for
you your content is a salesperson that
never sleeps That's The Power of a
well-built profitable personal brand
it's not about egoo it's about creating
something that lasts something that
resonates and something that drives
exponential growth to your business
business here's what happened when these
five pieces all fall into place your
business becomes a self-sustaining
machine suddenly your day-to-day stress
is gone you're no longer the bottleneck
and you have the freedom to focus on the
big picture in your life and the growth
of your business this is what changed my
life when I committed to these systems I
unlocked time freedom and insane growth
I went from being a slave to my business
to being a Zen CEO designing my life
exactly how I wanted it if you're a
founder and you're feeling trapped maybe
you're feeling stressed or constantly
putting out fires I'm telling you
there's a better way I've built a
company that now runs on autopilot and
pulls in over 840k monthly but it took
me 8 years to learn how to do this I
battled the chaos of hustle culture
daily it's a disease every modern
entrepreneur has faced then I realized
that hustle does not equal productivity
don't let your business run your life
set up these five pillars and reclaim
your time and if you want my my exact
templates Frameworks systems and support
from an amazing community of Founders
check out founder s plus it's where I
share everything that brought me here
today and so you can make it happen for
yourself like And subscribe and welcome
to the founder Freedom Movement
[Music]