Do you ever sat down to make content and
stared at a blank page wondering what to
post? This is [music] the workflow that
ends that problem for good. Most people
I talk to treat content ideas like a
creativity [music] problem. The problem
is that the things that should be
feeding your content, your sales calls,
your analytics, your candid [music]
frustrations you're dealing with have
nowhere to go. That's why I want to show
you the exact workflow that I use to run
my profitable personal brand. It's also
the system that we install for founders
[music] inside of FounderOS when we go
and build their content machine. The end
result is a full month of assets across
all platforms in their voice completely
scheduled in a content calendar. Section
one, organic sources. So, first things
first here, we're going to go and show
you how I go and think about generating
these content ideas, okay? We're going
to use a bunch of tools here and some
little-known insights that I've used to
drive some of my most profitable
content, which I'll be showing you some
of my dashboards as well to show the
proof that this stuff actually works.
So, first things first here, one tool I
love to use is called Poppy. Now, inside
of Poppy, I'm able to go and really come
up with a bunch of different ideas that
are all pulled from my best content
ever. And I also go and utilize a lot of
the data I get from Fathom as well
because inside of Fathom, I'm able to go
and record all of my core sales calls,
and then we use the core objections or
the hot buttons that people have come up
with to then infuse our content ideas,
okay? So, I can go and show you here,
right? Is inside of Poppy, what I could
do is basically go and look at the
outliers on my channel, whether
short-form or long-form videos. From
there, I can go and populate a lot of
the topics and hooks into the Poppy kind
of smart AI chat here. So, what I like
to do is pull them all in. I can create
basically a group of those short-form
videos, right? My top outliers. And
then, now what I'm able to do is based
on that group, I can go and start coming
up with a ton of ideas. And so, what I
may go and do is look at, you know,
other amazing creators, go and look at
their outliers as well. Look at my
long-form videos, take those outliers
in. As we look at this whole dashboard,
okay? The next thing, again, let's dive
into Henzo. Essentially, every single
Friday, I do a little founder walk,
okay? And there's this content ritual I
like to do where I answer about 5 to 15
different questions. And essentially,
I'm just using my actual voice to go and
answer each question in about 2 to 3 to
4 minutes, right? I like to do this
right after a nice iced Americano, so,
you know, the blood's pumping, my ideas
are flowing, I'm feeling fresh. And what
I try to do is just expand vulnerably
around the sort of stuff that has been
going on in my life, right? The wins,
the struggles, different lessons I've
learned. So, oftentimes, the best
content just comes from like the little
stories from my everyday life. And the
beautiful thing is that it's able to
take those kinds of stories and then use
the best formats for LinkedIn to go and
combine my actual voice with these
proven formats to then go and generate
my content. So, this is not AI content,
this is my actual voice. It's just then
formatted in a proven way so that it's
scannable, it has an amazing hook and an
amazing image along with it. And so, if
you're interested, by the way, in
checking out Henzo, you can go and check
it out via the link in the description.
Um this tool has been like 700 hours of
work on my side. Um I've been testing
it. If you like my LinkedIn content, you
know, we've grown to over 900,000 people
on that platform, all organically, and
Henzo has been the backbone of it over
the last 6 months. So, you know, now's
the time, go check it out. In addition
to that, I love a tool called One of
Ten. And so, inside of One of Ten, I go
and save different ideas that really go
and stand out to me. I have my ideas
area, and here you can see I'm saving
different outliers. An outlier is simply
a video that has gone and outperformed
that channel's average videos. And so,
when I'm thinking about creating titles
for YouTube, different packaging and
thumbnails, I'm constantly pulling from
one of 10 to come up with endless
content ideas. And because YouTube is
such a high-signal platform, the chances
are that if something's really
performing in a title on YouTube, it
could also perform really well as the
hook on an Instagram carousel, or it
could perform well as a newsletter
subject line, right? So, because YouTube
so high-signal, one of 10 is a really
powerful platform to be able to pull
really good titles and go and use those
to infuse into your content strategy.
So, here you can see as an example, you
know, I can see
a title like, you know, "Why I Became an
Extreme Minimalist." And I may go and
just remix that title to, you know, "Why
I Became a, you know, extreme
systematizer." Right? And just slightly
augmenting that title, and then making
it my own, right? And then just talking
about whatever I want to talk about that
day. That's a key piece to all this as
well, right? When we're coming up with
ideas, I you know, I'm taking data from
what's performed for me on LinkedIn, I'm
using things like X analytics and
YouTube Studio, as well as Instagram's
dashboard. But I'm also not losing sight
of just the kind of stuff that I want to
talk about because, you know, you can
also just get lost in all this sauce if
that's the only way you're pulling
content. As we keep going here, one of
the biggest hacks for creating content
that actually goes and drives
monetization
is going and hooking up your Fathom to
something like Cloud Code to be able to
go and take your transcripts from your
best sales calls, and then utilizing the
real words that your customer is saying,
the hot buttons, to then go and become
part of your content. And so, this is
just what we did um with one of our most
profitable YouTube videos. Here you can
see our YouTube dashboard. And here,
when I go and sort our videos by highest
revenue, you can see a video just here.
It's our sixth most profitable video
ever. It's called copy this content
strategy, it'll blow up your business.
And a lot of the language inside of that
video which drove us over $30,000
was taken from our most popular sales
calls. Before we go deeper, I want to
give you the content machine scorecard.
It's a free diagnostic that we run on
every founder before we install this.
You answer a short set of questions and
you get a score telling you exactly what
part of the content engine is your
bottleneck. It takes just 4 minutes or
less and you can bring that score
directly onto a call with me and my team
to get a head start on building your
content machine together with us. Link
is in the description, go and check that
out right now. Section two, your
performance signal filter. All right,
sources alone are not enough, right?
Because even if you post content based
on the right signals, you can easily
just lose track of which signals to
double down on if you don't have this
next layer installed. This is the signal
performance filter. Now that we've got a
bit of data, a bit of customer calls,
and the founder interview inside of
Henzo, we can then go and start actually
posting this content, okay? Now, one
quick side note here, okay, is that
along the way, as you keep on putting
out more content, you're seeing what
stuff works best, and I'd recommend
you're also talking to your customer.
There's nothing that beats just talking
to your actual customer, right? And
using that data to become kind of like
your voice of customer extraction. So
here you can see one from Founder OS,
right? Which is the community of
founders that I help go and scale their
founder-led brands, build their social
media machines just like I'm showing you
here in this video, but doing it custom
for founders inside of Founder OS. This
voice of customer document basically
gets into using the actual words that I
hear founders talk to me about all the
time, right? Like I'm doing too much as
of now, growing pains, you could say, or
my bandwidth is the biggest problem. I
just crossed the milestone of a
seven-figure top-line business, but I'm
doing too much. I hear about their
dreams as well, things like, you know, I
want to have more focused time and less
business-as-usual dedication, more
strategic space of mind to think. You
know, I want to be better, you know, not
just like Matt, but I want to, you know,
really have more time like him. You
know, I'd like to reduce the amount of
dependency the business actually has on
me. And so, this is exactly the stuff
that we help founders with inside of
Founder OS, helping them go from founder
dependent to founder independent
businesses, right? Where not
everything's relying on you and you're
able to remove yourself from more of the
operations and have a social media
machine that works while you sleep. it's
really helping founders go and develop
this kind of content machine that can
run without them. You know, and then
when it comes to these founder goals
then, right? You know, they're doing
about 180k per month right now and want
to triple that. You know, if I could get
to $5 million a year, that would be the
realistic next step. You know, they want
to 4x or 5x their revenue in the next
two to three years. So, with all of
this, right? You can imagine how this
would go and inform some of my topics
for YouTube, some of my newsletter
subject lines, right? I'm able to go and
generate endless content ideas off of
all of this customer data that I'm
extracting from things like customer
interviews, as well as the Fathom
transcripts. From there, you know, the
seeing things like objections and
constraints as well, right? Oftentimes,
the point of content is basically to
help presuade and pre-sell people before
they even get on a sales call with you.
And there's no better way to do that
than actually go and create content that
addresses those objections on Instagram,
on YouTube. So, before someone even gets
on a call, ideally, they're just ready
to open their wallet and get going
because so many of the common questions
that they ask on the calls have already
been addressed well beforehand. Now that
we've got that all nailed, right? When
it comes to posting the content itself,
okay? There's a lot of different things
that I look at here. So, first off, you
know, inside of YouTube Studio here,
right? This is where we go when we post
all of our YouTube content. One big
thing you can go and see in this Figma
doc over here is that prior to any post
on YouTube, right? We're actually going
and coming up with 10, 20 different
title ideas, right? Based on all that
research we just did and then we're AB
testing these different titles. This is
the benefit of having endless content
ideas is that often times when I'm
posting on YouTube, I don't even know
what the hell is going to work and
that's not the point. The point is to
have endless content ideas. You're able
to go and put up 10 to 20 different
YouTube titles and then just see what
the winner is, okay? And so that's how
we go and use YouTube and it's AB
testing functionality to go and grow our
content. Here you can see, you know, on
this video right here, the psychology of
selling anything, right now we have a
whole, you know, different batch of
titles being tested, right? The
psychology of selling anything, the
psychology of why people buy. We'll let
that run for another 12 days and kind of
see which title emerges as the winning
title for that given video. And so you
can imagine we have this going on across
every video we put out there and it's
only possible because we have an endless
stream of ideas. As we go and we look
through this as well, right? Every
single video and piece of content that
we put out there, right? Always has UTM
links, right? So unique trackable
identifying links, okay? And so when we
look at what that looks like over here,
right? You can see
every piece of content we have typically
below it, like this video right here,
you'll see that there's a core lead
magnet that we're giving away, right?
That lead magnet has a trackable link
and so there's a given URL, as an
example, my master plan here has a URL
where people can go and get it. That
leads to a unique landing page and that
unique landing page has an identifier in
the link. So we know when people go and
put in their first name, last name,
email and phone number to this and then
we're able to track those people all the
way from downloading that lead magnet
all the way through to sale. What that
allows us to do then, based on all of
these different lead magnets, is then
track inside of things like the YouTube
dashboard. So, what that allows us to do
is inside of this YouTube dashboard be
able to track which of this content is
actually generating the most cash flow.
Now, let's keep grooving here. So, we've
got HubSpot that I'm using there for all
of those trackable links, right? I go
and I have my website all built off of
Webflow, but it doesn't really matter
what you use. From there, all those
landing pages as you see, there's no
links around it other than just
inputting your information and getting
the guide. Okay, from there, our lead
magnets are often times and things like
Google Docs, Slides, and more recently,
I've actually been using Cloud Code to
go and generate different tools, right?
So, we've got a ton of tools we've been
making more recently.
Things like my personal brand scorecard,
which you can get below, my things like
my founder dependency test to see how
dependent your business is on you and
whether you actually have founder
freedom, which you go check that one out
down here as well. And so, we're using a
lot of these different lead magnets that
combine with kind of an application to
Founder OS. So, what we're doing is
providing people with an assessment, and
when they've gone through that
assessment, we're providing them with a
custom scorecard based on how they did
so they can go and immediately start
improving the areas that they're weak.
The cool thing is that it also serves as
an application to then, if the founder's
right, to go and get on a call with us,
bring their score, and get on a call
with a brand strategist from my team to
then get help going and evolving their
business. What I've been able to do with
these is essentially take the flow from
going from my content to sales call from
about 12 steps all the way down to just
three steps. So, you can imagine how
much that's also helped us go and
increase the amount of leads we have.
It's like 4x the leads to the company
and had a similar effect on the overall
cash collected as well. And this is
exactly one of the kind of core flows
that I'm going to be doubling down on to
get the business to $2 million
of cash collected per month this year,
okay? Ambitious goals, but it's these
kinds of systems that allow us to make
those kind of ambitious goals happen.
So, as we look at all these as well, I
just also just use the dashboards that
these platforms provide to help me go
and come up with amazing content ideas.
And so, the thing to do if you find
yourself in a moment where your content
feels like it's underperforming, what I
like to do is just go back and like I'll
look at a given dashboard, say, you
know, my Instagram dashboard like this
over the last 90 days, and I'll just go
and start studying the content that has
performed well. And so, I'll go and look
at it. Let's just say based on views the
last 30 days. Here I can see, you know,
people seem to have liked this more sort
of
>> [music]
>> aesthetic cool video that we had posted
up, No Founder's Perfect, but ones who
build a personal brand will survive. So,
you know, a pretty bold take there, but
my belief is that the future belongs to
founder-led brands. Um we can see that a
lot of these carousels are working. So,
this is like the five levels of building
a personal brand, and we've gone and
broken it down, and this was actually
waterfalled from a longer form piece of
content we made, which I'll show you how
to do that here in just a minute. You
know, we'll see things like even me
using the my handwriting to go and
create these custom carousels. So, it's
my handwriting plus just like a paper
background um that is providing a lot of
value and doing well. And so, what I'll
do then is when I look at this data,
right? I'll just start doubling down on
the formats I'm seeing working. So, I'm
seeing here some nice design carousels,
some handwriting carousels, and I'm
seeing a bunch of these kind of yapping
videos I've been doing more recently
that are also performing well. This is
my entire tech stack for a million per
month, you know, showing folks how I use
things like Cloud Code, HubSpot, Vercel,
Supabase, and 8 then Fathom, Slack, and
Calendly to go and kind of build the
stack of my business. So, it's content
plus this autonomous engine that helps
me scale. And it's on well. So, I'll use
then these videos to then come up with
just more ideas, right? Because clearly
this is what my audience on Instagram is
resonating with, all 960,000 of them.
Section three, the anchor piece. Once
you're able to identify the signals that
are working, they should point to the
specific piece of content that is worth
amplifying and multiplying. I call this
piece of content the anchor piece, and
it's the single piece of content that is
undeniably resonating. The one that
earned the right to be then waterfalled
across every other platform. As we then
go and we start going and posting this
content, what then ends up happening,
right, is that my anchor content is the
longer-form content that I will then go
and waterfall. I'd recommend you having
kind of a pod-based approach to all
this, right? so you're going to come up
with these ideas, it's probably going to
be you, and then maybe you have a social
media manager and a writer if you're
moving on platforms like X and LinkedIn
with your ideas, or if you're going more
video-first, it may be you and a video
editor and a social media manager, and
that being the initial kind of pod to
get your whole content machine rolling.
With that little pod, you're able to
then go and execute on the content
waterfall system. So, as you can see
here, this video here, how to build a
profitable personal brand in just seven
steps, goes and becomes multiple
different formats. So, here you can see
I made it into an Instagram reel, right?
It went and became, you know, a pretty
successful reel on my channel with over
110,000 views. I also turned it into a
carousel, how to build a personal brand
in just seven days, which also was an
insanely high performer, right? And from
there, you know, I'm able to take things
like, you know, this long-form video,
I'm 35 if you're in your 20s or 30s
watch this, and use that for things like
my major life hacks, right? And using
the pieces of that video to become
[music] individual cards within this
carousel. Now, the key thing here, too,
as you can see is that every end card of
this carousels has a course CTA that
then drives people to my email list and
drives them to a conversion, right? So
that we're not just coming up with ideas
here that are going to drive views.
We're always focused on actually making
sure that those views lead to cash,
right? Because cash pays the bills. And
so, not only that, right? You can see
across all these different formats, even
on LinkedIn, right? We're going and
using those same pillar YouTube videos
to then come up with long-form LinkedIn
posts. We're using it to come up with
the infographics for those LinkedIn
posts, which is a super key aspect to
going and building a high-performance
LinkedIn presence. You know, amazing
hooks, long-form value, and then a
value-dense image, okay? And now we're
using it as well for all of my Instagram
presence. You know, my most popular
video on my channel is how to work less
and earn more. You can check it out over
here. And we've used that to go and
create, you know, [music] different
carousel formats, even content for my X
as well, right? Including both
short-form tweets, as well as long-form
articles like this. This concept of
waterfalling content is key, and that
should be a core verb that you and your
content team are using constantly. When
you see a high performer on any given
platform, you should be saying, "Hey,
let's take this idea over here." Could
be an Instagram carousel that's gone
viral, and let's waterfall it. When you
hear that, what that means is, "Okay,
we're going to take this carousel, and
we're going to turn that into a
long-form YouTube video. We're going to
turn that into a LinkedIn post. We're
going to turn that into a newsletter as
an example, right? So it's just this
idea that we're going to repurpose that
into more pieces of content." Section
four, the content calendar. All of this
content that you're now waterfalling,
you're drowning, right? And just
amazing, profitable, high-converting
content ideas at this point. Now we want
to go and filter that through to our
content calendar. So this is an example
of a content calendar that I made for a
founder named Mark inside of Edge, which
is where I work with founders one-to-one
every single week, helping them go and
construct all of this for them, right?
Getting my hands in there, building out
content machines, building out um lead
magnets and landing pages and content
counters. Like this is the kind of stuff
that as you probably can tell jazzes me
the [\h__\h] up, okay? And so, this is an
example of a content calendar going and
making sure that Mark's got a LinkedIn
post per day, a YouTube video per week,
a newsletter per week, and then he's
taking that YouTube video that he's made
and also publishing that to Spotify as
well as Apple Music. From there, it's
then the conversion architecture, right?
And basically, without getting into all
that, you can go watch this next video
that I'll get into more of that, but
we're going and creating different CTAs,
landing pages, and things like workshops
to be the bridge between all of these
amazing content ideas and your
monetization. Now, just to show you two
behind the scenes how me and the team go
and construct all this, this is our
Asana internally that Diego goes and
manages. Here you can see all things
like the different ideas that we're
going to be recording. You can see the
bank of content then that we've shot.
So, at any given moment, you know, you
can see here, we've got a lot of content
in the backlog, right? Around like 16
different concepts at any given time,
which is going to last us like two two
and a half months. So, there's never
this feeling like I'm on some content
treadmill, right? I film in batches um
those content ideas I just showed you,
right? And then that content then lasts
me months. And so, this allows me to
build a peaceful content operation where
I'm not lost trying to freaking keep up
with some, you know, just, you know,
slave driving mentality of getting all
these things going. It's very much
something that like runs and it's just a
part of what I do, not everything I do.
I'd say I spend around probably 7% of my
time on content, the rest is just
actually building the team, the
business, the culture, um and new
products. The best part about this
content machine is it's not theoretical,
right? This is the exact workflow that
I've been using for about 18 years now,
and it's exactly what we build for you
and train your team on inside of your
business in Founder OS. By day seven,
your brand foundation lands. We've built
your own unique brand positioning,
right? So, you know your customer, your
content pillars, you're really clear on
your founder narrative, and you're
basically able to watch us, you know,
senior operators go and translate your
voice into core strategy documents that
are being built live in front of you on
calls. Day 30, your content machine,
just like this, is delivered. And by day
60, your conversion infrastructure is
live. BSL scripts, email sequences, lead
magnets, landing pages, workshops, the
full machine on every platform in your
voice, scheduled and executing without
you. If you're ready to finally own your
distribution, hit the first link in the
description and go and apply today. And
if you want to dive deeper into the
content strategy that's going to blow up
your business, go and check out this
next video. All right. Thanks so much
for watching. I'll see you in the next
one, and let's win together.