There's this Warren Buffett quote where
he says, "The difference between
successful people and really successful
people is that really successful people
say no to almost everything. I used to
have so many things going on in my life,
so many distractions that I hardly had
any ability to actually do the main
thing that matters." What I've learned
is that, you know, time is your most
valuable resource. And oftentimes it's
just saying no to 97% of things that
come across your desk. And if I wanted
to be successful and really happy, you
know, I had to say no to this to say yes
to something else. Helping founders,
building content, being creative,
working with an awesome team. These are
the things I love to do. You need to not
be afraid to say no. So, what are you
going to go and say no to