If you want to become consistent and do
hard things, you must realize that
discipline actually starts the night
before, not the morning of. Every single
night, I sit down with a pen and paper,
and I write down my power list for the
next [music] day. Then, I rank them from
one through seven in order of
importance. Next to each item, I write
down the potential long-term cash flow
or impact of each [music] task. I'll go
and write down all of these core things
that I think I need to get done. I then
take a step back, and I look at it, and
I go, "Okay, I'm going to go and rank
these things." And this typically
indicates the order by which I'm going
to go and accomplish those things the
next morning when I wake up and get into
my founder flow. Here, you can see
number one, I needed to come up with a
filming checklist, a video [music] I
needed to finish up. There were things
like getting the book written, getting
the book outline. And so, here, I've
gone and indicated which of these tasks
adds up to how much money. And so, this
transforms a boring to-do [music] list
into a high-stakes roadmap. And above
all, this removes decision fatigue for
the next day.