You only get 4,000 weeks on this planet.
That's it. Now, before you know it, it's
over. I've spent 200 plus weeks in
meetings around meetings. I spent 52
weeks working for the man. At the end of
the day, you got to go and realize time
is your most valuable asset and it's
nonrenewable. So, stop wasting it. I see
so many founders going and building
businesses that they hate. You know, if
you're in a niche and you're not
enjoying it, change it up. Don't keep
doing the same thing over and over. Then
the one thing that is most important is
to have the courage to say no. to
sometimes even leave things behind that
you've done for years and then go and
bet on yourself, on your happiness
because time's running