A personal brand is a money cheat code
if you understand this one thing. Your
brand is your most powerful [music]
asset. And I'm not just talking about
logos or aesthetics, right? I'm talking
about your literal brand messaging. And
so, how do you go and create your brand
positioning? Well, I like to break it
down into these three parts. First off
is you have your brand thesis, [music]
right? What is your overall point of
view in terms of where your space is
going? The second aspect is you're going
to go and describe the three core
components that make that point of view
come true. Now your last aspect now is
your core mechanism or unique approach
[music] to actually making this come
true. And so at Founder OS our unique
approach is that if you want to build a
systemized profitable founder brand, you
have to have a content GPS that helps
you [music] go and create amazing
content at scale, nurture those leads
and then monetize them. And so you need
to go and break down your three aspects
of your brand thesis if you hope to have
a clean and clear brand over the next