if you think making 50k a month as a
course creator is impossible think again
you can do it with one product launch
here's how step one build in public tell
people what you're working on offer them
access ask for feedback refine your
content and get amazing results now
you've got your testimonials step two
promote your launch create an incredible
offer using early bird discounts stack
the bonuses use scarcity and don't be
afraid to promote hard step three keep
the launch going create referral program
for past customers promote the launch
once a week automate sales with an email
sequence save this blueprint