Your brain doesn't know the difference
between what you imagine and what's
real. This is called your
psychoscybernetic mechanism. And the
question is, is it working for you or
against you? Right now, you have a
self-image. It's the story that you tell
yourself about who you really are. Your
subconscious will move heaven and earth
to make that image come true. So, if you
see yourself as someone that's
unsuccessful, that's not confident,
that's uncapable, that exact image that
you're imagining, it's going to come
true. But if you rewire that image, if
you see yourself as someone that's
successful, that's wealthy, that's
abundant, that's the image that's going
to come true. The moment you change your
self-image, everything changes. Your
decisions change, your actions change,
your momentum changes, and then one day
you wake up, you look around you, and
you're shocked to see the life you've
built for yourself because you're not
fighting your identity anymore. You're
flowing with it. So the question is, are
you going to remember who you truly