Do genuinely whatever it [\h__\h] takes.
And I don't mean grinding or hustling
yourself into the ground. I mean doing
whatever it takes for you to fill up
your own cup, for you to regulate your
own nervous system.
It's so easy to find yourself running a
business that's running you into the
ground. More meetings, Slack
notifications, waking up to fires.
And before you know it,
you don't even recognize the person
that's looking back at you in the mirror
while you're brushing your teeth in the
evening.
And
in reality, you are the most important
asset in your business. But so often as
founders, we forget this, right? And so,
you need to do whatever the [\h__\h] it
takes, right? To take care of yourself.
Whether that's taking a spontaneous day
off, right? Just to go and rest, right?
It's being okay with taking the weekend
to just put things down and give your
kind of mind a bit of
a recharge and some clarity.
You know, it's making sure that you're
also surrounding yourself with different
habits and routines that fill up your
cup. For me, you know, I've been taking
up Muay Thai twice a week. I do yoga
once a week to kind of down regulate. A
nice breath work session every single
Thursday for 2 hours. And it's these
sort of rhythms in my week that help me
kind of just chill the hell out. Um and
be able to kind of fill up my cup
because it's important.