Most of what you've learned about
productivity, it's a lie. It's not about
task after task, being more efficient
all the time, trying to constantly go,
go, go, do more, more, more, burning the
midnight oil, spending time hustling all
day. In fact, productivity and
happiness, the intersection there is
actually subtracting more than you add,
removing the distractions so that I can
be this well-rounded founder. You know,
my belief is that entrepreneurs are
athletes and strong founders build
strong systems build strong businesses.
Making sure that you have the time to
fill up your own cup is key because you
can't build a great business if you're
not doing