Reels are for storytelling and lifestyle
content. Carousels are for tactical,
educational content, and stories are for
more behind-the-scenes, vulnerable
content. So, my reels over here, as an
example, really paint this more
aspirational life of a founder. All the
systems that I go and show people allow
them to get their time back. And I know
when I'm getting my time back, I'm out
in nature, I'm traveling, and I'm just
enjoying the world. That's what I'm
trying to show people in a real like
this as an example. On the carousel
side, I'm trying to go deep helping
founders really scale their offer, get
to 300K plus per month, and be able to
go and build teams through proper
delegation structure, and the right
organic content. And so, that's exactly
what I do, breaking down all of these
systems in detail in these educational
[music] carousels. Now, behind the
scenes, it's all about just letting
people know just day-to-day what I'm up
to. just raw thoughts of things on my
mind, whether it's books I'm reading,
[music] places I'm traveling, different
things I'm learning, and just sharing
kind of the things on my mind directly
with people so they feel [music] like
they get to know the real Matt.