I have to pinch myself.
[Music]
We're all posted up here in Bali. Flew
in three team members for the week.
We're about to chop it up, go through a
bunch of product improvements, community
improvements, have a lot of fun, go on
some adventures. You know, it took me,
you know, 13 years to create a life like
this, a life of freedom, a life of
adventure, of fun, with an amazing team,
amazing relationships around me.
Honestly, I didn't even think this was
possible. You know, I felt like this
sort of life was out of grasp. And no
matter what I tried, what mentors I
surrounded myself with, whatever I
learned, nothing seemed to click,
nothing seemed to work. seriously led to
a lot of dark days, lonely nights, and I
felt like no matter what I tried, I just
couldn't put the pieces together. For
years, I kept on looking outside of me
for where the issue was. You know, was
it the team I was surrounding myself
with? Was it the friends that I was
surrounding myself with? Was it the
location I was working from? Was it my
eating habits? You know, what the hell
was it? I couldn't put my finger on the
pulse of why I wasn't able to go and
create the life that I truly felt like I
deserved, but that constantly felt out
of grasp. I realized that it wasn't some
external source that was preventing me
from where I was looking to go. It was
me. I was the bottleneck. I was the
constraint. I was the cap on my own
success. If I was going to get to where
I thought I deserve to be in life, I
needed to save myself. I needed to go
and change my habits where I was
spending my time, where I was focusing
my energy. And when I started to do
that, my whole world opened up. I
started creating more freedom in
different areas of my life. I started
being able to hire much better people. I
was a much better role model to those
around me, my community, my team, and
thereby causing them just by nature to
kind of level up themselves. I've been
dedicated to showing you all of the
proven systems that I've used across
audience growth, organic content,
personal branding, hiring, firing,
whatever. I think though as
entrepreneurs, we learn a lot just from
watching, from observing. And so what I
want to do here is show you how I
actually implement this stuff, show you
just how I live my life. I was with one
founder Qataro in Tokyo and he was
saying, "Matt, I just want to see kind
of behind the scenes, you know, how do
you actually function? How do you
actually grow this team? How do you run
your company? How do you live your
life?" So, this video is forQatara. It's
a bit of an inside glimpse of my life,
how I structure my days and the amazing
people I've been able to surround myself
with. So, you can go and take some of
those hidden secrets that I don't
generally open up about and apply them
to your current situation. You know, we
all deserve to live like this. I'm going
to show you how I live, how I work, and
you're going to want to take some notes
here because I think there's going to be
some inside secrets that you're going to
want to apply to your
[Music]
life. Today, we are chopping it up
around the VSSL part of the funnel.
Really nailing that video and so that
going into the calls, people are showing
up. They're stoked. They know what we're
all about. They already know if it's a
right fit for them or not. And you know,
we can hit the ground running with them.
So, that's the focus of today, just
making a badass
VSSL. Jordan and I have worked together
for the last two years. He's actually
like OG founder OS. Over time, we've
actually become really great friends,
which I think is the goal of any
teammate over time. At the end of the
day, you know, you hire weapons on your
team because your belief is that, you
know, when you're in a group, say
there's two of you, 1 plus 1 equals 10.
I have my perspective on things. So,
it's all about kind of getting his
perspective as he's on the ground floor
talking with thousands of founders a
year. Yo yo, here we go, sir.
Like, there's just too many slides. It's
got to be shorter, I think, within that
10 to 13 minute range. try and get this
thing down to, you know, 40 slides or
something like that. A human gets
overwhelmed if there's like too much
[\h__\h] I think it's like cutting all fat.
Like he's like, is this necessary? No,
you don't need that [\h__\h] Bam. Bam. Bam.
You know, I think a lot of people at the
end of the day are just looking to build
cool [\h__\h] Like, [\h__\h] all the eloquence
and like all the [\h__\h] Like, what do
you really want? I just want a proven
system. I want this [\h__\h] to work and I
want to build cool [\h__\h] with people I
enjoy. Build, you know, we don't need to
say all the stuff. It's the systems.
It's the support and the simplicity
across your content, your personal
brand, audience growth, and lead genen.
This is actually what's in this offer to
have no questions about like what do we
do inside Found Plus? That's my goal. We
can make something we're just proud of
where people are just like holy [\h__\h]
Like this is for real.
[Music]
So, we just took that VSSL deck, which
is around like 180 slides, and narrowed
it down to about 45. I think it's
trimming just a bunch of the fat. You
don't see Harvard making absurd claims
about the kind of people that are
graduating from Harvard. They just
basically say, "We're the [\h__\h] Look at
the kind of experience people have had.
Look at the feeling people have had
going through this." And they can just
hang their hat on that. And so when I
think about creating an enduring brand
with Founder OS, not just something
that's going to exist in two years or in
5 years or in 10 years, we're looking to
build this for the next 50 hundred
years. the effects of this like
downstream because it's I think this
like this will be the best it's ever
been. This will be the crazy part is you
cut from what we just did whatever
there's probably 4 minutes of just fuego
of that hour and then you just cut to
showing it to people on YouTube and it's
just like that is the YouTube ESL. All
right. Well, here it is. It's
like have you ever wanted to build
something incredible but you just feel
like something's missing? like you have
so much potential, but you're not sure
what your best next move should be. You
look at your business, this thing you've
poured your heart and soul into, and you
can see the vision so clearly in your
mind. Yet somehow, the gap between where
you are and where you're looking to go
feels insurmountable. You've plateaued.
You're overthinking, overwork, pulling
yourself in a hundred different
directions. My question to you is this.
Are you building a business that can
match the scale of your vision? Are you
building systems that will allow your
idea to reach its full potential? Or are
you stuck in the founder trap, playing
too small where your business can only
grow as big as the hours in your day?
And what you really need to know is
what's the right next
step? This is exactly why I went and
created Founder OS.
I told myself that when I finally
figured out the systems that would help
eliminate founder overwhelm and lead to
founder clarity, I would share these
systems. I would share them with people
like yourself, those action takers, high
achievers that have so much potential
but just need a bit of a guide and a
proven path to get there. To be clear,
it doesn't mean that you're not making
money. It just means that you see that
there's just so much potential in mind.
And that gap that exists between where
you are and where you're looking to go
is what we help bridge for founders just
like
[Music]
you. It's a system I've cultivated over
the last 14 years through blood, sweat,
and doing it the hard way. I then
learned there's a proven way to drive
people from your audience, you know, and
own that audience and then be able to
sell to those people in a more
predictable, scalable way that allows
you to sleep at night, have peace of
mind, and have a level of predictability
in your business. So, you're not
guessing where your next leads or your
next sale are going to come from. And
I'm not just doing it for myself. And
we've helped thousands of founders with
the help of my success coach. We've been
able to craft a higher ticket offer,
create it into an agency, and now our
biggest problem is we can't handle the
leads. I would highly recommend Matt's
Grace Mastermind to really any founder.
The money that I invested into this, I
know that I'm going to get back 100%. Of
a group like this, you know that they're
going to draw individuals that have that
same passion for what they do. It just
makes you desire to be the best at what
you do, even if others are in a
completely different field. He
definitely has the business acumen, but
he also shares content around the
well-being of founders. If you come to a
founder OS retreat, you're going to
leave refreshed. You're going to have
new friendships, a network of people. I
know that whenever the founder and that
puts an event together, it's going to
attract really high caliber people and
they're the people I want to be around.
I've worked with other CEOs and founders
and coaches and gurus and it's always
been so aggressive and Matt and his
team, everybody is just so aligned, so
soulful, but everyone is creating
creating monetary results as well.
There's no better way to shortcut your
path to success than by working with
people who have done it before. That is
the ultimate cheat code in
entrepreneurship. It's so much easier
just to go and leverage the systems that
others have built and then adapt those
to your business to achieve your
mission. I understand your struggle, but
I also understand how big your vision
is. If you're an action taker like me
and like the people that I surround
myself with, we'd love to chat with you
and we can't wait to help you win. I
want to encourage you to go book your
call below. Make sure you show up to
that call with your brand strategist. We
can't wait to learn more about you, your
business, and we can't wait to be
partners along the way and helping you
scale that. I look forward to connecting
with you and let's win
together. Like last time I thought we
made it, we were pretty damn rigorous
about it. But then it's like obviously
you come back to it and you're like,
"Okay, how can we make this better?" And
you just pick apart every word even
more. maybe even take a step back and
get a little bit detached from it. We
were just at first talking about a deck,
but now we're talking about all the
testimonials we can bring it in, how we
bring the footage from the events that
we do into it and how we go and actually
just show our screen and show them the
kind of work that we do in the
background, which you don't get when
you're just stuck on Zoom calls all day.
100%. Something cool as well is just
like also taking from direct experience,
not just from like what we see like how
we help founders, but like where is the
like the world going to and like what do
they drive with and like why do people
follow people now? like what type of
content are they people really after?
So, you're taking like a world global
view to just how people respond to
marketing in general. It's also the
offer has transformed a ton over the
last year. Like we put a lot of work
into having the content GPS experts,
doubling the sessions and the access
people get to me. Taking like the
in-person experiences to like insane
levels. The systems are just one small
part of it. The magic of it is access to
the humans behind it all. like the same
humans that have built all this content
for us and built all the amazing growth
that we've seen internally. Trying to
convey that now through the marketing is
like really important because it's not
just like oh look at all these systems
you get. It's like sure that but like
90% of this other stuff is the real
sauce behind it
all at the end of the day. Like this is
what it's all about. Hanging with good
friends, building cool [\h__\h] having fun.
So many people, they get started with
that sort of essence when they're
building something and then inevitably
you don't have systems. You find
yourself caught up in the [\h__\h]
working in your business and you find
yourself running a business that's
essentially running you into the ground.
What I'm most excited by in terms of
what we're creating at Founder West and
even just what we just created, it's
unlocking that essence of I think why
99.9% of founders are even getting into
business. The ability to work on your
business, not in it. the ability to
build something fun with cool people
building cool [\h__\h] for freedom versus
all the mundane crap that oftentimes
ends up occupying people's
[Music]
lives. All right, so it's like 8:05 p.m.
here. I got calls from around 900 p.m.
till around midnight tonight. We're in
one of those seasons of going a little
bit harder than usual, you know, just
making things happen. We're actually in
the process, too, of hiring two new
graphic designers. I talk a lot about
how I think that taste is the ultimate
competitive advantage. And the truth is,
you can't just rely on a team to just
set that. So, when you're actually going
and hiring for creative positions, you
can't just expect that somehow those
creatives are just going to read your
mind, which is, I think, what most
founders do. The founder needs to be
really intimately involved in setting
things like cinematography they're
looking for, the lighting, the design,
the copy. My favorite way to paint that
picture is to save references. So here
you can see the different collections
that I've gone and saved. So I have an
Instagram collection, a brand
collection, I have my YouTube
collection. Say we go into the YouTube
collection as an example. I've gone and
saved a bunch of different creative
here. Things like set design, the actual
L, really inspirational sort of B-roll
scenes that I think capsulate the kind
of vibe that we're trying to curate on
YouTube. This is Anamorph. A lot of
great sort of more fitness lifestyle
type content. My belief is that
entrepreneurs are athletes and I think
this guy does a great job of kind of
encapsulating that like athletic vibe.
I'll even just save a lot of photos that
I really like, a lot of stuff I'll off
film that really inspires me. That's
just the YouTube one. The brand
collection is probably my favorite one.
I've been really curating this. This was
kind of started more recently, so it's
still work in development. Yeah, just a
lot of cool stuff that I'm seeing. One
of my favorites here, Amy Leondor did
this awesome collab with Porsche
recently. That way I don't just have to
go to some new graphic designer, say
that I'm bringing on and say, "All
right, man. So, the brand that we're
trying to create here is this, you know,
creative freedom aspirational vibe." I
mean, you might as well be speaking
Japanese, you know, it's not going to
make any sense. The bigger thing is to
show the references, right? Helps to
kind of set that picture, you know,
paint it for that person so they know
exactly what we're looking
for. Yeah. So, to give you just a sense
of the creators that inspire me, Amy
Leondor, I think their style, their mix
of not just product placement, but then
just setting like a vibe and doing cool
collabs. This one with Porsche, you
know, Ronnie Fie from Kith doing stuff
with BMW. The kind of content I find
myself most attracted to on the branding
side these days is stuff that's much
more raw and real and authentic and
hence why we've also shifted our
strategy a little bit here just to being
more off the cuff. It's the kind of
stuff that has also allowed me to feel
like I'm just friends with some of the
folks that I'm watching on YouTube as
well. Yeah, all this kind of curation
that's going on serves as good
inspiration for me and where I want the
brand to go and then serves as an
amazing reference for these awesome new
people that we're bringing on so that
they don't come into the brand and then
have to figure things out for the first
6 months until they can contribute real
[\h__\h] that we're proud of. The goal is
that person can come on, see our
existing stuff and more importantly see
the vision for where we're trying to go
through these clear references and then
just get after it relentlessly.
[Music]
One opportunity here at Founder OS is to
do for founders what I think Apple's
done for creatives, what Nike's done for
athletes. You know, we're trying to
create that aspirational brand for
founders. So, if you're a founder that's
looking to upgrade your taste, remember
curation over consumption. And on the
actionable side, you know, on Instagram,
go and make specific collections. on
YouTube. Go make specific playlists,
things like titles, thumbnails, hooks,
editing inspiration, lighting on
Pinterest, create a board on my mind,
which is an awesome Chrome extension,
you can create spaces over there. It
doesn't really matter what you use, but
just start to set up just even the most
basic curation system so that when
you're inspired and you have that light
bulb moment and you think to yourself,
"Damn, I wish we did something like
that." You can instantly save that
reference, pass it to your team, and be
able to create that magic that you
desire.
[Music]
So about 5 years ago, I sobered up,
stopped smoking weed, stopped drinking.
I had actually been DMing with Andrew
Huberman on Instagram and one thing came
to another and I realized that some of
these habits were causing things like my
testosterone levels just to skyrocket
downwards which was obviously not the
goal. So stopped all those bad habits,
replaced them with journaling, with
writing, with working out, doing yoga. I
ended up realizing that I wasn't really
living life in my core calling. While I
had been building a couple businesses
that I thought were making me happy, I
had kind of grown out of them and
realized that it was time for a pivot, a
big life pivot. I started looking at the
things that brought me joy, helping
founders, building systems, traveling,
viewing entrepreneurship as a soulful
journey, almost like the ultimate
meditation in life. And I started
something called soulful entrepreneur
which at the time I just gathered around
40 founders over 6 weeks once a week to
help them with things like the mindset
around building leadership growing a
team and then building systems for
things like audience growth organic
content and growing their personal
brand. Over time I actually realized
that the soulful entrepreneur brand
maybe it's a little bit woowoo sounds
borderline like a yoga studio. So based
on people's feedback, I was hearing you
know systems Matt systems these are the
things that are the most valuable from
you. So I rebranded the company from
soulful entrepreneur to founder OS which
stands for founder operating systems and
the rest is history. In my own heart I
still view my own sort of personal niche
if you will as soulful entrepreneurship.
This idea that the more you take care of
your body, your mind, your soul, your
spirit, your inner world, your outer
world transforms. I know that when I
take time to reflect, to slow down, just
to breathe, you know, and my whole kind
of creative world opens up and the more
creative I am, the more that Founder OS
benefits, the more I benefit, the more
the people around me benefit. So, yeah,
it's kind of my own personal philosophy
on building.
[Music]
a calendar for next week. Getting us
back on track. The main rule is we can't
book end the day. You're really loving
it here. And like we have to like lock
in what your schedule's going to look
like. Kieran got to factor in Scooby
Ricks.
You're going to see in your calendar
now. Beauty.
It's like you know the ESTI that we
like. Good. Like that's done. I'm going
to be in that a bunch in a year. Now
there's the Baldi time. Like I'm going
to be here four or five months here.
Yeah.
[Music]
I think like 90% of my role in my
dayto-day just involves me being in that
sort of creative energy, right? Feeling
light, feeling playful, feeling
youthful, having fun. And the more
you're just having fun, everything
around you just kind of evolves from
there. So that filters then to things
like the Austin retreat for founders
that we have coming up and the kind of
speakers we're going to have there, the
different breakouts we're going to do,
the kind of stuff that we're going to
implement for founders across their
personal brand, their audience, their
organic content, and it doesn't really
feel like work at all. You know, we're
just trying to put together an amazing
experience, something that feels almost
like a founder camp where people aren't
just learning a bunch, but they're also
connecting with one another. We're going
and seeding it with other legends that
have inspired me over the years so that
people are able to connect onetoone with
people that I've learned a lot
[Music]
from. Oh my
god. You know that I'm this systems
nerd. The reason I love systems so much
is not just so that I can then
replicate, you know, say that travel
system the next spot I go. It's actually
so that I make that system and I don't
need to think about it anymore. So, in
the case of, you know, my schedule, my
meetings, my daily routine, and all the
little bookings along the way and the
nuances of that, I just hand all of that
off to my chief of staff, who in this
case happens to be my sister. Now,
that's probably a surprise to many of
you. Wow, you work with your sister.
Some would think that's awesome. Some
may be thinking, "Damn, I heard there's
a lot of warnings out there from working
with your family." You know, I had a lot
of these concerns on both sides, right?
I started my sister off honestly
treating her just like any other person
that I work with. We started working on
a 60-day trial, seeing how it goes. Sort
of our initial conversation when we
kicked off even potentially working with
one another. I said to Claire, my
sister, you know, we got to be okay that
if this doesn't work out on either side,
that there's going to be no hard
feelings. You know, if I have to remove
you because I'm just like, ah, you know
what? this is a good experiment, but it
ain't going to work. Don't worry about
it. You know, let's not take it
personally. We'll just move on. So, we
kind of started it off on that very, I
guess, conscious level. Well, sure
enough, we all working together. Within
about 2 days, I realized that Clare was
a complete weapon, which to some, you
know, it surprised me. I just had never
seen Cla in a working environment ever.
She's my sister. Inevitably, the nice
thing that I found about working with
Cla, I want to work with people that I
just enjoy hanging out with, that I can
just be myself and be creative with. I
selfishly would love to just spend more
time with my sister. We've got a good
thing going. It's been about a year and
I look forward to doing it for another
years. So, it's funny. I get messages
from people all the time that see sort
of some of the travels that I may be on
and it looks sexy sometimes from the
outside. The reality is is that on the
background there's a bunch of kind of
systems that make all of this run
smoothly. Now, I was running into a
nomad here in, you know, Changangu a
couple weeks back and he was talking
about how he had been traveling for
about a year and working and was just
completely exhausted and he couldn't
believe that I've been doing this for
about 12 years of my life. Like just how
the hell do you do this? Now, my answer
to that is that when you go and you
start working and traveling, there are a
bunch of considerations.
Wi-Fi, work setup, routine, where's the
gym, where's the healthy spots to eat
around you. And so what I've essentially
done is in a lot of the spots that I
frequent regularly, I've almost created
like a pack for each of those spots. So
I have a Google map save list of all the
best spots in that given location. I
already have a saved sort of ideal
schedule based on that location's time
zone so that I don't need to, you know,
do some guessing game around when I
should wake up, when I should take
calls, when I where and when I can have
my morning coffee, I've kind of
optimized that day. And instead of just
moving on to the next spot and
forgetting about that whole schedule,
I'll actually go and save that somewhere
so that my chief of staff, my sister can
go and just replicate that exact
schedule that was amazing, that was
peaceful, that was inspiring, and just
use that exact schedule when I come back
again. And so we have these sort of
schedules in Dubai, which I generally
spend about a month a year. We have
these in Bali, which I'll probably be
spending around four to five months at
least per year. We have these for Europe
because I like to mountain bite the
Dolites in the summer. So we have that
scheduled now. We have those for the US
obviously. So we basically got the world
kind of covered now and got these time
zone calendar travel packs for each
spot. So I have my kind of perfect week
every week no matter where I come.
[Music]
Just playing paddle with Jordan, friend,
teammate of Founder OS and two members
of Founder OS. We all met up here,
Changangu, at Jungle Paddle. I think one
of the best ways to meet new friends and
to make a community wherever you are in
the world is just through common
interests. And the best way is just to
meet people that just do the same stuff
as you. Here we are with new friends,
hanging out, working up a sweat, having
some fun. pass the spy.
I want to fly. I want to fly. I said I
want my One of the hidden benefits of
building a personal brand is that you're
putting your own interests out there,
your own passions, the things that you
love to do, and you end up attracting
folks that are also into those things.
And this is pretty effortless. We all
know from online that we all like
paddle. And so it just kind of makes
sense that when we're together here in
Djangu, we get together, chop it up over
a game. Again, you're kind of sharing,
you know, the sort of stuff that you're
into, your core identity, and you start
attracting people with similar values,
similar interests, hobbies, and it just
makes it that much easier to meet up
with people around the world. I was just
in Tokyo, met a new friend, Qataro. I'm
now in Changangu, met some new friends
here, Lincoln, Jordan. And you know,
wherever I go, I find that this is
happening more and more and more. It
just keeps compounding. So beyond
revenue, beyond talent, beyond cash
flows, all that stuff is neat. But far
more cool than that is community, you
know, is relationships, friendships.
I didn't know when I started putting my
brand out there that it would lead to
that. Honestly, I did it more for those
other reasons. But as I've done it over
the last few years, I've actually
learned that the biggest benefit of it
is this. you know, meeting fellow
legends all around the world, sharing,
you know, common interests and hobbies,
having fun, and, you know, building
lifelong friendships. Put yourself out
there, share what you love, and attract
people that are in the same stuff as
you.
One of the most valuable systems I've
used over the last 14 years, building
multiple seven and eight figure
businesses, is my personal board
meeting. And so I'm going to show you
exactly how I go and use this every
single month and then how you can use it
as well to transform your life and your
business. So let's get into it. First
off, I like to get into what is my focus
for the upcoming month. So right now I'm
thinking about things like doing less
but better. You know, focused on the few
things in my life that are going to make
a massive impact. And I'll show you
throughout this exactly how I dial in
that focus. The next aspect is obsessing
over quality. Quality is the ultimate
pattern interrupt and I really focus on
making quality products, building a
quality team and really having quality
relationships in my life as well. The
next aspect is that I focus on peace
plus profit plus purpose. You know, one
of my main goals here for 2025 is to
really just dial in the peace. When you
think about a business, oftentimes it
really kind of defaults to chaos. And so
as you're growing, it's important that
you're constantly going and implementing
different systems, bringing on the right
people that are going to help you dial
in the peace in your life and in your
business. The next aspect here then is
creating insanely simple systems.
Insanely simple is something I've
learned from Steve Jobs, reading over
eight books on the guy. I have enormous
respect for him. He's probably like my
number one go-to sort of mentor.
Insanely simple really means distilling
things down to what is necessary and
honestly saying no by default. So I'm
only saying yes to the things that must
exist in my life and in my business. And
by nature, most things are a no. And I
just tend to discard those things. So I
eliminate distractions and can focus on
what is absolutely necessary. When I say
yes to things, I then make sure that
those things are a whole body yes.
Meaning that in my heart, in my mind, in
my soul, this thing fires me up. I got
to do it. If I feel that whole body yes,
like a hell yes, then I'll do it.
Otherwise, it's a no. And the next
aspect here is being an artist. Really
unleashing my creative potential to the
world. You know, my mission in life is
to inspire 100 million people to
accomplish their dreams through proven
systems. So, when I think about my own
life, I need to unlock my creative
potential to be able to have a massive
impact on millions of other people. So,
what do I focus on? Well, when you're
building a business, I think it's most
important that you're focused on revenue
producing priorities. So for me that's
things like dazzling the founders inside
of founder OS. I'm spending time
scheming and plotting, you know, giving
myself time to really think about what
are those things that I can use to 10x
the business. What are those big swings
we can take? Those pieces of content,
those things we can do in the audience
side, the ways that we can serve
founders to the best of our ability to
help them scale their businesses to new
heights to achieve freedom and to have a
ton of fun along the way. In addition to
that, you know, I'm writing sales copy
on things like landing pages, emails,
because, you know, copywriting is a
salesperson that never sleeps. When you
create an amazing landing page as an
example, that thing just works while
you're chilling. And so, copywriting is
one of my superpowers. And so, I spend
time making sure that the copy across
every touch point of founder OS is
unbelievably dialed in. The next aspect
here then is building a high performance
team. At the end of the day, team is
everything. The people are everything.
And at Founder OS, we're constantly
going and leveling up the squad. We've
got we've got a team of 32 people here
and I'll show you our org chart in just
one second. And then I'm delegating the
rest of the stuff that could be on my
plate to my chief of staff, which is my
sister Claire. So, she goes and handles
the things that are not in my zone of
genius, so I can focus on the most
important things at any given moment,
and the rest of the distractions are off
my plate. And lastly, things like
shooting videos just like this one, uh,
that serve you, give you massive value,
and help you level up because again,
that's a core part of my mission in
life. So, I like to also go and revisit
every single month my icky guy, which is
really my calling in life. So, here you
can see I've gone and filled out things
like what I love, what I'm great at,
what the world needs, and what I can be
paid for. You know, I've been dialing in
this exercise over the last like seven
years. Now, here you can see in the
center is my icky guy, right?
Highlighted there are things like
growing an a team, you know, building
distribution, helping founders with
proven systems, coaching founders,
traveling. These are the things that
bring me massive amounts of joy, that
fire me up, that get me excited to wake
up every single day to make an impact
and to live, right? So, I'd really
encourage you to think about that. And I
got a cool template I'm going to show
you in a second so you can go do the
same for yourself. So, then I think
about my February personal goals as an
example. So, I want to go on one artist
date per week, right? Something that is
just creative that gets my juices
flowing. That could be going for a
massage. That could be going to an art
or pottery class. Could be just going
out into a nice cafe and reading a book.
something just to feed my soul, to keep
me creative. The next aspect is I'm
reading this juggernaut of a book,
reality trans surfing. I was actually
gifted this by a founder that I had met
up with from our audience here in Tokyo,
Japan. Shout out Qataro for the book.
Much love, man. It means a lot. This
book has been amazing. It's teaching me
to reduce the importance on things in
life and to loosen my grip on life,
which is great to kind of reduce stress
and to get in that creative flow I think
that we're all after. So, I'm always
trying to read one or two books a month
to keep on leveling up because my belief
as a founder is that leadership is the
cap on your own success. The next aspect
here is that I'm filming high-quality
videos. I had our content producer,
Diego, out here in Bali, Indonesia,
where I'm at right now. We went and
filmed seven YouTube videos over 7 days
all over Bali. It was amazing. It was
uh, you know, a lot of work, but
incredibly rewarding, and I can't wait
to show you what we got coming down the
pipe. Next aspect here then is I want to
go on an epic mountain biking trip. I
fell in love with downhill mountain
biking when I was in the Dolommites,
Italy, the Italian Alps, waking up every
day, ripping downhill, mountain biking
for four hours, getting creative. It was
a dream. And so I have a dream of going
on another epic mountain biking trip
this month. So stay tuned for that. Now,
when I think about my business goals,
first off, my core strength in life is
installing content GPS's in founders
businesses, which is the most powerful
system I've ever discovered. And so my
goal is to help 60 founders with this in
February. In addition to that, my big
vision for Founder West is to have a
retreat center in the Doommites where we
can go and level up as founders. I can
have groups of 60 to 100 founders out at
any given time and we dial in our
health. We help one another with our
businesses, grow our audience, dial in
organic content and just have peak
experiences uh and peak performance for
the best of the best founders out there.
So, you are invited. The next aspect
here is I'm really upgrading all of our
email sequences. Email is responsible
for about 70% of the leads that come to
my portfolio of online businesses
because people come from my audience on
social to my email and then come and
work with me. And so inevitably the
stronger the email sequences, the
stronger the business. So this is what
my org chart looks like right now at
Founder OS. It's about 32 weapons right
now. And so again, I'm focused on not
just growing this team, but really
dialing this team in. You know, finding
the best of the best people in the world
to join it. making sure that at every
moment we're a team of people that are
dazzling founders and bringing on people
that are really passionate about, you
know, building the greatest founder
community of the 21st century. This is
what jazzes me up if you can't tell. I
also every single month revisit my
vision, right? My 10 year goals with
Founder S, my three-year goals, my
one-year goal, and my 90-day goals. And
I'm making sure that every single week
what I'm working on ladders up to this
big vision that I have. In addition, I
do the same with my own personal life,
laying out what my mission is, right?
Which is to really help a 100red million
people, right? And be this amazing
example of how to build an amazing
lifestyle by design. In addition to
that, you know, I got my 10 year, my
three-year goals, and then I reverse
engineer that to what my one-year goals
are, my three-year goals, uh, you know,
90-day goals, all that good stuff. Now,
you know, it takes a great group of
people to build a great founder. And so
I'm going and making sure that
throughout my career I'm dialing in my
personal board of adviserss. So one of
the most important people on that side
of my life is a gentleman named Ryan
Begelman who's become a great friend
over the last eight years. Ryan and I
met when I was at a really low point in
life. I was down and out feeling
depressed and I needed a coach. I needed
someone to help me go and grow. You
know, Michael Jordan had a coach. Serena
Williams had a coach. If you want to be
a great founder, you need a coach. So
Ryan is someone that's really helped me
with the strategy, uh, you know,
lifestyle design, managing emotions,
managing teams, and I continually meet
with Ryan every other week for 90
minutes to dial in my growth. And this
is the same sort of approach we take at
Founder OS uh, to become that kind of
personal board of adviserss for founders
just like yourself. In addition, I have
a health coach named Sadi who's helped
me dial up my health, my performance.
I'm doing HIT workouts now about five
days a week, yoga three days a week. I
got a whole health protocol I follow for
breakfast, lunch, dinner, supplements I
take just to feel good, feel energized
because the more energy you has have as
a founder, the more you can contribute
to the big vision that you have in life.
In addition, Claire, I get help on
operations and hiring, Harry on
marketing and copy. And so then at the
end of every month, I reflect on, you
know, what went well. So for this month,
you know, I hit record high revenue
milestones, I made three insanely highc
caliber hires, and I launched the hiring
funnel um at Founder OS, which I can
show you here in a sec. In addition to
that, you know what didn't go well?
Well, you know, I need to tighten up my
morning routine. I've been traveling. I
was in Japan for a bit snowboarding. Now
I'm in Bali. And so I just needed a
second basically to dial in that new
time zone because it's about 13 hours
ahead of EST, which is where I kind of
see Founder S as being like a New York
kind of based company in terms of, you
know, where we generally operate in as a
company is EST. So that just took a sec.
Similarly, I'm bringing on an internal
recruiter to founder West because, you
know, hiring takes a lot of time and
we're at the size now that we need a
legend to help us scale our team, find
people that know how to make amazing
systems, they understand founder brands,
they know audience growth, they're
obsessed with organic content, you know,
they're one of us. And so that takes
time and so I need some help there. In
addition to that, what I learned, right,
was that focus is everything, right? So
continuing to say no to more things.
It's a continual battle. In addition to
that, just constantly upping the quality
of every single thing I do. Quality
writing, quality copy, quality videos,
quality social, quality founder
experience, quality hires, you get it.
Quality is everything. In addition to
that, you know, just like you guys,
right, I'm constantly building systems
as we scale, right? From where we're now
to 20 million plus a year. It's
important that we continue to upgrade
those systems, right? So that I continue
to get more and more freedom and more
importantly, we just keep having more
and more fun. I'm currently having the
time of my life, you know, living every
day here in Bali, controlling where I
work, when I work, who I work with, what
I work on. It's a dream and systems have
helped create that. And so it's a
continual mindset though, right? This
systems thinking is a mindset to keep
growing, keep systemizing things so I
have more time to do what I love in
life. What I provided you here as well
is your own personal board meeting
template that you can get via the link
below in the description. So go check
that out right now and go and fill this
out. I would recommend that go watch
this video back and fill it out just
like I've shown you. I've done mine. So
you're going to have your icky guy,
right? Which is again the intersection
of what you love, what you can be paid
for, what you're great at, and what the
world needs. From there, you're going to
really dial in your core focus, right?
What drives you? What's your mission?
What are your principles? And what are
your non-negotiables in life? What are
you really focused on this month? Right?
Focus is the scarcest resource as a
founder. And so, making sure you have
three to five things that you are going
to go deep on to really crank it this
month. The next aspect is your personal
30-day goals, right? What books are you
reading? Habits you building? What are
you implementing in your business? You
know, what are you focused on doing to
level up as a leader? You know, go and
write those down. on your business side.
Look at your sales, your growth, your
marketing, your content, your personal
brand, your audience, your email. Is
this stuff dialed in? And what do you
need to do to go and hit your big vision
in life? It's time, right, to level up.
Let's go. On the reflection side, you
then want to think about what went well
over the last 30 days, what didn't go
well, and then you want to go and think
about what did you learn? Okay. And then
from there, I'd suggest going and
thinking about your own personal board
of adviserss. So, what mentors do you
have in your life? Coaches, you know,
core team members, you know, I'd love to
even be an adviser to help you out,
right? And be in your corner helping you
grow. And hopefully that's a lot of what
you get out of being part of this
amazing community we we are building
here as part of this founder freedom
movement here on this channel. So, it's
been a pleasure. Let's win together. If
you want help going and accelerating
your goals, be sure to go and check out
and apply to Founder Os via the link in
the description. Much love and let's win