in his book contagious Jonah Burger
reveals four principles from real
research for creating content that goes
viral social currency people share
things that make them look good does
your content make people look good when
they share it emotions High arousal
emotions like excitement or anger make
people share what does your content make
people feel practical value people don't
just want to look good they want to help
others does your content provide real
value your audience can share with their
friends stories people prefer to share
stories more than products build a
Trojan horror story for your brand and
make you compelling and sharew Worthy