if you're in your 20s and you're bored
then you need a vision here's the goal
setting system I use to go from being
depressed to making seven figures a year
with more energy than ever first set a
10year goal this is your North Star ask
yourself what does your dream world look
like where are you trying to go come up
with a vision that makes you jump out of
bed in the morning dream big next set
threeyear goals one-year goals and 90day
goals reverse engineer the steps needed
to reach your 10year goal avoid goals
like I'm going to sell online courses
instead write something like by
September 30th I'm going to have help a
thousand people in my Niche through my
digital product now keep all your goals
together in one place on your phone look
at them every morning it'll motivate you
to take Massive Action