But first things first, you got to slow
down and notice.
I'm about to go head to the airport
right now. We're going to Niseko. It's
me, another buddy, and Daniel Dalen. Got
10 days of snowboarding in the epic
Japan powder. This is kind of part of an
annual retreat I do every year for about
3 weeks to Japan on what I call a soul
trip, a chance to rejuvenate my nervous
system, to reconnect with nature, and
overall to relax. Now, on the subject of
nature, right? I think it's important,
right? To slow down and notice. When
you're out there in the mountains or
you're in a national park, you get a
chance to slow down, to hike, to connect
with friends, to laugh, and to connect
with really who you are at a more soul
level. You know, when you finally give
your nervous system a chance to
downregulate, you give yourself space,
right? And that space allows you room
for what's really going on inside to
start coming up. And it leads to truth,
right? For me, I know time in nature
has helped me discover the kind of
things that
I think I was put on Earth to do. Things
like helping founders with systems,
going and viewing entrepreneurship as a
soulful journey, building amazing teams,
building brands for the next 100 years,
not just the next year, and focusing on
craftsmanship, on mastery, on beauty.
And so, you know, when you finally give
yourself a space to go [music] away, I
think you also focus on the real things
in life, right? You can get so stuck in
performing all the time that you don't
give yourself time to just play.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Oh, such an epic day
of snowboarding today.
Met
an absolute legend named Ollie
on one of the lifts,
a 60-year-old.
I asked him,
"What is one of your biggest lessons of
your career?"
Because
he's newly retired.
He told me, he goes, "Matt,
sweat
the details."
Then Ollie asked me, he goes, "Matt, you
know, what's one of your biggest career
lessons?" And I would say that it's the
importance of really having a massive
mission.
It's not only incredibly motivating,
obviously, for me
uh to jump out of bed every morning,
you know, Founder OS and what I'm
building,
that mission is really [music] to
help 100 million founders accomplish
their dreams
through proven systems. You know, I've
learned that it's important to
really find that in anything that I do,
because what's the fun in just going the
easy route? What's the fun in just
playing it safe? What's the fun
in just being normal or ordinary when
you have the opportunity to be so much
more. I think there's an art to creating
that resonance with people.
And when you find it with a massive
mission, I think your ability to
mobilize your own team of weapons, your
own team of Avengers,
uh becomes so much more easier. And
you unlock a whole new level [music] of
fun.
>> [music]
>> At this stage of my career, at 36,
one of the most important things is just
making
something people want.
You know, I feel really inspired these
days by what we're building, but that
wasn't by accident. You know, it was
much
intentionally created, and it was done
by really thinking about criteria.
I started thinking about well, what
would it be like for me to look at
myself more like an investor
versus just an entrepreneur. And so, I
then came up with some criteria
that were really important to me upon
reflection. I remember taking out a
journal about 8 years ago
and intentionally writing down like,
"What is it that's really important to
me?" And the kind of things that came up
for me were that
I must go
and do work every day that feels like
play.
The kind of stuff that most people would
feel
is work to me would just feel fun.
The second thing was that I had to love
the customer, right? I wanted to love
the kind of people I was helping. You
know, founders, when I reflected on it,
are like my favorite people. You know,
all my friends are founders for the most
part.
The kind of people I find myself in my
spare time just chopping it up with are
founders.
And so, that felt like something I
should really lean into. The third thing
was to love the problem.
Make sure that what I was building
was something that
I genuinely loved, right? And that the
problem and the solving of that thing
over decades would be something that
would continually fire me up. The fourth
aspect is that there's founder-product
fit, meaning that what I was building
really just fit my own strengths and
desires and quirks like a glove. You
know, really going and helping founders.
I love building systems for every aspect
of my life, and I want to help founders
avoid the kind of struggle that I went
through [music] in the first 6, 7 years
of building companies. And the next
criteria was then just being able to
work with unbelievable people. Because
at the end of the day,
yeah, that's the funnest part of
building, right? Is being surrounded
with fellow creators, builders, dreamers
that all are united and passionate.
So, I share this with you really because
honestly, this would have saved me like
a decade of my career. I picked some
kind of poor opportunities at times.
You know, things that I probably
shouldn't have even wasted
6 months on, right? That I could have
avoided if I had been more aware of what
was important to me. And I think more
important than just being aware of it is
giving myself permission
to say no.
And having the bravery and the courage
to
>> [music]
>> do something or pick a direction in life
even when
I didn't know if it was going to work
out, but I did know that it innately was
motivating to me and was something that
I was excited by.
I think the final thing I reflect on
here is
just basically to keep on
leaning into
that 10-year-old version of yourself and
what they want to do.
I try to remind myself of this as much
as possible, but it's tricky, you know.
Sometimes we make business feel like
work. We make life feel hard, and it
doesn't need to be, right? It can be
fun. It can be enjoyable. It can be
something that lights us up.
I've been practicing more recently
something when I feel an inner sense of
like anger or rage,
which comes up, right?
And I've been practicing the words and
the language that I use with myself.
Instead of going and saying, "Oh my god,
I'm so mad," or "This is such bullshit,"
or whatever,
I tell myself, "Oh, this is mildly
annoying."
And it almost sometimes even makes me
kind of giggle a little bit, you know,
versus getting super worked up over
something that, you know, I can't
control or something that happened to
me. Just tell myself, "Oh, it's mildly
annoying." And then just kind of shrug
it off.
Because
I know that the 10-year-old version of
myself, the number one thing I was into
was play.
You know, what would the 10-year-old
version of yourself be proud of
building?
Forget status, forget money, forget
society's [music] expectations of what
you should be doing.
What does that kid in you want to do?
What are you curious [music] about? And
what feels like play?
Somewhere along the journey of life, we
abandon that version of ourselves. We
don't do it intentionally.
It just sort of happens.
But that kid in you is still in there.
What would make them feel most inspired?
What would your life look like if you
prioritize what brings you joy?
I don't think it always feels obvious,
but with a bit of space, you can tap
into something special. And doing it for
this version of yourself isn't some
stupid exercise. [music]
It might just be the most important
thing you do this year.
It means prioritizing exploration and
meaning. Because at the end of your
life, all the numbers fade, and the
10-year-old version of yourself is the
only audience that really matters.
All right, if you enjoyed this video,
hopefully it was helpful. You can go and
watch this next video, which is you'd be
richer if you just relaxed. And I dive
into some ways to chill out, let go of
the grip, and along the way actually be
more successful. So, go and check that
one out. Thanks so much for watching. Be
sure to like and subscribe.
And welcome to the Founder Freedom
Movement.
Hey, this is Matthew's new toy from
Kieran.
So, it goes backwards and it goes
forward.
That's neat, Matty.
Wow, Matthew. That's pretty special one.
Let's see who's left in here.