What is the album that only you can
make?
I got this question from my
[clears throat] friend Dan
this week in a cafe
here in
Pererenan, Bali.
And it got me thinking.
You know, what's the album only I can
make?
And it got me thinking just about some
of the threads that I'm excited by that
I think define what I'm all about,
right? There's a part of me that's this
intense [\h__\h]
that's passionate about building. It's
kind of like Apple for founders. This
company that's a gorgeous community and
founder infrastructure.
I also love nature and aspire to build a
brand that's almost like a
you know, Arc'teryx or North Face, but
for founders.
At the same token,
you know, I'm really about building
autonomous engines, but also about art.
Right? And there's a bit of a
juxtaposition to all of that.
And
in general, I think it just really
encouraged me to start sharing more of
the texture of my life, right? Not being
so polished, right? And embracing
more of just
this, right? Just chopping it up. The
kind of raw, real rant sort of vibe.
And so,
I think a good question to ask yourself
today, right? Is what's that album that
only you could make? It's a famous
question
that Rick Rubin asked Kanye, and he went
on to create some magic. So, sharing it
with you.