If you're micromanaging, you're
admitting you built a weak system. The
problem with micromanaging is that you
make your business founder dependent
versus founder independent and you slow
down all decision-m in your company. If
every decision needs to come down to
you, well, you only have so much
capacity in a day and you become the
bottleneck of the business. What you
want to go is make sure that you're
asking the golden question. The golden
question in any business is what is best
for the enterprise. Now you've brought
on all these people around you so you
might as well be using them for their
maximum potential. And so one practice
is instead of going and making the
decision when someone comes to you go
and ask them what is your
recommendation? You're slowly empowering
your team to use their judgment, their
intuition, and data to go and make the