Every December, you go and you start
planning out your next year. But sure
enough, the plans that you make don't
even make it to February. But this year,
it's time to do it [music] differently.
I've gone and designed an entire system,
the same one I've used over the past
[music] 16 years. It's not just
prettier. It's actually designed on
proven [music] systems that'll help you
dial in your company, your health, and
your growth. So, we're going to go
through this whole thing live. I'm going
to actually fill out my plan for 2026
and you can go and get the entire
template that we go through here via the
link in the description. So, go download
that and follow along. Step one,
reflection. Before you design the
future, you need to actually go and
reflect a bit on the past, right? What's
worked? What hasn't worked? So, you
don't just keep on making the same
mistakes over and over. Let's get into
it. The first bit here is your camera
roll audit. So, this is a really useful
exercise. You know, when you look over
the past year, often times there's a few
core memories that stand out, but you
kind of forget about, you know, some of
the key things cuz, you know, we just
forget things. One of the key hacks here
is to just go and look at your camera
roll, right? Go and open it up, go back
to January 1st of this year and go just
through the photos recalling kind of
where you were, the emotions you had,
some of the highlights, and the real
things you learned. And so, you know,
when I go through my camera roll here,
you know, it starts off with me going
and snowboarding with some friends in
Japan. One of the best trips of my life.
From there, heading on to Bali, spending
some time there, going and dialing in my
health, dialing in my rhythm, going then
through Sedona to go and run [music]
some different nature vibes there. then
going on through Europe all through the
summer, hanging out with some friends in
Lafeton, Norway, doing a bunch of epic
hikes, and making my way down to Lisbon,
Portugal. And so, as I kind of reflect
on these photos, I'm honestly kind of
reflecting just kind of proud of the
year I was able to create here. Proud of
the life I was able to design for myself
that's not just about, [music]
you know, growth, but is also just about
enjoying life and traveling the world to
places I love with people I love. you
know, just a few weeks ago was back in
Bali hosting an [music] epic founder
experience with Founder OS, really
dialing in a lot of the systems, hanging
out with the community. Honestly,
[music] these were some pinch me
moments, you know, and when I look back
on this year, you know, I'm proud of the
community we've created. [music] I'm
proud of the team and the life that I've
created. And it's these kind of photos
in the camera roll that really just go
and bring back those memories. Then it's
about sort of reflecting, right, on the
winds and the scars. Okay, what went
right and you know what also went wrong.
Ray Deio has this [music] quote of pain
plus reflection equals progress. It
gives us the opportunity to set us up
for the best year of our lives, right?
So on the wins here, right, it includes
things like, you know, we've just
continue to dial in our content and I'm
proud of where that's going. The team
has [music] been immaculate. We've hit
new, you know, revenue milestones
[music] um that, you know, honestly, I
couldn't have dreamed of a decade ago.
Uh, you know, we've continued to go and
create just an exceptional product. I
just look at the reviews that we get
every single week from founders and, you
know, the impact that we've made on
their business, their systems, helping
them go and scale up their teams. That
to me is like what fires me up and fires
our whole team up. Now, in terms of the
scars and what went wrong, well, this
isn't that wrong, but the truth is that
we've been scaling so fast. I'm at the
point right now where I need a COO. I
have someone that's running the
operations at Herb and in all of my
previous businesses, I've gone and hired
that kind of chief operating officer and
it's now time to do the same thing here
at Founder OS. So, yeah, if you know
anyone, you know, tell them to reach
out. And so in addition to that COO who
can help me on the op side of things, uh
an evolution that needs to take place on
just energy [music] management. You
know, when I look over this year, at the
beginning in January, we were doing two
YouTube videos [music] per month. And
now as we scale things up, uh you know,
me and the team decided to start moving
to two per week. So in a sense, there's
an a aspect here where we're almost like
creator athletes going and putting out
content that we think is [music] going
to make an impact in millions of
founders lives. But with that, you know,
we just need to make sure that we're
scaling up the overall sort of media
company around us. And [music] so that
means systems, dialing in the people.
Nothing really wrong, but just, you
know, a [music] continual evolution of
the companies and requires just keep
leveling up people, systems, processes,
all that good stuff. The same stuff that
I help founders with in Founder OS.
Let's get into the forgetting curve.
Okay. What I like to do is kind of
reflect on what were my three biggest
lessons in 2025. Because, you know, I
fill this out every year. And it's cool
because I can go and reflect on the same
deck that I filled out [music] in 2016
and see over the last decade the amount
of growth and evolution that's happened.
All right, [music] so my three biggest
lessons. Number one, when it comes to
companies, okay, A players are, you
know, 100 times better than B players.
When you think about someone that's like
an unbelievable video producer or
someone that's an unbelievable chief of
staff, [music] they're not just twice as
good as someone that's all right. Right.
From my experience, they're about a
hundred times better. [music] And so for
me, it's continue to reflect on the team
that we're building and keep on doubling
down on the talent as we grow. The
health side, I mean, I was in Bali a few
times this year. Um, and when I'm there,
I'm always dialing in yoga. For me, it
helps me get rooted, grounded, helps me
feel good, and really take action with a
lot of clarity, and has this ripple
effect in so many other areas of my
life. And so incorporating yoga about
four times a week, that's the current
routine at least, and I want to stick
with it. Continuing to lean into what's
most important in life, which it
inevitably are relationships, whether
it's on the business side, focusing on
playing long-term games with long-term
people, the kind of folks like Diego
here behind the camera, you know, my
sister Claire who's my chief of staff,
it's like all about surrounding myself
with people on the business side that I
could see myself working decades with.
Now, let's get on to pattern
recognition. All right. So, now that
we've reflected, we need to go and
extract the patterns. You know, [music]
every amazing athlete, elite CEO,
unbelievable entrepreneur, they've won
because they've been able to spot
patterns, right, that other people
missed, right? Whether it was Steve Jobs
seeing that computers would be on every
single desk of every human worldwide,
you know, and then transforming the
world with Apple or Elon Musk like
understanding that, you know, space
travel would be this massive thing and
inventing SpaceX. [music]
every single founder, right, has built a
business off of pattern recognition
[music] and understanding a secret
before the rest of the world. And so,
you know, what are some of those things
that you're seeing and patterns that are
emerging and taking a step back for a
second before we just go and jump into
the new year? For me, you know, [music]
my 4 hours of founder flow every morning
are definitely, you know, the kind of
pinnacle of my career, honestly. you
know, without those four hours every
single day, um, I wouldn't be where I am
today. Um, you know, the things that
definitely accelerated me too are, you
know, my team, right? Having really that
team dialed in, um, has honestly been
the biggest leverage point for all of my
growth. The things to avoid. I want to
be honest here and there like anyone,
you know, I don't take advantage of my
mornings. So, you know, making sure, you
know, no morning
meetings, right? need to keep that going
right and keep you know my diet dialed
in which has been amazing but you know
when these things come up it's all about
correcting yourself and then I'm
removing any energy vampires in terms of
energy forensics here okay this is all
about really understanding my energy is
highest right when you know again I'm
kind of you know doing my yoga every
morning I'm getting my founder flow um
I'm making except exceptional content
and [music] you know I'm really dialed
in with our team. You know we have good
systems. I especially loved hanging out
in person with my team whether it was in
Bali or in Lafeton Norway just being
able to chop it up bringing great folks
together to actually jam in person. So
on the energy lowest side, sometimes
[music] you know a C player sneaks
through the cracks, right? And suddenly
you find yourself dealing with people
that maybe have some sort of victim
mindset. Um or candidly just need to
constantly be reminded of There's
been a couple instances of this across
my portfolio of companies in 2025. Um
and again, I'm just continually reminded
of the importance of [music] just being
super rigorous with our hiring. And hey,
if someone slips through the cracks that
shouldn't be there, make sure that
you're removing them in a timely manner.
So then on the behavioral debt side,
right, I mean for me it's just making
sure I'm being strict about, you know,
30 minute meetings max. Also making sure
that Tuesday is my only day for
meetings. I can do a day of meetings a
week, maybe two, but anything more than
that. And honestly, I just get drained.
And so, you know, I like to be really
strict about a lot of just open space.
Step three, set your core theme. So this
is all about building your operating
system. Okay, my 2026 theme is all going
to be around imagination. You know, the
more I'm able to go and imagine the kind
of world I want to live in, the business
I want to build, the life I want to
design, the more abundant I am in that
thinking, the more it kind of all just
happens, right? Cuz I start taking the
right actions every day in my 4 hours of
founder flow and start to hire the right
kind of people around me to [music] make
that vision come true. In terms of the
subdomains, then it's really about
seeing how does this theme come up in
each of these areas. Okay? And what is
that, you know, big imagination and that
big thinking um going to lead to in
terms of where I want to go in these
areas. So, it's all about going and
getting this YouTube channel to a
million subs. [music] And it's also
going and doing our V1 of the Dolommites
Retreat. The vision for Founder OS
amongst many things is to go and buy a
retreat center in the Dolommites to do
snowboarding in the winters, epic hikes
and mountain biking in the summers with
amazing legendary founders. And so we're
going to be hosting an insane founder
experience this year in the Dolommites
for [music] the founders inside of
Founder OS Edge. All founders that are
doing over a million dollars a year. And
so I can't wait for that and that's a
big dream this year on the relationship
side of things. really just making sure
you know I go and take my parents on
some epic trips um and go and hang out
with my my brother and sisters. I'm the
oldest on the health side, yoga four
times a week. The second thing honestly
that I find I always need to work on is
mindfulness. I like growth. I like
building. I like to be go go go kind of
by default. Um so that yeah, I'm also
taking time for calm, for presence, all
that good stuff. On the creativity side,
um we have a bunch of cool going
on. We're going to have a second YouTube
channel uh dropping shortly. And so just
pushing the creative bounds here on
YouTube is going to be a big theme for
us in 2026. And so I'm excited to lean
in there. On the growth side, getting
this damn book out there, let me tell
you, this has by far been one of the
toughest things I've ever done. I've
gone through four editors at this point
in time, probably seven different
manuscripts. So hopefully I can just get
this damn thing done once and for all.
Okay, so that's a big thing there. And
on the freedom side, I'm going to be
buying a new home. You know, just a
cozy, [music] dope space that I can
always come back to, a nice new home
base. Um, so I'm getting that set up.
That's a big goal for this year. Step
four now is your 2026 hit list. Okay.
What we want to do here is then get into
each of these different areas and think
about what's the most abundant version
of each of them. So on the people's
side, right? Who do you want to actually
spend time with? Who do you want to
build with? Who do you want to learn
from? One that comes to mind is my buddy
Blake Roka, an absolute legend that I
actually did an episode with of the
whiteboard sessions, which you can go
check out right here, going on an epic
snowboarding trip with the legend Daniel
Dalen. Excited to lean into that
relationship. Um, and honestly, just
keep learning and growing together. In
addition to that, going to be going and,
you know, hanging out with the guy
behind the camera here, Diego. We meet
up every couple months and I just want
to keep on leaning into that, keeping on
giving you guys the amazing content that
you guys all deserve. Build with Claire,
my chief of staff, and I've also brought
on some new tech folks [music]
um to help us on the dashboard side of
Found, which I'm super stoked about. I
think the more visibility and
sophistication you have on the data side
in a business like ours, [music] the
bigger the dreams you're able to
accomplish. On the travel side there,
where do you want to go? Right? The
world is your oyster. So, where are the
spots that you're looking to go and
check off this year [music] and go and
enjoy some epic experiences that are
going to create memories you're going to
remember for the rest of your life. So,
I want to hit up Patagonia. It's been on
the list for a while. Never been. Second
spot, which has been on the bucket list
honestly for way too long, is India. And
in [music] April, looking to do a
motorbiking trip with my buddy Nick and
go to the Himalayas, the Dolommites. So,
we're going to rip that for the retreat.
Now, the top one non-negotiable is
amidst all this travel, really making
sure that I'm also going and setting up
an amazing home base and leading into
this like cozy founder space that I'm
creating. [music] Now, when we look at
experiences, okay, things that I want to
do that I've never done before, like I
mentioned, Himalayas is high on that
list. An epic 5day trek in Patagonia is
on the list. Other than that, honestly,
I'm going to keep it simple and just
stick to those two. But I've left five
spots here that you can, you know, go
and add more. Again, dream big. If you
have a lot of things you're looking to
get done this year, go fill this all
out. Now, I'm not [music] proud of this,
but this whole Himalayas thing, I think
it's probably been on my bucket list for
like a decade. So, this is the year.
This is the year we are doing this thing
[music] once and for all. I talk about
this all the time, right? Healthy
founders build healthy businesses. And
for me, you know, I know that
transforming my health as a founder has
transformed my life. For me, first
things first is getting blood work done
every 90 [music] days, right? Doing
quarterly check-ins on all my core
health panels and making sure I'm
optimizing this stuff with exercise,
good sleep, and proper diet. [music]
Now, on that subject is making sure I'm
getting my 8 hours of sleep a night,
right? For me, quality sleep is the
ultimate productivity hack, right? And
honestly, the key to happiness. And so
in addition to that, it's continuing to
work with my coach, work with my
therapist on a monthly basis, just
making sure I've got the right support
system around me to make sure that as I
keep going [music] and charting new
waters, you know, maybe you guys don't
realize this, right? But a lot of the
things I'm doing, you know, I'm kind of
new to. And while it's also super
exciting, you know, it's really, really
uncomfortable at times as well, right?
And I think that's the fun of
entrepreneurship is constantly kind of
going and, you know, stretching
yourself. I think that entrepreneurs are
like athletes and just like athletes
need rest, recovery, [music]
good mentors and coaches around them,
well I think that entrepreneurs need the
same and so you know for me it's having
that right good board of adviserss
around me to make sure I'm solid right
so on the wealth side okay so for me
every single year I always have a net
worth goal I'm not going to share that
here because yeah there's some things I
keep private but you know let's just say
we keep charting those waters there's
also a dollar per month goal that I
always have in terms of the dollars I'm
going to invest every single month. And
then there's always the right sort of
advisers that I surround myself with.
Okay? So, I have my own sort of wealth
advisor I meet with every single month
to keep on refining my portfolio. You
know, tax advisor to [music] be smart on
that side of things. There's really two,
you know, main assets to most
entrepreneurs, right? There's your
actual portfolio of maybe stocks, bonds,
whatever you're investing in. That's one
piece of it. And then often times we're
also highly concentrated in our actual
businesses as well. So if I'm looking to
grow my wealth, I really just got to
keep on growing the portfolio and
growing my businesses, right? Pretty
simple. So the number one negot
non-negotiable is honestly just taking
care of my health. I'm feeling good. I'm
clear-minded. [music]
I'm dialed in. And I find again if my
health is dialed, my wealth basically
just takes care of itself. So let's move
on to work now. Okay. What do you want
to create? What do you want to launch?
What do you want to build? Right? What
are those things on your list that when
you look at them, you're like, if we
just got these [music] five things done
for me, this looks like really going and
continue to evolve the dashboard at
Founder OS. It's getting this damn book
launch like I mentioned. [music] It's
the Dolommites retreat, right? And
really running an epic experience there.
It's going and scaling up our founder US
edge to 100 founders. Edge is the
opportunity where founders go and are
able to text me any time inside of
Founder OS, get personalized voice notes
and messages from me. They're setting up
bi-weekly calls directly with me every
other week where I'm going and helping
them scale up their personal media
company, remove them from operations,
and honestly just deal with any of the
sticky situations or opportunities that
founders deal with on their journey. And
so this is the most [music] intimate
inner circle of founders that are doing
a minimum of $1 million a year that I'm
going and rolling up my sleeves and
helping [music] them scale. When I
dreamed up founder OS like 4 years ago,
you know, I thought that there'd maybe
be about a 100 or so founders that we'd
be impacting, but when I fast forward
now to 2026, [music] we've impacted over
18,000 founders, right? And across the
audience, we now have over 3.2 million
people. It's freaking insane, right? And
for me, I'm just excited about the
potential here to keep on scaling up
this amazing movement. Not just hang out
with these founders for the next year,
but to build this awesome community
where we all have one another's back for
the next, you know, two decades, right?
[music] So, just continue to lean into
that is going to be key. Let's get on to
step five, your vision board. Right?
This isn't about some dumbass
manifestation right? This is
neuroscience, okay? And your brain can't
execute what it can't see. And so a big
thing here, right, is actually having a
visual for where you're looking to go.
And so I simply just went to Pinterest.
I created a board called my vision. And
I went through Pinterest and then just
saved a bunch of images that
encapsulated kind of feeling and energy
that I'm looking to have in my life.
Everything from my home to my wife to my
life. I then go and insert this into
things like my personal board meeting
that I do with myself every month, which
you can learn more about that in this
video right here. I also go and
literally print this off and have it in
like four different places of my house
that I see all the time. Everything from
my bathroom to my bedroom. That's the
visual system. Now, let's move on to
step [music] six. Materialize your plan,
right? We want to make this plan so
real, right? That it is unavoidable. And
the way to do that is to make sure it's
physical. Where you going to put this
vision? [music] So I like to go and have
this in my bathroom, right? So when I'm
brushing my teeth morning and evening,
I'm looking at it. And I put it also
somewhere in my bedroom, right? So that
when I wake up, it's one of the first
things I see and the last things I see
before I go to bed, right? So it's just
those little reminders to gradually get
you to where you're going. Right? One of
the quotes that I have in my vision
board, you can see here, is, you know,
act like everything is working out
because it is, right? And that just kind
of triggers my mind to kind of remember
like, hey, everything's working out for
the best. Even if you're having a low
moment in your life, remember like the
challenges that you have in your life
has only made you stronger. Now, let's
move on to step seven. Now, your review
rhythm. Now, this is what separates
[music] the winners from the losers,
right? Because if you're looking to
actually go and execute this plan, the
key thing is that it doesn't just become
that New Year's resolution that by
February you forget about it, right? We
want to make sure that we have regular
reviews of this plan so that we're
actually executing against it. [music]
So on the monthly review schedule, I'll
show you what this may look like for
like the first quarter of 2026. Okay? So
when we think about the Q1 reviews on
January 30th, I'm going to have a review
of all of this. In February, I'm going
to do it on Feb 28th. Okay? And on March
30th, I'm going to have a review. And
this same sort of rhythm will go
throughout the year. And I'll literally
go and mark my calendar and put a spot
to go and review this plan. [music]
We're not just setting this and
forgetting it. We are setting it and
reviewing it 12 times throughout the
year. So, we're continually [music]
pacing against it. This is how to build
a plan for 2026 that's actually going to
help get you towards your goals. From
there, we want to go and have the three
Rs in place, which is our monthly review
framework. Okay, we're going to reflect
on what happened this month. We're going
to review and make sure that we're on
track to getting to where we're looking
to go. And then we're going to realign
and understand, okay, is there anywhere
new that we need to go and direct our
focus and make sure that we are dialed
in each month on what we need to double
down on and the things that we need to
change [music] to really go and make
this vision come true. Take some time. I
want you to actually go and print this
thing out, okay? And go and use this.
And by [music] the way, if you found
this useful, go and share this with
three of your friends as well. If you're
in your company, go and share this in
your company Slack, right? Go and pay it
forward, right? That's what it's all
about is helping fellow founders go
[music] and win. So, now let's get into
step eight, your systems implementation.
You know, if you're following this
channel, you understand the importance
of [music] systems. Goals are neat, but
as you know from folks like James Clear
out there, we don't rise to the level of
goals. We fall to the level of our
systems. Okay? And so we want to really
go and dial in our daily, weekly,
monthly, and quarterly system [music]
stack. Let me just give you a sneak peek
as to what this looks like for me. Okay,
the number one thing is daily founder
flow. 4 hours of uninterrupted work,
working on the most important stuff in
my zone of brilliance. Okay, now on the
weekly system side, right, it's honestly
taking some time to reflect what went
well, what didn't go well, and then
having a clear plan for the following
week. On the monthly system side, I'm
doing my own personal board meeting
every single month to go and reflect on
how I'm tracking towards my major goals
and then going and charting out the
goals for the next month. Okay? And on
the quarterly system side, one example
of something I do once or twice every
quarter is a soul trip. taking a trip
out to nature to unplug, get away from
my phone, go with someone I love, and go
and enjoy some time out in the world in
a spontaneous road trip or some new
mountain we're climbing or a
snowboarding trip, what have you, to
then go and get away from screens and
just gain some perspective and presence.
Okay, these are the eight steps to go
and build a plan for 2026 that's
actually going to help you achieve your
goals. I hope you enjoyed this. If you
want some help now going and
implementing the plans that you've put,
if you're looking to grow your audience,
your personal media company, remove
yourself from operations and get my
help, my team's help, that's exactly
what we do inside of Founder OS. If
you're looking to go and connect with me
every single week, be able to message me
anytime you need me. Well, that's what
we do in Founder OS. You should probably
go and book a call with my team below.
We'll get on a 15-minute call,
understand the systems that you got set
up and the ones that you're missing, and
let you know how we can help you. So, go
book a call. I can't wait to see what
you create in 2026. Be sure to go and
watch this next video all around how
success [music]
comes down to actually going and having
these deep systems in your life and
business. And I'll see you in the next
one. Much love.