Most people think discipline is about
waking up at 5:00 a.m., grinding through
your to-do list, and just working harder
[music] than everyone else. And I used
to think that, too. Then I built a
business, scaled it to eight figures,
[music] and surrounded myself with
founders doing the same, and I realized
something was backwards, all right? The
most disciplined founders aren't the
ones who show up the hardest,
>> [music]
>> they're the ones who build businesses
that run without them, and that takes
real discipline. But here's the problem.
>> [music]
>> The discipline that got you to six
figures won't get you past it. Personal
consistency doesn't [music] scale,
systems do. And in this video, I'm
walking through the five levels of
discipline [music] and revealing the
exact mechanisms I used each level to
make sure my discipline scaled with my
business. [music] Because once your
business starts working, once you've got
real revenue, a team depending on
[music] you, and every decision costs
you time you don't have, personal
discipline stops [music] being enough.
Section one, self-control discipline.
This is what everyone thinks of when
they hear the word [music] discipline,
the habits, the routines, the willpower,
waking up early. And look, this level
matters, okay? If you can't show up
consistently, nothing [music] else
works. But here's what nobody tells you.
Self-control, it doesn't scale. A few
years ago, I was at the peak of my
personal discipline, up at 5:30 a.m.,
workout, [music] then I had my smoothie,
you know, a nice founder flow block
before anyone else was even awake.
[music] But my business was still
leaking energy and potential. Clients
were slipping through the cracks, my
team was waiting on me for decisions,
[music] and revenue was growing, but so
was my workload. I was working 60-hour
weeks, and it still wasn't [music]
enough. And that's when it hit me. I
wasn't dealing with a motivation
problem, I was dealing with a capacity
problem. Every decision really flowed
through me, every quality standard
really depended on me being there, and
if I wasn't there, I just felt like
everything was going to fall apart,
right? Here's the truth. [music] Once
every decision costs you time you don't
have, self-control discipline becomes
fragile. [music]
It works when you're small, right? But
it breaks when you scale. And that's
when I realized if I wanted to scale, my
focus shouldn't be on my own willpower,
it should be on personal constraints,
[music] which brings me to level two,
constraint discipline, reducing decision
load. Here's what I learned, okay? The
real enemy at scale isn't a lack of
effort, it [music] is decision fatigue.
Every choice you make, no matter how
small or large, depletes your cognitive
[music] resources. You know, should I
take this meeting? Should I wear this
thing? Should I respond to this email
now or later? I'm constantly trying to
go and just reduce that cognitive load,
right? [music] Reduce the amount of
decisions that depend on me and push
them down through my organization. You
know, in the book The Outsiders, they go
and study eight CEOs that went and
outperformed the market over the last 25
[music] years by getting over 20% annual
returns, okay? The big thing was that
they decentralized leadership, right?
[music] Really pushing kind of ownership
and decision-making down and across
their organization, [music]
right? And so level two discipline is
about pre-deciding. It's about making
decisions once, and then designing rules
that enforce those decisions
automatically. [music]
If you just make rules, they just make
the decisions for you. And so, as an
example, everyone [music] knows I just
do my meetings on Tuesdays. If a problem
arises, the rule may be bring a
recommendation, not a problem, [music]
and then just redirect it that way,
right? I tell my team, you can make
decisions without me, just answer the
question, what is best for the
enterprise? When someone on my team
comes to me with a problem, I don't jump
in and solve it, I ask them one thing.
What is your recommendation, okay?
That's it. If you bring me a problem,
I'm just going to ask you, what's your
recommendation, all right? Because I'm
not here to go and solve the monkey on
your back. You got [music] to keep that
there, you got to figure this out. The
first time I enforced this, my team
pushed back and were like, well Matt,
you know, what if I'm wrong? Well, good,
okay? Cuz we'll course [music] correct,
but at least you're taking the
responsibility for that area versus
pushing it to me. Within 30 days, the
culture shifted completely, okay? People
stopped coming to me with problems, they
started coming to me with solutions
[music] that just needed a green light
or no light at all because it was
already moving along, okay? How I see my
business, okay, is that every single
leader within my business [music] must
be running their own business unit
inside of Founder OS. The broader
principle is this, right? Constraints
[music] aren't restrictions, right?
Constraints breed creativity and are
liberators. Real discipline is designing
your environment so you don't have
[music] to choose at all. Section three,
data-driven discipline, directing energy
to signal, not noise. Most of you
believe that if you just work harder, if
[music] you just add one more
initiative, one more content channel,
one more offer, you'll finally hit
[music] that breakthrough. But more
effort without direction is just noise,
okay? Level three discipline is about
directing all of your energy towards
signal, you know, the metric and
feedback loops that [music] actually
move the business forward and having the
candor to let everything else die. Let
me show you exactly how to do this. You
know, here you can see every video we
put out, right? And we are tracking
things like these core metrics [music] I
just shared, right? Subscribers, views,
applications, right? But also things
like cash [music] collected, right?
Because, you know, when I look at
building a profitable media company
within Founder OS, obviously the
profitable part is, you know, important
thing. And so we're looking at the
profit per piece of content, so we know
which [music] content to double down on,
and the kind of stuff that we should
maybe be careful of. This video here,
this 10-minute [music] system that makes
success inevitable, you know, this video
got over 208,000 views, right? In the
first 30 days. Amazing, right? You'd
think this video is an absolute banger.
But the thing is, you go and scroll over
and you realize, holy the cash
collected on that video was only 258
bucks in 30 days? So, not so bueno,
right? Now, here's the thing though, I
go and I look at this video down here,
right? Copy this content strategy, it'll
blow up your business. Now, this video,
if you look at it,
it only 44,000 views. You could be like,
oh, that's a failure. No, but you look
at the real metrics behind this, right?
And when you go over to cash collected,
we made $29,000 from that video, okay?
So, this is the importance, right? Of
really diving deeper, right? Into
[music]
the metrics and looking at the stuff
that really matters. And in this case,
we're looking oftentimes at cash, but
that's not it. Let me go and actually
show you some more magic here because we
don't just stop there. [music] So, the
legend on my team, Diego, has gone and
created this detailed analytics [music]
dashboard as well, right? Where we can
actually go and track things like the
views, applications, as well as kind of
like the Founder OS brand score for some
of the core categories across our
content, things like, you know, how is
AI content, content around content
systems, storytelling, mindset,
business, branding, productivity. And
what it we can see here, right? Is that
it's actually our content systems that
drive the most [music] cash collected to
the company, right? Whereby actually
mindset-based content drives us the most
subscribers. And so, this way, right?
We're able to also go and see the
distribution across the different kinds
of categories we have, and we also do
this across our different [music]
formats as well. So, we can see, you
know,
talking head formats as an example, it
drives us the most subscribers, right?
Whereas sometimes when I do system
screen shares, very similar to what I'm
doing here right now, this is actually
what drives us some of the most cash
within the company. And so, this doesn't
mean that we suddenly just seesaw and we
do, okay, we're going to do just this
format and just that type of content.
No, we keep it kind of balanced, right?
We use some content to grow the channel
and some content to actually go and then
monetize the channel. I think the thing
that you can do is make sure you have
trackable links for all your content, so
you're able to go and track people all
the way from when they download a lead
magnet all the way to when they convert
with you, so you can start seeing the
actual profit per piece of content and
build your own dashboard like this. Or
better yet, join Founder OS and we can
help you do just this. So, I've shown
you this like quantitative analytics,
right? And that's certainly one piece,
right? Of really making sure that we're
building this like data-driven
discipline in the company. The other
side of this though is making sure you
also have the discipline to make sure
that departments are not operating in
silos, okay? Inside of this Slack
channel, we have that is marketing sales
success sync. And you can see that
there's a constant interaction between
my marketing team and my sales team, and
we're sharing what we're seeing, what we
know is working, and making sure that
we're constantly dialing in the
marketing to better [music] serve sales.
And sales is doing their part to share
different insights that will help us on
the marketing side,
>> [music]
>> so we can go and dial in the content
that much better. And this is I think
how you build a rigorous [music]
discipline media team. If this is
confusing, I want you just to ask
yourself this. What are the three
metrics that actually move your business
forward? [music] If you can't name them,
you're stuck guessing. If you're
tracking them weekly, you're operating
with level three feedback loops. If you
can't answer those questions, you're not
operating at level three at all, okay?
You're busy, but you're not that
focused. [music] Now, here's where it
gets uncomfortable, because levels one
through three are table stakes. [music]
Every successful operator figures those
out eventually, okay? You're going to
get those. But level four and level
five, this is where 95% of people get
stuck. Not because they don't understand
the concept, but because they can't
execute it. [music] And if you're
watching this thinking, you know, I've
already got systems, what I'm about to
show you is why you probably will
realize [music] that you don't really,
which brings me to level four. Section
four, system discipline, process over
personality. Here's the trap I fell into
and the number one missing point of
leverage I see with almost every founder
I work with inside of Founder OS. You
get really good at executing, right?
Nobody can do this like I can, is what
people will say, right? But that pride
becomes a cage. Because if something
only works when you do it, you don't
have a business, right? You have
dependency, and that's the exact
opposite of what we're trying to
accomplish here, right? Level four
discipline is moving from individual
execution to organizational leverage.
It's really about moving from the engine
of your business to the architect. It's
understanding [music] that at scale,
consistency comes from systems, not
people. Let me tell you a story on this,
okay? We had a client deliver a
strategic audit we'd run for founders
inside of one of our programs, and it
used to take me about 6 hours to
complete cuz I was [music] good at it,
right? Really good, but it was also a
massive bottleneck. And if I was
traveling or I was on a podcast, I just
basically had to make [music] that
client wait. And that's not a business,
that's a job, okay? So, here's what I
did. I documented it, right? [music] At
Founder OS, we have one non-negotiable
rule. If you solve a problem, you got to
document it. And documentation means two
things, okay? A Google Doc that walks
through the system [music] step-by-step,
and then a Loom video showing how to
execute it. No exceptions, okay? If you
can't document it, it doesn't scale.
Then I recorded a 15-minute Loom video
walking through the entire thing,
[music] showing my screen, and talking
through my thought process, and
demonstrating the execution, okay? Then
I handed this off to someone on my team.
Sent them the Doc and the Loom, and they
were off to the [music] races. I told
them to run the next client audit for
me. The first time they ran it, took
them about 60 minutes, and the quality
was better than when I had done it
manually. Why? Because the system had
the cumulative wisdom of everyone
[music] who touched it. So, if it's not
documented, it's not a system. And this
is like really some tribal in the
company, right? Really making sure that
we live this as a company. There's still
one final level of discipline that holds
high-performers back from their full
potential,
>> [music]
>> and it's the scariest one because it
requires the one thing every founder is
terrified [music] of, letting go
completely, which brings me to level
five. Now, before I go and show you
level five, let me tell you about what
Founder OS actually is. Founder OS is an
operating system for founders who are
doing real revenue, going from anything
from 50k to 500k per month, and who are
stuck in that operator mode, okay?
You've proven the business works, you've
got clients, you've got a team, but you
are still the bottleneck. What we do is
help you architect the exact systems
[music] we just talked about, right?
Help you solve the constraints that are
going to free up your cognitive load,
help you with the data dashboards that
tell you on what to focus on, and then
the frameworks that let you finally step
out of the weeds. It's not a course,
it's not a bunch of videos you watch on
your own.
>> [music]
>> It's a 12-month build with me and a
small group of founders who are at the
exact same stage as you. We build your
operating system together with live
coaching, real-time feedback, and a
community of people who actually
understand what it's like to be trapped
in a business you built. Now, let's dive
into level five, leverage discipline,
freedom through ownership transfer.
>> [music]
>> This is the level that separates
founders doing a few hundred thousand a
year from founders doing a few hundred
thousand a month, and it's also a level
most people never even reach. Not
because they can't, but because it's
terrifying. It's not about delegation,
right? Delegation is, here's a task, go
do it, and report [music] back to me,
okay? Level five is about ownership
transfer. It's about, here's an outcome
that you own, make the calls, you make
the decisions, I trust you, [music] and
here's the system. True leverage, true
freedom requires you to transfer
authority, not just [music] tasks. Let
me tell you about the first time I did
this. We had a revenue-critical function
in the business, it directly impacted
client experience and renewals. [music]
It was really mission-critical, and I
was the only one running [music] it. And
so, I documented the system, a Doc and a
Loom, just like in level four, okay? And
then I found the right person on my
team, someone who had the skill set, the
ownership mentality, and the [music]
judgment. I transferred the full
ownership of this thing. This is yours
now, okay? You own this, right? I
transferred all of that ownership to
this individual. [music]
The first week, I was checking in, okay?
Making sure it was all good. The second
week, I forced myself to check in just
once, and by week three, [music]
I didn't check in at all, okay? And
nothing broke. And here's what nobody
really talks to you about, right? The
moment that I let go, the moment I
stopped being the hero to solve all
these problems, I finally got to work on
those stuff that I actually enjoyed,
right? I got to build, I got to create,
I got to think years ahead, right? In
this level, right? What it's really
about [music] is ensuring people have
that ownership mentality on your team.
You know, if you're looking to get to
$20 million a year, you need to have
multiple people in your business that
could run a $10 million business,
multiple people could run a $5 million
business in it, and then a bunch of
people could run a million dollar and
500k business units [music] inside of
it, right? You need real business owners
inside of your business. Let me tie this
all together because level five doesn't
work without the other four levels,
okay? Level one is where you start, but
it's not where you stay. Level two is
where you reclaim your brain through
constraints. Level three is where you
focus on signal and then kill all the
noise.
>> [music]
>> Level four is where you build systems
that scale beyond you, and then level
five is where you finally step into
freedom. So, here's what I want you to
do. Don't guess which level you're at.
Take the Founder Dependency Test [music]
in the link below, okay? It takes 5
minutes, and it'll show you exactly
where your business is structurally
dependent on you. If you score high and
you're ready for level five systems,
you're exactly the kind of founder we
work with inside [music] of Founder OS.
Bring your completed test to a strategy
call, the team and I will look at your
bottleneck layer, pressure test your
ownership transfer, and then decide what
systems will unlock that architect level
leverage for you. But, if you don't,
you'll stay stuck [music] at performing
at a very low level, and that's no good.
I created this channel to go and
document my journey building a business
that grows [music] without consuming my
life. If that's the kind of thing you
want, well, I'd love to help you.
[music] Be sure to like and subscribe,
and go and watch this next video on a
key system that you can copy to go and
blow up your business this year. Go
watch that one, and much love. Let's win
together.