At the time of this video, I'm 35 years
old. If I was in my 20s or early 30s,
this is the advice I wish I had given
myself. So, first things first, amidst
all of the talk around entrepreneurship,
I think something that's important to
remember is if you're not an
entrepreneur, don't be an entrepreneur.
And what I mean by this is there's a lot
of hype around building businesses. And
I talk to a lot of people and they're
asking me for help starting their thing
and they're instantly worried about, you
know, how can I go and start my first
business, Matt, I I want to make sure
that I'm just working on it though, 3
hours a day. I can't help them. I think
to myself, hey, just just stop in your
tracks right there. You know, you may
know me because sometimes I talk about
systems that allow me to work less, make
more. The truth is though, when I was
first starting, I had to learn
aggressively. I had to put myself in
crazy scenarios. I had to make a ton of
mistakes. It didn't come easy. If you're
going and you're starting something and
day one you're looking for the easy
route, just stop. Pack it in. Go get
that 9 to-ive job. This ain't for you.
The life of an entrepreneur, it's not
going to be easy. And if you're trying
to avoid the hard things, you're going
to find yourself actually living a
harder life. Now, there's this quote I
love from Naval Rabicon. Easy choices,
hard life, hard choices, easy life. And
so, in your 20s and 30s, make those hard
choices. Go and start that business. Go
and put the time that's necessary into
it. Go and reach out to those mentors
that could maybe help you. Go put
yourself in uncomfortable scenarios that
help you to level up. Do the hard
things. You're going to thank yourself
later for that. All right, so let's move
on to something a little controversial
here. Unpopular opinion. Avoid lazy
people. They're going to leech off of
you. They're going to waste your time.
They're going to bring you problems, not
solutions. They're going to weigh you
down. You need to make sure that you're
surrounding yourself with weapons. The
kind of people that when you're around
them, you grow. You know the saying that
you're the product of the five people
that you surround yourself with? It's
true. You want to make sure that you're
in rooms of people where ideally you're
the dumbest person in that room. Join
that community. Create your own group of
founders that are helping one another.
Join a mastermind. Anything that can
help you go and level up with others.
The truth is that you are your greatest
investment. 95% of my success over the
last 15 years has been the result of the
people that I've surrounded myself with
and really viewing myself as an
investment that had to keep on learning,
growing, reading, surrounding myself
with mentors, coaches, whatever it took
to get that next skill. Lazy people are
like energy vampires. They're just going
to suck the life out of you. And if you
find them in your business, get rid of
them. I know this sounds a little bit
harsh, and it is. It's supposed to be,
right? You don't have time to waste. Do
an audit, right? If in your company you
got people that just aren't making the
cut, now is the time to cut them. If you
got friends that when you leave those
conversations, you kind of feel drained,
now is the time to cut them and focus on
people that are going to actually help
you grow. This leads me to the next
point, which is you need to blaze your
own path. And my dad's a dentist, and I
thought that I would follow my dad's
footsteps until I went to take your kid
to work day. I saw old Dorothy take out
her dentures and sit in the dental chair
and I realized I am definitely not going
to be a dentist. Ended up going to
business school. Business school tried
to program me into becoming an
accountant or maybe a marketer or maybe
an investment banker or a management
consultant. And I said, "Fuck that." One
thing I'm super grateful that I did in
my 20s is not listen to the sort of
projections others were putting on me in
terms of the career path I should take.
Sure enough, after graduating from
university, I started my first business,
Bitmaker, where we trained full stack
software engineers and got them jobs at
tech companies across Canada. I had no
idea what I was doing. I made thousands
of mistakes. But the one thing I would
always remind myself of any single day
working on BitMaker, I was learning more
than the rest of my friends that had
taken those standard paths in one year.
When you're blazing your own path, I
think that what you're doing is you're
just maximizing your learning velocity.
You're putting yourself in really
uncomfortable scenarios. You're
following your heart, your soul, and
your true calling in life. I think on a
personal level, it leads you to being
way more fulfilled. And on a
professional level, all those
uncomfortable situations you're putting
yourself in, maybe where you feel like
you're getting into opportunities that
are way beyond your current capacity or
capability, that is where the magic
happens. My biggest regret over the last
probably 10 years is that I didn't start
building an audience sooner in my
businesses. The truth is that your
audience is an appreciating asset. Now,
let me double click into what I mean by
this. We live in a day and age where
people follow people then they follow
brands. Your ability to go and build
your brand is going to open so many
doors for you. We live in a world where
everyone is a media company. You are a
media company. By creating organic
content, you go and you become a magnet
for opportunities. You become a magnet
for your dream customer. You become a
magnet for the best talent out there.
And you become a magnet for luck. It's
hard to see it at the point in time. You
often times may think, "Oh, growing an
audience, I'm not sure. I don't have a
skill yet." Your personal brand will
reveal the product that you need to
build. When you go and you're putting
content out there, you're creating an
audience. people come to know and love
you for your interests, your passion,
your achievements, your lessons, your
systems, playbooks, blueprints. What
ends up happening is that you don't
actually need to know the product that
you're going to offer these people. Day
one, you're going to have people going
and asking you, "Hey, I love this piece
of content that you put out. Do you have
any product around that or can I buy
that from you?" And you'll start to get
these signals from your audience because
you're putting yourself out there. What
I see is two kinds of founders, right?
Type one founders say, "I don't have a
product yet, so I'm not even going to
start building my personal brand." Type
two founders go, "I don't have a product
yet, so I'm going to start building my
personal brand now, and I'm going to
start listening to the audience I create
to learn what they want and then build
that." Type two founders end up building
something way more valuable, having way
more fun. And I can attest to it cuz
this is how I've lived the last 5 years
of my life. And you don't need to build
it on the platforms that everyone else
is building it on. If you like to do
textbased stuff, pursue X, pursue
LinkedIn. If you're more into video like
this, go on to YouTube, Instagram, Tik
Tok, it doesn't matter. Just get
started. One of the most underrated
skills I honestly wish I had taken more
seriously earlier in my life is writing.
Writing is a superpower. Your emails are
writing. X is writing. Audience growth
is writing. Building a newsletter is
writing. Making a hire is writing.
Charting out your vision, your mission,
your values. This is all writing.
Copywriting is one of the most valuable
skills you can have. Because when you
think about it, about 99% of what you do
day-to-day as a founder is writing.
You're writing to teammates on Slack to
motivate them. You're writing to a
potential customer to try and close
them. The ability to go and convince
people with words is a gamecher. For
those of you that are looking to get
started with this and are like, "Okay,
sounds good. You've convinced me, dude."
I would go and suggest reading the ad
week copywriting handbook by Joseph
Sugarman. This book is going to give you
all the deep dive principles on writing
copy that sells and write copy that's
compelling. If you need more tips on
this, go and check out my X account as
an example. I believe that X is like a
copywriting gym and this is a great
place where you can see the best
copywriting from your favorite creators.
You can go follow me there. Go follow
other people that you love. People like
James Clear, Naval Ravocanton, Ryan
Holiday. these are some legends you
probably want to check out and just see
how they speak. There's a big difference
between that person that just writes
some massive paragraphs to try and
convey some point. And it's not that
their point sucks, it's that the writing
sucks. But what you want to do is learn
how to write like you speak. Use short
sentences. Keep things punchy. When you
write out stuff, be able to make it
scannable. And what you'll start to see
is that all this writing you're doing is
going to just have that much more of an
ROI. It's going to move the needle
forward more in your life. It's going to
help transform things at record speed.
We live in a world where so much of what
you're doing is remote. You're operating
remote teams, closing remote deals, and
building a remote business. Writing is
more important than ever. Don't sleep on
this skill. Now's the time to get this
right. Taste is the ultimate competitive
advantage. This is more true than ever.
With AI going and eating the world right
now, more and more skills are honestly
just going to be automated over the next
decade and longer. So the key thing is
what really sets you apart. It is your
taste. It's your style, your uniqueness.
It's you. Now when I look back on my
20s, many years I was just insecure. I
had certain skills, certain ways I like
to do things, but I didn't listen to
that inner voice. Instead, I just
followed the herd in many cases. You
know, create a business just like
someone else. I would create a piece of
content just like that other person.
Meanwhile, I had great ideas and I
should have just had the courage to go
and make them. This is your reminder
that if you have an idea, you know, you
have a piece of content you've been
wishing you put out, you had that
business that is kind of odd, but you
really want to start it, just go for it.
There's something unique about that
taste you have versus putting that aside
and being 40 years old to finally pursue
that. Now is the time to get after that
thing. All right, so let's take a step
back here for a second. I want to let
you in on an equation for success that
you probably haven't heard about before.
Peace plus profit plus purpose equals
success. Peace is one of the most
important things in life. When I think
about hiring someone as an example in my
companies, beyond their metrics, their
KPIs, their experience, I ask myself, is
bringing this person on my team going to
help me sleep at night. Now, a lot of
founders, they start building
businesses, they forget about this
aspect. And sure enough, you fast
forward 5 years and they're running a
business that's running them into the
ground. And so, don't forget about your
piece. Prioritize that. The next aspect
is profit. We live in a day and age
where everyone's just talking about
their revenue growth. When we think
about profit, you want to be looking at
the bottom line. How much are you
actually taking out of your business
every single month? As I've gotten
older, I've gotten so much more maniacal
about profits. What I see often times
though from the founders that I help and
I coach or advise is that they're not
even looking out for themselves. And
sadly too, no one's looking out for the
founder. You know, investors will tell
you to grow faster. Your team's going to
look for raises, but at the end of the
day, who is looking out for you, and
what you should be looking at is how
much money am I taking out of my
business per month? And does this ladder
up to know the goals that I have? Talked
enough about the cash. Let's move on to
the third part here, purpose. I was
talking with my good friend Steve, the
founder and CEO from pre.com about 7
years ago, and he said something to me
that I've never been able to forget. He
went to me when I was considering
different sort of business lines I could
go and start and a few things I was
building. He's like, "Matt, take a step
back for a sec and ask yourself, what
would you do if you knew you would be
successful?" So, think about that. Not
thinking about what I could do that
would make me the most money. No, no,
no. What do you want to do? For me, what
I found most useful is to really journal
around what I'm good at, what the world
needs, and what I can be paid for. And
the intersection of these things gives
me a lot of insights into the stuff that
really fires me up that's in my calling
in life. Helping founders, building
systems, growing communities, building
distribution, day one, traveling,
writing, journaling, design,
copywriting. These are the things, as
you can probably tell right now, that
fire me up. Take the risk. Take the
plunge. You're young. Now is the time to
go and live a life of purpose. One thing
that I've learned as I've gotten older,
health over everything. Yes, everything.
My belief is that healthy founders build
healthy businesses. What are the habits
that have helped me go and level up over
the years? There's a lot of specific
things I'm going to hit you with right
now that you may want to consider. I'm
not saying you need to do the whole
stack I'm about to say, but hopefully at
least you can take a few things away.
Number one, I have a coach. I have a
health coach, Sadi, who helps me with
all of my core markers, making sure that
I'm dialed in from a blood work
perspective. I have an actual business
coach, Ryan Begelman, who goes and helps
me with all the intricate details of my
business from people to systems to
growth, making sure that I'm just dialed
in there. And he also serves as almost
like a business therapist in some
senses, helping me also with just like
the hard things that come up as you're
building a business. Similarly, I have a
therapist. Inevitably, it doesn't matter
what business you're building and how
experienced you are. We've all got
edges, right? We've all got things that
we could just use some help with. On a
more physical basis, you need to make
sure that you're doing something every
day to be active. When I was younger, I
used to think, "Okay, I'm going to be
active 4 days a week." That's not the
move, right? You should just go and
architect your perfect day every day.
And a piece of that perfect day should
be working out, should be some light
stretching, hopefully. should be eating
healthily, meditating in some capacity,
reading your vision so you're constantly
clear on that. Surrounding yourself with
good people because good people in a
sense are great medicine. Lastly, I
think the thing that I took for granted
when I was younger was sleep. You know,
sleep hygiene, it's something that just
gets overlooked so much. Just the amount
of work that sometimes we put in as
founders, the thing that we are first to
neglect, right, is just a good night's
sleep. And so doing your best to get
into some sort of sleep routine, hitting
the sack, say at around 11:00 p.m.,
getting up every day around 6:00 a.m.
and just keeping that pattern is going
to keep you in the game. You know, I see
a lot of founders that go and have these
sort of sporadic productivity cycles.
They'll be super productive the first
week of the month and then they kind of
fall off for 3 weeks. You know, when
you're healthy, when you're feeling
good, when you're sleeping good,
basically every day consistently, right?
You're able to just hammer move things
forward and stay in the game. just get a
ton more traction consistently. Okay, so
practice doesn't make perfect. Perfect
practice makes perfect. I see way too
many people, and I've been guilty of it
myself, where they become so outcome
focused. How can I go and sell my
company for $50 million? How can I make
$10 million a year? These are all
outcomes. The reality is sometimes we
really can't control those as much as we
think. So, what can you control? You can
control the daily process. showing up,
waking up, finishing those seven tasks
that you had gone and scheduled that
day, coming prepared the next day with
seven things you're going to get done,
doing just the daily rhythm of things
that are necessary to ladder up to those
potential outcomes. I found myself when
I was too outcome focused as a founder.
Honestly, it caused me to be super
depressed, anxious, cuz all I could
think about is, "Oh man, I got to sell
this business for 50 mil or I'm a
failure." The truth is that when you're
just obsessing around the outcomes,
you're miserable and you're really not
focusing on what you can control in the
given moment. About 7 years ago, I
started shifting my focus drastically,
thinking a lot more about, okay, what
can I do every single day that I enjoy
and that's going to move the needle
forward. Oftentimes this looks like
interviewing new hires, writing, sharing
different thinking on platforms like X,
LinkedIn, YouTube, Instagram, building
my personal brand, launching products,
building community, and just really
helping founders day after day after
day. It ain't always sexy. Just the
daily process is where the magic really
lies. And I think if you stack up good
days, good weeks, good months, good
years, those outcomes inevitably just
take care of themselves. This last one
is probably the most important one. Now,
you're going to hear a lot of advice
from people out there, including me just
now. The reality is though, learning the
hard way is learning. In life, there are
no shortcuts, if there are any. It's
surrounding yourself with amazing
people, building great systems, and
building a personal brand. But aside
from those things, right, sometimes you
just got to go head first into
opportunities, make a bunch of mistakes,
and learn. I see a lot of people, say
it's someone that's going and selling,
and they get into a given week and
they've gone and tried to close 20
people and 19 people said no, and they
go and they come to me and they're like,
I feel so depressed and so down. You
know, I got in front of 20 people, 19
said no, only one said yes. Like, I feel
like I'm hardly moving the needle
forward here. That person needs to
change their mindset. Stack up those
nos. If you get 19 nos in a week, try to
triple the amount of nos you get the
next week. Inevitably, with every no you
get, you're going to get a hell of a lot
more yeses and refine your skills over
time. Don't be so afraid of failing.
Don't be so afraid of mistakes. Don't be
so afraid of getting a no. I almost
started making a game of this when I was
21, and it was probably one of the
biggest superpowers I developed. I would
find myself going and making lists in
the thousands of people that I could go
and get in front of for my businesses.
people that I could sell, people that I
could go and have them become my mentor,
people that could become partners of the
business, kind of people that I could go
and hire. And I made an effort of
emailing a thousand, 2,000 of these
people every single month, setting up,
you know, seven, eight meetings and just
getting after it. When I did these
tasks, I noticed in my mind sometimes
this voice that would tell me, "Is this
really a good idea, Matt? Do you even
know this person? This person's probably
gonna get back to you, Matt, and just
think like, what the hell are you doing
reaching out to me?" And I used to play
with that voice versus listening to it,
shutting my computer down and going,
"You know what? You're right. I'm just
going to stop." I would say, "No, hell
no. Like, you've got this. Send that
email." And in spite of those limiting
beliefs and that little voice in my
head, I would just do the thing. And
eventually, this becomes a muscle. Fast
forward to today, I'm 35. Every day, I
find myself doing stuff that scares me,
that terrifies me, that I really have no
business doing. I talked about my vision
being to help a 100 million founders. I
mean, a part of that is exciting. A part
of it sounds completely crazy. By going
and taking action, you open up a world
of opportunity. So, fight those voices
in your head that are telling you to
play small. Fight the voices in your
head that are telling you, you know,
you're not meant for those bigger
opportunities. Just go and get after it.
So, for those of you that are ready to
go and take action right this second,
which, you know, you're my kind of
people, I'm going to go and give you the
free system right now around peace,
profit, and purpose. This is the success
equation. I talk a lot about really
dialing in, you know, peace, profit, and
purpose. This is a major intention for
me over 2025 and has been the last
decade of my career. You know, really
building a calm company. So, I want to
go and show you how exactly I dial in
each one of these areas. I get it,
right? Building a business can be
exhausting. You are potentially super
exhausted, making money, but missing
life. Inevitably, there's so much more
to life than just business, right? in
making money. It's only going to get you
so far. And while I understand it's
important, you know, so are things like
time freedom and abundance and mental
freedom and being able to just control
your time and live life with people that
you love, right? And so what I want to
go and do here is help you really dial
in all of the aspects. And I'm going to
show you just how I think about this. So
I think there's going to be a lot of
hidden gems here for you. There has to
be a better way, right, than just making
money, but having life just suck the
soul and the joy out of you. So, what if
you could have peace, right? Time
freedom, mental clarity, and calm days,
right? Isn't that the zest of life,
profit, right? Making sure it's
predictable, being able to do it with
zero ads, all organic, which is, you
know, my superpower and what I love to
do. And most importantly, just have fun
along the way, right? You know, I love
adventures. I love traveling, as you
probably can tell. Just got back from
Japan. Amazing powder there. Got an epic
mountain biking trip this month.
currently in Bali, Indonesia. I head out
to Austin, Texas. Then to Wyoming, uh to
go explore the Titans as well as
Yellowstone National Park, bringing my
parents out there. So, so many amazing
adventures, right? Life is about having
fun and doing things you enjoy with
amazing people. On the purpose side of
things, right, you probably want to go
and you have dreams of impacting
millions of people, building a legacy,
right? and feeling alive, you know,
waking up every single day excited to go
and work on your business, to make an
impact on your customers, to work with
an amazing team. You know, these are the
things that really make a life worth
living. So, I don't think it's either or
here, right? I don't think it's peace or
profit or profit or purpose. No, here as
part of the founder freedom movement on
this channel, we believe in abundance,
right? You can have it all. And this is
my belief, right? I stopped telling
myself years ago that I had to choose
between one of these. You know, I can
have an amazing business, but I'm going
to have to sacrifice all my
relationships. Screw that. You don't
need to accept that programming from
society. Right? You have the power to go
and create a business you love, to
create amazing relationships you love,
and to live a purpose, to have peace, to
have harmony, to have tranquility. This
is a system that I use to make this all
possible. So, let's dive in here on the
peace side, right? It all comes down to
systems plus delegation plus automation.
So, the morning fortress, okay, how you
start your day is really what's going to
dictate, you know, the rest of your
productivity and your happiness. So,
every single day, I really have a single
focus task, right? what's the biggest
task that I need to get done that day to
look back on it and know damn I really
achieved some big things today. The next
aspect then is going and first thing in
the morning when my dopamine is highest,
when I'm feeling good, when I'm clear to
go and spend 3 hours of deep work,
really punching that task forward and
getting it done. I put my phone on
airplane mode. I eliminate all
distractions, no meetings before noon,
and I have my Vibe Soundcloud or Spotify
playlist playing, which, you know, is
just a great way to kind of dial it in
and just to have fun, right? Who who
doesn't love listening to great music
and getting important tasks done. I
think here as part of this movement, you
know, this is kind of a key part of how
we spend our time in the mornings. So,
let's talk about the decision frameworks
you need to be making, right? You should
be doing only the things that you can do
in your zone of genius. For me, that's
things like building systems, hiring a
players, building audiences, creating
really creative content, dialing in the
taste and the details across the company
so that I'm inspiring 100 million
founders just like you to accomplish
your dreams through proven systems and
anything that does not exist in that
zone of genius. I need to go and
delegate that to other legends on my
team who can do those things probably a
lot better than me, right? I need to
delete things that are unnecessary.
Focus on less but better. Only doing the
things that you know I should be doing.
At the end of the day, saying no to more
things, right? No is a superpower.
Default to no so you can focus radically
on the things that are going to be the
big needle movers in your life and in
your business. Things like, you know,
growing the revenue, growing cash flows,
building systems for freedom. These
things matter. you know, going and, you
know, setting up that 10th feature in
your product or that new shiny toy that
could exist, you know, in your business.
Ignore that stuff. Delete that stuff so
you can focus on the few things, the
critical few that are going to move
things forward for you. Next aspect here
is then delegating, right? A big part of
what I spend my time on is building a
team of weapons, people that are able to
10x my businesses. And so I delegate to
these people really the core things that
they're amazing at, which then frees up
my time to do the things that I'm really
skilled with. This is an example of what
my team looks like at Founder OS. And so
I have a team of people that I'm
delegating different things to that are
able then to go and orchestrate those
things much better than I can even do.
So I can focus on peace. I can focus on
creativity. I can focus on building more
scalable systems. I can focus on
dazzling founders and doing the things
that really fire me up that are in my
calling in life. You know, the more that
you're able to spend every day working
on what you love to do, I think the more
you produce everyday retirement.
Everyday retirement or edr is really
when every single day you're working on
stuff that even if you were retired,
you'd be doing that exact same stuff. So
for me that's like writing, reading,
traveling, coaching founders, building
systems, creating organic content, being
inspired and dialing in different
creative projects, creating amazing
videos just like this one. Those are the
things that I love to do. And that's
what everyday retirement looks like for
me. So I'm in my zone. I'm making money.
I'm having fun. I'm working with amazing
people. You know, I never want to quit
this life. On the piece tech stack side,
I love text expander, a sauna for
project management, loom to make sure
that I'm recording core tasks that other
people can do and then I can delegate
it. I use Google Docs and just keep
things simple to document every single
system across my companies. And then
Claude is the AI that I love the most
these days to go and help me carry out a
lot of these systems at record speed so
I can scale myself because at the end of
the day AI is an amazing productivity
tool that can help you really go and
scale a lot faster in your business and
you should be leveraging it. So energy
is everything as a founder, right?
Strong founders build strong businesses.
Healthy founders build healthy
businesses. And so I'm meditating every
day for focus. I'm moving every day to
dial in my energy. These days, I'm doing
about five HIT workouts a week at a gym
nearby called Beyond. I also go and I do
about three yoga sessions a week. So,
that's kind of my current health
regimen. I then use my peak hours of the
day, generally from around 7:00 a.m. to
11:00 a.m. for creativity and building
cool [\h__\h] I take nature breaks every
single weekend, watch the sunset daily,
you know, do things that just give me a
little bit of rest, relaxation. You
know, I like to get massages three times
a week right now. And I have rest
periods for recovery, right? If you want
to be an entrepreneur, you know,
entrepreneurs are athletes, and so
recovery is important, right? You can't
just be on all the time. So, making sure
that you're scheduling time to just
rest, relax, and recharge along the way
to growth, right? I think a lot of times
founders look at it as a top chart here,
right, where it's just steady growth the
whole time. But what I've learned over
building businesses for 14 years is that
you got to come to grips with the
reality, right? Stop trying to think of
every single day it's just this linear
growth. The truth is, you know, it's up
and down, right? And that's okay. That's
just how it goes. And so, you know, even
though it doesn't feel like progress,
really convince yourself that you are
making progress. You know, sometimes you
need to take a couple steps back to m
move a few steps forward. So, accept
that and move along along the way. I
love to have my vision handy at all
times. This is the screen on my iPhone.
So every time when I open up that phone,
maybe a couple times a day or sorry,
probably more likely 30 times a day, I
have that vision handy there that I can
go and visit to remind me of like what
I'm doing here, why I'm doing this, the
kind of life I'm trying to architect,
inspiring founders, building an
inspiring life, unlocking my creative
potential, helping others, you know,
these are the sort of things that matter
to me. And the more I can subconsciously
even remind myself of that vision, the
more I can keep on dialing it into my
life. Because I think about 95% of your
life is your subconscious mind dictating
what you're going to do. So you want to
make sure that you know you're basically
feeding that subconscious thought with
the clear vision, the slides in your
life that you want to make sure you're
living out. And you'll be remarkably
surprised at how quickly you start to
manifest that vision. So on the profit
side, let's get into it here. For me,
when I'm creating content, content is
always a core revenue driver of my
companies. I've never spent a dime on
ads. And when I think about making
content, 50% is to grow the given
channel and 50% then is niche content
that drives people down to then work
with one of my portfolio companies. So
the content GPS is the core system that
I use here which brings me enormous
amounts of peace, profit and fun, right?
So going and making sure that I'm across
all platforms, creating the highest
quality content possible, driving people
to a newsletter, driving those folks to
applications, to customers, and then
getting them through a dazzling
experience to love the product so much
that they go and tell five friends. The
more dialed in this whole system is, the
better off my life, the better off my
businesses. Again, this is the most
powerful system I've ever discovered
over the last 14 years building
businesses. I have my content calendar
dialed in because the more consistent my
content, the more I'm generating
eyeballs, generating leads, and building
the profit of my companies. In addition
to that, I make sure that I've gone and
mapped out using Fig Jam, which is a
Figma product, every single step of our
funnel at Founder OS and at every single
one of my portfolio companies. So that
people when they're inside, they get
different emails at different times that
are tracked and sent all via HubSpot,
which is the core CRM that we use at
Founder OS. So when they go and apply,
they get certain emails. When they join,
they get certain emails. When they
abandon a card or abandon an
application, they get into certain email
flows. So at every single step of the
way, we have about 80 different emails
mapped out in about a 150 page Google
Doc that no matter what stage you're in,
you get emails that are tailored to you
to move you to the next stage in the
process so that no one gets clogged up
and there are no bottlenecks along the
way of our content GPS and our email
sequences. And this is the kind of stuff
that we help founders with inside a
founder OS. So on the purpose side, this
is kind of what it all comes down to,
right? We're all after building an
amazing legacy and day after day being
jazzed up around what we're doing. And
it all comes down to me to an icky guy,
right? Icky guy is this Japanese concept
that I discovered about a decade ago. I
was traveling through B National Park on
Christmas of all days and randomly I
slid off the road cuz I hit some ice and
I crashed into a snowbank. So I was
stranded there in the middle of B, you
know, middle of nowhere over Christmas
and I came across this book called icky
and it changed my life. Icky is a
Japanese concept that refers to your
reason for being or you know what is
really your purpose in life. It really
sits at the intersection of what you
love, what you can be paid for, what
you're great at, and what the world
needs. In the center there is your icky
guy which is the thing that gets you
fired up to get after it every single
day. So this is what my icky guy looks
like, right? And in the center for me
are things like building teams, scaling
the distribution of my companies,
building systems, traveling, coaching
founders, really helping people unlock
their creative potential. And so every
single day, every week, I'm focused on
optimizing and really kind of dialing it
in even more, you know, really making
sure that every day I'm maximizing my
icky guy, right? because I think that
this is the reason that I was put on
earth was to inspire people to help
people with systems to give them more
freedom. And so every day I'm focused on
how can I maximize that purpose in life.
So what is your icky guy, right? And I
would recommend that you go and fill
this out and put down two bullet points
at least in each one of those four
quadrants. Look at the patterns and
what's at the center there. That's your
icky guy. And how can you go and lean
into those things more in your life? So,
here's an easy template that you can go
fill out that'll also be linked below in
the description. You can go and download
that for free. So, you can go and dial
in your purpose. And I'll be giving you
this whole resource as well. So, go and
check that out via the link in the
description. You know, this is just the
beginning, okay? And this process of
dialing in your peace, your profit, your
purpose is an ongoing exercise, right?
You're never really done. It's a
mindset. It's an intention that you will
continue to lean into over your life,
really. So, are you ready to make an
impact? If you want some help actually
dialing in these areas in your business,
you should definitely go and check out
Founder OS via the link in the
description or go to founder
os.com/apply. I'd love to help you dial
in your peace, your profit, your purpose
this year. Let's win together. Welcome
to the founder freedom movement. It's
been a pleasure helping you here. Like
and subscribe and let's win