Pretty people, good espresso,
nice light music, no distractions
>> or too many distractions.
>> Too many.
>> Either side of the scale is just fine.
It's just the messy middle we want to
avoid.
>> I don't give a [\h__\h]
>> Yeah. Yeah. I mean, we do our thing.
We've been creative and doing our thing
since
>> Yeah. And then Yeah.
prese
[Laughter]
like those people are definitely from
Canada.
Scrum furry.
We're ready to
Playlist is live. It's live.
In my heart,
my heart
on LinkedIn. And the vibe there is just
making these things
super on brand. They have to be
printable because we get that comment
all the time that people actually go and
end up printing this stuff.
>> So you mean standard size like 8.5 by
11?
>> You can leave the size like whatever
it's been basically as the biggest can
come up.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. cuz you want to
stop the scroll if you want it because
I'll show you if you want it um like
light background the lime green doesn't
pop as much. It works on the black dark
background
>> and white is kind of Yeah. Yeah. I'll
show you. So, I'm not sure if I want to
go like with these kind of colors. Even
though like it grabs the attention, I'm
still like I like the minimalism of it
and like just like let's say keywords in
green, but I can do more of that as well
like
like where I have space. I think it's
nice to do it just very delicately. I
would leave that how it is, but like
like it almost it's a mix of like
something that's welld designigned but
also like a piece of paper you'd get at
like university
>> or something like to study.
>> Yeah.
>> So, and that's good. Like people just
need to like Yeah. actually use it. I
don't I think when things get too
designy, over the top,
>> it takes away from the function.
>> No, exactly. And I just like that some
things are really small, so you have to
like let's say people are going to stop
and like zoom in and then read like I
know I do that for stuff that let's say
you see this graphic and you're like,
"Oh, what do you love? Like what are you
good at?" And then you just go over
here, you read, then you can just like
scroll all the way there.
Yeah.
Yeah. I think it's good. Nick, I guess,
right? And then he's going to get that
other designer and then me and you
should review that guy's work as he's
pushing it.
>> Yeah.
>> Cuz this is now like the template for
him to use.
>> Yeah.
>> And let's just like hold them to
obviously that standard.
>> Exactly.
>> And uh for me like there's two others
that uh Nate wanted me to to do as like
templates and examples. I'm going to go
over them.
>> Boom. Let's go.
We just have to like start to just
create a playbook for how we want them
to be. Like I think that we can make the
videos like Stefon Digs and like like we
just have to like say that we want it
and we have the squad now to do it.
>> You know, like if they're there waiting,
they're like just send us exactly how
you want them.
>> You know what I mean?
>> Yeah.
>> What they're going to do is they're
going to send us like a one minute like
sizzle of like, hey, you've sent us all
this [\h__\h] We understand your brand. We
understand your [\h__\h] They're going to
take some of our footage. They're going
to be this is how we're going to edit
your videos and they're going to include
like how they see the motion being and
you know what I mean? So it's like a one
minute now video almost
>> brand like you know sizzle or some [\h__\h]
you know so yeah we just want to like
lay them up to be like this is our
standard. This is how we do it. This is
like the title so that the glow this is
the text like this. This is the way that
we do motion but stuff. This is the line
work we want. Um, this doesn't have to
it's always evolving, so it's nothing
that also to be flushed out no matter.
But I think that's something for us to
like jam deeper on in Lisbon. Yeah.
Yeah. Now is the time for us to be like
this is it. Like not even Yeah.
Everything that bugs us, everything that
should be there, everything that we want
that we dream of, like just [\h__\h] lay
it down cuz the quicker we do that, the
quicker they're just going to [\h__\h]
>> Yeah.
>> extrapolate the [\h__\h] it. But yes, I
agree that like we should fix the most
broken [\h__\h] like for sure first.
>> No, it's it's just like adding too much
motion and too much effects is still
like it's like
>> um
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah.
>> It's like too much is also
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. I don't think it's a
matter of like uh adding too much more.
I think it's like deleting [\h__\h] and then
what's left? It's like do we believe in
every single thing here? Do we like that
title card? Do we like that subtitle? Do
we like that thing? Yeah. I don't even I
don't think we need to really add
anything probably. anything, it's
probably deleting. Kind of like we just
did yesterday Instagram where we're
like, "Okay, delete, delete, delete." If
there's like 10 different things we're
doing there, let's do five. And of those
five,
>> let's just be like the best with those.
And like whether it's a mix of data,
what we love to do, and what performs,
like triple down. I think it's the same
thing on the motion side.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So, the YouTube subscribe
animation
you right. I don't think we should do
that anymore. Right. I think you should
have it towards the end if any, but like
in the middle or like couple times
during the video too much. Yeah, I think
okay.
Or it depends. Let's say this video is
about like lead magnet. You're talking
about some systems. Makes sense to have
a link somewhere at when you're
explaining it, right? But if it's more
vloggy and stuff, yeah, I would not do
it. I would just like, hey, this one is
just like day in life or talking about
stuff. You don't need to sell anything.
It's like the one that's coming up there
is like when there's sections to a video
or there's four parts to it or I'm going
to go over these five things, you're
going to want to stay tuned, right? We
sometimes like it's good to be able to
>> Yeah, I have something for that. It's
not even that we use it all the time,
but just having something.
I don't like honestly
I would just instead of illustrations I
guess I would put
the the keyword in Helica something. The
only thing you don't want to do there
just a retention sense is if you put the
word in there and people think it's
something and they're like oh I already
know that thing I'm not going to watch
this. Right.
>> So, it's nice if there's like some
either just like four things like four
numbers or it's blurred out which is
kind of tacky. Um
or it like looks just like like I don't
know like I'm going to go over four
things like 1 2 3 4 over like a diamond
let's just say where it's like um
or there's like yeah some kind of thing
on the side like a t like kind of like a
clean line
>> like like
a shape like of a line like one two
three four and you're like oo that's
yeah there's it just looks clean and
minimalist. Yeah.
I think the thing I'm going to start
doing sometimes with Jake is like when
he's doing things I'm going to start
like drawing like I'll have a piece of
paper like this open and like time code
a certain part of the video and
literally draw what I want. I usually do
that but
>> that's exactly what I was like um yeah
that's the best way you do it like
>> from this and then you do arrow to that
part. So
>> I think it's the best way to uh put it.
All right. So that's the latest I've
done. I want to I want us to have like
one staple to just keep it tight and
just that's the one that's going to stay
on the brand. And like of course like
what I'm thinking about adding next to
it would be like let's say a little dot
in the corner just like black dot not
even green just like because it's a
black and white carousel I want to keep
it simple but then we have the dot and
it's there.
the same fonts as the playlist, as the
YouTube, as the LinkedIn poster,
like you said. I think you mentioned it
earlier. We just changing the direction.
Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's like again, you have like 20
different ones and then different
pattern. Just use them.
>> Exactly. It's kind of like that's what I
like here is different different,
>> right? Cuz some of them don't even need
that much. So he does like pop up just a
little bit.
>> Tangactum.
>> Um
like
>> that's an example of good line work for
motion.
>> Exactly.
>> Yeah. Like this one. There's like
outlines, thin lines.
>> Mhm.
>> It's like really clean
like this. Four words arrows and [\h__\h]
>> Arrows. Uh yeah, just super clean like
Yeah. I think it's like if it comes out
at the right time in the right script
and the right stuff, it just looks Yeah,
>> exactly.
>> clean.
>> And also what I'm thinking is that
sometimes there's so much copy
that even if I spread it out on like
more more slides, it goes up to like 15
16 slides. So we don't want above like
10 slides if we then we run like we
going to run ads on like even though we
don't normally do that but like
>> like um good practice also it's like
fewer words like clean lines and stuff
people are just going to it's easy to
read. You don't want to read a book
every time you close a carousel, right?
>> Mhm. Um, so yeah. And I think the one
that performed really well was this one.
And I'm trying to figure out like to
study. Is it because like it's so each
one is highly sharable.
>> Yeah. Each is like very like Yeah.
Sharable. Like you'd save that, you'd
share it. Um it's like because you
believe in this. It's like, "Oh yeah,
I've been telling people this." Or
they're going to share with their friend
going, "Fuck,
>> you got to check these out." Like they
have founder friends. And then they
share with their founder friend. Cuz
it's also calling out like, "Hey, every
founder should read this."
>> Yeah.
>> I feel I think it's like
>> I I would just keep playing with like 10
books every founder should read.
>> Yeah.
>> 10 songs every founder should flow to.
And then it's like the founder flow
playlist.
>> Yeah. And what I would add is if we
really break down the copy is like the
anatomy of the copy is that let's say
like you said 10 something whatever
should read and then it's like yes
there's the like the the sentence or the
prompt or the book but then you explain
why. It's like let's say this book and
then you just tell why. It's like hey
this book like was really part of my I
don't know a breakthrough moment for me
during my career. No. you put into
context what like this thing means to
you or how people can use it, right?
Like 10 tricks to
>> I don't know uh
>> Mhm.
>> 10 habits that made me like a like like
like a successful founder and then you
just like this this this is like the
kind of stuff copy that's super useful,
super functional, super sharable like
you said. It's like and then yeah, it's
like every slide is really uh easy to
read, you know?
So, there's nothing like really special
to this carousel. It's like text, but I
think it's just like what people want to
read more.
I feel like if we're going to start
using the brand kind of like we're
making it when like you're using that
helmet and all that, it's like it's more
like fashion. It is more like like kind
of lowkey like even it's less it's like
light it's it's not trying so hard. It's
like it's not so youtuby. It's more the
you know Yeah. Whatever. So you see some
of like the like this is the kind of
stuff we use.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and it's Yeah. Like we we shouldn't
be doing that [\h__\h] anymore. You know
what I mean? Not that like so on and so
forth. And you so I I basically took
some of our most popular animation
styles and just by even just looking at
whatever that was like 25 slides, we can
just take 15 of them, 10 of them,
whatever, and go, "Okay,
>> this is the way now."
>> Mhm.
>> And then we have a motion guy Jake.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Now I just start doing the [\h__\h]
And now it's like, okay, bang.
>> Hey, this is like this is our brand.
Operate within this. All right. Let's
see. Yep. What's up?