When you look at businesses [music] like
Starbucks or McDonald's, right, one of
the core things that they really
mastered early on [music] was thinking
of their business like an assembly line.
You know, someone goes and orders a
drink, then you have to go and prep it a
certain way. You have to have a
standardized menu in a repeatable
process so [music] that that same
franchise can be replicated thousands of
times across different countries and
different [music] cultures. Now, the
truth is too many founders view their
businesses as completely different. They
say, "Oh, no. You know, all my stuff's
got to be customized or, you know, it's
just not the same." And those kind of
founders will be left behind. Because
the truth is that every business is an
assembly line. The opportunity right now
is to start cloning yourself. Stop
thinking that your stuff cannot be
replicated because the truth is it can
[music] and it will be whether it's by
you or by a competitor in your space.
[music] Now, here's the beautiful part
about actually going and cloning
yourself. The truth is whether you're a
busy founder, high performer, busy
professional is you're constantly being
inundated with different tasks. You know
that feeling of like damn it like I got
to go do this thing today. And often
times that's the kind of feeling that
leads you to procrastinate. [music]
You should not be taking something from
0 to 100. You should be cloning yourself
and getting your clone to take it from 0
to 80 and then you taking it that final
mile, right? [music] That cognitive
dissonance can be offloaded to your
clone so you don't need to go and do all
this stuff yourself. You know, the other
thing that I see all the time is people
going and using hiring as some badge of
honor. But here's the deal. Hiring is
actually a badge of failure these days.
In so many cases, it's about slowing
down and realizing that this is no
longer optional. Right now is the time
to start leveraging AI, making it your
strategic business advisor, and using it
for [music] about 80% of your decisions
in a day. So, this is last Friday. This
is me documenting all [music] the tasks
that I need to go and create. Inside of
here, you can see things like creating a
COO, which is a chief operating officer,
job description, uh going and finding
places [music]
um where I can go and tap into different
founders that are doing over $300,000
[music]
of revenue a month. Beside each of these
tasks, as you can see right here, I've
gone and put a little square box and
inside it says [music] 10X. That 10x
goes and alludes to my 10x profit clone
inside [music] of chat GBT. And so this
10x profit clone is essentially gone and
trained on all of my core documents,
[music] around 39 of them inside of
founder OS and my own personal life. So
that this [music] thing can make
decisions 10 times better than me and
help drive 10x more profits from my
portfolio of online businesses that are
currently doing over $13 million a year
in revenue. You know, when I look out to
2027, it's the founders that go and
start cloning [music] themselves at an
elite level today that will go and far
surpass the rest of the competition in
their space. The beautiful thing here,
as you guys know on this channel, is
that we're all about systems. [music]
And AI eats systems for breakfast. And
so, when you're organized, when you have
clear documentation, you give AI the
power it needs to then go and make
decisions 10x better than you can.
[music] And so, you know, I'm able to go
and offload a bunch of just stuff that
candidly I don't want to be doing, and
then use that cognitive load to make big
hires, film content like this. I really
believe as a high performer, you need to
be a student [music] of the game, and
make sure that you're implementing this
at an elite level. There are new rules
being written out. There's a new way of
thinking and operating that is required
of you. So, now, let me reveal the
simple two-step system that you need to
go and clone yourself with AI. What
we're going to get into here is all of
the pieces of my 10x profit [music]
project. This is the ultimate clone of
myself and I want to go and help you set
this up for your business and life as
well. So, we're going to start with
documentation and documentation is just
a simple way of saying you need to have
systemized documents of all the core
pieces of your business. So, let me go
and show you some of the core ones that
I would recommend you get set up [music]
ASAP. What we have here is the Founder
OS brand positioning, right? And inside
of this, I've gone and synthesized all
the core pieces of our messaging around
Founder OS, which is the high- growth
community that I've built of founders
that are looking to build founder-led
brands and remove themselves from
operations [music] and have a business
that runs itself. And so, our real core
messaging is that the best way to build
an online business is with a personal
brand because people follow people then
they follow brands. Obviously, because
I've given my project this much context,
it really knows the
>> [music]
>> essence of my brand. You can see I've
gone and updated my own personal board
of adviserss, people that are going to
go and help me accelerate my vision, and
I'm also going to help them with their
vision. From there, I've gone and
synthesized things like my project
priorities. So, the core things that I
need to do to wrap up 2025 to make this
the most legendary year of my life. From
there, I've listed things like the
copywriting needs we need to nail down,
our tech needs, all detailed here. I've
also uploaded my vision for each of my
companies, right? Over 10 years, 3
years, one year, and then what we need
to get over the 90 days to make [\h__\h]
happen. And I've done the same with my
own personal vision here as well. Here
you can see the founder velocity offer.
And so what I've gone and done here is
detailed all of the things that people
get inside of Founder S velocity. access
to me, my chief product officer, my head
of distribution, my head of video, my
chief of staff. You know, this is just a
taste of what we have inside of there.
It's a [music] community of around 200
high growth legends. Our belief is that
we're stronger together. We're always
sharing cutting edge secrets and people
can message me anytime they need any
help and we're constantly going and
leveling up [music] as an amazing group
of high performance individuals. What I
then go and do is I download this and
this is one of the documents that I
upload to the project files of that 10x
profit project that I'll show you here
in a second. You can see that I've gone
and obviously systemized my whole
company. What I do is I go and upload
all the core systems from an awareness,
inquiry, sales, onboarding, delivery,
collections, and renewal. Right? Because
when you think about the seven core
aspects of the customer journey inside
of your company, there's generally about
three systems in each of these
categories. When you go and take those
21 systems across the whole journey and
you upload [music] those to your chat
GBT project, now the clone of you
essentially has an understanding of not
just how every piece of your business
works, but it also has an understanding
of all the core stakeholders inside of
your business and who has decision
rights over different pieces of the
flows. That way, as you start asking it
to complete tasks and organize plans for
you, it can go and not only create those
plans, but also create the delegation
systems necessary to go and get [\h__\h] off
your plate and help you build more
leverage. Because as a founder, there
are a number of ways to help you get out
of the core operation and build
leverage. You have media, which is your
personal brand. You have code, which is
the technology that you build around
you, including AI. You have capital
which is leveraging your cash flows to
reinvest that to make more cash. And
then you also have your team, right,
which has the ability to go and, you
know, work without you and help you go
and get to your dreams a lot faster.
Now, it's not just that that I go and
upload to this clone of myself. I'm also
going and giving it different stories,
right? So, I want to make sure it
understands my authentic voice. And so
these are 29 pages of my writing, my
stories, different kind of vibes around,
you know, the identity that I have and
the way that I speak so that it knows
actually like who I am at like my core,
right? So I'm getting into different
stories um that I've gone and written in
my journal and uploaded them here to
this doc. I'm coming up um with more
flushed out sort of enemies that I have
um different things I'm passionate
about. Trying to just give it like that
personality. so that this clone actually
has a soul. The key thing is that most
people find that their clone doesn't
sound like them or doesn't sound
authentic. And I just think that that's
a lack of you going and giving it the
context it needs. So I'm giving it
stories in the form of this doc as an
example, but I'm also going and in my
case, I've uploaded my entire book as
well. Now, this is coming out soon, so I
can't show you everything here, but
let's just say there's about 70,000
words here that I've scrubbed pretty
hardcore that I also go and upload to my
[music] clone so it can ensure that when
it's giving me stuff, it's writing like
I speak. When it comes to the business,
right, an example of something that's
important is making sure that you have
clear expectations of every single
department. Okay, so here you can see my
sales expectations as an example, right?
So we have a culture where things like
extreme ownership, high agency, high
standards, and no complacency are
required. And so from there, we're
making sure that, you know, over the
remaining 12 pages of this document, I'm
going through the key kind of escalation
practices, who does what, the importance
of updating things like CRM and hitting
metrics. I've also got things like our
marketing motivation here. This gets
into things like our target market, our
core client avatar, what they care
about, what they're all about. The fact
that we're targeting with founder OS
established business owners. Whenever
you're creating content, the area where
most people screw up is that they don't
have the infrastructure in place. And
the infrastructure is something that the
content GPS solves and includes things
like your CTAs, your newsletter, your
email sequences, and how you go and
create your own application router. By
the way, if you want my help and my
team's help going and implementing your
own clone because you're looking at this
and you're going, "Damn, I'd love to get
someone to set this up with me." Well,
that's exactly what we do in Founder OS,
you can go and book a call with my team
below. We'll learn what you're really
trying to do with your clone and see how
we can help. All right, so when it comes
to going and setting up your
instructions and prompting inside of
your clone, the area where most people
screw up is that they make it way too
skinny. It's vague as hell. you're
expecting this thing to work like you,
but you're not giving it the
instructions that will do such. Now, if
we want it to act like you, or you know,
a 10x version of you, we got to get into
the details because it's where the
details happen that the real leverage
happens. So, when I'm going and tooling
up the instructions for my clone, I'm
putting in things like, you are the best
business coach and growth strategist in
the world, hired to help me scale
Founder OS from 500K profit a month to
$2 million profit a month. I wanted to
advise me like the best founders in the
world. People like [music] Larry
Ellison, Charlie Mer, Warren Buffett,
Jeff Bezos, and Bill Campbell, the
trillion dollar coach. So, it has deep
expertise in things like design, ops,
strategy, sales, marketing, finance,
[music] and is going to think in terms
of constraints, compounding, and giving
me massive clarity. Now, [music]
that's not all. as it goes and designs
things. I need systems, I need road
maps, and then core documentation that I
can go and 5x the profit of [music]
Founder OS in just the next 12 months.
So, I need the playbook to scale
revenue, expand margins, [music] and
simplifying operations without adding
any more chaos. From there, I give it
even more detailed breakdowns. things
like helping me go and identify
constraints in specific ways by
diagnosing the one bottleneck that we
need to attack to go and unlock the next
level of leverage. I need to then
prescribe systems, right, and make sure
that they're scalable, repeatable, and
documented. From there, it needs to
define the KPIs if I'm delegating things
to other people with clear due dates so
that, you know, there's some
accountability there. I then wanted to
prioritize leverage in everything that
we do by increasing things like average
order value um lifetime value of a
customer making sure that we're driving
lead flow at scale and overall also
reducing the founder dependency and
everything right because the truth is
I'm focused on working on the business
not in [music] it and having a business
that completely runs itself. So in terms
of the kind of tone right I want it to
be systematic and calm kind of like that
naval ravocant mixed with Rick Rubin
energy I want there to be a core loop
which each thing right I want it
thinking about the fourth and fifth
order consequences of everything. I also
wanted to think in terms of
psychological constraints, right? And
think in terms of things like inversion,
some of the core principles from folks
like Charlie Mer who helped grow
Birkshar Hathway at like some insane
exponential growth rate over the last
100 years. And so I want to leverage
some of the best thinking that's existed
amongst the best founders ever and apply
that to my business. Now keep in mind
too, right, inside of the project files,
I've gone and uploaded all of our
financial model, right? So I have all of
our, you know, profit and loss as well
as balance sheet for the last 3 years.
And then I've also gone and uploaded our
projections for the next 5 years. And so
it has all the context it needs now to
go and be basically the best business
coach that I've ever known. That's for
sure. So this is what I mean by the
details, right? And when you're going
and building your project instructions,
I think there's a few things you want to
think about. Number one, you want to
think about the bar that you're setting.
And the way to do this is thinking
about, you know, what do you want it to
be for you and what are some references
as the kind of people in the world that
are the best at that thing? You should
probably go and list them. The second
aspect is you should probably go and
list detailed instructions in terms of
what you want it to do for you. Systems,
KPIs, different documentation. Go and
list that out. And then the third thing
is probably thinking about the sort of
tone that you want to be thinking about
as well. you know, are you looking for
someone to go and kind of give you the
harsh truth, or do you like it when it's
more kind of relaxed and chill? That
combined with all the documentation you
give in terms of transcripts from calls
and your own voice, whether it's through
your different content or the best copy
you've ever written, is going to make
sure that as this thing's actually
delegating things on your behalf, that
it sounds actually like you and your
authentic voice. And so, you're probably
looking to go and set up your
instructions. Okay? So, let me show you
how I'd think about it if you're trying
to do this relatively fast. Okay, so one
tool I love to use for this is Whisper
Flow. All right, which allows me to go
and press just the function key on my
MacBook um and then just speak and get,
you know, text perfectly um formatted
and dictated based on what I say. So,
say I was running an agency and I was
looking to get it from 200k per month to
a [music] million a month. Here's what I
would do. We go and open up Whisper Flow
here. And you can see just for a second
[music] as I talk, it's kind of tight.
So, you are the best agency owner,
adviser in the world. I'm looking to get
my agency from 200k profit a month to a
million dollars a month. I need you to
go and make sure that every area of my
business is upleveled from sales,
operations, marketing, tech, design, and
finance. [music]
I want you to go and give me um clear
instructions that help increase my
margins, help make my business more
smooth so I can remove myself from the
operations and have a business that runs
itself. I want you to go and advise me
like the best founders that have ever
existed like Jeff Bezos, Charlie Mer,
Warren Buffett, Richard Branson, and
Steve Jobs. So, you can see there that
in seconds, right, it's able just to go
and take my thinking right right off my
head and go and smack that onto this
dock. I can then simply go and copy and
paste this into the instructions inside
of the chatbtd project and get rolling.
Now, a pro tip here is you could
actually go and say to Chachi BT, I'm
trying to create a project instructions
for a clone of myself. This is my
general thinking of what I'm trying to
do. Go and make these instructions 100
times better. All right. So, I'm going
to go and break down how I go and use my
clone across things like hiring, core
life decisions, you know, smart ways I
think of learning, telling the future,
and really where it's going, and then
things like financial analysis as well
as prioritization. Okay, so we're about
to get into a lot here, so buckle up
because this is behind the scenes stuff
that I've never shown before, but you
know, for you guys, we're always trying
to be insanely generous. So, [music]
let's rip it. Right now, I've been
really focused on bringing on a COO into
Founder OS. Someone that can go and
remove me from all the final pieces of
the ops and then allow me to go and just
enjoy my life and most importantly go
and work on way more strategic things
for found. closing up deals with
Netflix, buying a founder retreat center
in the Doommites, and a lot of other
insane stuff that we're cooking up. You
know, our mission here is big, and I
need a [music] [\h__\h] cracked operator
inside of our company to help get us to
where we're trying to go. And so,
[music] what I've gone and done here is
created a COO interview system. I've
gone and prompted my clone to go and
come up with the entire interview
process so I can make sure that I'm
hiring a weapon. [music] You know, as a
CEO, you know that there's really three
things you need to nail down. your
numbers, your people, and your culture,
right? And when it comes to people, the
hiring process is one of the most high
lever things you can nail down. But so
many people screw this up. And so,
inside of this, you can see it's coming
up with a structure and questions for
the interview, the dos and don'ts in
terms of the red flags that I may see
that would determine that someone's not
right for what we're doing, and [music]
the green flag answers that would
determine this is high signal and you
could move this person forward in the
interview process. It's giving me all
the different projects this person
should be creating and completing. And
it also [music] has kind of the core
things that I should be looking for,
right? Someone that can document my
actual recurring responsibilities.
Someone that's [music] able to assign
core systems, the people on our team.
Um, someone that's really great at a
leadership cadence across the company.
And someone that's really done this
before over multiple years inside the
exact sort of space that we operate in.
[music] So, this is just one example,
right, of leveraging your clone to make
sure that when you're getting into a
bunch of interviews in a day, you have
that all systemized and ready to go. So,
you're not thinking, "Fuck, [music] you
know, what am I even asking this person
or how do I even know if this person's
right for my company?" Your clone has
already done all that work for you. So,
now let's move forward into life
decision optimization. All right, in
2026, I got big dreams, right? And I
know you do, too. Now, one of the big
things that I'm going and setting up is
an [music] epic home base in Bali. What
I asked my clone to do is go and come up
with an insane plan for a home. Okay.
What it's going and doing here is
crafting [music] not just some villa in
Bali, which is not what we're looking
for. You know, we're really trying to
create this kind of like Frank Lloyd
Wright vibe, right? And construct this
environment, right, for creativity, for
peace, [music] and for longevity. What
it's now doing, right, is dialing in how
all of this home base needs to be dialed
to not only help me personally with
things like silence, nature, but it's
also going to help me go and leverage
this home [music] base to dial in the
business goals that I have as well. I
then go and transfer this to a Google
doc that actually ended up being around
30 pages long. That's printed off and
it's now handed off to every core
stakeholder that's helping me with this
exact project. All right. So, you can
also go and leverage your clone to just
learn in a much more curated and
personalized manner. So, here you can
[music] see I'm also going and using my
clone to come up with top book
recommendations for me. As you use your
clone, it's developing a memory around
the things you're struggling with, your
current challenges, the obstacles, and
the goals you have, right? It's going
and recommending books like the four
agreements, the power of now, untethered
soul. These are just some of the books.
And what I typically then go do is like
pick a few of them, buy them physically,
and I'm just reading these mostly before
bed or when I'm just chilling throughout
the days. Now, I also go and use my
clone to really help me go and tell the
future. And so, one thing as an example
is the fourth turning, which is this
whole kind of societal reset that's
going on, and it happens every 80 to 90
years. And right now, there's a fourth
turning going on. There's a Nobel Prize
winner, which is a Schiller cape ratio
that right now is kind of showing that
this adjusted price to earnings ratio um
[music] which typically dictates crashes
um is spiking right now, indicating that
there's likely going to be a correction
[music] in 2026. And so I'm looking at
that. I'm getting ready for it. Um, the
truth is that most of entrepreneurship
is really about not just going and
looking for your upside, [music]
but also inverting things and asking
yourself, how could we fail? I'm already
preparing my contingency plans across
all my businesses so that when it
happens, I'm actually looking forward to
it because I've got plans in place and
we're ready to rock. And now when it
comes to the fourth turning, as an
example, this is exactly part of the
reason why I've created Founder OS,
right? You know, we're talking about a
time where things are going to be
collapsing, right? The old guard is
going away. The new guard is things like
AI powered teams, founder brands and
[music] systems for everything that you
do, right? We live in the most
remarkable time ever. So this is exactly
what we help founders with inside of
founder OS, helping them with the
systems, helping go and leveraging their
entire team with the AI so the founder
becomes the least important person in
their business. Again, if any of this is
interesting, you should definitely go
and book a call via the link in the
description. we'd love to tell you more
about it and learn what you're really
trying to do with your brand this year.
Now, here's one of the most exciting
ways that I go and I use my clone. Okay,
we all know that when we're building
there is sometimes this level of
overwhelm. The general issue is not
time, okay, it's prioritization and
having the right systems and AI around
you to go and knock down those
priorities. So what I do is when I have
all these project files updated and it
knows what I'm working on, it's able to
go and effectively help me prioritize
the next 20 tasks I need to do ranked
from most important to least important.
So in here it's telling me to go and
build the 2.0 version of the found
dashboard. Go and give the Found
application funnel and GPS an entire
overhaul. Go and continue to optimize
the velocity offer. Launch Black Friday
Cyber Monday, which you know, fast
forward, we've done this. We made over
$280,000 in just 7 days. So, you know,
let me tell you, this clone is
profitable, [music]
right? It's helping me with my book
launch of my new book, which is coming
down the pipeline soon. And it's
continually helping me with things like
going and systemizing more aspects on my
behalf so I can remove myself from my
business [music] and have a beautiful,
calm, peaceful empire that runs itself.
I'm not doing this stuff. I'm just
simply using the AI to create detailed
plans and then delegating that stuff to
the 10Xers on my team that can go and
[music] help implement it at a insane
level of quality. So the whole purpose
here, right, is that you need to become
the least important person in your
business. You have leverage from your
team, you have leverage from your
systems, [music] and now you have an
insane amount of leverage from your
clone. The beautiful thing here, right,
is that you can actually start
interlinking these elements as well,
right? So now that you've created a
clone of yourself, you guessed it,
[music] you're going to share that clone
as well with your team. So now your team
all has the leverage of all this
documentation, the instructions, and the
memory, and they're now able to go and
use these projects [music] for
themselves. So that now they each have
five clones of themselves. And so, you
know, if you have an 8 person team,
including yourself, that 8 person team
quite possibly is operating even more
powerfully [music] than a 40 person or
50 person team, your clone now can act
on your behalf and help defend your
time, which is your most valuable
resource as a founder. To make sure that
you use everything that we covered in
this video, be sure to go and download
the clone yourself checklist via the
link in description [music]
and go and apply this to your business
and life today. The founders that are
involved in this channel are the
founders that are focused on getting
ahead, right? finding those little
pieces of leverage so we can build a
vibrant business and more importantly an
amazing life. Thanks so much for
watching. If you enjoyed this video and
you want to find out how I leverage AI
even further for things like my content
and operations, go and check out this
next video. Check that out right now. Be
sure to like and subscribe.