Jay-Z went from the streets to building
a billion-dollar empire after he learned
this one thing. And it wasn't because he
started building all these companies, he
started building his own brand. You
know, there's this line that I love in
one of his songs. It's, you know, "I'm
not a businessman, I'm a business,
[music]
man." You know, there was this innate
understanding early on in his career
that it was him, his own brand, his own
voice, his message, his struggle, his
story. That was the ultimate moat. You
follow people, then you follow brands.
And Jay-Z understood this from day one.
So, he built massive distribution
through all of his albums, his story,
his music, his lyrics. And all of those
eyeballs were able to be funneled into
clothing, to music, to alcohol, and his
different ventures. And so, it was
switching from the logo at the top and
you hiding behind it to, you know, Jay-Z
being this example of, you know, the
person at the top feeding the portfolio
of brands.