This is the exact system behind my
profitable personal brand. It powers
eight figure revenue, millions of views,
and high ticket client flow. All built
from content. But here's the truth that
no one tells founders. The future of
entrepreneurship isn't ads, it's not
funnels, it's attention. And if you're
still treating content like a side
project, you're already invisible. The
founders I work with are doing at least
50k to 100k a month, but they are maxed
out. Every week feels like survival
mode. Content is inconsistent. Team ass
are piling up and you don't know what
your next hire should be. There's no
space to think and no system to scale.
In this video, I'm breaking down the
infrastructure behind my profitable
personal brand. Not as a creator, but as
a CEO. Every tool, every conversion
path, and exactly how to plug it into
your high ticket offer so you can build
a business set to scale for the future.
You'll have the exact system I used to
build what I call my personal media
company. A systemized, beautiful, and
sustainable personal brand that
generates leads while you sleep and
gives you complete control over your
time, freedom, and income. And the best
part, you're going to get the exact
blueprint. No theory, no fluff, no BS.
Just copy what I'm about to show you.
Let's get into it. My belief is really
that the future belongs to founder-ledd
brands. Founder-led brands simply means
that you're one part founder and then
you're one part creator. I love this
quote that your story is your strategy.
Okay? Posting isn't a growth strategy.
Alignment is. And what we want to make
sure that's happening is that the
content that you put out there really
aligns with what's going to actually
convert people to your business. Because
the key thing we want to do here, right,
is that as we're building the brand, we
want to be able to invest some of those
cash flows back into our systems, our
product, and our team so that we don't
have to be making that content for the
next 5 years and be on some content
hamster wheel. We want to be able to go
and hire amazing weapons around us, be
able to delegate core aspects of the
content creation process, things like
the posting of the content, the
creation, the newsletter, and be able to
find amazing people that can do those
things even better than we can. And when
you've done that, you haven't just built
a profitable personal brand, you've
built a personal media company. You
know, this is exactly what I've built
around myself with Founder OS, which is
the community that I've built to help
founders go and scale their businesses,
their brands, and be able to remove
themselves from operations. But it's not
just me, right? It's people like my good
friend Brian Johnson, you know, who is
building Blueprint, his own sort of
e-commerce company, or, you know, take
Alex Herozi, you know, had him on the
podcast last year building
acquisition.com, a more private equity
type company. All of us are deploying
this sort of system in our own unique
ways because this is the future of
entrepreneurship. This is how you unlock
an insane amount of leverage, which is
what you should be focused on as a
founder. The next piece I want to show
you here is the founder flywheel. We're
building a personal brand, not to become
famous, not to become some influencer or
some pure creator or just make AdSense
money in YouTube. That's not what this
is about. This is about building your
business, right? Building an empire
around you. You know, for me, a
transformative moment was I really
realized that as I was growing, I should
be more of an investor than
entrepreneur. And I started to have this
portfolio manager approach where it was
me at the top and then all of my
portfolio companies underneath me like
Herb and Founder OS. I figured, damn,
for the rest of my life, if I could go
and compound this asset of my personal
brand, I could feed Founder OS, feed
Herb with leads, and also feed any
potential business I make down the road
with leads as well. This is the power of
building an amazing personal brand is
that it's an appreciating asset that you
own for the rest of your life. that
personal brand we're going to use to
then feed our business brand then drive
insane word of mouth for our businesses.
You know, 50% of marketing is word of
mouth. And when you're actually going
and owning that conversation, that
creates an insane amount of leads to
your business. Now, from there, you're
getting more and more customers, which
is creating a referral flood. All of
these people are talking about you
online. People are talking about you
over conversations, over coffee drinks
because they're seeing your content on
their phone, on YouTube, in a
newsletter. You've essentially become
omniresent where you're constantly top
of mind and tip of tongue. When you do
this right, you become a category
champion, right? Someone that people
think as the dominant player in that
given space. Let's go and get into each
aspect of this a bit on the word of
mouth side, right? When you're building
an amazing founder brand, right, you're
going and you're delivering an amazing
product and you're generating tons of
reviews. The importance of reviews
cannot be overstated. People don't buy
what you're selling. They buy what
others want to buy. And so, as you're
going and building your personal brand,
you want to make sure that you're
racking up reviews on sites like
testimonial.to, to Trustpilot and any
other reviews that are, you know,
popular sources of reviews in your
industry. And so here you can see, you
know, people are constantly saying great
things about me, my team, and the
awesome work that we're doing at Founder
OS. When it comes to customers, now you
want to go and obviously make sure that
your content that you're putting out
there is converting those leads to
customers. When you're going and
actually putting out content, you want
to pay attention first off, what are
people asking you for, looking at the
comments, looking at different responses
you're getting from your newsletter. I
know that a lot of the founders that I
help, they're looking to get more of
their time back. And so, I'm going to go
and create content, whether it's here on
YouTube, Instagram, X, LinkedIn, Tik
Tok, you name it. We're going to create
content that gives people proven systems
to get more of their time back. Because
we see that as founders scale, their
real desire goes from, you know, just
making more money to actually getting
more time back, which for successful
founders is the real currency. We want
to see what content topics really
resonate with our audience. And you can
do this a lot of ways, right? One
amazing way is you can go to your best
customers, right? and go and ask them
via type form survey, you know, what is
it that you're trying to accomplish with
me? What's your biggest challenge this
year? What's keeping you up at 2 a.m. at
night? And if I you could wave a magic
wand. What would you want to have
accomplished over the next year? Then
you can go and create all of those
questions into a uh probably a Google
sheet or an Excel sheet. go and upload
that as a PDF to ChatGBT and then have
ChatGBT go and come up with a hundred
high converting content ideas for you
that go and serve your core market. This
is a major hack and something that can
help you go and unlock an insane amount
of high-converting content topics based
on actual research from your existing
customers that are already paying you.
You should have your CTAs, right? And
make sure you have the right CTAs across
your newsletter, your social media,
trainings, free resources, and your
VSSL. Here you can see, you know, on X,
I have, you know, CTAs driving people to
my workshops here in my newsletter,
right over here, you know, on Instagram.
So, we use a combination of me in the
DMs, but as well as we use many chat for
automations around core lead magnets.
Here you can see on YouTube as well
below my videos, I have two call to
actions. One says, you know, want to
scale your business and audience? Go
here. Which leads to a link to apply to
Founder OS. And then the second link
here says, want to learn proven systems
to grow your personal brand? Go here.
And that leads to my newsletter. We want
to make sure that across every piece of
content we put out there, we have CTAs
that lead to the newsletter. The reason
why is because you want to own your
audience. You don't want Zuck or Musk to
control you completely, right? You want
to make sure that you're driving people
from your rented audience across. social
media to your owned audience in your
newsletter and phone numbers and then
driving those people to either sales
calls or sales of your product or
service. This is the way. Okay. And so
as we move along here, right, again I
want to double click. This works in any
business guys. Okay? So if you're
e-commerce, health, startups, coaching,
courses, agencies, it doesn't matter.
The truth is you would benefit from
organic content. You would benefit from
having core calls to actions. You would
benefit from having a massive email list
and be able to put out content to an
engaged audience of people to not just
convert them but also convert their
friends. And so here you can see, you
know, this has worked for folks like
Mark Mloud. You know, former CFO of
Shopify, actually helped raise their
seed in series A. You know, Mark's gone
on to be a really successful private
equity and venture capitalist, and we
helped him double his coaching business.
Now, some people will see bigger growth,
some less. The point really that I'm
just trying to show you here is that
this works no matter what industry
you're in. Let me just kind of give you
a bit of how I see the old model versus
the founder flywheel. The old model, you
would just go and outsource all of your
marketing, right? But I see this all the
time. Founders have no idea how to
market their product, and then they're
just outsourcing what I believe is the
most important part to just some agency
that hardly even knows what they're
doing. and they just start blowing
money. First time founders focus on
tech. Second time founders focus on
distribution. And if you don't know how
to market your product, you are missing
out. The future here is that you
actually are using organic content in
building a founder brand that's built
around your values. You know, my values
are things like insanely simple, being
founder first, and you know, being
obsessed with quality. The old model
focus on products and ads. You know,
transactional sales funnels. The founder
is just hidden behind a brand. And I
know because I did that for years. You
know, the old way was that your team
executes and you just disappear. Random
content with inconsistent results, no
storytelling, so you really have no
differentiation in the market. And your
growth is just more volume and more ad
spend. I see this all the time where
founders are just spending so much money
on their ads and then they stop working
one month and then suddenly everything
tanks. It's pretty terrifying. So the
founder flywheel, right? It's a focus on
trust, a focus on actually controlling
your visibility, building evergreen
content, which then leads to high ticket
relationships. The cool thing is that
you can start to understand what are
your most valuable customers coming to
you for and then simply just make more
content that solves those people's
problems. The thing here is that the
founder is the face, right? You are the
competitive advantage and your systems
support you know your presence and you
have strategic content which is really a
compounding asset and the founder story.
Well, it's a product of your positioning
plus, you know, you being a magnet and
growth really comes down to more
leverage and more connection. That's
really the difference between the old
school model and where the future's
going. And if you're watching this, I
want to really remind you, you have the
opportunity to make the decision right
now to not go this old model and become
extinct and instead to choose to go
towards the founder flywheel. So the
common misconception that I see right is
people saying, "Oh, you know, personal
brands don't scale. They depend too much
on the individual." That's a load of
Personal brands certainly scale. I
mean, look all around you, right? When
you go and you look at the people you
follow on Instagram, do you follow
people or brands? If you look at your
ex, right? Are you following people or
brands? Look at your LinkedIn. Are you
following people or brands? YouTube,
people or brands? People follow people
then they follow brands. This is the way
trust goes. And we live in a day and age
where, you know, trust is at an all-time
low. And so, if you want to build trust
in your market, you need to be building
your own profitable personal brand. And
so, now I'm going to get into my
operating system. Okay, this system
changed everything for me inside of
Founder S. Honestly, I've tested the
system for the last 4 years on over
10,000 founders, and I've found
personally that it works better than
ads, SEO, and influencer marketing. None
of them have even come close. How this
works is as follows, and I'm going to
use my own personal media company as an
example. Here you can see on X, I'm
known there as the systems guy, and over
the last couple years amassed an
audience of over 370,000
followers. on X. My content strategy
really is based around compelling
copywriting, right? I write two threads
per week, generally on Wednesday and on
Saturday. I publish those at 8:07 a.m.
EST. Each of those have curiositydriven
CTAs, really compelling hooks, right,
that people can't help but scroll
through. And this works. This was one
week on X um driving over 31 million
organic views. to know this is a
powerful ass platform and has a ton of
opportunity and it's worth going and
growing on. So on LinkedIn I've become a
top voice there grown to over 819,000
followers. Pretty insane. LinkedIn is a
beast, right? Because people are
basically using this as like an online
professional network. You have some
really high quality people, especially
if you're targeting business owners. So
insane for professional leverage. What
you want to make sure you're doing is
optimizing your featured section that
you have curiosityd driving CTAs that
lead people to your newsletter. You want
to have long- form content. I post there
7 days a week, 8:04 a.m. EST. They're
long- form storytelling with an amazing
hook, long- form stories. Then I have a
CTA that drives people to my newsletter.
So I'm driving people from my rented
audience on LinkedIn to my newsletter
and then from my newsletter to Founder
OS for those that are interested. And if
you're interested in joining Found and
learning more, speak to me or my team,
you can go and check it out via the link
here in the description. When it comes
then to each post that you put out,
okay, you want to make sure that you go
and you have a compelling hook that you
have a highquality image ideally along
with it. And again, you're driving
everyone back to your newsletter. This
has driven me, you can see here in my
analytics, over the last 90 days, over
22 million organic impressions, right?
And over 372,000
followers. So again, this system works.
And the cool thing, guys, is that if
you're looking to understand, you know,
what I'm currently doing across any of
the platforms, you can literally just go
check me out and follow me on these
platforms because the awesome thing
about all my strategies, I open source
them. They're all public. And the best
way to learn from me is l just to follow
me on each of these platforms. And so
Instagram and Tik Tok, I use a very
similar strategy. It's a visual
storytelling strategy where I'm
converting people primarily from my bio
or from my DMs through to leads. It's
important that your brand's consistent.
You're using amazing stories and using
your Instagram stories to convert people
as well. That you have daily reels. So I
post two times a day, one reel and one
carousel. and then driving people
oftentimes through CTAs to my DMs where
many chat goes and works people gives
them a lead magnet that I'm giving and
then I have either me or my team hopping
in the DMs to chat with people there.
Here you can see all of my branding,
right? It's tight. It's consistent. It's
got that sort of freedom, aspirational
vibe, beautiful b-roll, showing, you
know, the places that I'm living in the
world, showing me in Bali, Tokyo, you
know, the Doommites, Sedona, Mexico
City. You know, I'm generally traveling
every few months. And I think, you know,
the content we put out there through the
B-roll, the imagery, the photography
captures that sort of vibe. As we move
on here, YouTube is honestly the
platform that I'm most excited by these
days. I think if you're a founder and
you're not making YouTube content,
honestly, you're missing out. YouTube is
a beast for driving leads. Okay? And the
reason why is when you think about all
the platforms, right? What you're trying
to do is build trust. And on YouTube,
because you're building so much long-
form content and there's a visual aspect
to it, you know, one video may be say 30
minutes long and that's 30 minutes of
trust building, right? So you can drive
leads fast because people feel confident
in you and then they convert. You want
to make sure that you have descriptions
that are optimized to drive people to
your newsletter as well as convert
people to your landing page of your
product. You want to play the long game.
Okay? When I started building on
YouTube, I told myself I wanted to make
a 100 videos that I was proud of. Okay?
Quality over quantity. Get your
thumbnails right because 90% of your
success on YouTube is your packaging.
It's your title plus your thumbnail. And
you want to make sure that you have an
insane value per second. I'm super
focused on just making sure that every
single second of any video I put out is
just mindblowingly valuable. And so I do
this through things like my systems
breakdowns with which you can go and
check out here and in this video as
well. I do it through my real systems
demos just like this video here where
I'm breaking down core systems that I
have in my business. things like my
content waterfall system, you know, my
content GPS, the most powerful systems.
I just give them away to you guys. And
so then we're also sharing things like
founder mentor sessions. You know, these
are actual sessions of me mentoring
founders inside of Founder OS, helping
them with their brand, their business,
scale up, all the kind of stuff that
founders get when they're working with
me, my seuite, my core team inside of
Founder OS. And so we do about one of
these videos every single month. and we
got a lot more coming to you. The last
format that we have are our vlogs,
right? Giving you guys a bit of behind
the scenes of my life, what it looks
like building the online empire that
I've built. And my goal there is just
it's kind of like more character
development just so you can get to know
me a little bit more behind the scenes.
Kind of has that more authentic vibe and
gives you guys a sense of, you know,
what I'm all about. So whether it's me,
you know, snowboarding in Japan or it's
me, you know, enjoying life in Bali, I
just like to open up so you guys can
kind of see what it's all about. The key
thing here, guys, is just getting
started. You know, when I got started,
right, I just was getting started dirty,
right? I was getting started in a messy
way. It was me off my iPhone in my
backyard in Porto Escandido, Mexico. I
was just filming whatever I felt like.
It felt good. It was fun. I finally was
just opening up and sharing myself
online. And it felt like years of
wanting to go and share. Finally, I was
fulfilling this mission, this inner
calling that I had. It felt so good. And
sure, it was scary. It was
uncomfortable. At times, I was
wondering, you know, what am I even
doing here? But oh my gosh, I'm so glad
I just stuck with it. And fast forward
just one year later, you know, we were
hitting views over 500,000 views per
video. We cleaned up the thumbnails
more. We got our aesthetic right. But
you can't expect to be perfect day one,
right? The thing you want to go and get
in the rhythm of initially is that done
is better than perfect because initially
you got to get that muscle going of
sharing content, sharing yourself. It's
going to feel a little weird initially.
If you're watching this and you're
going, "Damn, I need to get going on
this." Go and apply to Founder OS right
now. We can get on a call, learn more
about your brand, what you're really
trying to do with it, and we can help
get you started on this right away.
Don't miss out and don't let another day
go by that you just wish you got started
on this. Here we've just shown you the
rented audience side of things, right?
So this is all the social platforms.
Okay, this is kind of your, you know,
cold audience mechanism side of it. Let
me show you what that looks like on the
owned audience side of things. Okay,
this is your kind of content GPS
mechanism right here, which is where
you're going to convert consistent
content and then nurture people through
to revenue. Okay, so your owned
audience, right, is built through your
call to actions. Okay, you're going to
put CTAs in every piece of content you
have. I funnel both to my newsletter and
my main application form on my website.
On YouTube, we have CTAs at the bottom
of descriptions. You know, in X, we have
CTAs at the end of tweets. On, you know,
Instagram, we have them at the end of
carousels. And on LinkedIn, we have them
at the bottom of long form content and
in the images. We have this across all
of our content. And, you know, my
content, it ranges, right? The overall
content categories that I think about
are things around personal branding
systems, but getting founders more time
freedom and then helping founders
actually live vibrant lives. We're
talking about things like, you know,
helping you build your appreciating
asset around you, which is your personal
brand. I interview folks like Alex
Herozi, who's opened up around this,
saying that media is one of the most
valuable things he's ever built. I talk
about the importance of building on a
chief of staff to your business so you
can go and remove yourself from more of
your operation and have that first line
of defense in your business so that you
don't have to do everything yourself.
You know, I've helped Ali Abdal and I
help other big names, a lot of the
biggest guys you've probably seen across
YouTube, Instagram, they work with me uh
so that I can go and really help them
unlock a lot of value in their business.
You know, you'd be surprised about the
amount of creators and founders that
despite being successful, they aren't
happy, right? They're stuck in the
operation, stuck doing stuff that they
hate. And I get a lot of joy in helping
break down founders businesses,
understand what they're really trying to
do with it, and then relieve them from
the stuff that's just weighing them
down, and then unlock a level of
lightness, right? where they can go and
work on the stuff that they probably got
into business in the first place to go
and do and then be able to delegate that
stuff that just doesn't fire them up
anymore. When we're thinking about
content, we're generally making content
that's highly educational. It's got to
be authentic, right? And speak from my
actual experience. We're always trying
to make stuff that's just insanely
generous. We just give away everything.
Our systems, our playbooks, our
blueprints, it doesn't matter, right?
we're just giving it away because the
truth is if people want, you know, help,
which often times founders do, they'll
just join Founder OS, right? That's
where we roll up our sleeves and are
helping founders hands-on inside of
there, me, my team, so they can really
get the insane amount of correction they
need. Here you can see the different
things that my content leads to, right?
So, this is my newsletter, which is the
only newsletter you need to grow your
personal brand. Again, twice per week,
we're putting out value and just giving
insane amounts of value to founders.
Okay? all my short form educational
content. I have all of this across
LinkedIn, Instagram, and X, right? Just
honestly giving people the stuff that I
wish I had five years ago. The lessons,
the mentorship, the systems, the
playbooks. I'm just trying to help Matt
at 30 years old. I'm 35 now, and I'm
just constantly thinking, you know, what
would Matt have needed at 30? And that's
a lesson for you to think about, too. I
call that the five-year test, right?
going and giving value to yourself five
years ago when you're sharing online.
And then I have tons of long- form
educational content on YouTube. Things
like how to scale a high ticket offer.
You know, I'm giving away full courses
for free because again, my belief is
that the more I can help founders, the
more that we can build this movement,
build this amazing community of people
just like you that are changing lives
yourselves. And there's this amazing
ripple effect that I can have through
all this content. Then what you have
here, right, is you have all of this
content that start to drive you an
insane amount of leads. So those leads
that you're driving from your content
GPS come down. They're going to go to
something like an application page,
right? And so this application page is
where you generally would have a VSSL
and an application to then work with
you, especially if you're building like
a high ticket offer. The conversion hack
here is to keep things simple, right?
use a simple form on your website and
that's all you need, right? You can go
check out mine at founderwest.com/apply
and if you want to join Founder, just go
through the application process and
we'll get on a call. The next aspect is
then you go and you get on the call.
What we have is this pre-all page and
this page is super important because you
want to make sure that people are
showing up and they actually know what
you do, right? And so we have a pre-all
video that people watch that gives
people an understanding of exactly what
they can expect on the call and what
Founder OS is all about. I even have a
demo there showing what Founder OS is.
So people know what we're about. They
can see the community. They can see what
we give, the value we have, our Slack,
the access to my seuite, the support,
the 50 plus calls per month. They get it
right. So when they show up to the call,
boom, they're ready to go. Now, for the
call booking, we generally only open up
spaces for 48 hours so that when people
come in, they're hot. They're looking to
talk with someone and they get on a call
with ideally within like 12 hours if
possible. Okay. We get a lot of leads
though from organic content. So, it's
not always possible, but that's what we
aim for. Okay. Now, from there, you're
converting people to your magnetic
offer. Okay. Now, it's important that
you communicate clearly what the
customer will get. If you create
confusion, you will get people to close
their wallets. So, you need to make sure
that you're being crystal clear what you
do, what you don't do, who you're for,
who you're not for, so that you get
people through the pipeline as quick as
possible. You want to use testimonials,
case studies, right? People buy what
other people buy. Make sure you have an
insane amount of testimonials, like we
do across all of our Trust Pilot, our
testimonial.to, to the different case
studies we have, the different videos we
have of case studies across YouTube. You
know, we want to make sure there's an
insane amount of proof that we are
legit, right? And it's important you do
the same. And then you want to make sure
that you have all your benefits clearly
laid out. And so examples of additional
benefits that you know we have at
Founder West are things like we have a
onetoone onboarding call, we have
mentorship calls, tailored support,
detailed road maps we give founders, we
have founder experiences we run in
places like Bali, Sedona, Mexico City.
We give founders in-depth business
audits as well as social media audits to
go and look at their LinkedIn, their
YouTube, their Instagram to make sure
they're structuring things correctly.
And then we have access to our talent OS
where we give founders access to
copywriters, ghost writers, content
creators, video editors, newsletter
writers, executive assistants, chief of
staffs. Essentially, you don't need to
put up all your job postings and hope
you find amazing people. You can go and
tap into my network that I've built over
15 years of trial and error and honestly
trying a lot of people that didn't work
out, but I've found a select group of
legends that are amazing. And inside of
Founder us, we give people access to
that talent pool so that you can go and
build your personal media company. So
now people are finally becoming a
customer, right? And we need to make
sure that we leave an insane first
impression. So you need to nail your
onboarding. Most people are really just
looking for that sense of belonging. And
what you'll see is when people first
purchase from you, we all have it,
right? That tiny bit of buyer's remorse,
wondering, oh did I make the right
decision? So, it's your job as a
founder, right? As a founder brand, when
someone goes and purchases from you,
show them that how yes, you made the
right decision, right? And you can do
this by making them feel at home. Making
sure that they instantly are getting
connected to seven friends in the
community so they have that sense of
belonging, right? You want to go and
make sure that you have that immediate
time to value. Giving them exactly what
they paid for and doing it in a good
amount of time. They're like, "Bam, I'm
glad I made this decision." Right?
They're in the community, right? They're
getting on Zoom calls with you, your
team. you know, they know when the next
mastermind is, you know, just like, you
know, here's kind of clips from, you
know, our Sedona mastermind or LA
mastermind or Mexico City or Austin.
We're trying to make sure founders know
that they, you know, have a true partner
in crime with us. Our belief, our core
value at Founder OS is to dazzle
founders. And it's in everything we do.
Every email, every message, every video,
every piece of content, every tweet,
every newsletter, everything, every
interaction is a chance to show founders
that we are their best friend. We want
to go above and beyond to make sure that
they're taken care of. Now, a key piece
of this is when you think about
onboarding your clients or your
customers, you want to make sure that
you have an insanely optimized client
journey so that people have an
unbelievable experience with you. So the
key thing to do here then is to map out
the journey of your customer, the
different things that they can expect.
So for us, you know, we're going to
instantly help founders go and evolve
their offer, build their content GPS,
have different accountability calls.
We're going to help them with detailed
launch plans, set up their VSSL, help
them launch what they're doing, help
review sales calls if they need it.
Right? This is just an example of what a
founder journey could look like. You
know, each founder is different. So
we're customized based on, you know,
what the founder needs, right? There's
no oneizefits-all, but I want you to go
and think about what is your customer
journey. And if you don't have that
mapped out, this is your sign you should
probably do that. If there's one thing
you can get from this video, it's to get
in the details. Okay, so that is the
delivery mechanism. That's how you
create client happiness. And happy
clients lead to results. They lead to
referrals and they lead to positive
reviews and obviously amazing word of
mouth which is the flywheel we're about
to get into. So when you create not just
happiness but actual joy, right? This is
when you can then start preparing
clients to potentially be upsold and
make sure that you're not just closing
people initially, but you're actually
expanding your revenue, right? And
increasing your customer lifetime value
cuz people are so fired up. they love
you and they can see themselves working
with you not just for 6 months or a year
but they're subscribing to the next 10
20 years of working with you. So we're
gen generating testimonials, you know,
tons of testimonials every single month.
And you can go and see some of our
testimonials if you want at
found.com/precall.
You can see it on our trustpilot. You
can see it on our testimonial.to link.
You know, here's a quick clip from Ali
Abdullah as an example.
That is freaking phenomenal. I had a
long session with him when I visited
Dubai because my goal was to go get our
business from five million in annual
revenue to 10 million in annual revenue
through high ticket products and he just
did an amazing job of being able to be
like okay based on all that spiel that
you've given me here are like the eight
systems you need to build. I was like
I don't realize there were eight
systems we need to build. Thank you,
Matt, for the amazing co amazing
coaching session. And yeah, if you're
thinking of working with Matt, you
should do it.
Or, you know, here's another clip from
Michelle Garabido, a founder that
absolutely crushed it inside Founder OS.
When we started, our biggest challenge
was that we were charging too low for
our process. Now, with the help of my
success coach, we've been able to craft
a higher ticket offer, create it into an
agency of well, helping people go from A
through Z into moving abroad. And now
our biggest problem is we can't handle
the leads that are coming in. So our
goal now is to scale and hire. I'm
really surprised at like the operation
that he has and how it's not aggressive.
It's a very soulbased partnership that
he has grown here. And I love that Matt
and his team, everybody is just so
aligned, so soulful, but everyone is
creating monetary results as well. after
you've gone and made your customer super
super happy, okay? They're referring,
they're recommending you, they're
leaving testimonials, and now you can
drive upsells. And the key thing in many
businesses is when you drive upsells to
your back-end offer, you double your
revenue, and you typically more than
double your profit because there's no
additional customer acquisition cost.
When you figure out this piece of your
business, this is when you unlock an
insane amount of value. This is the
personal media company and this is the
personal brand operating system. All
right. And again, another common
misconception that I see is people
saying, you know, personal brands work
only if you already have millions of
followers. You know, it's impossible to
break in. That's just some
limiting beliefs. You know, I've helped
folks like Leon who in just one month
started generating more than his
previous year's salary. Now, this isn't
everyone. This is not typical, but just
an example of what's possible. You know,
he's sitting at over 15,000 followers on
LinkedIn. Or Zach, right, who in his
time in Founder OS saw an enormous
amount of growth, right? And he only had
6,000 followers on X. Everyone gets
different results. It depends on your
business, your effort, the systems you
install, and how seriously you take
this. Um, but it just it gives you a
sense of what's possible, right? Let's
move on to, you know, how I really turn
one long form idea into 20 strategic
pieces of content, right? Because what
we want to do here is maximize output,
minimize effort, and this is what I call
the content waterfall system. And so,
here's an example of a long- form video
I put out just a few weeks back, okay?
It was all around how to scale a high
ticket offer. and I gave away literally
everything that you need to go and scale
your own high ticket offer, no matter
what industry you're in. If you haven't
watched this, it's worth checking out.
This was a long- form YouTube video. And
then you can see I actually broke this
into LinkedIn posts into carousels,
okay? It became Instagram posts, a real,
multiple YouTube shorts, and multiple
Tik Tok videos. It became a newsletter
it that I put out on a Wednesday, and
then on a Saturday, I plugged it in that
newsletter as well. And it also became
three X threads. Okay? And so one video
over 20 other pieces of content. This is
leverage. And this is how you get off
the content hamster wheel, right? By
having a system that builds leverage
from one pillar piece of content
becoming multiple other pieces of
content. Now, I have tons of real world
examples to show you here, right? I'll
break it down so you can see the content
waterfall in real pieces of content.
Here is one of the most popular videos
on my channel. How to build a profitable
personal brand in just 30 days. In this
video, I share all the details on how
you go and build a profitable personal
brand really fast. Okay? And then on X,
LinkedIn, and Instagram, you can see a
bunch of different content I went and
shared all around building a profitable
personal brand, right? And so I was able
to take the course script from this
video, transcribe it, and then use it
into a bunch more piece of content that
those piece of content got like 10x more
views than that original video. So think
about all of that additional impressions
I'm getting, all those additional leads
I'm getting, all from the same piece of
content, right? And the cool thing is I
don't even need to make this stuff,
right? Nick, my chief distribution
officer, Yan, my designer, you know, my
team, Diego, my YouTube producer, they
go and help create all this other short
form content. It's not just that video,
though. It's this video. How I went from
15K to 8.7 million my story right on X,
LinkedIn, and Instagram. We went and
shared a bunch more content in short
tweets, in threads, and you can see
here, 207k views, you know, 1.9 million
views, 252,000 views. This stuff's
driving hundreds of other leads
downstream than the original pillar
piece of content I put out. You know,
another thousand likes, probably another
million views there. You know, same deal
on Instagram carousels. So, this just
works. Okay. And this is exactly what we
help founders with inside of founder us
immediately is really get this going.
You know, another example here is this
video I put out. I'm 35. If you're in
your 20s or 30s, watch this. Right? This
video already has like over 120,000
views. And then across X, LinkedIn and
Instagram, it garnered over 2 million
more views. Right? Branding principles.
I know at 35 I wish I'd known at 21.
This generated 100K on X. Same thing
with this post. It got 127K. And then
this one with 81K. And then across
LinkedIn, we're putting out posts around
it as well that are garnering a hell of
a lot of views and attention. And then
same thing on Instagram. You know, this
post here got over 6,000 likes,
around 400,000 views. Okay. So this is
content multiplied, right? One piece of
content over 20 other short form pieces
of content from it. So insanely
powerful. Now from there, right, you
have an offer stack across X, LinkedIn,
YouTube, Tik Tok, Instagram, the Mac Ray
Show, which is my podcast on Spotify and
Apple. You know, my Found US newsletter.
I have fiveday email courses that
convert people to my business. have
converted around $2.5 million in the
last 9 months alone. And then I have my
workshops which drive millions of
dollars a year as well. Okay, so to give
you a quick sense here, people join my
newsletter. Okay, and when they join my
newsletter, right, they come from social
media, they get on that email page, they
then join a fiveday email course, right?
And then have a fiveday FOMO series that
generally sells them harder on actually
joining Founder OS. Okay. And then from
there, they just get put into my regular
weekly newsletter sequence and may even
join a workshop um every month that I
run. So along the way, right, people
will go and apply at
founderwest.com/apply.
If they ever abandon the application
sequence, we have email automations that
go out there. Similarly, there's a book
a call page and a dynamic email CTA on
every single email I sent out so that
people get dynamic CTAs depending on
where they're at in the process. So,
some amazing automations that we have
hooked up. Um, our automations typically
are going on in HubSpot. Along the way,
people then will go and get driven to
the foundress.com/apply page. They
complete the application. When they
apply, they go to the found.com/preall
page. Um, and again, along the way,
they're getting different emails and
text messages from us so that they're
showing up to calls, they have context,
they're showing up on time, and if they
are the right fit, they're joining
Founder OS. From there, we use Panda Do
make sure that all agreements get
signed. They get an onboarding call. And
there we go. They're inside at the
community. They're getting the support
they need, and they're off and running.
Now, along the way building this
personal media company, you're probably
wondering, well, am I going to do this
all myself? Hell no. I'm traveling,
living my life, enjoying the moments,
and I have an amazing team that ensures
that I'm not in the weeds, right? You
don't need to scale chaos. You need a
system. Okay? And so your team doesn't
need to be this big. This is just how I
structure my team. Um, but you know, at
Founder West, we want to make sure that
founders have an insane amount of
support, right? So you're getting access
to the same people that have helped me
build my personal media company and I
unlock those people for you, my YouTube
producer, my brand strategist, my COO,
my CTO, my CFO, my creative team, right?
So that you can go and get your own
personal board of adviserss and unlock
it instantly when you join. It's people
like Shawn who's sold over $3.3 million
online. Yelina who's generated over $2.3
million revenue from newsletters in the
last 16 months. You know, Claire, my
sister, who's my chief of staff, who's,
you know, been with me for a long time
and before that was 10 years leading
marketing across some of the top brands
in the world. Or Niels who's generated
over $2 million from newsletters the
last year, right? And so we got Don,
Diego, Nick, my chief distribution
officer, you know, an absolutely
legendary team. So this is how to go and
build your own founder flywheel your
personal media company and an insanely
profitable personal brand. You know I
hope this has been helpful. If you want
access to this entire system so you can
just go copy it. You can go and check it
out via the link in the description.
Also know if you want my help, my team's
help, our proven systems and to join our
next founder retreat in Bali, you should
definitely apply to Founder OS via the
link in the description. You'll get on a
call with me or my team. We'll learn
more about what you're really trying to
accomplish with your brand and then see
if we can help you. So, go check that
out. Welcome to the founder freedom
movement. Like and subscribe and let's
win