Essentially, what the personal board
meeting is, this time every month you do
a reflection on how you did the previous
month and then go and chart out your
goals. So, I'm going to go through my
July personal board meeting right now.
So, starting off, we got our personal
board of advisors, right? These are the
people that are helping me go and scale
out my businesses, people across
strategy, tax, sales, AI, copywriting,
everything in between. My one big domino
every single day is to have an
unbeatable 4-hour deep work system that
produces at least one high-quality,
exceptional piece of high-leverage
content every single day. Content is the
fuel for all of my businesses. It drives
organic growth. It drives top talent to
what I'm doing. It helps propel the
movement. It drives conversions,
viewers, applications, all that good
stuff. We've been crushing it there with
consistent, exceptional content. And
then I kind of chart that out over 30
days, even over the year, of the one
thing I need to do that will make
everything else easier or unnecessary.