most Founders are really good at the
money game they know how to create
killer products build trust with their
audience and make sales they're too good
because what ends up happening is even
after they make millions of dollars they
set new benchmarks 10 million 50 million
100 million and the entire time they're
forgetting why they wanted to make that
money in the first place I've seen this
happen over and over again but here's
what you have to remember the next Peak
is always a false Summit because there's
always another level screw everyone
else's definition of success don't just
build a business that makes you money
build a business that gives you freedom
and lets you spend more time doing what
you love if you're an entrepreneur you
need to value your time and autonomy
just as much as you value money