And this is why I write everything out
by hand. First off,
writing by hand with a pen and paper, it
forces slowness, it forces clarity and
deeper thinking. Right? So, get out of
cloud code, get off your computer if
you're trying to solve a deeper problem,
right? You're trying to go and
systematize your business, you're trying
to go and structure your org chart, use
pen and paper, right? Get off the
computer. Second, I think typing just
leads to a lot of clichés, right?
Whereas when you're handwriting, right?
That's where your real unique stream of
consciousness out. I know for my best
content I've ever created across all
platforms, it all started with an idea
on pen and paper. You know, in fact, my
LinkedIn, which I've grown to 950,000
subscribers or followers there, all
organically, it started to really blow
up after I started sharing my
handwritten
drawings and attaching those to other
posts I had created, right? It blew up.
So, people really resonate, right? With
just pen and paper.
And I think from there, often times what
I'll go and do is take my notebook and
then add some of the core themes to a
Google Doc and then I'll just go for a
hike. And my best content typically
comes from voice memos then that have
come from some of these reflections that
then I turn into things like newsletters
and then I content waterfall that
newsletter into about 26 other pieces of
content for YouTube, X, LinkedIn,
Instagram, TikTok, all that good stuff.
So, keep a notebook on you daily. I like
a Muji notebook, a nice uh pen and uh
4 hours of founder flow daily, and
you're off to the races.