But essentially what I want to go over,
guys, is the Founder OS code. What is
this all about? Well, I've been
reflecting a lot on what principles have
made me successful over the last 18
years building multiple eight-figure
companies, the kind of stuff that I see
in the kind of mentors that I have. You
know, I was just on a call couple weeks
back with Ryan Kagg who's doing about
100 million a year, Neil Patel who's
doing about 70 million dollars profit a
year and has been for the last 20 years.
And these are the kind of principles if
I was to distill it into 10 things that
I seek to live by. And I'm not saying
it's always easy, but it's it's, you
know, the stuff that I kind of use as my
North Star. And it's the stuff that as a
community here inside of Founder OS, I
see like the most successful founders I
work with living by. So, I want to get
into these and I'm going to kind of
speak to some of these as well as I go
through them. So, number one here,
right, is really like moving like it's
going to work out because it is. Now,
what is this all about, right?
Essentially, first things first is like
when you're building any business,
right? Like it's hard, right? And
there's points that you definitely are
going to doubt yourself, right? I think
there's an aspect say when we're
building content, right? Are you someone
you know, I was just on a call with a
founder and she had mentioned that she
was making authentic content and then
some friends went to her and said, you
know, your content doesn't seem like
that solid anymore. Like it seems like
it needs some work. So, she stopped
making content. And then took a break
from it cuz she wanted to figure out how
to make authentic content and then would
come back to it. And that's an example
of exactly what not to do, right? I
think that the process of creating great
content, finding more authentic voice
and putting yourself out there is a
process of brick by brick, just like
carving out your voice, carving out your
style by just being confident, not
stopping, pushing daily, and over time
from the shipping, the iterating, you
then hone in on your core voice. It's
not from like sitting on the sidelines
or, you know, letting that voice, that
insecure side of your, you know, your
brain get to you and cause you to, yeah,
not show up, right? And so, this idea of
also as a founder like trusting your
judgment, right? I see it all the time
where, you know, founders are like, you
know, should I do this or this, you
know, A or B, C or D? And it's going to
be like, well, what do you want to do?
Like imagine a world where it would all
work out, right? That whatever direction
you went in, you would be really
successful. You know, what would you
want to do?
Right? And then go do that thing
confidently knowing that like if you put
your all into it, you put the energy
into it, you stay consistent with it,
you will be successful. The second piece
here is like keeping it insanely simple.
Now,
this is a thing that I live by in my
life and in my business and it's a
continual practice.
Okay? We live in a day and age where
some [\h__\h] gurus will try to convince
you that, you know, you need to go and
have all these like crazy complex
funnels and these crazy complex
businesses. And my belief is often times
like it can be really damn simple,
right? Pick one platform. Pick one
offer, right? Pick, you know, one lead
magnet even to start with and just stay
consistent with your content and just
push people through that core flow,
right? When I first started Foundr us,
it was Foundr us program, one offer on
Twitter and got that to $50,000 a month,
right? It wasn't like some complex
system in place that I needed to get up
and going, right? I didn't have 10
offers, I wasn't on five platforms. I
started just super simple and scaled up
from there.
Now, you know, I think that all
businesses, mine included, they default
to entropy, they default to complexity.
So, it's also a continual practice to
get it back down to simplicity. You
know, over the last 6 months, I've
implemented a bunch of skills, a bunch
of cloud code elements, dashboards,
different automations in my business,
and cut around $670,000
of head count. Right? In the name of
keeping things insanely simple. Cuz the
last thing I want to be running is a
complex company with 28 humans. My dream
is really to have 12 core humans on my
team, a 70% margin, and a business that
I love, working with people that I love,
and be able to have a true freedom,
right? Controlling the four Ws in life,
working where I want to work, with who,
on what I want to work, wherever the
hell in the world I want to work.
The next asset here, guys, is doing the
work. Okay? The only place that success
comes before work is in the dictionary.
Okay? And the reality is is that it's
the work that matters, right? And so,
all the systems, all the, you know,
different automations, or, you know,
different lessons we go over, these
things are all for nothing if there's
not a real degree of work going in on
the background there, right? And so,
you know, for me, the core, like,
basically domino that I can do every
single day, right? That's going to help
me go and get to where I'm looking to
go, is 4 hours of founder flow. In fact,
that's where I'm at right now, right? In
my cafe right here. In my same spot
every day. This is where I post up every
single morning. It's about 8:00 a.m.
right now in Bali. And this is my
routine. Got my iced Americano. And, you
know, my notebook and checklist of the
things
I want to get done today.
You know? And here I am, just posted up.
And I'm just going to go do the work.
Right? And this is, you know, rain or
shine, you know, not feeling good,
feeling good, feeling a little down,
feeling great. And, you know, I tweaked
my neck the other day doing some Muay
Thai.
Doesn't really matter. I'm going to be
here showing up, doing the work, right?
And I think that the same goes for you
guys, right? It's like that just kind of
chop wood, carry water mentality, right?
Is a key aspect to like the compounding,
right? Especially early on,
right? Like early on when you're
building something, you need to just get
that momentum going. You need to kind of
like get that snowball rolling down the
other side of the hill until it turns
into an avalanche. And the way to do
that is just to put in the reps. Next
aspect here is like protecting your
nervous system,
okay? Inevitably, you know, it's like
removing [\h__\h] people around you,
removing [\h__\h] influences around you,
removing things that are [\h__\h] up your
sleep, right? Like taking care of your
body, of your mind, of your soul, right?
Because
if you, you know, strong founders build
strong businesses, right? And if you are
letting things around you, whether it's
like
late night television or a coffee that
doesn't allow you to sleep because
you're drinking coffee at 5:00 p.m. or
it's a [\h__\h] person on your team that's
really just aggravating you, or it's
brutal customers that despite making
some money from them, they're just like
wrecking your week and like ruining your
happiness. You got to really, like at
the end of the day, I was talking to a
founder
just yesterday. He had just crossed a
new milestone making about 500 grand a
month,
but he was unable to sleep all weekend
because some of his marketing he was
putting out there, he was worried that
it was uncompliant, right? And that he
could get in trouble with the government
because of what he was putting out
there. And I called him up because I
could tell he was really stressed. So, I
called him out of the blue on Monday,
like actually 2 days ago, and I was
like, "Hey, look, what's going on?" He
told me what was going on and
I was just like, "Dude, like, what is it
even worth whether you're making a
million a month, 3 million a month, 10
million a month, if like this is how you
feel?"
Right? Like the money's not going to
make you more happy, right? We got to
solve this marketing thing because at
the end of the day, real wealth isn't
like what your bank account shows,
right? It's peace, right? And peace to
me, one of the best metrics for just
peace is quality sleep at night, right?
And so, really optimizing a business for
like, you know,
not growth, not just cash flow, right?
But like, what is it that you actually
going to make you happy that you can be
proud of yourself and look at yourself
in the mirror at the end of the day when
maybe you're brushing your teeth and go
like, you know what? I'm really proud of
what I'm building here. Um versus
something that like you're just like
that's killing you. Next aspect here,
guys, is staying focused and staying
lean.
I think that the kind of community that
we're building here at Founder Alliance,
right? We're not a bunch of people
looking to go and build some [\h__\h]
unicorn, right? You know, we're not
looking to build 10,000-person
companies, right? We are here to build
like small, mighty, beautiful bootstrap
businesses, right? So, you have to
understand that with that like head
count is some vanity metric, right? What
we're here is like you should first be
asking, you know, is your offer super
dialed in? Do you have a platform that
you're really focused on right now? Do
you have content going out regularly on
that platform? Week by week are you
finding more of your voice? Are you
finding more of your own magnetism? Are
you staying focused on the core say
three things that you need to work on
right now, right? So,
on my list as an example, right?
Today, you know, I'm doing a bunch more
of a scrub of like some stuff that we're
doing right now to go and be able to
sell more by chat inside of our funnel,
right? So, we're going to be moving a
lot of our sales to say DMs and reducing
the reliance on a sales team. It's a new
experiment that we're doing. And I have
been making this kind of like offer doc
which we'll use to send folks so that
they can understand the details of
Velocity and a bunch of new updates that
we have coming which I'm really excited
to talk to you guys about over the
coming weeks.
But essentially, like this document,
right? Is a big important thing. And
I've probably gone and scrubbed through
this document maybe 20 times at this
point. And today I'm going with my team
and scrubbing through it three more
times, literally is line by line.
Right? Because it's such an important
thing I need to get done. Because then
it feeds all the different aspects of my
business. And so that's just an example
of me just staying radically focused on
one four thing, not getting distracted
with 20 other things I could be doing,
and just not leaving today, not stopping
until, you know, me, my COO, and my
chief of staff have scrubbed every
single line of that offer doc and feel
good about it. Now, next thing here is
building only what you can build. So,
you know, I've been doing a lot of, you
know, reflection these days as an
example to show you guys how I think
about stuff. I actually have a coach
that you may not know, but I I pay
$20,000 a month to a coach named Dan,
and we've been working a lot on creating
magnetic content. So, even me, after
doing content for, you know, it's been I
mean, technically it's been like 18
years. I probably published across my
business brands and personal brand
around 37,000 pieces of content, not
missed a single day in 18 years. Even
I'm still like a student of the game.
Right? And trying to like, oh, how could
I make my content more magnetic? You
know, what's the one sentence that maybe
I'm trying to get out there, you know? I
think one of the big things is like,
your business should increase your
aliveness, not consume it. What's the
identity maybe I'm trying to really
capture in my content? It's that people
should be an architect, not an operator.
You know, what are some of the pillars
of our my point of view, right? It's
like, calm is the highest form of scale.
Fear is the ultimate competitive moat.
What are some of like the different arcs
that I want to be talking about, you
know? It's things like, screw the church
of hustle, make art not content, and
importance of owning the four Ws in
life. And so I'm constantly like
revisiting my content strategy,
revisiting what we're putting out there,
because I know that, you know, when I go
and say look at the different platforms,
right? And say I go to our Instagram
right now, right? I know that when I
invest in and of thinking about magnetic
content, thinking the details, right?
It's what ends up, you know, producing
content like this post that we put out
just 4 days ago, right? This thing got
like, you know, it drove over 2,000
newsletter sign-ups to Founder OS,
242,000 views, it had like over 23,000
interactions on it. Right? And
my belief right now, guys, and I've
spoken about this a bit on some of our
calls is that
we're in this season right now where
content has swung back to that people
want to see raw, real rants, the triple
Rs. And what that means is making
content that's really you, right? Like
just your edges, what I would call like
your wabi-sabi, right? That Japanese
principle that's like the beauty in your
imperfection. So, hence like I'm really
trying to find like just like even go
deeper on like what's my authentic
voice, what am I all about, what are the
things that make me different, and then
vocalize these things, and also just
kind of find that voice by just writing
and pushing things and getting it out
there. Not by sitting on the sidelines
or thinking about it too long. You know,
once I maybe made a document like this
document that I just showed you, right?
Then just like experimenting with this
[\h__\h] Just getting it out there and
seeing what stuff resonates. Some stuff
resonates like this, some stuff maybe
doesn't like this one, and either way
though the benefit is I learn, right?
Versus the people that sit on the
sidelines and just hope that someday
their content gets magnetic. The next
piece here then is making
art, not content, right? Which is
similar to what I just was going over.
Right? So, the key thing here, right? Is
guys, like sometimes you guys will ask
me like, you know, Matt, should I make
content like this? Should I make content
like that? I talk to you guys a lot
about the different formats that I think
are best. The other thing too is like
you've got to put stuff out that you
think is unique to you. Like what do you
want to make out there in the world? How
do you want to show up? The same way
that you wouldn't ask me how to get
dressed in the morning, right? Is like
the same thing like you have your own
style. You have a fashion sense that
speaks to how you like to show up. So
yes, on Instagram as an example, you
should have stories, you should have
carousels, you should do short-form
videos, right? But inevitably like how
you want to show up there is a mix of
maybe being inspired by what I'm doing,
but mixing it then with like what's your
authentic way of showing up. The last
few here that I'll just kind of breeze
through, right? Are like having high
standards, right? My belief is that you
get what you tolerate in life. Whether
it's a hire, whether it's a customer,
having a standard for the kind of people
you want to be around and not accepting
scrubs, stragglers, pedestrians, and
tourists. Really making sure that you
hold a high freaking bar. I know the
kind of folks that I want to work with,
right? I want to work with founders that
have high agency, are self-directed,
right? Are willing to put in the work,
that live by this code. I do not want to
work with folks that are looking for a
magic pill, are looking for me to do the
work for them. I know that in terms of
the team I work with, right? I want to
work with a team of people that are
independent, high agency, live by the
Foundress values, right? Obsess around
quality, keep things insanely simple,
dazzle founders. I don't want to work
with people that bring me problems, that
bring me more work to do, right? That
don't make my life easy.
Which lead me to kind of like inevitably
here, guys, I think it's all about like
we want to have businesses that actually
enhance our joy, right? If we're not
laughing daily because like we're
enjoying who we're working with and what
we're working on, something's freaking
wrong. And I think that the last thing
I'll say here is that, you know, we talk
about things like your content
infrastructure, right? And a key part of
that as an example is being like lead
magnets. When I think about all my
content, the number one kind of
principle that's allowing it to blow up,
right? That's allowed me to build my own
brand of 3 and 1/2 million people over
the last few years is because I'm being
generous in this content. We find out
different systems, we learn different
things internally, and then we're
sharing that [\h__\h] on YouTube, we're
putting that in a lead magnet, we're
making a tool for founders. You know,
just this past week as an example, we
went and launched a new tool that you
may have seen called Henzo, right? Henzo
is the product of how I've been going
and creating my authentic LinkedIn
content the last 12 months helped grow
it to over 900k organic folks and we
just put all that into a core tool that
now founders can go use themselves,
right? So whether it's tools like Henzo,
it's the updates that we make to the
curriculum, it's the investments we make
in the community, it's new team members
we bring on board, like it's all in the
name of trying to be as insanely
generous as possible. And it's a
continual practice, right? Of how we
can, you know, what new curriculum do we
need to add? What new systems do we need
to get founders? We're launching a new
software inside of Founders Velocity
soon called Founder Clip, which, you
know, is also going to be kind of like
taking things to the next level in terms
of like different skills and such to
help you guys deploy these systems
faster. So
these are just some principles that I
think are important to live by as a
community that I see separate kind of
the real ones in the founders that are
super successful and build amazing
businesses and lives versus the ones
that, you know, don't embody these and
find themselves spinning their tires or
wishing someone would just save them or
looking to be rescued and I think are
important as you're like scaling up your
guys' businesses. So leave it there.
This is all kind of in the name of like
architecting freedom and embodying this
kind of architect identity as well where
we're building lives that are
intentional and businesses that help
serve us versus running businesses that
just run us into the ground.