there's one lesson I learned that I
think is super relevant to how I
approach business today versus how I
used to approach it you know when I
first started building businesses
everything felt like a rush send that
email to get a customer to deliver I was
impatient and I approached everything
like a Sprint now what I learned over
the years is that slow is smooth and
smooth is
[Music]
fast you know often times you just slow
down you take a breath you breathe now
you realize that everything's going to
work out for you and there's no reason
to you know be so fearful be so rushed
feel like you're behind you know all
that stuff just leads you to forget
about the process to lose track and to
not enjoy the journey