If you're running every part of your
business, you're not the CEO, you're the
bottleneck. Let's fix that. You can't
scale if you're stuck in the weeds of
your business. What's the reason why
most founders can't step away? They
haven't built a business, they've built
a job. Here's how I remove myself from
operations without all the
chaos. Step one, document everything and
make Loom videos. Write down how you do
every single thing in your business and
then record yourself actually doing that
thing. Your brain needs to stop being
the operating system. Step two, delegate
to weapons. Hire people who are better
at execution than you are and then give
them the playbooks that you've made and
then let them just run with it. Core
hires are your tech lead, chief of
staff, executive assistant, closer,
setter, and customer success. Step
three, build deep systems. Automate
repetitive tasks with tools like a
sauna, notion, and Zapier. And then have
your systems run on autopilot so
everything in your business is nice and
calm. So the secret sauce, let go.
Freedom comes when you stop
micromanaging. Now, your business isn't
just a job. It's an engine. One that
grows while you just live your life,
travel the world, and have things like
time freedom, location freedom, and
financial freedom. That is the ultimate
goal.