you can do a lot of things wrong in your
business and still succeed if you get
the foundation right think about the
business owners you look up to they
don't do everything perfectly but they
do the important stuff really really
well specifically these three PS product
they are obsessed with the quality of
their product they are wildly
competitive and they want it to be the
single best offer available to their
target market personality they are
authentic their personality is not
perfect it's flawed and that's what
makes them human this builds trust and
Authority with their customers profit
ability they focus on results they
understand good business is good math
and if something isn't profitable it
needs closer examination