If you want millions of followers on
social media, you have to be boring. I
built a personal brand with over 3
million followers and a business doing
over $700,000 a month using a content
system most people overlook because it's
not flashy, but it's repeatable. [music]
In this video, I'm going to walk you
through the structure of that system.
Not the trends, not tactics, the
underlying framework that makes boring
content compound. But, first you need to
understand this. The best-selling books
from 100 years ago are still the best
sellers today and there's a reason for
that.
>> [music]
>> The reality is people chase the newest
trend, the latest vlog format, sexy
lifestyle content, but there's proven
stuff that works and [music] always
works. Think and Grow Rich, How to Win
Friends and Influence People, these
books are still best sellers decades
later. They're not creative or original,
they're fundamental and there's a
pattern to what actually works with
humans. So, yeah, there's this pull to
be the newest thing, [music] but if
you're actually trying to build
something that lasts, certain stuff, the
boring stuff, it just [music] works and
that's what I'm about to show you. So,
let's start with the biggest myth you
need to kill, the entertainment myth.
When I first started building my
business, I could have made lifestyle
content, you know, me just traveling,
working from beaches, you know, that
whole digital nomad aesthetic, but
here's what I noticed. That content gets
likes, it gets views, but it doesn't
[music] get customers. The content that
consistently drove revenue, systems
breakdowns, operations workflows, and
delegation frameworks, the boring stuff.
This content, [music] it's not
necessarily sexy and it wasn't going to
win any creative awards, but people kept
telling me, "I shared this with my whole
team in Slack." That's when I realized
[music]
views don't equal cash, value equals
cash. Here's what most people miss.
Virality is just noise, right? It's
dopamine. You're not building a
business, you're building an addiction
to notifications. The Affluence Paradox
is real. Chasing millions of views
attracts beginners with no money.
Targeting a specific affluent audience
with high value content results in fewer
views, but significantly more cash. The
content that makes money is about
solving real problems, not getting
applause. Before I post anything, I ask
myself one question. Would someone pay
$10,000 for this information? If the
answer is no, it's entertainment, not
growth. So, before you post anything, I
want you to ask yourself the same thing.
Focus on high value content, systems,
operations, frameworks, the stuff that
actually helps people build and scale.
Part two, proof-led content. When I
looked at the content that made me the
most money, it wasn't the polished
stuff. It was things like my whiteboard
sessions, ones that I've done here with
Blake Rocha or this one with Ali Abdaal.
These are me live, unscripted, helping
actual people solve real problems in
real time. I'm not reading from some
script, right? I'm riffing off the top,
pulling from 15 years of experience
helping real founders. People watch me
help Ali Abdaal build a $5 million
funnel or sit down with other business
owners and actually coach them through
their challenges, mapping out their
business, the math behind it, their
offer stack, and going deep into the
what and how to actually solve their
real problems. Real systems, no fluff,
no BS, just helping these founders go
and scale up their business. It's these
real, authentic, raw moments, right,
that show people what it's actually like
to just jam with me. And I think you,
the viewer, get kind of pulled into that
room. And these are the videos that
we've actually gotten some of the best,
you know, feedback from. And so, for you
in your own space, right, it's really
thinking about what's that proof content
that you can make? That's proof. That's
legitimacy. That's holy this guy
actually does this stuff. You know,
content without proof is kind of just a
joke. I always say to people, details
create cash." And if you can show people
the detailed ways that you help folks,
it's going to become undeniable for them
to go and trust you and actually go and
buy your thing. Right? General advice
like, "Build your personal brand." It's
weak and it's forgettable. Instead,
here's how I grew my Twitter from zero
to 214,000 followers in 12 months using
three specific content formats. Well,
that's proof. So, when you show proof,
right? You collapse skepticism. People
go from, "Is this real?" to "I need to
work with this person." So, stop
teaching theory and start showing
receipts. Every piece of content should
include specific numbers, time frames,
and before-and-after case studies. If
you're making a claim, back it up with
evidence. Screenshots, testimonials,
live demos, show people you've actually
done the thing you're teaching. The
strategy I use, be generous to a fault.
Give away so much value that people
think, you know, "Is this actually free?
I can't imagine what's inside his paid
stuff if this is the free stuff." If you
go and you hold stuff back and become
some gatekeeper, you're just like 99% of
other people going and creating
online, right? That's like the default
state. And so, many of you, right? Are
watching this channel because you want
to stand out. You want to win, right?
You want to be the dominant brand in
your category. And so, when everyone
else in your space is just giving people
little nuggets of trust, you can flood
them with trust by just being insanely
generous. So, this one principle and
this one rule with all of my content is
what's allowed me to go and scale an
audience to 3 and 1/2 million people
over just the last few years. But even
if your content isn't polished, you need
to have a structure to your content. And
that's where the third part comes in,
mastering repeatable formats. The reason
I was able to grow to 200,000
subscribers on YouTube, 900,000
followers on Instagram, and 800,000
followers on LinkedIn is that I don't
wake up every day wondering, "What
should I make?" I know exactly which
format fits the idea that I want to
communicate. So, let me show you how we
approach formats on YouTube. So, here we
kind of have three main formats and then
one bonus one, okay, that we use just
from time to time. So, the first one are
systems breakdowns, okay? This is where
we go really deep into the how, the
what, and the specific steps that go in
to a specific repeatable process in a
founder-led business, okay? And so, here
you can see an example of this system
turns my content into profit in just
seven steps. [music] And so, we're
breaking down the exact system to go and
build profitable content. Now, the next
format are real systems demos, okay?
This is when I'm showing behind the
scenes, sharing my screen, very similar
to what I'm doing right now, and showing
exactly what goes into a specific system
within my companies. And then, the next
format are founder mentor sessions,
okay? These are whiteboard breakdowns
where I'm helping folks either inside of
Founder OS or other large creators like
Blake Rocha or folks like Ali Abdaal and
helping them go and actually build their
business live by breaking down a
specific challenge they're having, and
then
basically using the systems I've built
over the last couple decades to go and
help them overcome that challenge. Now,
here and there we also do vlogs. These
are few and far between because
honestly, vlogs, first off, take a lot
of work, and second [music] off, are
kind of entertaining. So, we just do
them here and there, and I see it as
just an awesome opportunity to flex some
of our editing chops, some of the
creativity, and give people a little bit
of behind the scenes as to what I'm all
about and the kind of businesses I'm
building. And so,
>> [music]
>> in your space, you want to figure out
what are your repeatable formats, right?
Constraints breed creativity, and your
formats will make you well-known in your
space. When you master a format, you can
control every variable, the lighting,
the sound, the pacing, the delivery, and
your energy that goes into it, right? Is
able to be sustainable, right? So,
you're not reinventing the wheel every
time. So, pick three content formats max
and rotate them forever. If one gets
boring, substitute one other one in,
right? But don't constantly change
everything. Change the input, not the
structure. Same format, different topic.
This is how you build a sustainable
content operation that doesn't burn you
out. piece here that I don't think
people talk about enough as well is that
50% of marketing is going to be word of
mouth. And if you have a format that you
become known for, it's really easy for
people to go and tell their friends what
you do. But if you're changing your
format too much, it's kind of hard for
people to pinpoint exactly what you do.
And thereby, it's really hard for them
to tell their friends. [music] And so,
you miss out on so much marketing
leverage. Next up is the consistency
cadence. The reality is posting when
you're inspired is a mistake. You want
to treat your content like an index
fund, [music] not day you get hits, you
feel alive in the moment. But index
funds, they compound slowly, they're
reliable, and they actually make you
rich. The same is true with content.
Boring content
that posts consistently compounds,
whereas viral spikes, they don't
compound. They just spike and then they
die. But when you show up every day with
valuable systematic content, the
algorithms will reward you, and your
audience trusts you, and you become
known as that person online. So, if you
want to make creating consistent content
a lot easier, you can follow a simple
formula here. The content that sells
follows the SELL formula, which stands
for stories, educate, and lists. So, on
the story side of things, right?
Storytelling is the number one vehicle
for going and conveying a certain lesson
to people, right? People don't recognize
stuff if you're just hammering them with
facts, right? But on the other side, if
you tell a compelling personal story
where you learn to give an lesson or a
lesson in history that is relatable to
what it is you're trying to get across,
this is what's going to make your ideas
so much more sticky. Now, E stands for
educate, right? And on this piece,
>> [music]
>> where I see a lot of people screw up is
that they're just trying to make
entertaining right? But
entertaining content doesn't sell. And
so we're trying to educate people, and I
think the number one format there are
how-to or how I videos, okay? Every
rule's meant to be broken, but you know,
these are a common format that I've used
across every different platform that I'm
on that consistently are not just the
best performers, but when we look at the
profit per content, which is the number
one metric that I use when I'm building
any media company, those formats are
consistently the most profitable. Now, L
stands for list, okay? And
>> [music]
>> the truth is that anything is a list.
Now, I don't just simply mean listicles
like BuzzFeed, right? Cuz that does
not sell. What I mean [music] is that
any piece of content that you're going
and putting out there should follow some
clear value structure. [music] And what
happens is is when you have some sort of
structure, maybe it's a bunch of systems
or lists or hacks or tools or whatever
it may be, right? When you structure it
in a list, it's easy for people to
follow, right? It may be step-by-step or
here's five systems or here is a, you
know, flow and a process from start to
finish, right? You just want it to be a
logical flow, so it's not all over the
place and it's more sequential, so it's
easy for people to understand and then
go and implement. Part five, favor
distribution over creativity. I see
people create one amazing piece of
content and then just move on. They made
it, they posted it, they got some
engagement, and onto the next thing. But
that's leaving so much on the table. For
every core idea or long-form post, you
should ask, "How many places can this
one idea live?" If the answer is fewer
than five, you're not distributing,
you're just creating endlessly. I take
stuff that crushes it on LinkedIn, and
then I adapt that for YouTube, X, and my
newsletter. The same insight gets
packaged differently for each platform,
so it's native to that platform, but
that core idea now is multiplied. Now,
this isn't laziness, right? This is how
you actually scale reach without
creating 10x more content. So, look at
your content and use the rule of five.
For every piece of content, it should
exist in at least five places: YouTube,
X, LinkedIn, Instagram, TikTok, your
newsletter. If it doesn't, you're
leaving reach and money on the table.
This is usually where founders realize
something uncomfortable. Their content
looks like it's working, but the
business isn't moving. That's exactly
why I built a short content ROI reality
check. It helps you score how your
content system actually behaves by
default, and then pinpoint the one place
where ROI is leaking. If this is hitting
close to home, do that right after this
video. Now, when it comes to going and
ideating content, all right? We've
established the fact that views don't
equal cash, and that we're looking to
make stuff that has strong signal. But,
you're likely also wondering, "Matt,
what's the way to do that?" That's where
the buyer survey comes in. You likely
have a ton of amazing customers that you
serve with your business, okay? So, what
do you think is the best way to go and
come up with highly profitable content
ideas? Well, you guessed it, those
actual customers. So, we are going to go
and do is use Typeform or Google Forms
to go and send a three-question survey
to them. "What's your biggest goal this
year? What's keeping you up at night?
And if you were to wave a magic wand,
what would you most want my help with?"
You then can go take the answers those
questions and go and create content that
goes and solves those problems and gets
them towards their goals. And if you
want further ideation around this, you
can go and upload the whole CSV file
that you download from Typeform, upload
that to ChatGPT, and ask it to go and
come up with 100 banger content ideas
based on that survey information you
just got from those dream customers.
This is going to help you go and
increase what I believe is the most
important metric in any personal media
company, cash flow per piece of content
or profit per content, right? Because
when you're going and stacking up every
piece of content and increasing the
profit from each piece of content, well,
you're building a hell of an
anti-fragile business. A business that
doesn't matter whether in a recession or
something crazy happened in your space,
that content just keeps [music] printing
cash. Part six, build the
infrastructure. Content can attract
millions of people, but without
infrastructure, you're just collecting
vanity metrics. When someone discovers
you, what happens next? So, let's get
into the details here, right? Cuz it's
the details that will help you create
cash. So, over here,
what's going to happen, right? Is from a
given piece of content on social media,
you're going to drive people to some
[music] sort of email landing page. It
could be to your newsletter or to a more
specific email course. I have a bunch of
email courses. As an example, a personal
brand email course and an AI clone
yourself course, okay? So, people would
come to that landing page and from
there, they get put into a five-day
educational email course and then a
four-day FOMO series. So, the five-day
email course is educating them and
giving them the value on the thing that
they signed up for. The FOMO series,
though, is part of the magic here. Let
me just [music] show you a sneak peek.
We're essentially FOMO email number one
is probably going to start describing
the transformation that takes part when
people go and join your [music] thing,
okay? From there, email two is going to
probably get into things like
some financial outcomes or it may get
into what they can expect or how it all
works, okay?
>> [music]
>> Email three then is going to talk about
the price of it, right? And give people
more sense on, you know, how they should
think about it, the ROI of it, all that
good stuff, okay? And then email four is
likely going to get into more challenges
that you see a lot of people come to you
for and that you help people with. And
then the different benefits of what you
deliver. Now, these are just some
examples, right? But what you're doing
in those four emails now is driving
people more directly to the sale. So,
you just have this running on autopilot
and what happens is your infrastructure
is essentially a salesperson that never
sleeps. So, [music]
we have them then going through the FOMO
series and at any point in time clicking
a dynamic CTA that exists in those
emails and driving them to a book a call
or directly to purchase and monetizing
those people. So, it's this
infrastructure [music]
that makes all the difference as you're
building your founder-led brand. No
infrastructure, shitty business. Robust
infrastructure and you've got an
antifragile empire. And so, on the kind
of detailed aspect here, too, the things
I want you to think about are number
one, set up an email landing page. Two,
get your educational email course five
emails going. Three, get a four-day FOMO
series written up and then just launch
that, right? Like anything in life, it's
all about iterating, but those three
things get you about 80% of the way
there. Audit your infrastructure right
now. What happens when someone follows
you? What's the next step? If the answer
is nothing, well, you're leaving a ton
of money on the table. All right, so
here's the path forward. Step one, use
the content ROI reality check linked in
the description below to go and score
your content system and identify the
single constraint stopping it from
compounding to that next level. Step
two, if you want help going and fixing
that constraint, you can go and bring
that completed exercise into a short
call with my team, which is also gone
and linked below. That's where we map
the systems that turn attention into
revenue without any guesswork. And if
you want hands-on help building this
infrastructure, not some theory, but
inside your actual business, that's
exactly what we do inside of Founder OS.
This is where serious founders design
content systems that compound alongside
other operators who are done [music]
guessing. If you want to see how this
actually gets built behind the scenes,
well, there's a link below. We'll look
at your situation and decide together
what makes sense. So, thanks so much for
watching. If you're interested in going
and building a business that runs
without you, go and check out this next
video and I'll see you over there and
let's win together.