All right, here are three things you
will not regret spending your money on.
First things first,
spontaneous trips into nature.
You know, taking some time
to go
and really ponder life, right? Whether
that's journaling,
going for a hike,
new exploration with friends, you'll
never regret it. Second thing is
investing in your own learning. You
know, whenever I go and I examine my own
finances and how my own net worth has
scaled over the years,
the one thing that's obvious is that as
I invest more in coaches, mentors,
courses, masterminds,
uh just, you know, books, it could be
anything, right? Like anything that's
like a learning experience in the stock
of Matt, um has always been my best
investment and has far outperformed any
stock investment I've ever made.
So, invest in yourself.
The third thing
is an investment in relationships.
You know, I think so many people can be
so transactional
and, you know, you're always trying to
figure out how you get something out of
someone. And the most beautiful thing in
life is, you know, being able to do life
with amazing people, friends, partners,
family, making sure that you're
investing in those people around you uh
because at the end of the day,
you know, you're not bringing
your money to the grave. It's going to
be those relationships and experiences,
I think, that stick with you.