I've been sitting with something for the
last few weeks that I think that every
founder needs to see. After reading this
article, my mind was honestly shattered.
This is one of the craziest articles and
predictions that I've seen. It's a
research piece about what happens when
intelligence becomes abundant. Really,
I'm seeing some trends that I think are
important that people don't ignore. I'm
going to be bringing together 20
unbelievable founders in Bali for 2 days
to go and figure this all out together.
We're going to be going and automating
different aspects of our businesses. I'm
going to be going and showing you guys
how I'm currently leveraging Claude code
to go and really just compete over the
next 2 years. So, you can check it out
via the link in the description. So,
this isn't a prediction, right? This is
a thought experiment, but there are a
few core pieces of this that got me to
drastically shift the way I was thinking
and acting within my businesses. I'm
going to go and walk you through some of
those changes so that you can learn and
make some changes before it's too late.
This article is all around the 2028
global intelligence crisis, okay? Now,
the general vibe here, okay, is that
they're acting like they've written in
June 2028 after AI has candidly just
ripped across the economy. This is
probably going to scare you in certain
parts, but my intention here is not some
doom and gloom vibe. If we can
future-proof our businesses now, I think
we set ourselves up to actually benefit
from this enormous amount of change
versus finding ourselves just reacting
and missing this incredible wave that is
just getting started. So, imagine again,
we're in June 30th, 2028. Let's first
talk about the consequences of abundant
intelligence. What it gets into is that
initially, you know, in 2026 when AI was
taking over, you have Claude code,
ChatGPT ripping it. There were all of
these layoffs going on across companies.
And those initial layoffs, right, the
economy actually responded to incredibly
positively. Companies' margins started
to expand, right? They were beating
their earnings, right? Stocks are
rallying, and they're setting
record-setting profits. Less humans,
more margins of these companies, and
they're being rewarded with the highest
stock prices they've ever had. We're
seeing this play out right now.
Salesforce just laid off people. Block
and Jack Dorsey just laid off 8,500
workers, right? Oracle just laid off
like 20,000 people. Facebook's about to
go lay off another 15,000 people, and
Zuckerberg says he's going to build his
own mini CEO AI inside of Meta.
Companies right now are being rewarded
for laying off their white-collar
knowledge workers. In every AI in this
thing, right? AI is exceeding
expectations, right? The market was AI.
The only problem was that the economy
was not. And so, it gets into this whole
scenario, right? And starts to kind of
outline this negative feedback loop
that's going on with no natural break,
something that we've never seen before
in the history of humanity. Human
intelligence is abundant. AI is
everywhere, and white-collar workers
now, for the first time really ever, are
seeing their earnings power structurally
impaired. You can now start to see the
economy starting to break, right?
Because white-collar workers make up
around 15% of the economy, but they make
up around 60%
of the discretionary spend. Well, what
do you think's going to happen here,
right? You start laying off all of these
knowledge workers, right? Because AI is
replacing all these jobs, and suddenly
now all of those folks that have just
been laid off can no longer afford to
spend on discretionary goods. It starts
to then shift from good news to bad
news. This is what founders are telling
me on calls right now. And so, this is
what I want you to listen for. It says
here, in late 2025, agentic coding tools
took a step function jump in capability.
Now, I know I'm using Claude code for
about 6 hours a day right now,
automating everything across my
business. By the end of April, 97% of my
portfolio businesses will be completely
automated. We have been going in
slimming down overall headcount inside
of my companies because we simply just
don't need as many people because of the
power of these tools. People are using
Claude code, Codex, right? I'm sure,
hopefully, if you're watching this,
you're already onto these tools. And
it's not that they're using it
perfectly, but even out the gate, right?
You can start to see people already
asking, "Well, what if I just built this
stuff myself?" I know recently, as an
example, you know, I don't necessarily
need some fancy designer to go and
design things like LinkedIn
infographics. I can simply go and
leverage some skills I've built inside
of Claude code to go and create my own
beautiful infographics based on the
thousands of data points that I have
from my best infographics ever on
LinkedIn that have helped me grow on
that platform to over 900,000 people. We
live in a crazy day and age. And this is
all the stuff that we actually build for
founders inside of Founder OS. Done for
you funnels, done for you content
strategy, done for you content formats
to help you stand out. And if you're
looking for some help implementing some
of these done-for-you things that I've
just mentioned, your landing page, your
content, your funnel, go and check out
the link below and book a brand strategy
call with my team. We'd love to start
building it for you. And so, this is an
interesting part of it, right? It says,
"The salesperson had expected to run the
same playbook as last year. A 5% annual
price increase, the standard your team
depends on us pitch." The procurement
manager told them that they'd been in
conversation with OpenAI about their
forward deployed engineers, use AI tools
to replace the vendor entirely. They
renewed at a 30% discount. "That was a
good outcome," he said. The long tail of
SaaS, like monday.com, Zapier, and
Asana, had it much worse. Leverage is
shifting now. For me, as an example,
across different projects I've been
building, this is a project I've been
using to go and automate all different
parts of our business. Everything from
the end-to-end functionality, from going
from content to a call with my team, and
going and automating things like
short-form clips, or automating things
as simple as really just different
project management. Cuz I'm actually
able to go and load this up and have a
calendar, have a Kanban board, right?
And essentially, go and make sure my
entire business is organized. But I
don't need Asana to do this, right? I
can just go and build this myself. And
this is the crazy day and age we live
in, that it just took me 2 seconds to go
and whip up my own calendar, Kanban
board, to organize this whole project. I
didn't need to rely on Asana. So there
goes a $900 a month software bill. Same
with it, Notion, have cut that out,
being able to snip one at a time
different software bills and roles
around the edges of my company that we
just no longer need. Like that
infographics designer I had just
mentioned. And when you think about this
as a founder, I think it's a time to go
and think about all of the different
workflows across your whole company.
What are the different workflows you
have across sales, customer success,
marketing, across delivery, in your
finance or operations area of your
company. I've talked a lot about the
importance of systemizing your business,
right? Anything that you do twice should
be systemized. Nowadays, anything that
you end up doing, you know, two, three
times, right? Should also be a skill
inside a Claude code, a workflow that's
now automated, so you can reduce your
load and work on much bigger things.
Software, though, in the replacement of
SaaS companies, right? Is just the
opening act, according to this. What
ends up happening is far greater. It's
predicting that by early 2027, LLM usage
is the default. I know that this is how
I've already been living for about a
year or so now. All of the team were on
a Claude code enterprise account. We
have our own MCP, right? That's running
with all of the around 75 skills that we
have there for a lot of the core things
we're doing. You know, our meetings are
all recorded inside of Fathom. The
follow-ups are automated and sent out by
Claude code and Slack. Anything that can
be done by a machine is done by a
machine so that the people in my company
can be ultimately creative, right? And
work on the most amazing things possible
that only they can do and know that the
mundane BS, right? The, you know, data
entry, the follow-ups, the
accountability, the project management,
that whole layer is just automated. I
know for some of you this may sound a
little crazy, but whether it was the
internet back in the day or mobile
phones, those flip phones, they all
seemed a little crazy at first, but
eventually humans adopt these things
fast and you want to be early to the
adoption versus one of those people
that's too late. This paragraph really
changed how I think about my own
business, okay? It says, "Over the past
50 years, the US economy built a giant
rent extraction layer on top of human
limitations. Things take time, patience
runs out, brand familiarity substitutes
for diligence, and most people are
willing to accept a bad price to avoid
more clicks. Trillions of dollars of
enterprise value dependent on those
constraints persisting. But now, agents
remove the friction." I was recently
watching an interview with Jensen Huang
and about hour 20 into this interview,
Chamath Palihapitiya, uh the gentleman
who grew Facebook from a million to a
billion users, asked Jensen Huang the
how do startups compete in this new
paradigm?
>> In your mind, what do you think for
these companies that are building at
that application layer? What's their
moat? Like, how do they differentiate
themselves?
>> Deep specialization. I believe that um
these models that they're they're going
to have general general models that are
connected into the software company's
agentic system. Right. Many of those
models are cloud models and proprietary
models, but many of those models are
specialized sub agents that they've
trained on their own
>> Right. So, the call to arms for you for
entrepreneurs is look, know your
vertical.
>> That's right.
>> Know it as deep and as better than
everybody else.
>> That's right.
>> And then wait for these tools because
they're catching up to you and now you
can imbue it with your knowledge.
>> That's right. And the sooner you connect
your agent the sooner you connect your
agent with customers
that flywheel is going to cause your
agent to get
>> It very It very much is an inversion of
what we do today because today we build
a piece of software and we say, what
generalizes? And then let's try to sell
it as broadly as possible and then sell
the customization around it.
>> And we trap
>> fact In fact, with exactly right. We We
create a horizontal, but notice there
all these GSIs and all of these
consultants who are specialists who then
take your horizontal platform and
specializes it into
>> Exactly.
>> And that's arguably a five or six time
bigger industry is the customization.
>> It is. Absolutely.
>> Yeah, the whole very much is.
>> That's right. So, I think that these
platform companies have an opportunity
to become that specialist, to become
that vertical.
>> Now, why is that? Well, this article is
talking about the intelligence crisis.
And what actually needs to happen from
my perspective is that all companies
need to become intelligence companies.
And what does that mean? Well, you need
to make sure that you go and you have an
agent inside of your company that your
customers are able to interface with and
over the next few months that agent is
able to learn, ship code, improve your
business without any human intervention.
Or maybe just a human in the loop to
double check what it's pushing is
correct. I was recently talking to a
founder and you know, he's got a
dashboard that helps different parishes
across America. And in that dashboard,
customers are able to go and leave
feedback and an agent actually goes and
takes that feedback based on you know,
different bugs that may be happening in
the dashboard and is able to then just
go and take that and automatically go
and fix things. This is an example of an
intelligence layer. And my belief is
that every company will just become an
intelligence company. And it's not just
me, right? Jack Dorsey, the CEO, one of
the only that's ever run two
multi-billion-dollar public companies at
the same time when he was running
Twitter and Square at the same time. He
recently laid off 8,000 people, saw the
stock price jump as this article
outlines, and he's recently gone and
built almost like a mini AGI, right? A
mini AI company inside of Block that he
believes is basically going to go and
just eat Block over time. Many CEOs are
waking up to this, really understanding
that over the next decade things are
about to change drastically. Companies
as we know it will not be as the same as
they are today. And one of the reasons
is is because, you know, agents are
going to become more and more capable
and our own need for all these humans,
all these processes, right? Is going to
change a lot. Why do you need a whole
customer service department when a few
agents can go and handle all that? It
says, "We had overestimated the value of
human relationships. Turns out a lot of
what people called relationships was
simply friction with a friendly face." I
talk to, you know, coaches, consultants,
agencies all the time, right? And often
times when I go and look at their
organic content funnels as an example,
they've got all this unnecessary
friction. They make you hop on the call
with someone to then hop on a call with
someone else. And they'll lay out a
12-step process basically to go from
initial interest, right? All the way
through to a closed deal. When you look
at it, some long process like that often
times could just be one or two clicks,
maximum three stages. We live in a time
already where an agent can go and
understand your entire product menu of
your business, and based on
inbound demand you have for your product
or service, an agent could be going and
curating the best product or service for
that individual based on a few
qualification questions. You don't need
a human to do that. And this article
goes on that, you know, this is really
the destruction for that intermediation
layer, right? So many of these layers
that we have that we think are all about
relationships, honestly, just become
unnecessary friction. It goes on to say
technological innovation destroys jobs
and then creates even more. This was the
most popular and convincing counter
argument at the time. It was popular and
convincing because it had been right for
two centuries. You know, there's two
kinds of ways of looking at this, which
is that, you know, AI goes and replaces
jobs and there aren't new jobs being
created per se. AI is just really eating
that whole workforce. On the other side,
the other school of thought, which is
kind of the John Maynard Keynes school
of thought, is that, you know, this AI
will lead to more innovation, right? And
then people will go and be more
productive and find new frontiers of
things to build and there actually be
growing job creation. And really both of
these paths, none of us know what's
going to happen. Whether it's one or the
other, I really don't care. Anytime that
this level of destruction is going on,
I'm going to go and take a page out of
Charlie Munger's book, right? Charlie
Munger is the legend that was Warren
Buffett's uh business partner for over
50 years. He has this concept called
inversion. And instead of asking how
could your business succeed, you want to
ask how could my business fail? In this
example, what this article's outlining
is one way your business could fail,
which is that you're not prepared for
this, right? You're not adopting AI,
you're not thinking about how will your
business compete in 2028 when
information and intelligence are
abundant. How does your coaching
business succeed? How is your consulting
business set up for success? How's your
software business exist anymore when a
competitor can go and duplicate your
entire infrastructure in 10 minutes?
These are the kind of questions that I
think entrepreneurs need to be asking
themselves yesterday. Because whether or
not everything here comes true, that's
not what matters, right? I think on some
given time scale, this is what things
are going to start looking like. The
question is like, how quick are we going
to be to adopt this stuff? And as
entrepreneurs, how antifragile are we
going to build our businesses?
If you thought any of this has been
scary so far, I want to talk about the
part of this that scares me the most.
So, what it gets into, right? Is that
there's no natural break, right? On the
cycle. Meaning the pressure, right? Just
keeps on increasing. There's this new
kind of recession that starts to kick in
that we've never seen before in
humanity. So, in a traditional
recession, right? It's self-correcting.
You'll see different slowdowns and
things like construction. So, we lower
the interest rates and then new
construction and recovery come back. It
starts to correct itself, right? And
this is typically how a central bank
will go and fix um some sort of
recession. With this AI-driven, you
know, economic feedback loop that they
outline in this article, things are
different. And this is the one part of
the article that I can totally see
coming true. So, basically, AI
investment, okay? Goes and increases and
AI capability keeps on improving. And
we're seeing that already today.
Companies then need fewer workers. They
start laying off white-collar workers.
Those layoffs keep on happening more and
more and those displaced workers now are
spending less. And they have no job. And
even the ones that do have jobs, they're
bracing for impact here. So, the economy
is weakening. Cuz like I mentioned,
right? White-collar workers, while
they're about 15% of jobs, they make up
60% of the discretionary spend. This is
where it gets interesting. Because
there's less discretionary spend going
on, the companies, right, start to feel
it even harder because there's less
people spending money with them. In an
effort to go and increase their profit
margins, they cut more people and invest
further in AI. And AI investment
increases, right, as AI capability
increases, and more workers are laid
off, which keeps this economic feedback
loop going, right? And there's no
natural break here. More and more of
these businesses, they're too late to go
adopt these technologies, too late to go
and become agentic, right, to become
AI-native. They just get left behind.
And I think that's probably even a lot
of you watching this, right? When I talk
to a lot of founders out there, I'm
like, "Okay, so are you on Cloud Code?
Have you gone and been able to automate
a job or two of the last month?" They're
like,
"I have no idea what Cloud Code is." I'm
like, "All right. How do you think about
workflows in your company? Do you have
those documented? And which ones are you
thinking about going and automating
first?" "Oh, you know, my company's a
mess right now, man." All right. I think
there's a point in time, right, where
it's not just a nice-to-have to have
your company systematized and automated,
right? I think now we live in a point
where the market is dictating to every
founder that you get on this now. Our
really why I'm even making this video is
because I really just want you guys to
go and check out this article. And I
want you to go and just prepare your
mindset for what if 2028 looked even
remotely like this, right? Are you
prepared right now? Do you feel like,
you know, you have your systematized
empire built? Do you feel like you have
automations across your company for
things that you don't need humans for?
Do you feel like your team is being
AI-native? Are you as a founder going
and helping your team adopt these
skills? This is one of the parts that I
think really is important for you guys
to listen up. Here it gets into the
intelligence premium unwind. You know,
forever, human intelligence, right, has
been scarce, but now in this new AI age,
it's everywhere. And so then the
question is, what is defensible in your
business? First things first, right?
Your distribution, right? When you have
a personal brand, when you have a
content machine, when you have a social
media sheet machine around you, you're
able to go and own your distribution.
And that data is more important than
ever, right? Because as, you know,
people are able to go and replicate your
website, replicate your product,
replicate your service, they can't
replicate you, right? They can't
replicate your distribution. It's that
distribution, right? That trust, that
brand that is insanely defensible, which
is really the reason why you need to be
going and building your brand now.
Here's the thing, you're not reading
this in June of 2028, right? You're
likely reading this and seeing this
right here, it's around April 2026. The
S&P right now ripping, the negative
feedback loops here have not begun. And
so what I'm encouraging you guys to do
if you're watching this is to go and
disrupt your own business now. What
aspects can you automate now? What roles
in your company are no longer needed?
What are things you could do to
simplify, to delete, and then to
automate? We're still early, but the
window is gradually shrinking. And the
only question I think that matters for
founders right now is, how are you going
to go and compete in 2028? All right, so
I'm going to be bringing together 20
unbelievable founders in Bali for 2 days
to go and figure this all out together.
We're going to be going and automating
different aspects of our businesses. I'm
going to be going and showing you guys
how I'm currently leveraging Claude code
to automate different roles, to go and
increase my margin, to go and drive more
leads to my business, and to go and
really just compete over the next 2
years. For those of you that are
interested, definitely go and check it
out via the link in the description. I'd
love to see you there. It's an awesome
chance for you to go and join me and
actually going and building formidable
anti-fragile brand that is AI native and
set to compete in 2028. I hope you
enjoyed this and let's go take some
action and I'll see you in the next one.