These are the two metrics that I've
learned predict every churn.
First things first is your time to first
win. You know, when you go and onboard
someone, are you helping them go and get
to that core promise of why they joined
as fast as possible? The longer that
takes, right, the more that risk of
buyers' remorse goes, and before you
know it, they're like, "What the heck?
Why did I even join this thing thing?"
The next thing is understanding that
retention is a psychology game, right?
People want to feel like you care.
They want to feel like you genuinely
want to see them win. And so, an example
of this, right, is if someone has joined
and maybe they're looking to go and have
you grow their brand for them, right?
They not only maybe want you to help
them grow their followers, say grow the
amount of cash flow that they're going
to generate from their audience, but
they also want to feel that, you know,
if they have a question or maybe they
got stuck on something even outside of
that sort of area, that you're there to
support them. Maybe they had a team
member left and you helped go above and
beyond to make an intro for them. Or
maybe they're having some issues on the
finance side and you hopped on an
impromptu call just to build that trust
and show them that you care, right?
It's those little things um that go the
extra mile and make people feel like you
generally give a [\h__\h] And so, make sure
you're getting people to their first win
in 14 days. And if customer goes quiet,
check in with them.