Stop posting like a creator. Start
operating like a content CEO. See, the
difference here is that a creator has a
mindset where they need to be powering
and be the engine of everything [music]
they do. When you think about building
something over 6 months or 6 years, you
need to become the content CEO of a
personal media company. Having the right
team in place, the right systems so you
can remove yourself from all the stuff
that someone else could do [music] and
build something that is going to allow
you to have longevity. Creators burn out
at an insanely high degree and CEOs do
as well. The reason that both these
people generally quit is because it just
becomes too much. And so you need to get
ahead of this reality, right? By making
sure you have the right people, [music]
systems, and leverage in place so that
you know the pressure doesn't all come
down to