This is how I'm going and automating 97%
of my business. And I'm just going to
show you behind the scenes, raw,
unfiltered here, how I'm thinking. So,
first things first here, this dashboard
here is my project automate. Inside of
this, I've gone and listed some of the
core insights and strategic plans that
we have across my company. Things like,
you know, going and upgrading our
closing team or implementing more MCP
skills to go and upgrade different
aspects of what we're doing, or
integrating more tools instead of lead
magnets, which is something I'm using
Claude Code and AI for right now.
Overall, in my company, we are shrinking
the amount of folks that we have working
in the company. We kind of are not
hiring much more, and then we are
defaulting to automation. So, what we
have here, right, is this like, first
things first, I can understand from one
dashboard my strategy, right? And myself
and my leadership team are all aligned
around this. From there, I can see all
of the weekly actions I need to go and
take. Things like, you know, setting up
Claude Code for different AI tools we
have internally, right? Going and moving
our company to a SDK, more of a shared
knowledge brain across our company,
being able to then also have an
orchestrator which, across core
processes and workflows that we have,
versus even having to have someone
pressing an automation and moving, say,
you know, a landing page to an offer
page on the website to then making email
sequences. Simply having an orchestrator
that we can speak to the orchestrator,
which is an AI or an automation, and
that orchestrator inside of Claude Code
then knows, okay, if we're spinning up
an offer, go and make the landing page,
go and make the offer, go and make the
email sequences. And then what happens
is the humans on the team become more
editors that are being queued up
different tasks that the orchestrator is
saying that we need to get done. So,
inside of this dashboard as an example,
I can see the weekly actions. I can see
the Q2 OKRs across my entire business,
right? So that we're all aligned, we
know what's going on. You know, this is
where the project management piece comes
in. And so, there's both a calendar and
a Kanban board for what we need to get
done. And so, to show you this example,
right? As we go and start, you know,
completing different tasks, we move
those into progress. As those get
complete, we move them into completion.
And thereby, we're not just setting
these goals or just using AI to then use
AI and getting lost in AI projects,
right? Which I think I think what most
companies are doing, right? There's some
studies that most companies AI
investment leads to zero return. And so,
what we're trying to do is make sure
when we actually are building AI, we're
either reducing costs and or we're
increasing profits, right? That's the
only reason to use it. So, we've got the
calendar that shows up. We've also got a
sprint checklist outlining every single
piece then of Founder OS in this area,
being like the automation and tech side,
and what are the different tasks that
need to get going. So, getting managed
agents in the API going, auto-generating
different deliverables that we have to
go and get for folks, um making sure
that, you know, our authorization flows
are all built out. You can also see like
different aspects that we're currently
automating. You know, we currently are
testing out something called Alberto,
which will completely go and automate
all of the DM flows and outreach inside
of the company. On the DM side, it will
handle things like LinkedIn, like X. On
the cold email side, it can handle
outreach using things like Instantly,
Apollo to go and find folks that have
gone and commented, say on my LinkedIn
posts where I have 900 thousand
followers over there, and then go and
send personalized messages in my voice
to those folks. And if they're
interested, getting them set up on a
call with one of my portfolio companies,
depending on which one is right for
them. What I like to think about is not
just the growth of the revenue that AI
is going to contribute to my companies,
but also what automations can I put in
place that will replace roles in my
company. So, that if humans are on the
team, they're doing stuff that only
humans can do. We don't have people
doing stuff that robots can do. Too many
people are just vibe coding a bunch of
They build all this stuff, but
it's not usable. No one on their team
knows what's going on. And so, I like to
think when I'm building this, my process
typically is that I'll take a given
leader on the team, say Nick, who's my
chief marketing officer, okay? And when
Nick and I were making this marketing
machine, I went and met up with Nick. We
got a nice boardroom, big whiteboard,
and Nick and I came prepared going and
modeling out the whole marketing
apparatus, right? What is every piece of
it? What are all the documents and
Google Sheets that we have across the
whole company? And I wanted to make a
rule for ourselves, right? Basically,
let's eliminate all of these
spreadsheets, and let's build a
centralized place where we can
understand our metrics, and where we can
understand what people are working on,
and hold them accountable to certain due
dates. And so, similar pattern here. I
have the core initiatives across all
things across the marketing squad. As
we, you know, check off different
aspects of this, right? You can see the
progress bar for that core initiative
gets
implemented. The cool thing is is that
along with this, right? As we go and
work on these things, we can start to
also understand which stuff is getting
behind, right? Too many founders are
just letting open loops populate
everywhere in their company. They have
these products that are started, but
then are never finished, right? And you
think when you stack that up, you are
just looking at the potential of your
business disintegrate, right? Day by
day. From there, it's also easier for
the manager, in this case Nick, to see
every single person on the team, right?
Understand what they're responsible for
this week, this month, this quarter, all
with due dates, all how they're tracking
as well, right? And this just allows us
to really sync this all. Now, in
addition to this, this data is also
coming from platforms like Asana, which
is where we organize our whole content
calendar. And here you can see it just
synced, meaning that we go and plug in
the API from Asana to this dashboard, so
it's getting a live feed about every 3
minutes of anything that's changed over
there, right? So, that's the core
project management for our content
calendar is Asana, and this is the kind
of core strategy dashboard for the
marketing machine. Cool thing is, you
can see every single platform here, as
well, LinkedIn, Instagram for me, X, and
again, this is all synchronized with
our Asana, which is pretty insane. All
of our workshops are organized in here.
You can also see the different cohorts
we have going on. By the way, if you're
interested in joining me over six
sessions, two weeks, to go and build a
beautiful cash-flowing business, I'd
recommend you go and check out the link
below to cashflow machine, uh which will
be six live sessions with me, uh and
it's going to be a lot of fun. This is
actually something that I was working on
with Claire, my sister, just yesterday.
So, this is still a work in development,
but after a 5-hour whiteboard session,
which you can see the whole whiteboard
over here, we came to the conclusion
that there were some gaps operationally,
right? And And I say this just to be
real, even with my businesses, right?
There's constant constraints, constant
problems. It's kind of just how it goes,
right? As you're scaling and growing,
not staying status quo, you're
inevitably embarking in new areas that
bring new challenges, right? So, I'm
challenged all the time in my daily
life, and honestly, I like it that way.
So, inside of this, right? Same sort of
pattern, right? It's got the command
center,
it's then got our whole level 10
meeting, and essentially, this is an
operating system by which you go and you
plan out your year, then your quarter.
So, this is the ops machine, right? And
this is what allows us to go and deliver
on an exceptional founder experience,
because this then feeds into things like
our founder success machine, which helps
us go and make sure that the onboarding
inside of FounderUs is seamless. You
know, when you go and you join
FounderUs, within 24 hours, you're on a
call with us, and we're doing a brand
deep dive call with you. Understanding
your offer, what your current status is
on your marketing and positioning, where
the gaps may exist, what you're really
looking to do with your brand here in
2026, and we start to map out a
customized roadmap for you based on
exactly what stuff we need to go and
build for you right now. Now, by day
seven, we've gone and built your entire
brand positioning for you. And for by
day 21, we built your content GPS. You
have all your platform strategy for
every single platform that you're on. We
then built out your email sequences,
your newsletter, and 14 pieces of
content across every platform that
you're on, which then leads to the next
30 days. We're building things like your
content machine and all of your content
monetization as well. So, we're making
sure that you have things like your
newsletter, your offer stack, your lead
magnets, so that we're going and taking
people from your audience across social
to your owned audience in your
newsletter, and then driving people to
your product or service or whatever it
may be that you're selling. And so, that
is how I'm going and automating 97% of
my business. This is going to be an
ongoing journey. I'll keep you in the
loop. There's a lot of exciting stuff
coming.
I'm not done yet. Every single day
chipping away on this stuff, and I'm
going to keep you abreast as the newest
tech that I see, so you can have more
peace, profit, and purpose in life, and
have a ton of fun along the way. So, if
you enjoyed this video, you would love
Founder OS Velocity. If you're
interested, go and check out this video
over here where I go deep into how I
help you build a social media machine
and actually do it for you. So, you can
go check out that video. Be sure to go
and like and subscribe, and I'll see you
in the next one.