making money online isn't rocket science
you can make millions of dollars every
year with these three simple side
hustles and anyone can do them one
affiliate marketing sell other people's
products to your audience if you're not
doing this consistently then you're
missing out on a lot of income potential
two providing Services anyone can
provide services the more in demand your
skill set and the better your expertise
the more money you can charge
copywriting design advertising learn a
skill and monetize it three consult
Consulting and coaching are amazing
people are literally paying you for the
knowledge you've accumulated and you can
charge a premium for that you just need
knowledge that's in demand