I recently built a new AI content system
that I've been using to basically
interrogate me about you know the most
vulnerable pieces of my life
and ask me questions every week
and surface those
to become
content ideas.
Damn, is this thing
ever powerful.
I think that we're
in this new content season right now.
Almost like a new fashion season.
I call it the triple R's. Raw,
real,
rant.
You know, people
people
don't want that polished version of you.
They want the real you.
Right? The first question most people
ask is, you know, "Was this thing made
by AI?"
So, you want to
you know, just tell your real story,
flaws and all. You know, that wabi-sabi.
The beauty is in your imperfection.