What matters the most is your velocity
of learning. Are you putting things out
there, getting feedback, incorporating
that feedback into what you're doing,
learning from it, doubling down,
stopping the things that aren't working,
and keeping that cycle going? It's the
fastest learners that are the biggest
winners. Perfectionism feels safe
because it just keeps you in control.
But it's actually procrastination in
disguise. Don't let yourself wait to the
perfect moment to launch something
because truthfully, it's never going to
come. Start to program your mind to
think perfectionism is procrastination
and that done is better than