Two years ago, I went on a journey to
build my personal brand across the four
most competitive social channels in the
world with a goal of 10xing my audience
size and doubling my revenue. Here's
what I wanted to prove. If I started to
increase these numbers, would it also
increase my company's revenue? It's an
experiment that every entrepreneur
behind a modern founder-led business
wants to know. I identified the four
most effective channels. I set my
benchmarks and tested every strategy I'd
heard of and a bunch of madeup ones that
I just came up with myself. Here's
everything I learned about growing each
platform broken down into the four key
pillars you must understand to grow on
any social
platform. The first platform I decided
to scale the brand on was X. I started
with just 5,000 followers. At the time,
it was one of the biggest followings I
had on any platform. and my growth here
convinced me that this whole experiment
could be worth it. Let's start with
pillar one of X, platform. I realized
that if I wanted to use X to grow my
business, not just increase my follower
count, I had to share value and help my
community. My goal switched from
entertaining to offering ideas,
playbooks, and systems that could help
others grow. Start to absorb what's
working and feels good to you and keep
track of the posts so you can identify
trends and have a source of inspiration
and ideation. Once I got an idea of how
great accounts operated and studied some
of their best work, I needed to figure
out how I wanted to share my ideas.
That's when I came up with this
exercise, the 5-year look back. This is
for X, but honestly, this would work for
any content platform. I sat down and
reflected on how far I've come over the
last 5 years. Then I identified specific
lessons, experiences, and pieces of
knowledge that made me grow the most
over those 5 years. I then came up with
seven categories to organize everything
I could think of around things like
mistakes, challenges, insecurities,
achievements, biggest lessons,
underrated skills, and successful
routines. These were the content
categories I noticed in high-erforming
ex accounts. And when I looked a bit
deeper, I noticed something that was
quite unique at the time. The content
was highly personal. It wasn't that the
best or most established experts won on
X. Success and growth came from being
willing to share from your own life
perspective on topics that had mass
relatability and appeal. This allowed
you to be differentiated in your
approach, but universal in your subject
matter. The next pillar we want to focus
on for X is frequency. For each
platform, I tested how often to post to
get the best impact. When I first
started, I thought I should post all day
every day. So, I tried posting five to
10 times every day because everyone told
me extra rewards posting frequency. But
that intense frequency ended up annoying
my followers and hurting the performance
of every piece of content that I posted
that day. So, I finally landed on the
sweet spot for growth that was posting
one to two times every day. And then
four out of the seven days a week, I
posted one long form post. These posts
were packed with value, but took a lot
of time to create. But if I was starting
again from scratch, I wouldn't start out
this complicated. Just post two times a
day and on Thursday and Sunday have one
post be a long form thread. Now let's
talk about the exact strategy for
growing on X. I found that the best
performing X post used the following
elements. Number one, short sentences
did great, usually one per paragraph.
Number two, I avoided long paragraphs
and made it easily scannable. Number
three, I got as specific as possible.
Specific numbers, specific details.
Generic information dies on X. Number
four, I used I and you pronouns to make
things as personal as possible. And
number five, I realized that I could
pack more value into an image than into
280 characters. If you combine a short
sentence or two with a powerful image,
it often does far better than the text
alone. When I put together threads, I
use the first post as a headline. The
goal is to introduce something
interesting or novel that makes
followers interested to read more. Then
my audience will click on show more to
see the rest of the posts that are
connected. Threads let you share way
more interesting insights, usually in
the form of lists, you know, item one,
insight two, tip three, that kind of
thing. One big difference I discovered
between threads and posts are that
curiosity phrases and threads help keep
people reading. Phrases like, "But
there's more, so read on." But I didn't
stop there. Let me explain. Here comes
the good part. They keep the interest
high and the minds of your audience
engaged. Because threads take more time
to craft, I only posted two per week.
Only after I was able to grow my team
and practices did I start scaling that
up to four times a week. Now for the
final pillar of X, conversion. The whole
reason I was doing this in the first
place was to drive revenue for my
business. The best way to do that was to
drive traffic to landing pages. Landing
pages offer value in exchange for
joining an email list. On X, I
discovered two primary ways to convert
my audience to an email list. The first
one was my profile. There's multiple
spots that I added CTAs to encourage
signups for my newsletter. I updated my
banner to make a promise about my
content combined with a call to action
to join the email list. Then I set my
location and link to promote my
newsletter. Finally, I pinned my
high-erforming thread as my top post on
my profile. One thing you have to be
aware of on X in many other platforms is
that if you add a link to a website
outside of X, X isn't as likely to push
that post out to the available audience
as it would a normal post without an
external link. I realized that I could
get around this by waiting before I
added a link to existing posts. I would
post and then wait until the post starts
to get a lot of likes and retweets and
then at that point I'll add a new post
to turn it into a thread and this post
will be the call to action to join the
email list. the real results of
implementing these strategies on my ex
over the last 2 years. I started with
5,000 followers and after 2 years of
following this exact approach, I was
able to grow that to 360,000 followers.
This grew my revenue, too, but I'll
share those numbers a little later
on. Let's talk about LinkedIn. Before my
sprint to grow on LinkedIn, I started
with just 11,000 followers. To be
honest, at first, I thought nothing of
this platform. I completely
underestimated it. I thought it was just
for recruiters and random business
updates. When most people start on this
channel, they think the same. They feel
it's hardly a social network that can
have bottom line results. But it's
actually insane how many leads LinkedIn
drives my business every day. It's
actually my number one channel for
generating leads. The density of
highquality business owners means the
leads that come through LinkedIn are
much more qualified for business growth,
coaching, and consulting communities
like mine. LinkedIn uses an algorithmic
approach, but it's a lot more
connection-based. It's one of the last
genuine social networks where virality
and reach don't smother the quality of
the content that gets pushed out to a
wide audience. I found that posting one
long- form post on LinkedIn every day
kept me top of mind without
oversaturating my audience. And the
strategy behind each of my posts is also
quite intuitive. Since I had poured so
much time into X, I just used a lot of
the same lessons from X and then just
applied those to LinkedIn.
Cross-pollinating across textbased
platforms is a great way to grow the
online presence of your personal brand.
But beware, there are differences
between X and LinkedIn. Unlike X, I
found that short posts on LinkedIn
underperformed unless I used a super
valued dense image. But for this reason,
I almost always find it better to go
long form. The first three lines of your
LinkedIn post are a textbased thumbnail.
Meaning, the goal of the first three
lines is to get my audience to click
more to read the rest of the post. Make
sure your first three lines follow the
best practices for attentiongrabbing
techniques that you've seen work in your
niche. I found that over time, the image
you attach to your point itself will
drive most of your interest. I treat
this image like my post thumbnail. I
found that LinkedIn cares more about the
length of time that someone's engaging
with your post than anything else. I've
optimized a primarily long- form post
list once a day with a really engaging
image that takes a while to read. Here
are three examples of LinkedIn posts
with all the ingredients to high
performance we just discussed. The
process of converting people on LinkedIn
to customers is pretty similar to X, but
LinkedIn is even better at giving you
way more ways to add links. The best
places I've discovered for conversion
are my cover photo image, my bio text,
the CTA that appears under my name every
time I post, the featured sections of my
profile, and finally at the end of my
LinkedIn post. Now, let's look at the
results. I started LinkedIn with 11,000
followers and over 12 months posting in
line with all the strategies I just
shared with you. I was rated the fastest
growing creator on the platform by
Taplio, growing at over 110,000
subscribers a month and generating 59
million monthly organic impressions, all
while spending 0 on ads. That's like
$340,000 a month in free advertising.
So, in the span of 2 years, I went from
11,000 to $760,000 followers on
LinkedIn. Who would have
[Music]
thought? Now, I started my YouTube
sprint with a grand total of zero
subscribers. When I started, I thought
YouTube was too hard to get going. I was
nervous to be in front of the camera. I
had no video equipment. I didn't think
there was anything valuable I could even
talk to people about that people would
even want to watch. I was wrong.
Perfectionism is the enemy. I refrained
my initial approach on YouTube to better
calibrate my expectations. I made it a
goal to become great at cinematography
in video composition and gave myself a
bunch of runway for the next 3 years. I
played the long game. I told myself I'd
do this by making each video 10% better
than the last one. Improving scripts,
hooks, thumbnails, titles, and
everything else that makes a video go
viral. YouTube as a platform has huge
diversity. But just like X and LinkedIn,
you want to follow people who are
winning in your niche and learn what
works for them and then model them. When
we talk about frequency on YouTube, I've
discovered that the best frequency
varies a lot based on the kind of
content that you're trying to make. If
you're just starting out, a video a week
is fine. If you're keeping production
light and not working with a big team,
if you're trying to be more polished,
you might want to slow down a bit and
begin with two videos a month, even once
a month to get a feel for the platform.
Scale up only when you feel you have the
quality there and the bandwidth. Do not
burn yourself out chasing some
unsustainable cadence. What really
determines how well my top videos have
performed is a combination of three
factors: the idea, the title, and the
thumbnail. If a video's idea is
thoughtfully researched, validated, and
tailored to my target audience, it
outperforms any other video where the
idea was less strategic regardless of
the production quality. And if the idea
is not packaged using a strong thumbnail
or title, then no one's going to click
on your great idea. And if they don't
click, they don't watch. And if they
don't watch, it becomes a sad day to be
posting on YouTube. Next, the idea
should be novel and appear to core,
casual, and new viewers. If it's just
helpful to new people or experts, it
won't drive as many views once it gets
pushed out to a wider audience. When
designing the title of the video, you'll
want to keep in mind familiar phrase
structures paired with eye-catching and
search relevant words. The title should
further provide context to the value
that you're going to actually deliver in
the video so potential viewers have an
accurate understanding of what they will
get in return for them clicking on the
video and watching it. The title should
stop viewers in their tracks. But the
title doesn't work alone. This is
because of the thumbnail. The holy grail
of YouTube strategy fixation is often on
that thumbnail. The goal of a thumbnail
is to build massive intrigue and open a
question loop that is so irresistible it
can only be satisfied by watching the
video. It would not be an overstatement
to say that the idea plus the title plus
the thumbnail equals 90% of the formula
for my YouTube success. One of the
hardest but most powerful ways to
convert people is generating a helpful
offer built into the video itself. If
you can share useful resources in the
description and then give it to anyone
willing to share their email, you
convert a lot of viewers to email
subscribers that way. But it has to be
good and relevant to the video and it
has to be worth slowing down your video
to share. The results for my YouTube
journey are still very much a work in
progress. I started with zero
subscribers and now 2 years in, we've
grown that to over 136,000 subscribers.
Rewind two years and my personal
Instagram page had just 4,500 followers.
Over time, I started to think of my
Instagram as a variety show. I have
carousels, photos from my daily
adventures, reels around specific
systems, and tons of value per second to
encourage people to save my content and
then share it with five friends. I
realized frequency boils down to three
formats: reels, posts, and stories.
Reals are 90-second vertical videos.
When I posted reels, they would go out
to the audience I was building, but they
also went out to Instagram's algorithm
for video sharing, which means people
see my videos when they're swiping
through other videos on Instagram. Posts
are one or more images or media that go
mainly to those who are following me
already. This is great for continuing to
nurture my core audience. Stories are a
series of posts that are only available
for a little while before disappearing.
I discovered these are great for sharing
a little bit more behind the scenes,
micro updates on my life, and for
sharing more about upcoming events or
business offers. I eventually arrived at
this posting frequency. One reel a day
so that my videos reach a bigger
audience. One post a day so my existing
audience engages and is rewarded for
following and two to five stories a day
to share what previous posts, mini
updates, or drive email signups or
sales. By now, I have a full-scale team
keeping this posting cadence in check.
If you're just starting out, make this
your goal and scale slowly and
sustainably. Here's what's performed the
best in the past 2 years. I have two
main types of videos. Talking head
videos and animated videos. I found that
for 90 secondond videos, I can sit down
for one long writing session and create
up to 30 scripts for those short form
videos. These are usually about 120
words long. And if I do that, it's going
to be roughly 2 months of content
written all at once. Then I can just go
and film them and then share them with
my editor. The scripts themselves follow
a similar format to other platforms,
usually list-based. I focus 80% of my
time on the first 10 seconds of that
video with most of that time going
towards the first 3 seconds and usually
start with one of these four power
words. I, I've, when or if. For my post,
I will occasionally post a single photo
if it's really useful, like a photo of
my notebook. But usually, I found that
raw carousels perform best. Raw
carousels are posts that share multiple
raw photos, memes, behind the scenes, or
day in my life lifestyle content. These
work because they showcase my
personality and human side, and they
drive engagement and increase reach.
Stories are the third example. You can
just post interesting moments from your
camera roll, say hi with short form
videos if you want to go and connect
with your audience and just have fun
with it. Or you can use stories to share
promotional content, which leads us to
conversion. I spent a lot of time
cracking the system for Instagram
because I saw the potential to make a
lot of money. I set up my bio to be well
written and have a link there to my
newsletter. Then I use stories at a
cadence of a few times a week. I'm going
to create a story that links to my
newsletter or other promotions. I make
sure that those promotional stories are
only about 20% of my total stories.
Next, I use captions. For some of my
posts, I'll add a CTA that drives people
to join my newsletter. And finally, I
use direct messages or DMs. This works
by adding a CTA button to a story that
prompts a direct message conversation.
Okay, so how did this all pay off over
the last 2 years? In 2 years of work on
Instagram, I grew from zero followers to
over 900,000 followers. This is by far
the biggest glow up across all the
platforms, but it was also the platform
that I put the most effort into.
[Music]
I talk a lot about the content GPS, but
I want to actually give you a checklist
that you can follow so you make sure you
have every core element of the GPS
implemented. And so, let's get started
here. You know, 2 years ago, believe it
or not, I only had 43,000 followers
across every platform. Before that, you
know, I started from zero, just like
you. And today, well, I have over 2.8
million followers across X, LinkedIn,
Tik Tok, Instagram, and YouTube. and I
run a portfolio of profitable companies
and the size of that portfolio is only
possible because of the audience and the
content that I put out there. I'm able
to travel the world. I have freedom and
I was just in Japan currently in Bali,
Indonesia. I'm heading to Wyoming, then
Austin, probably then back to Bali. So,
you know, I'm able to travel the world
and control where I work, what I work
on, when I work, uh, and who I work
with. And this is really what brings me
joy. And all while I've spent zero
dollars on ads, this is all from organic
content. So, what I want to show you
here is my system so you can go and
steal it. First off, let's talk about
the content GPS component starting with
your platform strategy. You got your
content system, your audience growth
system, and your conversion engine. And
we're going to get into each part of
this um in the next few minutes, as well
as how to go and build an amazing team.
Because at the end of the day, you want
to make sure that you're not just
growing your personal brand, but that I
think you should be focused on growing a
personal media company so that you're
not just the one doing all the things
and on some content hamster wheel. You
want to have the systems and the people
in place to make it enjoyable, to have
fun, so you can focus on the stuff you
love to do and delegate all the stuff
that just does not bring you joy. So the
content GPS looks something like this.
Okay, at the top here you have your
personal media company where you have
all the different platforms that you're
on, right? X, LinkedIn, Tik Tok,
YouTube, Instagram. From there, you want
to be growing that audience, but you
need to drive them from your rented
audience, right, to your owned audience.
You know, you're not Zuck, you're not
Musk, you don't own those people on X or
on LinkedIn. So you need to drive them
to a newsletter. If you're getting
started, you may use something like
ConvertKit. If you're more experienced,
I currently use HubSpot because it's a
lot more powerful, but it's also a
little bit more pricey. From there,
we're driving folks to leads, right, and
driving applications to my different
portfolio companies. And then we're
converting those people either via a
sales page or a sales call to then
customers inside of the actual product
or service that I'm offering. We make
sure that we have an unbelievable
customer experience, right? Where those
people want to refer their friends, they
want to recommend us, they want to leave
reviews, and that creates a profit
flywheel. Well, then those people will
go tell their friends, they drive more
customers, and this organically just
starts growing itself. And this is how
I've been able to build all of my
businesses without spending a dime on
ads. Now, when I think about the four
big platforms that I think are most
important to be focused on right now,
it's X if you're really good at writing
and you want to go, you know, writing
first. YouTube is great for long- form
authority. You know, on YouTube, you
really develop deep relationships with
people because they're seeing you,
they're hearing you either on a weekly
or bi-weekly basis, and it's a great
place to build rich one-to-one
relationships with your audience. Also,
YouTube is the largest video search
engine in the world. So, when people are
searching for core terms around what you
do, they're going to find you, and
that's super valuable, as I'm sure you
can understand. On Instagram is great
for visual storytelling. And we put a
lot of work at Founder OS into our
brand, into our aesthetic, and we put a
lot of work into the taste behind it.
It's a great chance to build a brand,
but it's not going to be as deep as
growing an audience on YouTube because
on Instagram, they're maybe seeing a one
minute post from you, and on YouTube,
they're likely watching a 15inute video.
So, the level of relationship you're
going to build on YouTube is far
greater. LinkedIn is amazing because
it's essentially this professional
network, right? Everyone on there for
the most part are super legit. There's
not many bots. And so, what you're going
to do is if you're targeting business
owners, LinkedIn is incredibly powerful.
And I've been able to build an audience
there over the last two and a half years
of over
783,000 people. Um, and it is a massive
source of leads for my businesses. So,
when you think about your content
strategy, I think you really want to
base it on your brand positioning. So
for me that's things like personal
brands, founder-ledd brands, systems,
organic content. I talk about these
things and those things become, you
know, my content strategy. So your
content strategy should be coupled with
your brand and it should help exemplify
it. It should help amplify it versus
being disconnected from it where people
don't even know what you do. So on X,
here is my operating system or my OS.
When you're getting started, I would
recommend two threads per week, which
are longer form posts on X. You're going
to want to make sure you have
curiositydriven CTAs that drive people
to your newsletter from your ex content.
You want to make sure that you're
replying to the community, replying to
different comments under your stuff to
help form these more authentic
relationships with people. And then you
want to make sure you're also
repurposing your content, you know, from
other platforms and putting it on X. So,
I'll share my YouTube videos there. I'll
share short form videos there from time
to time. In addition to that, you want
to make sure that you have daily content
going out at 8:07 a.m. in whatever time
zone your dream customer is in. So for
me, you know, it's people in EST
primarily, and so I go and make sure
that my content on X comes out every
single morning at that time. And then I
have another post at around 2 p.m. every
single day. So these are examples of the
different hooks that I write for X. And
it's important that you're using tools
like Tweet Hunter X to go and dial your
content in. So you have scroll stopping
hooks that stop people in their tracks
and hit. Here on the left side, you can
see this piece of content I put out on
the 10 best Christmas ads of all time.
This post got over 292,000 likes, over
32 million organic views without paying
a dime on ads. So pretty insane. So you
need to make sure that you dial in your
hooks cuz if you can't get someone to
read your first sentence, they're not
going to read the second sentence or the
third. And so making sure that you have
a hook that stops people in their tracks
is key. You know, this is what's allowed
me to go and hit over 31 million views a
month on X and at times grow my
following by over 7,000 followers a
week. And so I have a writing workflow
that I use on these platforms, right? I
have all my ideas in a Google sheet. I
then go and write these things or I get
help from someone on my team. We then go
and add designs to them and images to
make them much more multimedia enriched
so they stand out more and again stop
the scroll which is the goal. And then
we distribute this. I have a social
manager on my team that puts it out
there. And then that social manager is
monitoring performance and then letting
us know what content did the best on the
given platform. What's the stuff that
did the worst and then bubbles up
content ideas based on what they're
seeing from our content and other high
performing content on the given
platform. So this is what my writing
workflow works like. You don't need to
do the exact same thing I'm doing, but I
think this will serve as some
inspiration for you as you scale up. So,
let's get into my LinkedIn operating
system or my OS. So, what I love to have
are valued dense images because LinkedIn
rewards you for having quality time on
post. And so, images almost act as like
your thumbnails, stopping the scroll and
getting people to spend more time on
your post, which then causes the
algorithm to go and boost that post to
more people um in your follower base. In
addition to that, we have quality CTAs
that drive people from the given post to
my newsletter where then they join to
get one proven system every single week
from me and if they're interested in
working with me or one of my companies,
they can go and apply to join. From
there, I love long- form storytelling
because again, we want quality time on
posts. So, longer form posts work much
better on LinkedIn. You know, you want
to make sure that they're scannable,
easy to understand, using language
that's easy to understand for an eighth
grader so that they're easily consumed
and then shared with others. You know,
the main thing that LinkedIn rewards is
repost. So, we want to always be
engineering our content so that someone
will go and share that piece of content
with five of their friends. In addition
to that, you want to make sure you have
a profitable profile set up. So, you're
looking at things like your cover photo,
link in bio, your featured section, your
profile photo, and making sure it's
professional and it's engineered to
drive people from awareness through to
joining your community and then
transacting with you. Lastly, just like
everything, right, your community
engagement is super important. And
making sure that your featured section
is updated with a product link to drive
people to actually work with you and
then a newsletter link to convert people
from your rented audience on LinkedIn to
your own audience in your newsletter.
Okay? And then again, on these
platforms, I like to have the post go
out there around 8:04 a.m. EST every
single morning, 7 days a week. Again,
remember though for you, if you're just
starting, the best content strategy is
the one that you can stick with. So
don't feel like you need to post every
day, just like I do. for you. If four
posts on LinkedIn are the limit and
that's what works for you, then just do
that again, right? Like consistency is
key. So, this exact strategy I just
showed you is what has allowed me to
grow my LinkedIn in some months at over
102,000 followers a month, generating
over 59 million organic views. You know,
just a few months ago, I was ranked as
the fastest growing creator on LinkedIn.
And so, what I'm showing you here, it
genuinely works. Here, you can see all
the different components of what make up
a profitable profile on LinkedIn. The
cover photo with a clear CTA to my
newsletter. I have all the relevant
links in there. So, I'm driving people
to my product, driving people to my
newsletter, making sure it looks
professional and it's all on brand. So,
that that first impression, which is
everything, really convinces people that
I'm legit and in one way or another,
they kind of get involved with the
different things I got going on. Here
you can see an example of a valued dense
image, which, you know, gives people a
ton of value and then causes them to go
and again likely repost, which is a core
metric I'm trying to drive in every
single one of my posts. And it also
causes them to join my newsletter. So,
I'm bringing people from my LinkedIn
audience to my newsletter and I'm
currently growing that at around 8,000
subscribers per month organically from
LinkedIn. So, pretty insane. In addition
to that, if you need to come up with
different ideas for the platforms, here
is my chat GBT prompt um which will also
go link below um via the link in the
description. You can go and use this
prompt to come up with 30 plus content
ideas in just 30 seconds. It's super
powerful. I've customized it just for
you um so that if you ever feel like you
hit writer's block, well, say no more.
that should be gone because this prompt
is a beast and will help you out. All
right, now let's get into your YouTube
operating system. This is YouTube OS.
Okay, first off, your description on
your YouTube videos is a great place
where you can go and drive people to
your newsletter and your product or
service. And so, you want to make sure
that you dial that in intentionally, and
you can go just check out my
descriptions to see how I do this. From
there, you want to make sure that you're
playing the long game. YouTube is not
going to be one overnight. Just like
most things in life, it's going to take
long-term consistency. So versus
focusing on say growing to 100,000
subscribers, I would much rather focus
on the craftsmanship of creating quality
videos and making the goal of I'm going
to go and make 50 videos that I am proud
of this year or over the next 2 years.
That is a great goal that focuses more
on the process versus the outcome. In
addition to that, I think it's important
on the platform like YouTube to focus on
quality over quantity. Unlike other
platforms, YouTube really rewards you
for really giving people a ton of value,
keeping an amazing aesthetic, great
taste, and making sure that things like
your lighting, your sound, your video is
really dialed in. So, you can just start
with an iPhone, right? You don't need to
have some fancy equipment to start. But
with each video, focus on getting 10%
better each and every time. Now, your
thumbnail, your title, which is called
your packaging, is going to be about 80%
of the battle, right? If you can't get
someone to click on their video, you're
not going to get them to watch the whole
thing. So, getting that click is
imperative. And your title and your
thumbnail need to be curiosityinducing.
maximize the intrigue to get people to
click in and watch your content. I like
to focus in all of my content on this
metric, which is an insane value per
second. Every single second, I want to
make sure that I'm giving people so much
value that they can't help but watch and
then eventually share the video with
five friends. You know, my goal is that
in the comments of any single video that
I create that people go and comment,
"Damn, Matt, I cannot believe this is
free." You know, that means to me that
I'm putting enough effort in these
videos, delivering enough value, um,
that I'm helping founders just like you,
and I'm fulfilling my mission of
inspiring 100 million founders just like
you to accomplish their dreams through
proven systems. So, this is where I
started, right? You know, it was me
filming videos off of an iPhone with a
super janky setup in Porto Escanido,
Mexico. It was pretty embarrassing to be
honest, but I'm proud of myself, right?
Cuz I just got started and I focus on
just putting in the reps week after
week, getting 1% better every day, 10%
better every week. And sure enough, you
know, a year later, I was 37 times
better. And here's where I am now,
right? Some of my videos have gotten
over 500,000 views. You know, I'm
regularly getting videos over 100,000
views. So, like a hundred times better
than when I started. But that would not
have been possible if I just didn't put
in the reps. Mr. Beast has this amazing
quote that I love. You know, he went and
was asked by someone, you know, how do I
go and get amazing at YouTube? And what
he tells them is, hey, all you need to
do is make a 100 videos and improve
something every time. Do that. And then
on your 101st video, we'll start talking
because you learn from the doing, right?
Not from sitting on the sidelines, from
getting in the game, moving from the
stands to in the arena. That is where
you learn. And so get started now to
start putting in the reps. And you'll
see each video you'll get 10% better.
And before you know it, you'll be
hitting bangers. So again, focusing on
packaging is imperative, right? So we'll
go and test a bunch of different
thumbnails. We'll test those thumbnails
in YouTube's AB testing tool to keep on
dialing in um our clickability of any
given packaging of all of our videos. In
addition to that, in the hooks of our
videos, I'll often times go and record
three different hooks, and then we'll go
and choose the one that feels the best
for really going and getting someone's
attention and introducing the value
we're going to give in the road map in
the rest of the video. So, you may be
wondering, well, what's your process for
making videos, Matt? And what parts are
you involved in? So, I like to think of
it as this flow. And for me, I'm
involved in actually coming up the
ideas, writing them out, and making sure
the ideas then are flushed out. From
there, I film them, right? Because I'm
the creator behind this founder-led
brand. But the editing, the publishing,
the repurposing, the analytics, that is
people on my team that goes and handles
all the rest of that stuff. So I can
focus on the stuff that only I can do.
Everything else is handled by others.
Let's get into Instagram OS here. So you
want to make sure that you have your
profitable profile set up with an
amazing bio that's consistent. It's on
brand. It's inspiring. You want to make
sure that you have your Instagram
stories going out every day, probably
three to five. And we post two times a
day on Instagram. One carousel and one
Instagram reel. You want to make sure
you have your real strategy dialed in so
you can keep up with that quantity over
time. Again though, if you're just
getting started, the best content
strategy is the one you can stick with.
So you you can only do say three reels a
week. Just stick with that. From there,
I really love carousels. And on the last
card of my carousel, I'll go and have a
call to action that then drives people
to my newsletter. So again, I'm driving
people from the audience on Instagram to
my newsletter. And then we use Many Chat
automations. You know, ManyHat is a tool
that allows you to go and send automated
automations and DMs on autopilot when
people use a certain word under your
post, story, a real, whatever it may be.
And so it's a super powerful tool for
driving people to a given lead magnet
you may be releasing. And I'd recommend
that you go and check this out. So when
I'm growing on any of these platforms,
I'm always looking at the data and we're
doubling down on what's working and
stopping the formats that are no longer
working. So as an example on Instagram,
we saw that our animated videos were
blowing up as well as our raw carousels
on the platform. So we doubled down on
that format, which we saw working. And
along the way, there's been a lot of
formats that are just like dead bodies
along the way, right? There's a
graveyard of formats that never worked
that we just stopped doing those things.
Now, this is my content calendar. This
lays out the different quantity that
we're posting certain kinds of formats
on each of the platforms. You don't need
to stick to this content calendar. I
would recommend initially that you pick
one or two platforms to start. If you
like writing most, then go to X or
LinkedIn. If you like video most, go to
a platforms like YouTube, Instagram or
Tik Tok. And remember that just keep up
with the quantity that you can stick
with. Don't go too far too fast because
you want to keep it sustainable. Keep it
fun because winning on any of these
platforms is about longevity, about
staying in the game and not burning out.
This is my content waterfall system that
allows me to turn one piece of content
into 24 other pieces of content. So
we'll go take one XRE and that'll become
things like a newsletter in eight weeks.
It'll become part of the script for a
long form YouTube video. We'll use it
for things like you know short form
Instagram reels or short form YouTube
shorts. So when we go and create one
amazing idea on X, it doesn't just
become that, right? we are able to
repurpose that piece of content which
allows us to get that much of an ROI
from my time, my energy, my creativity
because one idea can become many other
ideas um and pieces of content across
all platforms. So when it comes into the
revenue side, right? Because we're not
just looking to build followers here.
We're looking to grow dollars. You want
to make sure that you have your offer
structure dialed in. Your CTA placement
needs to be immaculate across all
platforms. And I'll show you that in
here in one second. You want to make
sure that your landing pages are all
designed immaculately so we're driving
people from visitors to customers. You
want your newsletter page optimized so
you're driving people from your
newsletter landing page to subscribers.
This is what my CTA system looks like.
So these are all of the CTA areas or
call to actions that you can have across
each platform. I would recommend taking
a screenshot of this and then going and
reflecting on each of your platforms. Do
you have all of these CTA set up so that
when you think about your audience,
right? It's like this massive ocean of
attention. You want to make sure that
you're using call to actions across
those platforms to basically form a net
where you're kind of catching the fish.
And so your CTAs allow you to go and
take all those eyeballs you're
generating and drive them into leads and
eventually into revenue for your
business. This is what my sort of
distribution schedule looks like in a
given month. So for the most part
throughout the month, anything that's
marked here as an N, I'm promoting my
newsletter in my CTAs. Then for around
10 days of the month, I'm promoting a
workshop that I run that is a free
training for founders and CEOs to help
them level up their business. So again,
roughly 20 days a month, my CTAs lead to
newsletter signups and 10 days a month,
they lead to workshop signups. Now,
let's get over to the time freedom spot
because it's all good to build an
audience, but as you're growing your
content, you don't want to be doing
everything right. You're going to need
some help. I believe in building
personal media companies, not just
personal brands. And the difference
between the two is that a personal media
company is when you have a team of
weapons that are helping you scale up
and you're working on only stuff that
you can do. A personal brand is when
you're the sole creator. And while
that's fine to get started, I think that
CEOs generally have ambitions of being
the CEO of a media company versus being
the sole creator. Because again, the
enemy is burnout. And so when you have
more systems and more people, you get
more help. So first off, you probably
want a tech lead, right? Someone to help
you actually orchestrate your entire
funnel behind the scenes, right? Things
like Web Flow for your website, HubSpot
for your CRM, and making sure that, you
know, Stripe and things are set up for
your checkout. You probably want a video
editor, right? Probably someone to be
handling your short form videos for
reals and for shorts. And then another
person to maybe be handling your long
form videos over time because you should
be creating things and be maybe the
talent on camera, but not be the one
actually editing every single video
because that can get exhausting. Your
social manager is basically your chief
distribution officer. They're making
sure that all your content goes out um
to the highest quality possible on each
of the platforms at the right time
without any mistakes. Your content
manager is someone that can help you go
and come up with ideas, help you kind of
manage this team over time so you can
focus on more important parts of the
business that drive you revenue and have
this content operation running on
autopilot. Graphic designers are super
important because I think that quality
is the ultimate pattern drop and taste
is the ultimate competitive advantage.
And so having amazing design is going to
set you apart in your industry. Lastly,
along the way, right, you need to make
sure that every single system across
your content, the different platforms,
your calendar, how you orchestrate
different formats is all documented. And
this is the sort of documentation that
we provide people like you with inside
of Founder OS. Along the way, don't lose
sight of the fact that while there's all
these systems and there's revenue and
you're running a business, you know, I
like to focus on being an artist over an
entrepreneur. I like to focus on the
creativity, the design, the taste, the
script, the copy, the artistry, the
cinematography, the lighting. All of
those elements really excite me. And the
numbers are important. And sure, you
know, we got to make sure that the
business is thriving. Don't get me
wrong, but I feel like actually when you
focus most on the creativity, the love
of the process, the ins and outs of the
details, the business just tends to take
care of itself. So along the way as
you're creating your content, just
really remember to unleash your full
creative potential. spend time, you
know, creating beautiful designs. Really
enjoy how you're showing up. Have fun,
right? Just be creative. Do what you
love, right? Don't do what everyone else
is doing. Focus on the things that are
authentically you, right? Because at the
end of the day, that's what's going to
really attract people is your
personality, your design, your energy.
This is the stuff that's going to help
you stand out. So, over the next 30
days, it's important that we take
action. So, I'd recommend that you go
and you dial in your brand positioning.
Where do you separate yourself from
everyone else in your space? Get your
content bank going and aim to create 20
pieces of content over the next month.
Go and set up your profitable profile in
each of the different platforms that you
exist on. Make sure you have a systems
documented to drive more freedom in your
life. Get a newsletter landing page
going with a platform like ConvertKit or
Web Flow so you can go and drive people
from your audience to subscribers. On
the 90-day side of things, these are the
sort of metrics I would be looking at.
Weekly follower growth, email list
growth, and then just your own energy,
right? making sure that you're
continually enjoying the process and
you're being consistent because at the
end of the day, consistency wins. These
are the sort of metrics that you could
be looking to track across the different
platforms. Things like your follower
growth, your best posts every month,
your worst posts every month, coming up
with different content ideas, your
revenue the last 30 days, and your
profit the last 30 days so that you're
growing a profitable media empire, which
is the key thing here, right? We want to
make sure that as we're growing all this
content, we're growing our team that
it's sustainable so we can stay in the
game long term because like anything,
right? content and your audience are
like an asset and they compound over
time. So the key thing is that we're
making sure that asset is self-
sustaining, it's systemized, it's fun,
and it's working well so that we can see
those big returns over the long term,
which is the sort of mindset you want to
have along the way. Remember that slow
is smooth, smooth is fast. You know,
you're not going to get all this stuff
overnight, right? It's going to take a
second, and that's just part of the
process. So fall in love with it, enjoy
it, really loosen your grip on, you
know, perfectionism, right?
Perfectionism kills creativity. Take
time to just love the process, love the
creativity, lean into the artistry
behind all you're doing, and people will
be able to feel that and that's going to
allow your audience to compound and your
business to grow. So, this is what my
profitable profile on X looks like as an
example. You can see I got a great
headshot there, you know, looking good.
I got my uh dialed in kind of core copy
and my cover photo driving people to my
newsletter, which then is linked there
as well. So, people would go from my
audience to my newsletter page. You see,
when you open this, you land on a no
scroll landing page. So on this page,
you can't scroll, right? And you
basically are being prompted to just
drive people from this page to my
newsletter where they're going to get
one proven system to grow their business
every single week for free. So let's
move on to my Instagram profile. My
Instagram profile, you can see here
we've driven over 96,000 followers
there. People can go and see that I have
proven systems to grow a profitable
audience with content. If they want to
work with me, they can DM scale and then
there's an many chat automation that
goes and sends them the relevant
information to get started. You can also
see here in the link in bio, I've gone
and linked my newsletter. So again,
driving people from Instagram to the
newsletter. Along the way, I view
Instagram almost like it's a variety
show. So we have raw carousels, animated
videos, we have talking head videos, we
have different photos and different
sorts of designs and graphic designs
that we use to basically just give
people a taste of my brand and my
personality. I put a lot of work into
this, a lot of taste into this, a lot of
creative energy because that's just what
I love to do. And I think that Instagram
is this mood board for the kind of brand
I want to create, which is really an
inspiring brand, a brand that stands for
freedom, that's aspirational, that shows
founders that you can run a business and
have a vibrant life. And you don't need
to run a business that just runs you
into the ground. And I think that my
Instagram exemplifies that. On the
LinkedIn side, you want to make sure
that you have your profitable profile
dialed in. And the key elements come
down to your cover photo, your amazing
profile pick, hopefully, uh, and that
you got your featured section dialed in
with one link that drives your product,
and one link that drives to your
newsletter, so we're driving more
subscribers there. On any given post,
the big thing is that you want to make
sure that you have a scroll stopping
hook. You have long form value that's
easily scannable, so people can easily
digest this and then save it and share
it with their friends. You also want to
make sure that you have your value dense
image dialed in so that you're
increasing the time on post which is
going to help your post go and be on
more people's news feeds. In addition,
you want to have a dialed in CTA. So my
CTA here is enjoy this. We post it to
your network and follow Mac for more.
Want more systems to scale peacefully?
Join our community of 137,000 plus
subscribers today. And then I drive
people to my newsletter link. So here
you can see on my YouTube on any given
video in the description here, I go and
have a really intentional description.
And we've tested this a bunch and this
is what works. And so we have a link
there where people can go and apply to
Founder OS to work directly with me and
my team. They can also go and join my
newsletter. So core CTAs inside of the
description that lead people from a
YouTube viewer to someone that's more
within my network and has closer
proximity to me. And so you probably
want to go and check out my descriptions
and use those as templates for how you
go and create your YouTube descriptions
and dial in your growth on the platform.
All right, that's it. Welcome to the
founder freedom movement. Like and
subscribe and let's win