Something weird kept happening in my
coaching calls. I'd be talking to people
who looked successful on paper, good
revenue, growing teams, strong brands,
but they all felt, you know, trapped. I
decided to dig deeper. I surveyed 99
smart and ambitious people in my
community and asked them one simple
question. What's the one thing quietly
holding you back right now? The answers
all pointed to the same 10 core problems
that keep ambitious people stuck. Here's
what surprised me most. The number one
problem isn't about money, growth, or
trusting people. It's something deeper
that affects every ambitious person I
know. Even if you think you've got it
all figured out, don't worry. I used to
think the same thing. Let me show you
what I discovered. I'm Matt Gray, and I
used to be trapped in my own successful
business. Great revenue on paper, but
zero freedom in real life. After years
of building systems to solve my own
problems, I realized other founders were
stuck in the same cycle. I've developed
frameworks that help founders create
businesses that actually give them their
life back. That's what this is about.
Systems that work so you don't have to
work all the time. But first, let me
show you these 10 problems because even
if just two of these hit home, it's
probably time to rebuild your approach
entirely. Problem number one, I'm stuck
in the weeds. One founder I worked with
was clearing $70,000 a month but
couldn't take a vacation. Sound
familiar? This is the broadest pain
point. It hits every founder regardless
of business model. You've built
something that looks successful on
paper, but you're trapped inside it.
Here's what I learned after building my
first company, BitMaker. Revenue isn't
freedom. I was making millions, but I
felt like I was in prison. I was the
bottleneck to everything. The solution,
I created what I call the AED sheet.
Automate, eliminate, delegate. List
every activity you do in a week. Mark if
it gives you energy or it drains it.
Then mark if it can be delegated. Most
founders discover they're doing $10 an
hour work instead of $2,000 an hour
highle lever task. Here's where it gets
even more interesting. Even after you
delegate, you might still feel stuck.
Which brings us to problem number two.
Problem number two, I hired ops, but I'm
still stuck. This one surprised me. I
surveyed smart, ambitious people who
already had operations managers,
assistants, even full teams, and they
were still drowning. Here's why. Hiring
people doesn't fix broken systems. It
just creates expensive chaos. I made
this mistake with my cannabis company,
Herb. I hired 15 people thinking it
would free me up. Instead, I became the
manager of 15 people's problems. My
revenue went up, but my freedom went
down. The real issue wasn't the people.
It was the process. You can't delegate
what you can't systemize. And you can't
systemize what you don't understand.
That's when I discovered something that
changed everything. The difference
between delegation and true systems
thinking. One scales you, the other
scales your problems. But even with
perfect systems, if your core offer is
broken, you're building on quicksand.
Problem number three. I don't know how
to price my high ticket offer. This one
hits different because it's about
confidence, not just about strategy. I
was on a call last week with a coach
doing $40,000 per month. His coaching
was incredible, but he was charging
$2,000 when his competitors charged
$10,000. Why? Fear of scaring away
clients. Here's the truth. Underpricing
doesn't protect you from rejection. It
attracts the wrong clients and repels
the right ones. I've seen so many offers
out there and truth be told, I think the
most beautiful offers are the ones that
are simple, they're repeatable, and
they're scalable. Where I see a lot of
founders screw up is they just keep
adding more things. And I've even done
this years ago myself where there was a
point in time with Herb that any given
offer we had, it was all just
customized. And with any single person
we worked with, we would adapt to
whatever they wanted from us. While this
seemed good on sort of a customer
success level, on a business level, it
just created an insane amount of
complexity. We told ourselves after that
that we would only create offers that
were simple, repeatable, and scalable,
which allowed us to specialize, to get
really good, to put in reps, and become
the best at that one narrow thing. Often
times when you're creating an offer
that's really scalable, it's weird,
right? because you end up making it so
uncomfortably narrow and specific,
right? Cuz you're like, "Damn, we're not
going to do this. We're not going to do
that. We're not going to do that." It's
like, "No, no, no, no, no. Just focus on
this one specific thing. Just do that,
but be the best in the world at it." And
that's where the magic happens. But it's
also really, really tough. When I raised
my mastermind from 25K to 68K, something
amazing happened. I didn't lose clients,
I gained better ones. The entrepreneurs
who invested at 68K were more committed,
got better results, and became my
biggest advocates. The psychology is
simple. Price creates the perception of
value. But more importantly, higher
prices give you the margins to overd
deliver. Here's a simple pricing
experiment to run. Take your current
price, double it, then add 20%. That's
your new price. If that terrifies you,
you're probably on the right track. Try
selling it at that price and just see
what happens. If your close rate is
still above 25%, you can stick with it
and scale stronger. But pricing is just
the surface. If your offer itself isn't
converting, you got bigger problems.
Problem number four, my offer isn't
converting, and I don't know why. I see
this pattern everywhere. Founders create
offers based on what they think people
want, not what people actually buy.
People don't buy solutions to problems
that they can solve themselves. They buy
solutions to problems they can't solve
themselves. The difference
implementation and accountability your
offer shouldn't just teach it should do.
It shouldn't just inform it should
transform. I restructured my entire
business around this principle. Instead
of selling courses, I started selling
outcomes. Instead of just teaching
systems, I started installing them. In
my case, that shifted my close rate from
15% to 30%. Here's where it gets tricky.
Once your offer starts converting, your
instinct is often times to scale even
faster. That's where most founders make
their biggest mistake. Problem number
five, how do I scale without hiring a
big team? Every founder asks this. They
see other businesses with 50 person
teams and they think that's what scale
looks like. But it's not. I know
founders doing $3 million a year with
four person teams. I know others doing
500k with 20 person teams. The
difference systems thinking versus
people thinking. Never hire a person to
solve a problem that systems can solve.
Never. Before you hire your next
employee, ask yourself, can I systemize
this instead? Most of the time, the
answer is yes. I think the most
important hire that I ever make in any
of my businesses is my chief of staff.
And they block and tackle anything that
could go and disrupt my time. I build
businesses and because I really want to
when I'm building, I my goal is really
to reach my highest creative potential.
And I can only be my best self if I'm
not getting distracted all the time. You
know, the worst feeling is like all day
when you're just task switching and then
someone's hitting you up and then
distracting you over here and suddenly,
you know, you end the day and you
wonder, did I even get anything done? My
chief of staff owns my calendar and owns
all internal communication, thereby
allowing me to be focused on the
external side of things, right? I'm able
to go and kind of be our creative
director, our chief detail officer,
going and helping us build this almost
this Pixar for founders, focusing on
crazy ideas, building this amazing
movement, helping us create content that
inspires over 81 million people a month
these days. The biggest thing that I can
do in any business is to set the organic
audience on fire. Anything else I like
to either delegate, eliminate, or
automate. And the beautiful thing is
that when I have a chief of staff in
place there, they're able to go sift
things into those buckets without me. So
that the only things that get to me are
things that actually will go and not
just be a 1x or 2x for the company, but
be 10x, 20x, 100x opportunities that are
actually worthy of my time and of my
mental bandwidth. This is why I can run
multiple 8 figureure businesses without
being trapped in operations. But there's
one thing that trips up even the most
systemized founders. Problem number six,
I have content but no sales system. This
one's painful because these founders are
doing everything right on the surface.
They're posting daily. They're getting
engagement, building an audience, but
their content isn't making money. Here's
the brutal truth. Content without a
sales system is honestly just expensive
marketing. I learned this building my
personal brand, 2.8 million followers.
For the first three months, I had
massive reach but tiny revenue. Then I
discovered the content of profit system.
Every piece of content I create now
serves three purposes. One, it builds
authority. Two, nurtures prospects.
Three, drives sales. The key is the
bridge between content and commerce. But
here's where most founders go wrong when
they try to scale that connection.
Problem number seven, I think ads will
save me. Plot twist, they don't. I've
seen founders spend millions on ads
across multiple businesses. Here's what
I've learned studying their businesses.
Ads amplify what's already working. They
don't fix what's broken. If your organic
content isn't converting, your ads won't
either. If your offer isn't selling at
small scale, throwing money at it won't
help. Organic is better than paid for
most founders. Why? Because organic
forces you to create real value. Paid
media lets you hide behind targeting and
creative. Listen, I'm not against paid
ads, right? I'm not really against
anything. I think one mindset I have is
I'm basically infinitely flexible. I
just know that based on my own
experience, organic content systems have
literally changed the trajectory of my
life. I've built massive assets around
my personal brand of 2.8 8 million
people, millions and millions of emails,
and all of this creates this compounding
appreciating asset that I control. And I
don't need to keep putting money into
the slot machine to go and produce
leads. I can just produce them on
command because I own my audience. The
most successful founders I see, they've
built organic audiences. When you build
an audience organically, you're building
relationships. When you just buy
traffic, you're renting attention. I've
been fortunate to build Founder OS and
my other portfolio companies to
significant scale without ads. Results
that took years and aren't typical, but
it happened. Not because I'm against
ads, but because I wanted to prove that
systems worked organically without
adding paid traffic. Organic first, paid
second, always. But even with perfect
systems, most founders still struggle
with one thing. Problem number eight,
hiring stresses me out. I get it. Bad
hires can kill your business, your
culture, and your sanity. But here's
what most founders don't realize. Hiring
anxiety usually means you don't have
clear systems for what success looks
like. Now, there was a moment running
Herb, right, where it's like 2016.
Cannabis industry was going bonkers.
Herb had recently received two $50
million offers. I had said no to those
because I could see a clear path to the
company hitting 500 mil, even a bill.
And so I bet big. I put my chips in. I
went and hired another 15 people because
it looked like demand was just going to
soar. Canadian legalization. And it
seemed like at any point the US might
legalize as well, which would just cause
the industry to 10x. But something weird
happened. Canadian legalization
happened. The US got a little softer
though. Everything started to slowly
crumble, which was shocking to everyone
in the industry. And suddenly almost in
a month demand started drying up. And so
here I was a big bloated company with 15
people too many. I had to roll in there
one Monday morning. I had to terminate
15 people back to back. And I told
myself that for the rest of my life I
would view hiring a lot different. I
would be way more conservative. My
friend Orin Hoffman once said to me, "We
view hiring as a failure. It's a failure
to automate that role. And I remember
hearing that thinking that is bold. When
at the end of the day, if you just took
a step back, there's probably a couple
simple moves you could make and yeah,
maybe a bit of rolling up your sleeves,
but that would create an automated,
systemized way of doing something versus
having more complexity. You know, we
don't want to just scale up people.
We're trying to scale freedom. When I
hire now, I'm not hiring people. I'm
hiring systems operators. Before I post
any job, I create three things. one, the
exact system they'll operate. Two, the
specific outcomes they're responsible
for, and three, the metrics that define
success. This changes everything.
Instead of hoping they'll figure it out,
I'm training them to execute a proven
system. The fear goes away when the
guesswork does. But even with great
hires, there's one problem that can
sabotage everything. Problem number
nine, wrong clients keep showing up.
You've built a strong brand. You're
getting inquiries, but they're all
wrong. Low-budget clients, tire kickers,
people who don't value what you do. This
used to drive me crazy. Then I realized
it's not a marketing problem, it's a
messaging problem. Your content is
attracting exactly who it's designed to
attract. If the wrong people are showing
up, you're sending the wrong signals.
The solution, what I call magnetic
messaging. So when it comes to magnetic
messaging, I think one of the most
powerful things you can do is think
about the core psychological barriers
that your market gets stuck with and
then coming up with your own languaging
on how you'd go and help them overcome
that. So an example here is if I find
that customers in founder OS are
constantly getting stuck with
procrastination, I may have a phrase
that is do it messy which encourages
people just to get going. Even if you're
just at 50% just take that next step.
Another example is people may be going
and getting hung up with impostor
syndrome. I may have a phrase that you
know done is better than perfect. And so
what I'm doing is I'm inserting these
unique magnetic messages into core
blockages that my core customer has.
When they go and throughout their day
they run into these different blockers
say 10 20 times a day. It's not just
anything that's on their mind. It's
hopefully I've inserted these little
phrases like do it dirty, do it messy,
you know, progress over perfectionism,
you know, done is better than perfect.
these little things that just can inch
my audience a little bit further towards
their goal, maybe even to working with
me, but all along the way having my
messaging inside of their subconscious.
Instead of trying to appeal to everyone,
repel the wrong people on purpose. Be
polarizing. Take stands. Make it clear
who you're for and who you're not for.
When I started saying Founder West isn't
for everyone, my inquiries dropped by
50%. But my close rate doubled, which
brings us to the final problem, the one
that surprised me most. Problem number
10. My business falls apart when I
travel. This is the real test of
entrepreneurial freedom. Can you
disappear for 2 weeks and come back to a
business that's better than when you
left? Most founders can't. They're not
business owners. They're highly paid
employees of their own companies. We've
all been there, right? a founder that's
looking to take a trip but just finds
themselves constantly just being pulled
back into the business. Back in 2015, I
was road tripping through New Zealand
over 2 months while building my second
business. While I had more freedom in
this business, there were still those
times where a crisis would come up
there. I'd have to pull over on the side
of the road, go and hotspot my computer
to my phone to deal with some insane
fire that was happening, you know, all
the way on the other side of the world.
Fires can be expected in any business,
right? But when you find that that's day
after day, sometimes even hour after
hour, you got to look yourself in the
mirror and wonder what the hell is going
on because that's no way to live. And as
you probably can tell, I've experienced
this years ago. And by putting the right
systems in place, you can get rid of
that feeling. Because I think that the
number one feeling that we're all really
after is peace.
The feeling that the business is
actually stronger without you. It has
this ability whether you run it for the
next 20 years you'll be successful or if
at some point you wanted to sell it it's
systemized and sellable. I think beyond
peace the other thing that we want as
founders is optionality. You want to
have that option that you know if you
want to go on a vacation you're good.
You want to have that option that if you
want to take that spontaneous weekend
away you're good. You want to have that
option if one day you wake up and you
want to sell the business you're good.
That level of just being good no matter
what. Being antifragile as a business
really all comes down to the systems
being in place. Systems work no matter
the weather, your feelings, or what
bullshit's going on because systems just
run. Building real systems means
designing yourself out of the equation.
It means creating something that runs
without you, grows without you, succeeds
without you. That's not just business
freedom, that's life freedom. Here's
what I discovered after analyzing all 99
responses. Every single problem traces
back to one thing. Most smart, ambitious
founders are building businesses that
need them to succeed. But the goal isn't
to build the business that needs you.
It's to build a business that frees you.
The difference is systems thinking. This
is what I call the founder freedom
formula. Systems plus team plus offers
equals autonomy. The goal isn't just
making money. It's creating choices.
choices about what you work on, when you
work, where you work, and who you work
with. These problems are fixable, but
not with hacks. You need systems.
Systems that work whether you're in the
office or on a beach in Thailand. That's
what I teach inside of Founder OS. The
frameworks I've developed through
building my portfolio of successful
online businesses. Results that took
years to achieve and won't be the same
for everyone, but the systems tend to be
universal. If you're ready to stop being
stuck and want to see if these systems
could work for your situation, click the
link below in the description to apply
to Founder OS. I made a one-pager that
walks through the exact systems I use to
solve these 10 problems. It's called the
Unstuck playbook, and you can download
it below in the description. This isn't
theory. This isn't motivation. This is
the actual playbook I use with founders
doing 30K to 500K per month who want to
scale without losing their sanity. If
you see yourself in these problems,
you're not alone. And more importantly,
you're not going to be stuck forever.
Like this video if it opened your eyes
to something new. Subscribe if you want
more systems that actually work. And
download the playbook if you're ready to
stop being a prisoner in your own
business. Welcome to the founder freedom
movement. This is my life's work. I'd
love to see you on the inside.