if you're going to be happy and
successful then you need to accept these
three truths one your life is your
responsibility certain things might not
be your fault but it is your problem
you've got to take responsibility for
changing your life if you don't like the
way it's going two your actions create
outcomes the stuff you do matters you
are not just lucky or unlucky it's a
direct result of the actions you've
taken or not taken if you want different
outcomes take different actions three
failure is feedback failure is an
evidence that you're inadequate it's
feedback for what you need to do
differently in order to succeed learn to
adapt and change based on your failures