You don't need to hustle your way to
success. You just need to do this one
simple thing instead. A ton of
successful creators will go, they'll get
going, and before you know it, they're
editing, they're writing, they're
shipping, they're filming, and while it
all looks successful from the outside,
that YouTube creator that you've been
following suddenly just goes dark. This
is creator burnout 101, and you have to
go and be proactive about preventing it.
We want to go from how do I do this and
how do I do that to who do I need to
bring on to help me? You're probably be
thinking, "Well, how do I go and afford
all these people?" This is why it's
important to also have a scalable offer
behind all your content. Too many
creators are focused on ads, and the
truth is that ads is not going to make
you rich. So, the core thing here is
that you need to go and make sure that
you actually own your own offer. Choose
the thing that's in your zone of
brilliance, the thing that you love,
that you know your audience is going to
buy, and that you can see yourself
spending the next 10 years of your life
on. And then, start refining and selling
that thing.