I grew from zero to 368,000 followers on
X using a simple system. Go and follow
50 people in your industry and aim to
reply to 10 of the biggest thought
leaders [music] that really you find
attractive on the platform. Right? The
kind of people that you want to get to
know, well, just start engaging with
their content and building those
relationships. And don't hesitate just
to go and DM five to 10 people a day.
The way that you want to be connecting
with folks is by first [music] giving.
Really trying to think of how can I be
insanely generous on this platform. That
I think, [music] you know, that level of
reciprocity starts to kind of compound
and you build some real rich
relationships.