Here's what nobody tells you about
reading books. Most of them are useless.
But a few of them have the power to
rewire how you think about money,
health, focus, and business. Over the
last decade, I've read hundreds of
books. Not to sound smarter, but to
rewire how I think about the four
quadrants of life. In this video, I'm
breaking down the exact books that help
me think differently than 99% of people.
Let's start with the first quadrant,
business. Let's start with business
because the way you think about money
and focus changes how you think about
everything else. The One Thing by Gary
Keller. If you're waking up with 17
priorities and then going to bed and
feeling as if nothing's moved, this
one's for you. The One Thing showed me
that success is about saying no to
almost everything. The core focus of
this book is that ruthless
prioritization is what's going to help
you go and get extraordinary results.
And so, you know, the one question that
he really gets you to think about in
this book is what's the one thing that
when you do it, it makes everything else
easier or unnecessary. You know, in
life, what I see with so many founders
and just people that I work with is
that, you know, at the end of the day,
people think they don't have time. When
really what they don't have right is
their priorities. And oftentimes, as
Gary goes over in this book, it's about
taking a bit of space from everything
for a second to think about, you know,
what is that one big thing that when you
get that done in life, everything else
is so much easier. You know, for me, it
helped me reflect on, you know, my own
one thing, which is to create
exceptional content. You know, when I
create exceptional content, we drive
leads to my business. We're able to
build this revolutionary brand for
founders. And so, it helped me get a ton
of clarity and something that, you know,
I've taken with me for the rest of my
life. But knowing what to focus on only
matters if people actually understand
what you do. Obviously, awesome by April
Dunford. You know that feeling when
someone asks you what you do and then
you have to describe it in three
different ways so that they actually
understand it. That's the case, this
book is for you. This book flipped how I
think about positioning. You know, it's
not what you sell, it's how you frame
it. You know, the real core idea behind
this book is that people don't spend
enough time actually thinking about
their positioning of a product. You
know, I know 14 years ago running an
agency that I was selling a bundle of
goods and it was so complex because we
had to slap together all these different
things that people didn't really know
exactly what we sold. And the issue
wasn't that the product didn't work. It
was that our positioning just confused
people. And when people are confused,
they close their wallets. This book goes
over how to go about positioning your
product so it actually sells all the way
through to how to create a sales script
for your sales team so they know how to
accurately communicate your product to
the market. It's a no-brainer as a high
performance individual. Once I learned
how to focus and frame, the next lesson
was how to go and scale a business and
the people of it fast. Invent and wander
by Jeff Bezos. Terrified of sitting on a
decision because you're scared that
you're just going to go and screw it up.
This book will fix that. Bezos taught me
that most decisions are reversible. So
stop overthinking them. There's this
concept in the book, you know, which
really is just a culmination of like 20
years of Amazon shareholder letters
where you start to learn this concept as
an example, two-way doors versus one-way
doors. One-way doors in life are those
things that when you make that decision
once, you know, it's hard to kind of
turn back from there. An example is if
you go and buy a super expensive domain
for your company and you know, you brand
a company a certain way, like that's one
of those decisions that's going to be
pretty difficult now to go and change
your mind on although still possible.
Two-way decisions are the decisions that
most of us get faced with every single
day. You know, what should we eat for
dinner? Should we hire this person?
Should we build this system or that one?
The reality is is that at some point,
you just got to make the decision with
imperfect information. That's just one
of a thousand lessons from this book.
I'd argue that Jeff Bezos is probably a
top five business thinker to ever live.
And so, this book is a must. But
building with speed only matters if
you're building something that lasts.
And that's where Ryan Holidayiday comes
in. Perennial Seller by Ryan
Holidayiday. Tired of building things
that are good for a week and then just
vanish? Well, this book taught me to
build for decades instead. So much of
online businesses and the culture that
we just live in today is all about
following a trend or building something
impactful over the next year. It becomes
much more fascinating and I think just a
lot more motivating to go and try to
build a timeless iconic brand for the
next 100, 200 years. You know, look at
some of the brands maybe that you most
admire. LVMH or Nike or Apple, right?
These brands have been around for 50
years and it's more than likely that
they're going to be around for another
hundred or 200. As you're going and
creating that next book you're about to
write or maybe an art piece or a piece
of content, you know, this book really
encouraged me to start thinking way more
long term about the projects that I'm
building. Not thinking in a year or 5
years or even 10 years. You know, how
can I create an upcoming book for
Founder OS that people are still
referring to in a 100red years from now.
This book will get you thinking a lot
bigger about those creative pursuits and
I think is a must readad as well. All of
this matters, but nothing's going to
work if your culture is slow. Amp it up
by Frank Slubman. Your team's
comfortable, your culture is nice, and
your growth has completely flatlined.
Sound familiar? Amp it up reminded me
that culture isn't about vibes, it's
velocity. You know, Frank Slugman's
energy after reading this book,
honestly, I found it infectious. And it
showed me that in order to make change
happen and to get to this big vision
that I have in life, I need to amp it
up. Which to me sort of means like any
given moment, any given hour in a
company, you have the opportunity to
really push the boundary or on the other
side to kind of kick back and be more
chill. We have big visions of what we're
trying to build. You always want to be
pushing the envelope hour by hour, day
by day, week by week. And it's, you
know, this book allowed me to start
building companies that were more like
sports teams versus families. High
performers that have fun when we're
winning. And once you're moving fast,
here's how you make what you're building
irresistible. The luxury strategy by
John Caffer and Vincent Bastion. Ever
wonder why luxury brands have 10x the
prices and have 10x the demand with
people lining up around the corner to
pay? This book cracked the code for me.
One of the quotes I love in this book is
that luxury is the art of creating the
unnecessary and making it desirable.
When I go and think about many of the
businesses I'm building, when it comes
to the brand, the experience, how people
feel, I want it to feel like this luxury
experience. You know, these ideas of
symbols, creating a community around
what you're building, and often times
going to distances, not because you have
to, but because the general brand and
this experience you're trying to create
requires that. I think there's a lot of
inspiration that we can find from them
and bring them in to our companies and
the experiences that we create. A lot of
these brands stand the test of time
because they just go so far with the
actual handmade aspect of the brand that
just creates something that people can't
help but line up for, right? And pay
through the roof for as well. That's
business. Six books, six mental models.
Now, let's talk about something that's a
little bit close to home. Your health
and personal performance. Now, while
you're going through all these, you may
be suffering from certain problems
you're having going or you have big
goals in life. And what I've done is
I've synthesized my entire reading list
via the link in the description. And
I've put each book that I think is a
must- readad and then why you should
read it and what it will help you solve.
So, if you're interested in checking
that out, go and check it out via the
link in the description. Your body and
attention are the operating system that
everything around you runs on. So, if
you're not paying attention to them, you
know you're going to suffer. These are
the books that showed me how to work,
rest, and focus. And what I learned is
it's not just about the outputs in life.
It's about what you actually input into
your system to thrive as much as you
can. Deep Work by Callen Newport. Busy
all day, but you can't remember the last
time you created something that actually
mattered and that you were proud of.
Well, start here. Deep Work taught me
that focused attention is the new unfair
advantage. People do the most shallow
work ever. a little 30 minute thing
here, checking emails first thing in the
morning, you know, checking social media
as soon as they wake up. But what we've
lost sight of as humanity is that the
real genius, the real art, the real
beauty that has been created around us,
most of that has been created from deep
work. Know that sacred time that you
have every day to block out all
distractions and work on the thing that
is most important, that's going to move
you forward in the biggest way possible.
You know, these days now, I wake up
every day and from 8:00 a.m. till noon
every day, I have 4 hours of
uninterrupted time to work on the stuff
that only I can do. You know, if you're
looking to go and accomplish a
masterpiece with your life, this book is
a must. But focus without boundaries is
just burnout with better lighting.
Essentialism by Greg Macau. If you say
yes to everything and secretly resent
half the things on your calendar, you
need this. This book taught me that
saying no is how you protect what
matters. If you don't prioritize your
life, no one else will. You know,
there's constantly different things
tugging at our time. You know, family
have obligations. Society asks us to do
certain things. Work comes up. And at
the end of the day, we can lose track
of, you know, what we're really trying
to accomplish and how we want to go and
live our lives. This book taught me that
less but better, right? doing less
things, filling my schedule with less
stuff, going and surrounding myself with
less people, and focusing on quality
relationships, quality work, quality
days versus just being busy all the
time. And once you've cleared the noise,
here's how you think bigger. The Magic
of Thinking Big by David Schwarz. This
book is going to give you the kick in
the ass you need. This book taught me
one thing. Action cures fear. And most
of us think way too small in life. You
know, when I think about, you know, the
big vision I have for my life, the big
way I want to go and manage my
lifestyle, the big vision that I have
for Founder OS and my team and the
businesses and the community, the real
thing that comes there, right, is the
gap between, you know, where you are in
that big vision is action. Action cures
fear. You know, when you're not sure,
you should send that email, send the
damn thing. When you're not sure if you
should reach out to that mentor, reach
out to them. It's the action that you
take that's going to help you bit by
bit, tiny win by tiny win, get to where
you're looking to go. The Creative Act
by Rick Rubin. Remember when you used to
have ideas that actually excited you?
This book brings that back. Rick Rubin
taught me that creativity isn't about
output, it's about awareness. You know,
this book kind of gives me a sense of
like, you know, it's Rick Rubin, this
really successful music producer, one of
the most iconic, you know, people in the
music industry over the last hundred
years. It's got this mix of sort of
creativity, spirituality, and
philosophy. When we think about, you
know, pursuing some creative project,
often times we make it way too big in
our heads. And often times it's, you
know, is there that first little action
you can take that's going to create that
ripple effect that isn't only going to
impact the project, but as that project
gets released to the world, it's also
going to have that amazing ripple effect
in terms of the benefit you're going to
have to thousands, if not millions of
lives as well. And the best way to stay
creative, well, stay curious. Zen Mind,
Beginner's Mind by Shinru Suzuki. This
book is really good. If you're looking
to read a book that basically just feels
like a meditation. You know, when I read
the pages of this book, I really take it
in, slow down. I think this is one of
the most legendary books on Zen. I've
read it a few times in my life, but
often times just like to come back to
it, you know, every 18 months, 2 years,
just to kind of ground back in and root
myself into the beauty of the Zen
meditation process and way of thinking.
In the beginner's mind, there are many
possibilities. In the expert's mind,
there are few. You know, quotes like
this from the book get you thinking
about this idea of, you know,
simplifying your way of thinking. It's
not about trying to do everything in
life and getting so caught up in stress
and anxiety. At the end of the day, most
of our lives are actually really simple.
Die with Zero by Bill Perkins. Keep
telling yourself you'll travel, you'll
slow down, you'll finally do that thing
you've always wanted when you just hit
that next milestone. Well, this book
will get you to stop lying to yourself.
Die with Zero asked me, "What's the
point of being the richest person in the
graveyard?" And this book kind of made
me rethink how I think about my own
wealth at each age. You know, there are
core experiences that are best to do at
that given age. And so when you are
given the opportunity, you should just
go for it. As an example, you're in your
20s. It's a great chance to go
backpacking, go explore. Because if you
don't do that experience in your 20s,
you know, you may not have that
opportunity in your 40s when you have
kids and family and other obligations.
So you should just go for it. In your
30s, in your 40s or 50s, there's also
these sorts of experiences that come up.
You know, maybe going to Europe, going
to different vacations, going on
different experiences, flying out your
family to different things on your own
dime. You know, there's opportunities
that we can do to kind of live a
fulfilling life, but most people put off
living and just get so lost in the
day-to-day. And this book forces you to
kind of take a step back and go, you
know, all this money you're looking to
make, you know, what's it all for? The
Surrender Experiment by Michael Singer.
So deep in the grind that you forgot
what surrendering feels like. This book
taught me that letting go is key. Now,
this book taught me really the benefit
of surrendering. You know, I know in my
own life I often times have troubles
letting go. You know, we let stress,
anxiety, priorities all accumulate to a
point where sometimes it can kind of
break you. You know, there was a point
about a decade ago in my life where, you
know, I was under a ton of pressure and
it was causing me to crumble. This book
came to me almost at just like divine
timing. really then showed me this way
that this really successful entrepreneur
and spiritual teacher was able to start
incorporating the concept of
surrendering into more of his life to
really get over some insane challenges.
You know, letting go, I think, is
something that we need to practice,
right? Letting go of stress, letting go
of those difficult conversations,
letting go of the mistakes and the
failures that we've had. Let that
go. This book, you know, isn't just a
bunch of advice. It's telling the story
of Michael Singer's life. And along the
way, you can see these pivotal moments
where surrendering has helped him go and
evolve to a new level of a human. So
that's health. Seven books that taught
me to protect my energy, my health, and
you know, my vitality. Now, let's get on
to the third quadrant, relationships.
You can't scale a vision if you can't
communicate it. These are the books that
taught me to become a better leader by
talking less, listening more, and really
investing in communication in those
around me. The coaching habit by Michael
Stainer. You know, in this book, I
learned the one critical question. You
know, what is the real challenge for
you? And then the key follow-up question
when you're trying to help and coach,
whether it's your team or another
individual, what else? You know, often
times I think about leadership back in
the day, I would always default to I
need to talk. I need to be the one
owning the conversation. You know, often
times it's come at my detriment, right?
You just talk too much and listen far
too little. This book kind of goes
through a series of core questions that
are essential if you're really looking
to go and coach someone. I think when we
think of ourselves as CEOs or managers
or leaders in any aspect of our lives,
often times we can learn a ton from
being an amazing coach and the coaching
habit helps you do just that. But asking
questions only works if you're in the
right state. The 15 commitments of
conscious leadership. Walking into
meetings and feeling reactive and
defensive, well, it's not just your
strategy that's a problem. It's your
state. Now, this book taught me to have
an overall demeanor as a leader that was
much more curious, you know, versus
going and being accusatory of someone
that you think has done something wrong
or going and pointing out initially, you
know, the things that you need done. Can
you approach a given conversation with
your team, colleagues, family, whoever
in a way that's just much more curious,
inquisitive, and just ask questions? You
know, we all have these opinions and we
think that those opinions must be right.
But often times, you know, what's
actually true is that the opposite of
that opinion is equally as true, if not
more true. And so, if we can approach
conversations being more curious, we're
opening up an environment where we can
learn. We can come to some common
ground, and we can actually make 1 + 1
equal 10. And when you're in the right
state, here's how you connect. Quadrant
4, lifestyle. All the success in the
world means absolutely nothing if you're
miserable while you're living it. These
are the books that reminded me that
freedom, peace, and meaning are the real
skills and that you can actually grow
them by practicing them. Meditations by
Marcus Aurelius. Marcus Aurelius figured
out 2,000 years ago that the only thing
you can control is your mind, not all
the things around you. Meditations
taught me that I can't control events,
but I can control my response. You know,
it's duty over drama and really
practicing self-governance. You know, I
find myself often times if I'm not
careful, right, blaming external events
for how I feel. And the reality is is
that, you know, we can't control all the
things outside of us. What he had done
is at the end of every day kept this
private journal where he'd go and
document his own philosophy on life. And
it was always meant to just be this
private thing, but it was found
eventually it was published and it stood
the test of time. And so what you're
getting while you read this book is this
famous emperor's take on how he was able
to manage his own energy, his mindset
amidst all the turbulence of life. The
psychology of money by Morgan Howell.
Morgan Howell is by far probably my
favorite author. This book taught me
that wealth is about what you don't see.
Everyone's financial behavior is
actually emotional, right? Often times
it's not logical. At the end of the day,
the money, the wealth, it's all about
peace of mind. And the core metric
behind peace of mind is sleep at night.
And so when you're thinking about
investments or money, what you really
should just be thinking about is does
this thing that I'm about to buy or this
money I'm about to make, does it get me
more peace of mind and does it allow me
to sleep at night? There are sometimes
these investments that we can make that
don't necessarily make financial sense,
but they do bring us peace of mind. For
some people, I know that's like buying
their house. you know, they know they're
not going to make a lot of money on it
over time, but it just makes them feel
good knowing that they have a home base.
They're safe, they're secure, you know,
make sure that you're thinking about
that, right? Taking care of your peace
of mind, not just your bank account. And
if you want to be truly wealthy, here's
what the Stoics knew. A Guide to the
Good Life by William B. Irvine. The
Stoics show you that comfort makes you
weak. And Irvine shows you how to stay
sharp. One of the most powerful lessons
I learned from this book was this idea
of negative visualization. Often times,
you know, we'll find ourselves maybe
walking on the street and all we're
circulating our mind is all these
negative thoughts, how our life could be
better, how we could be doing more, how
we screwed up that thing. Sometimes it's
just useful to visualize, well, this
morning when you were walking, you could
have just gotten hit by a bus yesterday.
You know, when you were playing that
sport, you know, you could have died on
the field. And when you start to think
about, okay, life could be so much
worse than it is right now. Suddenly,
you leave yourself with just some
gratitude. Another thing I took from the
book is the idea of practicing voluntary
friction. Going for hard workouts every
day or taking on some difficult
challenge or doing things that you know
make you feel uncomfortable every single
day because it kind of sharpens iron.
And here's the freedom that comes from
that. The courage to be disliked at
Chiro Kushimi. Managing everyone's
opinions is exhausting. And this book
shows you how to stop. This book taught
me that other people's approval isn't my
task. I had a buddy Steve years ago that
when I started building my personal
brand, he goes, "Matt, you know, why are
you doing that? Why are you trying to be
famous?" The reality was I wasn't doing
it to be famous, right? I was doing it
because I knew I could have a big
impact. And to me, it kind of fit my
core zone of brilliance. I just had to
do what I knew was right and go and get
out there, build content, grow my
audience, and make something that I
wanted to make that I knew could help a
lot of people's lives. And this was the
genesis of Founder OS, which is, you
know, this amazing community of high
growth entrepreneurs that I've created.
And the reality is is that you have to
have courage to be disliked. You have to
have courage to just be your true self.
Don't wait for the crowd to applaud you.
Don't wait for that friend to pat you on
the back. Give yourself the pat on the
back you need and just do that thing
that sits in your soul that you know you
were meant to do. The Almanac of Naval
Ravocon by Eric Jorgensson. Naval taught
me to play long-term games with
long-term people. You know, when you're
going and building a team, building a
business, surrounding yourself with
people, ideally, you want to have a
circle that you can keep for the next
20, 30, 40, 50 years until you die.
Every business, whether you are aware of
it or not, is really a people business.
Make sure you're surrounding yourself
with people that you want to do life
with. One of the quotes that helped
change my approach to things was earn
with your mind, not your time. And from
the exercises he recommended in the
book, I came up with this ambitious
hourly rate. And from there was able to
start going and delegating, deleting or
automating the core things in my life
that I knew I shouldn't be doing any
longer. And here's how you use chaos to
grow. Antifragile by Nasim Talib.
Antifragile taught me to really benefit
from volatility, not just survive it.
You know, I remember in life at certain
times there's been, you know, a lot of
my friends or the world that has been
scared to go and start things. But it's
in those moments that I actually see the
greatest point of opportunity. Some of
my businesses have actually been born in
some of the biggest crisises out there
in the financial markets. You know, it
was in those moments when everyone else
was panicking. I was able to go and
really build something seriously
valuable by staying focused and building
a business as well that was
anti-fragile. This book gives you some
of the core tenants to anti-fragility
and how to go and implement them in your
life today. Wabishabi by Naboo Suzuki.
The Japanese mastered imperfection 400
years ago and it will save you from
perfectionism today. Wabishabi taught me
that beauty lies in imperfection. You
know, when I first started going and
sharing content online, as an example, I
thought that everything had to be
immaculate. The sound, the color, the
design, my outfit, my on camera
presence, it all had to be perfect. I
had to say the exact words. So much so
that I thought the only way to go and
deliver content was, you know, I needed
a teleprompter because I needed to make
sure that every word was immaculate.
What I quickly learned was that Matt,
people are watching these videos cuz
they want to get to know you, your
insights, your playbooks, your systems,
and also just your vibe and your energy.
This concept of wabishabi really helped
me out in life because, you know, it's
this beautiful Japanese philosophy of
that there's actually a ton of beauty in
those imperfections and that it's
through those little chips in how we say
something, those little mistakes that we
make, those little isms that make us
unique that actually help us create
something beautiful that's recognizable
um and that people can really resonate
with. If even one lesson from these
books hits you today, well, go and apply
it. You know, don't wait for tomorrow.
go and take the book that really stuck
out to you the most and go and get it
and start applying it to your life and
your business today. Along the way, if
you want to go and see my whole reading
list as well as recommendations as to
the best book that you should read based
on the maybe the different problems or
goals you have in your life, you can go
and check that out via the first link in
the description below. Go and get that
in the description. I can't wait to see
you in the next video. Go and watch this
video on how to go and level up your
life in an insanely simple way. And I'll
see you in the next one. Let's win
together.