Here's the harsh truth. Being busy isn't
the same as being productive. I used to
work 16-our days thinking I was making
progress until I realized I was
completely burnt out. The moment I
started building systems, everything
[music] changed. Now, I've built and
scaled multiple successful online
businesses that make millions in profit,
all while living life on my own terms.
[music] So, in this video, I'm going to
walk you through the five core systems
that will help you hit your goals
faster, [music]
get more of your time back, so you can
focus on what really matters in life.
The first system is the 30-day vision.
This might be the most important system
I've ever developed, and it's so simple.
I've been using this template for the
last 15 years of my life, and it's been
enormously helpful in helping me design
the life and business of my dreams.
You've probably heard of the 8020
principle before. Well, when you 8020
the 8020 principle, what you get is the
[music] 4% formula, which really goes
and dictates that 4% of your actions are
going to lead to 64% of your results.
Think about that, right? What is the 4%
that's going to go and lead to 64% of
the benefit? So, first off, we're going
to [music] go and kind of chart out our
vision here. So, what's the one word for
this month? I'm going to put in
unstoppable. That's what we're going for
here. Now, when I think about the dream
outcome for the month, right, this could
be anything. It could be a revenue goal
you have, a profit goal, could be a
health goal. I'll go and put here 800k
of revenue, let's just say. Okay, that's
going to give us what we need to go and
invest in some insane stuff we have
coming down the line. And how I want to
feel at the end of the month. So, how I
always want to feel is I want to feel
peaceful
and calm. Now, when I think about the
one domino, what's that one thing I need
to do to really achieve these big goals
that I have in life? You know, inside of
founder OS, it's the content that builds
the movement that drives founders to us.
And that is one of the core flywheels.
It's really the founder flywheel that
exists inside of our business. It all
comes down to [music] exceptional
content creation. Now, why this matters?
Well, for me, you know, my mission is to
really go and unlock human potential. My
goal is to help 100 million founders
accomplish their dreams through proven
systems. And each piece of content that
we put out gets us one step closer
[music] to that big, hairy, audacious
goal. Now, I like to get into the one
things. What's that one thing that you
can do in these four areas of your life?
Your [music] business, your personal
growth, your health, your relationships
that when you do that thing, it makes
everything else easier or unnecessary.
[music]
And so when we think about business
growth, the one thing is say creating
two amazing YouTube videos [music] per
week. On the personal growth side of
things, okay, for me, the one thing
there is to make sure [music] that I get
4 hours of founder flow every single
day. So 4 hours daily
of founder flow
and then when it comes to my health one
thing currently I'm going to berries
every single morning 6:00 a.m. to 7:00
a.m. here in London England. So that's
what we're going to keep doing you know
just those hit workouts every morning.
[music] Then you know on the
relationship family one thing let's just
put here call my parents weekly. So on
the execution side of things, we now
want to think about, okay, week by week,
what do we [music] need to do to go and
ladder up to these big goals that we
have for the given month. So for me,
it's maybe hiring a new editor, building
a new company dashboard, getting [music]
the team retreat going to create maximum
alignment amongst our entire team at
Founder OS, [music] and then hosting an
epic bully retreat here at the end of
the month um for 50 special [music]
founders inside of Founder OS. Now the
constraint right now is as we're scaling
up the video engine is that [music]
honestly we need another video editor.
So you know I've gone and put that as
the constraint here and hey if you know
anyone tell them to reach out and you
saw that right that was like 3 minutes
you can go and spend 3 minutes right now
like right now [music] and go and fill
this out for yourself so that you go and
set yourself up for the best month of
your life. So go check that out via the
link in the description. System number
two is radical deletion. Imagine trying
to clean your room but not even taking
the trash out inside [music] of it.
Right? And the same thing goes for your
life. We oftenimes think that to become
the person we're looking to become or to
create the business of our dreams, we
need to keep adding things. But often
[music] times the best approach is
radical deletion. You know, going and
stripping away all the noise, the
clutter, [music] the stuff that's just
distracting you. The system I use before
I actually go and build a system is that
I ask myself, what can I remove? You
know, I look at myself like, you know,
Matt, [music] you know, eight years ago,
right? Here I was and, you know, I was
smoking way too much. I was consuming
way too many substances. [music]
I had a lot of toxic people in my life
that I allowed just bring me down.
[music] I had multiple different
ventures I was focused on all at once.
And, you know, honestly, I was
incredibly distracted. And so what I
realized [music] is that first things
first, before I just built some insane
system around what I was doing, [music]
I actually had to start with just
deleting so much of this. So, you know,
I became sober. I cleaned up more of my
friend group. I got clear on just one
thing [music] I wanted to build, which
became founder OS. I started stripping
away all these habits that were not
supporting me. I was really radical
about this. If there's something that I
wasn't a hell yes about, I just [music]
deleted it. The same thing goes for your
life, right? What are the relationships
that are no longer supporting you?
Delete them. What are those health
habits that are actually moving you
further away from your goals? Delete
that So, here are the three steps
you need to go and build a more simple
life and be able to actually go and run
this radical deletion process in your
own life today. Number one is you need
to do a deletion audit. [music] Number
two is then when you look at the stuff
that's left, what's more of that stuff
that you could automate to get more of
your time back? And then thirdly, is
there anything that you can go and
delegate that's currently on your plate?
You know, then what you're left with is
[music] just the few core things that
exist inside of your zone of brilliance.
The stuff that you are uniquely capable
of, the stuff that's in your circle of
competence. You don't need new habits.
You need fewer bad ones. System number
three is the northstar principle. This
applies to your business, but it also
applies to every relationship in your
life. If you don't share the why, people
won't care about the what. [music] So we
need a system that translates meaning to
those around us. So whenever I'm
building a new business, I like to have
people in the room with me where we can
actually go and chart out the vision for
that company. You know, the vision for
found is something that I've constructed
closely with my sister who's my chief of
staff. And so you know how I look at the
vision is [music] it's kind of broken up
into 10ear, 3year, 1 year, and then
90day goals. All right, so let's first
start off with the 10year [music] goals.
All right, these are the ones that
should fire you up, get you insanely
excited for what you're building. Well,
first off, I want to have [music]
founder retreat centers globally so that
founders can share peak experiences with
one another. In addition to that, I want
to ladder up all of our YouTube content
[music] here to getting a show on
Netflix. So, we'll put that there. I
also want to make sure um that we just
have a remarkable company [music]
culture. So, you know, amazing A players
all across the [music] company. When it
comes then to the three-year vision of
what I need to do to ladder up to that,
you know, we [music] need to get our
newsletter to 3 million subs. Okay? And
it's well on its way, just [music]
crossed around 300K subscribers. In
addition to that, we need to continue to
grow the audience around Founder OS
[music] and this amazing movement that
we're building, the Founder Freedom
Movement to over 12 million people
across social. Now on [music] the team
side, what that needs to be is that we
just continue to reinforce, you know,
the company culture and our values over
the next year. The things that will help
me go and build out this audience. It'll
help our team scale. Well, there's a
number of [music] things. We need to
have an amazing, say, company dashboard
to show us all the core metrics. I need
to get my book published once and for
all. So, the [music] book needs to be
released.
In addition to that, we need to grow
social to an audience of over [music] 5
million people on social. Okay. So,
we've got all of that detailed out. And
then what I'm able to do then is then
take all of that and then create [music]
clear 90-day goals. So, right now to hit
our content goals, we need to hire a
video editor.
We also need [music] to
go and finish the manuscript of the
book.
And then lastly, we are going to host a
team retreat. Um, so the team can come
together in Bali and jam on the 2026
plan. So here you can see, you know, the
10-year, 3year, and one-year [music]
goals all synthesized that then allow me
to go and make sure that what I'm
working on for the remainder of this
year go and ladder up to the big goals
that I have in my life. So, [music] if
you're serious about actually going and
accomplishing what you're looking to do,
first off, you need to go and map out
your northstar just like I've done it
here. Now, if you want this template,
again, [music] go and get it via the
link in the description. Now, in
addition to that, what you want to do is
go a layer deeper and make [music] sure
that you start going and really talking
about this vision with your team, with
your audience, your community, so that
people start to kind of band around it
because [music]
nothing goes and motivates people more
than a compelling vision. And so, you
need to go and map out your vision today
so you can start building that movement
around you. System number four is
drawing the blueprint. Do you even
understand something if you can't draw
it out on a napkin? I remember when I
was first going and building founder OS,
I knew that I should build a business so
simple that I could draw it on a onepage
flowchart [music]
and then make sure that over time that I
have key owners for each aspect of the
business so that it's as simple, it's as
peaceful and profitable as possible. So,
first things first here, right, we start
with the content side of things, right?
Which is really the fuel for how it all
grows. You know, at first I had started
on X and LinkedIn and then over time
brought all of that writing I was doing
to platforms like IG, YouTube and to Tik
Tok. Okay. And this part is all [music]
owned by a content manager on my team
named Diego. Okay. Inevitably, the
content is going to lead to leads
[music] being generated, right? And
first things first, that is an owned
audience inside of a newsletter. We have
a weekly newsletter going out and this
is owned by someone on my team named
Niels. [music] Okay. Now, inevitably as
people go and book sales calls with us
and [music] you know we make sales. This
kind of process and all the sales area
of my company is managed by a guy named
Zach. Okay? And so things like sales
call reviews, the sales script, the
different payment links, all that stuff
is owned in sales. Now you got to
actually go and deliver on that thing.
And so the delivery behind Founder OS is
simple. Okay, we have systems,
we have support,
and we have community. Okay, a community
of over 800 high growth founders, over
180 powerful systems that I've used to
build multiple profitable companies and
support through over 50 live [music]
sessions every single month with my
team. And so in this area, this is all
owned by a gentleman named Shawn. Now,
you're delivering on the given thing,
okay? But as part of that too obviously
you need to write collections department
right or finance function in your
company. So here you know it's all the
finance functions around you know
accounts receivable reporting all that
good stuff. And so that is all owned by
someone on my team named Hayden. Okay.
And then obviously once we've collected
cash the key thing here then is you've
delivered an amazing service. People are
really fired up. You essentially want to
drive renewals
and recommendations, okay? People
leaving amazing reviews,
right? And then people being upsold to
bigger offerings. We have all of this
process so far gives us an enormous
amount of data. That's all tracked
inside of a CEO dashboard [music] that
I've created inside of Founder OS. And
this is owned by someone on my team
named Dawn. [music] Now, as we start to
collect all this data, okay, we can
essentially go and actually drive
insights from the data, which is
honestly the most valuable part of it
all, right? Because, you know, it's one
thing to actually collect data, it's
another thing to actually then use it to
inform different areas of the business.
So, the insights here come through a
weekly report that is generated, okay?
And that is owned by Nick on my team.
Okay? So, so the insights that we go and
generate then are able to go and fuel
our approach to audience growth. Okay,
we get different insights as an example
that let's just say a lot of founders
are actually really obsessed with
getting their time back. Well, we're
going to then go and use those insights
to go and create [music] more high
converting content, okay? And the type
of content that you know you guys
actually care about. So, we're making
more of the stuff that you guys are
signaling to us that you really want to
see and less of the stuff that honestly
you don't care about. So, on that side,
it's a gentleman named Yan on my team
that owns that. That audience growth,
right, then feeds in to our content GPS,
which is [music] the most powerful
system I've ever created. Okay? And that
really consists of an amazing video, an
application,
okay? and then a a smart router that
routes the right people um to [music]
the right product for them, right?
Because there's a bunch of different
offerings that we have for different
[music] kinds of founders. And then you
guessed it, right? We generate, you
know, a lot of insights from that as
well that feed our content. And this
whole thing creates this amazing
flywheel behind Founder [music] OS by
just simply drawing it like this where
it's like simply laid out. All these
like nine pieces are all labeled.
There's a key [music] stage, some
bullets underneath it, and then an
owner. I can really just get a snapshot
of what this business is supposed to
become. Now, every time I create any
system, it always starts with pen and
paper. So, before you make a system or a
plan, just draw it up. Put the nine
different stages or seven different
stages. Put a key owner and then the key
bullet points for each aspect. And then
look at it and ask yourself, you know,
where's this going to break? and start
building different redundancies there so
that you have a strong simple system. If
you can draw it like I've just shown
you, you can achieve it. This leads you
to my next point that AI eats systems
for [music] breakfast. This is where
you're going to get insane leverage if
your systems are documented. All right,
so as with most things, I'm a lot better
at showing you than telling you. So what
I've gone here is I've opened up the
Claude app on my desktop here. So
[music] inside a claude you can see that
all the core systems that I've made and
that I've even shown you here [music]
they become claude project. So a system
becomes a project. Say as we've gone
through things right I showed you that
map that I made of my entire business
for founder OS. Now I've gone and made
that whole image and system into a
project called clockwork to basically
ensure that my business runs like
clockwork. Each project can now have its
own memory and instructions. So I can go
and add in [music] clear instructions
that allow me to go and scale my
business to hit its revenue goals,
profit goals, and the overall mission,
vision, [music]
and values that we have, right? And so
what I get here is almost like a COO at
my fingertips. And so [music] you can do
the same with your Claude project,
right? Set up projects for your [music]
different systems. Make sure that you
add in really detailed instructions. As
you can see here with mine, you know,
we're talking like two, [music] three
page prompts here, right? They get into
the exact words I use, [music] the exact
systems that I have. I help it go and
map out different strategies to get
found from where it is today to $20
million a year. I use it to go and run
different reports and analysis on the
company to go and find the most high
lever tasks that I have. And I use it
also in those monthly plans that I
started this video [music] with so that
I can go and outline, okay, well, what's
the one thing I should be most focused
on [music] this month? This is what the
future of entrepreneurship and really
high growth individuals looks like,
right? It's yes, being systemized, but
[music] it's not optional anymore,
right? So, what do you need to do to
take advantage of all this? Well, number
one, you need to go and document your
core systems. [music] Number two is that
you need to go and then build leverage
by running those by others in your life
to refine them. Number three is then you
want to make sure that every system has
an owner. And number four, in the
[music] new AI era, you need to make
sure that every system you create has a
project inside of Claude or Chat GBT.
From there, number five is that like
anything in life, right? It's about
iterating, making the project better,
the instructions better, the outputs
better. [music]
This is how you go and build a legendary
life. And this is also how you go and
accomplish your dreams 10x [music]
faster than those around you. So, if you
want to go and set up your claw the same
way I've set up all my projects, well, I
provided you with a complete guide via
the link in the description. So, go and
check that out [music] and go and take
action building these things today. At
the end of the day, freedom doesn't come
from working harder. It comes from
building better systems. Start small,
keep it simple, and remember, the more
clearly you can think, the more leverage
you create. If you like this video,
don't forget to subscribe and go and
check out this video [music]