Most creators guess what content to
make. I use AI to create content for me
that'll make me millions. All right. So,
what we're going to do here is leverage
Fathom AI, which can go and record calls
that you're having to then be able to
replicate the voice of my dream
customers, feed that into Chat GBT, and
then use that to create things like
landing page copy, email copy, and a lot
more. Right here, I have a full doc that
is all of our paid and full deals over
the last month. We've gone and simply
pulled these transcripts from Fathom AI,
gone and copied these into a Google doc.
I can then go and download this doc and
upload it to a voice of customer project
that I've created inside of chatb. This
voice of customer doc has a project
instruction to it that says, you know,
to transform real customer language into
high converting marketing copy. From
there, I can use it to create things
like headlines for my website, CTA lines
for different calls or workshops. I can
use it for things like email subject
lines as well as social and video hooks
for platforms like Instagram and on