Jan 12 avalanche gear ready to go.
[Music]
It's like 20 years ago if you told me
I'd be snowboarding with some of my best
friends here in Japan, I tell you,
you're freaking crazy. But here we are,
a dream come true. Now, I've been
thinking a lot about just loosening the
grip on life. You know, if you're
putting in the work, you got good
systems, you got amazing people around
you, like my friend Jordan here behind
the camera, you can kind of just let God
take the wheel, you know, and good
things happen. It's been good to
disconnect, enjoy some backcountry, some
adventures, fun, play, and complete
serenity out here in
Dece. Let's go.
[Music]
Woo! That's how we do
it. I think 97% of founders out there,
you know, they just don't prioritize
peace. You know, my motto over the last
decade has been peace, profit, and
purpose. And as I go into 2025, it's
really that peace component that I'm
leading into. Peaceful people around me,
peaceful
operations, and just an overall peaceful
culture. So that you're building a
company that you could spend the rest of
your life doing. And that's what I think
contributes to everyday retirement.
Waking up every single day working on
stuff that brings you joy that even if
you were retired, you'd be living the
exact day that you're doing that day.
And so that's exactly what we're doing
out here in Japan. Everyday retirement,
baby. All right. So this morning, woke
up, started kind of planning out the
future vision for this channel and for
the video side of the Founder US brand.
The goal really to create this Pixar for
founders, make something inspiring,
insanely creative, and help you go with
proven systems, build your
dreams. This afternoon now, we're on an
artist date, just cruising around Tokyo.
Going to find some inspiring sites to
fuel creativity, get some new
ideas, have a bit of fun.
[Music]
You got to pinch yourself, you know.
What a city. What a life. Being able to
travel the world, work from anywhere.
This is
[Music]
living. Octopus ball. You want one?
All right. Wow, these are like fluffy.
Oh my god. Why is it
chopsticks? So hot.
So I like to do what I call artist dates
about once every month when I sobered up
6 years ago. Stop smoking weed, stop
drinking. I read a book called The
Artist Way. And it encourages you every
single week to just go do something
different. That could be going to an art
gallery, a museum, getting a coffee by
yourself, going to nature, doing
something just to kind of escape the
general vibe of day-to-day life. And so
today, we're just going on a random
adventure around Tokyo. No destination
of mind. Just an artist day, just time
to kind of rest your brain, be creative,
explore different places, new sites, new
people, new vibes, and yeah, just coffee
every hour. You know, the deal.
[Music]
Damn.
So, one of the things I think is like
crazy about when you're building an
audience is not just the fact that now
you can find customers and you know you
can grow an audience and a community for
your business, but that just yeah, you
can have random encounters with cool
people. Met a fellow Canadian here in
Tokyo. Now just getting a tour. Ended up
finding then a videographer. You know,
serendipity happens when you're, you
know, growing an online audience. But I
know you had some questions you wanted.
If you were starting out, what systems
would you set in place for maximum
success? I talk about it all the time,
but growing an audience, building an
online personal brand, literally changed
my life. And it's something that when I
look back on my career, I regret not
doing it sooner. And so organic content
on things like YouTube, Instagram X,
LinkedIn, you know, doing it in a way
that it's not just enjoyable, but is
scalable over time so that you can have
fun, be an artist online, and share your
message with a bunch of people uh and
connect with folks. So when you were
building your first business, if you
were going to create content then, what
kind of content would you have created?
You don't need to create necessarily.
It's more just documenting, right?
Documenting your journey. You know, what
are the challenges you're going through?
What are the wins that you've had? What
did you learn this week? you know, not
overthinking it. I think the thing that
stops a lot of first-time creators is
that they feel like they're not good
enough or they don't know enough about
business to start making content. If you
were first starting out, how would you
have approached content creation? What a
lot of people I think get tripped up on
is that they think they need to have it
all figured out at the get- go, right?
The truth is that you launch and then
you figure it out. like the process of
actually just taking action, putting
content out there, you know, making
mistakes, looking like an idiot. It's
the process that then allows you to
learn what your voice is, what your
message is, what your mission is even,
right? So, same thing on YouTube. I just
kind of versus starting being like, oh,
I need to be at 10,000 subscribers in 6
months. I just told myself, I'm going to
make aundred YouTube videos that I'm
proud of. They could be around my
interests, my passions, my strengths,
different experiences I'm going through,
personal stories, just experimenting,
right? The truth is out the gate, you're
likely not going to know what your niche
is. You're not going to know what topics
you maybe want to talk about, and that's
okay. I think it's just getting going
and remembering, too, that you can
change your niche any day. Amazing.
Thanks so much. Yeah, of course. Here we
go. That was awesome. It was good.
[Music]
All right, we're just wrapping up a
4hour drive from Tokyo to Hakoba. Got
about four or five days of backcountry
snowboarding coming in. We are in for an
adventure to say the least. Got my
trusty guy over here. Thanks for the
ride, man.
All right, here we go. Day one. Kuba.
[Music]
Damn, has this ever been the experience
of a lifetime. Soaking up Japanuary and
the Japow. Been out here enjoying time
with friends. This is the kind of
stuff that I've dreamt about for years.
Being able to enjoy nature with friends,
take a break, unplug,
recharge,
relax, let my mind
wander, embrace boredom, and then refuel
myself for the epic year
ahead. But one major lesson and thing
I've been thinking about a lot lately is
this
concept of loosening the grip on life.
You know, if you're putting in good
work, you're building a good team,
you're building strong systems, you
know, you're creating content daily,
you're growing a personal brand, at some
point, you just got to loosen your grip
and let compounding work its magic. I
know sometimes I'm guilty, right, of
just like holding on to things so
tightly, you know, making sure that
every single thing is done just the
right way. And and I think that's
important in many senses. I think that
founders and CEOs are like chief detail
officers overlooking every little piece
of the business to make sure that it's
running just right. There's also that
counterbalance of loosening our grip,
having belief in our team, trusting the
process. And so I've been reminding
myself every day, every morning as I go
through my vision kind of my early
morning manifestation journal, what are
ways that I can loosen the grip, trust
that team member more?
Let that system run
itself. Take some space away from things
to
bring newfound
creativity, a restored sense of
rejuvenation, and just let my inner
child play. I'm actually flying in a few
team members to Bali. We're going to be
doing some creative jams. We've charted
out a pretty ambitious vision for the
next 5 years for the company. a vision
that's equally exciting and scary cuz in
some senses it's really pushing us to
levels that I don't think any of us had
previously thought possible. But that's
the fun of it all, right? So I figured
instead of going and, you know, living
in a world where August 2025, you know,
the year is going, we're halfway through
it and we're looking at each other
going, "Ah man, we're not quite where we
needed to be. Not quite where we wanted
to be, you know, we're not we're not
doing it big enough." I figured, let's
not even allow that moment to happen. I
don't even want to exist in a world
where that conversation is even
possible. So, I asked myself, well, how
do I avoid that conversation in August
then? Right? How do we make sure that
we're attacking this year? We're hitting
the ground running. The momentum is
palpable. And I figured, well, just
bring the people together. Bring the
legends to Bali. We are going to be
jamming on the upcoming experiences that
we're running for founders. Uh the new
systems that we're launching inside of
Founder OS. Uh the new team members that
we've brought on board and making sure
that they're onboarded. New team members
that we're hiring, which we have about
five open roles right now. And so things
are growing, things are moving, but
growth isn't the goal here. For me, what
fires me up is the art of
entrepreneurship. I want to build
something that's beautiful, that's
inspiring, that stands for
craftsmanship, obsession, and next level
quality. And quality to me is about the
details. It's about every interaction,
every email, every pixel, every piece of
content, every word. Because when you
stack up each of those details, that's
what creates an emotion. So follow
along. We got some cool stuff
planned. Life is good.