I built a successful media company that
uses custom AI to go and comb through
Reddit comments to discover what content
I should create. [music] This is
actually insane. Reddit is a gold mine
for customer insights. [music] And just
a side note, even if you're just
starting a business, this thing will
work for you as well. Here's how this
[music] works. It's going to go and
target your dream clients inside of the
different subreddits that they exist in.
[music] It's going to go and comb
through every single post and not just
the posts themselves, but all of the
nested comments within those posts.
[music] Every single piece of content
then passes through our AI, which we
call the angle finder, which is going to
go and find 13 different marketing
angles to go and hit people with based
on [music] the different insights that
we gather from these subreddits. And so
you're getting this massive database of
customer sentiment [music] and how the
trend line of your customers is changing
so that you have the most up-to-date
strategies every given month and are
tapping into the core things people are
talking about and [music] inserting your
brand into those conversations. If you
want to learn how this architecture
works under the hood, well, you guessed
it.
>> [music]