if you find yourself not wanting to get
out of bed in the morning then you need
a new vision for your life something
that excites you a destination that
makes you enjoy every step of the
journey ask yourself what your best life
looks like what will you have achieved
how will you feel about yourself how
will you look what are you working on if
your vision doesn't set your soul on
fire then go back dig deeper dream
bigger think of an insane 10-year goal
that lights you up break it down into
three-year goals into one-ear goals into
90-day goals start taking Massive Action
knowing that each day is an opportunity
to bring you closer to your dream