Building a customized chatbot and then
selling access to it is an actual money
glitch. I created a bespoke AI chatbot.
Her name is Arya. Well, [music]
actually, she named herself. And I use
this for the customer service across all
of my companies. And even [music] if you
don't have a business, I promise you,
you can go and train an AI agent on
everything you do. Whether you're in
real estate, education, parenting,
hacks, you name it. So, let me go and
show you how valuable this is for my
company, Founder OS. The cool thing is
that Arya, for most of our founders,
lives inside of our Founder OS Slack
community and you can just go and chat
directly with Arya and get answers in
seconds. Most importantly, she scales
without [music] me. Because of this AI
agent, I'm able to spend way more of my
time on higher [music] leverage tasks
like hiring people, strategy, and
building exceptional content. Let me
know in the comments if you want me to
do a deep dive video on Arya. [music]
And if you want to go and get your own
access to Arya, you should definitely go
and check out Founder OS via the link in
the description.