Most people focus on getting more
followers. Smart people focus on what
happens after someone follows them. When
someone discovers you, what happens
next? Let's get into the details here,
right? From a given piece of content on
social media, you're going to drive
people to some sort of email landing
page. It could be to your newsletter or
to a more specific email course. And
from there, they get put into a 5-day
educational email course, and then a
4-day FOMO series. So, the 5-day email
course is educating them and giving them
the value on the thing that they signed
up for. The FOMO series, though, is part
of the magic here. We have them going
through the FOMO series and at any point
in time clicking a dynamic CTA that
exists in those emails and monetizing
those people. What you're doing in those
four emails is driving people more
directly to the sale. You just have this
running on autopilot, and what happens
is your infrastructure is essentially a
salesperson [music]
that never sleeps. It's this
infrastructure that makes all the
difference as you're building your
founder-led brand.