Perfectionism costs way more than
failure. Thousands, if not millions of
other people also struggle with this
same limiting belief before launching
something. There's this myth in
entrepreneurship that you need to have
it all figured out and then launch it.
When the truth is that you launch it and
then you figure it out. The ship messy
protocol all comes down to launching
something when it's at 70%. Mark
Zuckerberg famously said, "Move fast and
break things." And this is what has made
him one of many Silicon Valley
billionaires. And the truth is that when
you're building something, you just need
to get it out there. People would much
rather have a 70% solution today than
something 100% in 3 years. The market,
AI, everything is moving so fast these
days. And speed is your competitive
advantage as a founder.