I grew from zero to 368,000 [music]
followers on X using a simple system.
But the best part wasn't how easy or how
fast I grew. It was all the connections
I made with Fortune 500 CEOs, legendary
founders, and best-selling authors that
opened up a world of new opportunities
for me. [music] So, in this video, I'm
going to share my sevenstep system to
grow an X so you can go and connect with
the top 1% and grow an audience that
changes your life. Let's get [music]
into it. Step one, study the masters.
You really need to go and study the best
of the best on the platform and start to
pick up on the patterns of success.
[music] X is like a copywriting
Olympics. When I started studying some
of the greatest on the platform, people
like Naval Ravocon, Ryan Holiday, and
James Clear, their content wasn't just
amazingly valuable, right? But it was
also life affirming. It got you [music]
thinking, right? I think this idea of
creating stuff that's novel and
non-obvious is important, right? One
example of a legend that [music] I found
myself studying was Naval Ravakon who to
a lot of founders is [music] like one of
the goats. There's this post that he has
on how to get rich without getting
lucky. So as I [music] went and
dissected some of these top posts that
ever were posted on the platform, I
started to notice a lot of patterns.
Right? [music] First off, the hook of
this post is super simple, right? It's
just one sentence and it's got also the
parenthesis going on, right? kind of
[music] giving you just something a
little bit contrarian. Then from there,
you know, each of the individual tweets
underneath is super easy to read, really
short sentences, really compelling copy,
right? [music] Over the years, um, I've
gone and, you know, applied this to, you
know, a lot of my own copy, right?
Making it specific and actionable. Um,
and [music] it's worked right here. If
we go and look at the Read Wise
leaderboard over the last [music]
3 years after putting out, you know,
hundreds of posts, I'm actually now the
sixth [music]
most saved thread writer on the entire
platform ever. [music] Um, which is
pretty insane. I see it kind of like a
chef refining their pallet for amazing
food. Same thing here, right? is as
you're writing, you're able [music] to
go and curate some of the best writing
that's ever existed on the platform and
study [music] the patterns. You know,
the sentence structures, the words they
use, how they start different sentences,
[music] what are the common sort of
phrases you see coming up, and how can
you go and apply that pallet [music] of
copywriting to the different ideas that
you're looking to put out there. Often
times, it's not just the idea [music]
that's going to spread, right? It's how
you package that idea. You can have
[music] run-on sentences and complex
thinking that allows it to go nowhere.
Where [music] on the other side, you
have short sentences that have a rhythm
to it that when people read it, it feels
like a symphony and they can't help but
go and share it with their entire
audience. And what we're trying to do
here is the ladder. So, here's how you
go and then put this into practice.
[music]
You're going to want to go and create an
X swipe file. What I'd encourage you to
go and do is start bookmarking the top
posts [music] on X that when you read
that post, you can't help but save it.
Okay? Then you can go and take the top
[music] 20 ever, right, that have
inspired you the most and go and copy
and paste those into a Google doc. This
becomes your kind of [music] source of
inspiration for the stuff that you're
going to put out. And so as you start
going and writing your own ideas to
share on [music] X, make sure that they
feel like they're in the same league as
that best content [music] ever.
Initially, I think when people get going
on these platforms, they don't realize
the bar that exists, the stuff that
people are used to seeing if [music]
they're really going to save and share
it. And doing this little bit of upfront
homework, right, is going to allow it
your writing sessions to be that much
more impactful. Step two is about
finding your true voice. So for the
first 60 days of sharing content, I
didn't really have a clue what I was
doing. [music] Now, as I kept on putting
in the reps, right, I started to
discover my own voice, right? The kind
of stuff that I enjoyed creating and
that I could tell that the audience on X
was also enjoying. What I started to
realize was that I was appealing more to
a psychoraphic, right? A group of people
just like me, you know, kind of like me
five years ago. Someone that's looking
to level up, get the right systems in
[music] place, scale with organic
content, remove themselves from
operations, build a business that runs
itself, and so forth. And from that,
over time, I emerged as this [music]
systems guy on X. And these also became
the perfect tie-in to founder OS [music]
and what we really do inside of this
amazing community of high growth
founders. So your positioning statement
has [music] three parts. First is your
thesis. Second are the three components
that make the thesis true [music] and
the third is your mechanism. So the next
aspect here is then once you've got your
positioning [music] statement nailed,
you want to go and think about your dos
and don'ts, right? The kind of stuff
that you want to lean into on the
platform and the stuff that you want to
avoid. And so, as an example, for me,
early days, it was really leaning into
getting specific [music] in every post I
create, sharing numbers, sharing the
details, going and getting into the what
and the how I did things, right? So,
there was no fluff. And [music] so, what
you want to do is probably flush out
five dos, five don'ts, and then just get
going with this as your initial
guidelines. From there, you really want
to go and start writing 10 posts as if
you're just going and talking to a
friend. That allows me to [music] speak
in my authentic voice. So, we're not
trying to use a bunch of industry jargon
or verbose right? Just talk
basically and start attracting people
based on that authentic voice you have.
Step three, create your writing system.
Now that you know what type of content
works in your voice, it's time to build
your writing system. The reality was
that as I kept on putting out content, I
kept on learning things. I started to
document a checklist of every [music]
single thing I was learning as I was
posting. Every best practice, every do,
every don't. I started putting it down
in my list so that each writing session
I had my swipe file of the masters and
the best content ever on the platform
combined with my writing guidelines so
that I was able to then go and begin
every session with a degree of taste and
research and then start to go and really
hit the mark every single time. These
are my X writing guidelines. Okay, what
I've done here is really make sure that,
you know, inside of everything that I
put out on X. [music] You know, we want
to make sure, as an example, that every
single tweet ends with what I call a
bar, right? I almost want it to hit as
hard [music] as like a rap lyric. I want
to, like I'd mentioned, get into the how
and the what to do. One thing to note,
too, is never, I mean, have stuff that's
produced by chat GBT and sounds like AI,
right? It will go nowhere. Now, on the
writing checklist side, okay, be
specific with numbers and obsessed
around the details, mentioning how I did
something, right? What I actually did
and being as specific as humanly
possible because we learn from specific
examples versus just highlevel
[music] right? Examples of bars. And
what I mean by this, um, I think James
Clear, he's got bars like the famous
quote, you do not rise to the level of
your goals, you fall to the level of
your systems. And so along the way too,
I've noticed that the more you put
images [music]
when relevant in your content, the
greater it does. In terms of the actual
sentence structures, I believe short
sentences by default do incredibly well.
You need every sentence to be a banger
if you're hoping for people to save and
share your content. [music] So, this is
just kind of a taste of, you know, my ex
writing guidelines. If you want to go
and get these, you can actually go and
check them out via the link in the
description below this video. I want you
to go and be able to kind of learn from
all the wins and the mistakes that I've
made over the last 3 years. [music] And
so, like all systems, right, this is not
just for me. This is actually most
useful as well for my team because it's
having these guidelines that allows you
to actually over time build an amazing
team around you as well, which is the
leverage that we're all after. So,
here's how you go and take action here,
okay? commit to 30 days of consistent
content on the platform. Just post
something, anything. [music] Eventually,
what you'll find is that you're building
up the shipping muscle. You're building
up this muscle of progress over
perfectionism. And you're also just
starting to kind of develop some
connections and some community. And hey,
who knows? Maybe you start to get a lot
more traction than you could have ever
imagined. Step four, listen to the
feedback. This is where you're actually
able to go and analyze the results from
all your work. So I posted every single
day. You know, actually over the last
three years, I have [music] not missed a
day. Now, one thing that's been really
helpful for me there on the consistency
side is a platform called HypeFury.
[music] Inside of HypeFury, I'm able to
go and schedule all of my content. So, I
don't need to physically go and post
every day. I can go and do one [music]
batch of a writing session and then go
and schedule out say 60 posts to go out
over [music] the next 30 days so that I
can kind of set it, forget it, and have
those posts go out. And the key thing is
to basically go and look at your top 20%
of content, looking at the patterns, the
topics, the hooks, [music] the words
you've used, and then do the same with
your bottom 20% of content. From here it
becomes pretty obvious what's working
and [music] the stuff that is not
resonating with people. You know it's
from my audience that I learned even
that people wanted more systems [music]
from me and less mindset stuff. You know
it was from these audits that I also
learned that using more specific numbers
in the hooks of my content helped them
perform 10x better than my other
content. You can see over the last 3
[music] months we've been able to grow
impressions to over 12.3 million and
this is all organic. Okay, [music] we
have an engagement rate of 8%. We've
gotten close to a million engagements in
that period of time. [music] Over 39,000
people have hit my profile and you know
we've generated over 113,000
saves on my content. Okay. And so it's
this level of just continuously going
and implementing the feedback from
[music] the posts that are performing
best and then upgrading my entire
content strategy that allows me to keep
compounding the overall growth in terms
of followers, [music]
engagement, and just the overall brand
awareness of, you know, my platform and
my profile. Step five, now here's an
interesting fact. Most people's profiles
convert at 5%. [music]
Mine converts at 20%. And this is what's
allowed me to go and scale up [music] to
360,000 followers. The one key thing
that I think a lot of people miss out on
is [music] the profile efficiency ratio,
right? Which is the number of people
that follow you divided by the total
[music] amount of people that visit your
profile. This is important because over
time you're looking to make yourself
[music] sticky on the platform, right?
And not just have someone see one of
your posts and then bounce. So first
off, the cover photo needs to
immediately convey the benefit of
someone following you. And in my case,
people can see it's because they
probably want to get more seamless
[music] and scalable growth. It says,
"The systems guy, proven systems to grow
a profitable audience with content,
founder and CEO of Founder OS.
Establishing a clear benefit to someone
following [music] me and then giving
them information on what I'm all about."
Now, the profile photo, right? It's
clean, it is clear, and [music] it's
professional, right? So, nothing special
there. But the key thing is that it's
also consistent with exactly how I show
up across all platforms. It's important
that your pin post here is strategic.
You know, just [music] a few weeks back,
we updated mine because we crossed
200,000 YouTube subscribers. In this
case, I'm trying to make sure that when
people go and follow me on X, [music]
they're now going and becoming YouTube
subscribers as well. And it's working.
And I've ideally driven someone from
[music] X to a YouTube subscriber to my
newsletter list and brought someone from
being just on one platform with me to
then following me on X and across two
other platforms. and we've already
become that much more omniresent. And so
as you scroll through this, you can see
I'm actually sharing the same videos I
put on YouTube [music] onto X as well.
And we generally post to YouTube and
then about a week later, we post that
entire video onto X. So where [music]
most creators are just kind of
onedimensional, just simply sharing
their writing, I hope to be
multi-dimensional and kind of be that
triple threat. Step six, understanding
that X isn't just social media. It's a
place where you can meet people that
will actually change your life. I've
been building on the platform for about
3 years now and the connections I've
made are honestly insane. [music] You
know, whether it's best-selling authors
like Robin Chararma, you know, amazing
entrepreneurs like Russell Brunson,
powerful political figures like Jared
Kushner, the list goes on. It's these
kind of serendipitous connections that
happen to me all the time on X. And
beyond the views, beyond the engagement
and all that stuff, I think the most
powerful part of the platform is the
people that you're able to meet. But it
wasn't always like this, right? My
journey on X goes way back to about
[music] 6 years ago. I had sobered up,
stopped drinking, stopped smoking. I
decided to replace these negative habits
with journaling three [music] pages
every single morning. I had learned this
from a book called The Artist Way by
Julia Cameron. I decided that I wanted
to start sharing a lot of that thinking
[music]
somewhere. And I randomly just decided I
was going to start sharing it on X. But
here's the truth. You know, I didn't
really understand the platform. I didn't
understand the culture on it. I didn't
even understand what would work. I
figured just like [music] anything in my
life, if I just kept on chipping away at
it, getting 1% better every single day,
you know, eventually I would start to
learn the rules of the road and become
better and better at this platform and
also refine my own copywriting skills.
And now X has become the platform where
I've built some of the most valuable
relationships in my life. Here you can
see Brian Halagan who is the co-founder
of HubSpot. um being able to go back and
forth and ended up connecting me with
the team over there. One other person um
is Bill Aman, one of the richest men in
the world. Bill um had actually gone and
shared my threads that I put out a few
months back. Um and then me and him are
currently just coordinating schedules to
go and meet up in New York City in the
coming months. And so, you know, I've
also gone and been able to connect with
the bestselling [music] non-fiction
author of the last 20 years, James
Clear, on the platform as well. And I
ended up getting on a call with James
around my upcoming book. James actually
went and then connected me with his book
editor um who's now working with me on
my upcoming book release. So, how do you
start making connections on the
platform? I'd recommend that you go and
follow 50 people in your industry and
aim to reply to 10 of the biggest
thought leaders [music] that really you
find attractive on the platform. Just
start engaging with their content and
building those relationships. And
[music] don't hesitate just to go and DM
5 to 10 people a day. The way that you
want to be connecting with folks [music]
is by first giving, right? Really trying
to think of how can I be insanely
generous on this platform that I [music]
think you know that level of reciprocity
starts to kind of compound and you build
some real rich relationships. Once you
go and apply all these systems, you're
probably going to go and grow to
thousands of followers fast. But here's
how you actually make money from it. All
this X content that I'm putting out, it
drives an enormous amount of audience
growth. that audience when they're on my
ex profile, they're typically going and
being funneled in to my newsletter via
the different lead magnets that I go and
couple with a lot of my different posts.
Okay. So, once they're in the
newsletter, then at given times, they
get updated on the different things that
we have going on in Founder OS. From
there, we're actually now generating
cash flows from the audience that I'm
building on this platform. And then
we're able to go in and reinvest into
amazing content, not just on X, but
across Instagram, LinkedIn, YouTube, Tik
Tok. you name it. This is [music] the
flywheel that I'm creating from sharing
exceptional content on this platform.
Another thing that I've created over the
last 15 [music] years building multiple
media companies is what I call the
content waterfall system. What this
allows you to do is take some of your
best performing content on X and then
get the most legs [music] from it. And
so how this works is essentially going
and taking your best performing content
and then asking yourself how could this
show up on the other platforms that I'm
on. This is the content waterfall and
this whole document you can actually go
find in the link in the description. I
wanted to give it to you guys so that
you can follow along here and then go
and implement this in your own X content
strategy. What this allows you to do is
take one X [music] post or thread and
then turn it into 26 more pieces of
content. I show you this example. I'm
33. When I was young, I wasted years
drinking, smoking, and chasing things
that don't matter. Learn from my
mistakes. Here are 13 life lessons at 33
I wish I knew at 23. So, [music] this
post got over 4.6 million organic views
on X. From there, I can go and turn that
into 10 short form tweets. Here, you can
see some of those examples like three
principles I live by. Similarly, I was
able to use a lot of the concepts from
this to go and produce a lot of short
form videos. I created an animated video
from this. [music] I went and used it to
create some long- form videos as well as
then went and created it into a
newsletter that was shared a month
later. The real thinking here, right, is
I generally take my content waterfall
system and apply [music] it to my best
performing content. You know, it
performed really well on X, so it's
likely to perform really well across all
platforms. It's this exact strategy that
I've used and applied to LinkedIn to
grow that to over 850,000 people over
the last 3 years. I've used this to then
take my best X ideas and take it over to
Instagram to grow that to 950,000 people
in [music] the last 2 years. And it's
also where we get a lot of the ideas for
our best YouTube concepts, which has
allowed us to now grow to over 215,000
[music]
subscribers on YouTube. And so what I
often times see happen here is that a
given, [music] you know, content
waterfall strategy could get as many as
like 20 times more views than the
original post itself. That's pretty
insane, right? Often times when you have
that amazing post and you've created
[music] it, you're missing out on like
95% of the views you could be driving
from it by not going and distributing it
correctly [music]
using the content waterfall system. So,
inside of the Google doc below, I share
my entire content waterfall system so
you can take action on this today.
[music] This is how you go and multiply
your effort, your content, and your
impact. [music]
The next aspect here, right, is that you
need to have a newsletter in place.
[music] Okay, without a newsletter, you
are way too reliant on the platform and
you are not Musk. You don't own X. And
so, you need to actually make sure that
you're owning all of this attention,
right? And the way to do that is to
build your email list. [music] So, what
I do is I have a web flow page set up
with my entire newsletter on there. If
you go to founder OS.com/newsletter,
you'll see that this is the best
newsletter that founders are using to
grow their personal brand. I give
[music] two free systems every single
week on Wednesday and Saturday to help
you scale faster from there. Now, I'm
developing a much richer one-to-one
relationship with people. [music] You
know, when you share content on X, it's
about 15% of the people that follow you
that will actually even see that
content. But when you send out a
newsletter, 100% of people in your
newsletter list will get that email,
[music] right? So your ability to now go
and not just build a relationship with
them, but also convert these people to
sales calls or to a product landing page
into revenue is that much higher. It is
no exaggeration that X completely
changed my life and it can change yours
too. If you want all the templates,
guides, and playbooks that I shared in
this video, be sure to go and get it via
the link in the description. And if you
want to go and learn how I built my own
automated empire, check out this next
video. I'll see you over there. Be sure
to like and subscribe and let's win