This tool [music] writes faster than I
can think. I speak into Whisperflow and
this tool will convert it into perfectly
formatted writing instantly. Here's how
I use it to work twice as fast. You
know, it's someone's birthday on my
team, so I'm in my Slack channel. I can
say, "Hey Sean, happy birthday, man.
Hope you have the best day ever. Let's
get it." And Whisper Flow is going to go
and just perfectly format that exact
statement so it's ready to go and send
in [music] Slack. Or as an example,
maybe I'm going and messaging a friend.
Hey Diego, filming today. I'll see you
in a few hours. Let's get it. And boom.
You know, here's an example of a quick
email sending my [music] chief of staff,
Claire, something. I need to book
accommodations in Dubai. Looking to get
accommodations in the palm. Let me know
if you're able to go and book something.
Thank you so [music] much. And again,
perfectly formatted, ready to go, and
makes it a thousand times easier. And
the reality is, I think in the future,
you shouldn't really ever have [music]
to touch a keyboard. Whenever you feel
that cognitive load to go and type
something, you should just use Whisper
Flow and dictate