All right, here's how to discover what
you were born to do.
The one exercise that I find most useful
to do about every 90 days
is filling out my Ikigai, which is a
Japanese term that stands for your
reason for being. Essentially, what we
got here is reflecting on what do you
love to do? The things that you lose
track of time doing. What's the stuff
that the world needs from you? Just kind
of writing down three to five, maybe
even seven bullet points there. Looking
at what you can be paid for, right? And
then what you're great at, right? Your
unique strengths.
Inevitably then, once you've written
down, you know, a bunch of bullet points
around these areas, and just letting
your mind kind of wander, just write
down whatever feels natural. Don't
overthink it.
You start to
see some patterns, right? When I go and
complete this, oftentimes what comes up
in the center for me are things like
helping founders, writing,
you know, creating videos,
helping folks build communities and
movements,
traveling, right?
Helping others with the soulful journey
of building companies.
And
this exercise is something that's been
powerful in my own life to lean into
more of my calling and find what I'm
really born to do here on this planet in
this short life we got to live.
And so,
hope this is helpful. Short little
exercise, worth 1 hour tomorrow. Give it
a shot.