I built a $13.8 million business because
I trained my brain differently here's
the exact system I use to generate
million dooll ideas first I do what I
call idea Sprints 30 minutes zero
distractions write down 20 ideas that
could 10x your business most will suck
that's good keep pushing Second Use the
DI framework data what do the numbers
tell you Insight what patterns do you
see Vision where's this leading execute
what's the next step third and this
changed everything take a walk in nature
without your phone let your mind wander
the magic happens in the space between
thoughts I generated the content GPS
system on a hike that now drives over a
million dollar monthly stop consuming
start creating your next breakthrough is
waiting