My dream was to have 100k a month.
That's been my objective. There's a
moment where every founder hits, where
you stop and wonder, am I really
building a business that gives me
freedom or did I just build myself
another job? Like actually, what's the
most important thing for me? It's like,
how regulated am I? And am I still
making enough money to be able to do
whatever I want? Today, I'm sitting down
with Lincoln and he's built something
successful and he's making money, but
he's quickly realizing that growth
doesn't equal happiness. I don't have
any like anyone give me reassurance when
it comes to the business side to
actually have some reassurance of like
that's actually on the right track where
it's like that's silly dude I struggled
with this for a long long time. So I
dive into the frameworks that help all
founders help you get crystal clear on
your objectives really understanding how
to go and package and price your offer
so you can hit consistent 100k months
without going and burning all of your
time. Let's get into it. This is great.
You could increase price and you could
also increase the size of if you really
wanted to. Like it's tricky even for me
at times. It's like you can do whatever
the you want. If you've ever wondered
what it really costs to chase bigger
goals, well, I'm going to go and share
some of the core systems that you need
that you probably didn't even know that
you needed. Let's get into it. We just
start with a bit of like where's the
offer at today? Where do you want to go
with it? From there, we'll start to
outline as we're just talking through
some things, some of the challenges,
some of which you've outlined, some that
may just also come up now. Identify
general objectives. We'll understand a
little bit of the math of like where
you're looking to go here, the team you
have and the people that you need to
bring on potentially the content GPS for
kind of how it all how we're going to
drive people from your audience to the
offer and then along the way like it'll
become clear kind of like
recommendations, next steps, and make
sure you're leaving with like a bunch of
actionable practical items. Mhm. Sound
good? Amazing. Thank you. All right,
cool. On the offer side, like how do you
think about your offer stack? So, I
guess I've only ever had really one core
offer. Perfect. mocker which is the
business MOCA stands for modern
corporate athlete. My vision was
actually like it was to change it was
like the corporate counterculture and
and the normal culture of corporate. So
what do you think? Bunch of drones just
like working 9 to5 in the matrix 9 to5
work hard burnt out. So they'll come to
me for 3 months and they're getting you
know onetoone high ticket coaching.
Basically we're assessing like what is
their number one performance blockage?
Is it an energetic issue? Is it a
mindset issue stopping them from getting
to the next level? Real estate agency
was just the first fora because I was a
real estate agent. I've coached a lot of
the best agents in Australia and I can
speak the language. And so then they
bring on me to actually find out like
what's the core issue. Is it sleep? Is
it the relationship? Is it like not
being able to communicate in the
relationship which they turn up to work
tired and therefore they feel guilty and
then so they overwork and they just kind
of like it's on this this cycle. Um and
so like I'm like a patent interrupt for
them. The core customer that you're
serving, how would you describe that? a
high performing real estate agent. Yeah.
Okay. And what's the price of it? Uh 6K.
6K. Yeah. And what will you go up to? I
mean, I've been as high as 11, 12.
Just curious. Yeah. But that will then
change the amount of input that I give,
amount of handholding. So, for example,
I have a functional medicine doctor that
I use. I have a therapist that I use. I
also have another like high performing
agent that can handle the skill set
side. So depending on what the scope of
this person needs in that discovery call
will determine the amount of input that
comes in and the price. Where are you
looking to go with this? My dream was to
have 100k a month. Like that's that's
been my objective. The most I've ever
done is 70k. Right now it's like
averaging 20. Yeah. When you think about
like hours worked per week. What's the
overall lifestyle you're trying to
build? To be honest, I think that's
something that I'm still actually trying
to figure out because in my mind like
and I'll just be completely honest. It's
like I look at your world, it sounds
amazing, but in reality, would that work
for my my world and what I what needs to
go into building a business of, you
know, such income each month? Do I
actually want to manage that? Like, is
that actually aligned with my core
values? It's important as founders to
take a step back at times and reflect on
our goals and make sure that they're
actually our goals. We can get
influenced by peers, friends, fellow
founders, our parents, mentors and
oftentimes it clouds our own judgment
and you got to reflect on the fact you
know what would I want if no one else
was watching? What would I do if I knew
I would be successful? You know, in this
case with Lincoln, I think I've given
him the opportunity to think of why does
he really want 100K? Is that really the
number he's after? And it became
apparent that he wanted 100k, but it
can't be at the expense of his own time,
his own mental freedom, his ability to
still enjoy life with his wife and his
new kid that's on the way. This
importance of really understanding your
true goal, really, really what you want
and making sure that it's actually yours
and not just some random goal you have.
you know, you end up building a business
for the next decade that's serving you
versus something that's just running you
into the ground. I've sort of hovered
around that 20K level because I I
haven't had enough skill in building
systems to get me to the point where I'm
able to generate more money while still
staying inside my capacity. I'm very
cautious around taking myself outside of
my comfort zone, as people like to say,
just based on having more money. Like
actually, what's the most important
thing for me? It's like how regulated am
I? and am I still making enough money to
be able to do whatever the [\h__\h] I want?
So, what I'm hearing for you is 20K is
where we're at now. There's this world
one piece of it, which there's obviously
a lot more to the objectives than just
money as you're saying, like regulation,
your peace of mind, excellence, feeling
like play, like those things are
actually more important than the money.
You're never going to sacrifice those
things just to make an extra buck. And
you've learned that the the hard way in
some senses. There is this general goal
though of like I mean guys like us, like
we all believe in abundance. There's got
to be a world that we can both have this
or be close to it, you know, or surpass
it and have this. Like, it doesn't need
to be one or the other. I'm a big
believer in abundance and as a founder,
you know, we have so many opportunities
at our fingertips. My belief is that
it's never been a better time to be a
founder. But it also presents this
paradox of choice, right? There are just
so many options. You could start a
coaching business, a course, a digital
product, a SAS company. You could hire
people domestically, hire people
overseas. These days, you could build
with AI, you could build it by hand. The
possibilities are endless. And sometimes
in this sea of possibilities, we just
drown in almost too many choices and it
can become confusing. This is where
sometimes it's best just to take a step
back, right? Slow down for a second.
Often times we get so caught up in the
go go go that we get lost and forget why
we even got started in the first place.
So this is your friendly reminder. It's
even reminder to myself to be honest
just to reconnect with why we became
founders in the first place. Was it
freedom? Was it to help others? Was it
to build cool [\h__\h] Hang with cool
people? You know, get back to the root
of why you began this all in the first
place? Because that's the kernel of
magic that's going to help you build
something amazing. not just next week or
next month or next year, but for decades
to
come just to kind of like start to
understand what the operation size would
be. Like how many customers are we
talking about here? Say the price was
9K. It's simple math because it's a
3-month program. Let's just say the
average person bought a 9K offering from
you. This is the kind of like big
objective on the math side of things. We
need 33
customers, right?
Times the 3K per
month to get to, you know, 100K.
If you're just looking to get to 100 as
we start to work through now the
operations of all this the delivery the
challenges you've outlined we could just
think in our head for a second even
having this constraint a known like
scarcity in your model at any given time
allow 33 people in this community build
something excited you this is great
there you go yeah cuz like what you've
done actually it solidified a goal you
know it's like actually something I can
point out and like because when you say
well what if we just capped it at 33 and
not like let's get the fifth, we need
100, we need all this like, oh [\h__\h]
that's overwhelming. But if you're like,
dude, this is all like that's it makes
sense, you know? Totally. We don't need
to talk about some insanely scalable
offering. We just can pinpoint it maybe
to that number if we agree with these
general assumptions. I love it, dude.
Sounds amazing. I think as founders, we
can be so focused on giving our
customers clarity, giving others
clarity, but often times what's most
needed is that we just have clarity.
What I find I can help people with when
I work with people like on my team, you
I'm sure have this too, right? It's like
they need structure. People need to
understand like what are my objectives?
What are my KPIs? And then as founders,
we starting our own thing. And while
it's nice to like control it all, have
this freedom, whatever, there's an
aspect where like we need to be
absolutely like have some structure or
else sometimes you just find yourself
like out at sea. And so I don't think
you are out at sea though for years in
the open ocean and I'm sunburnt, bro.
Yeah. this guy's like Wilson. Um, I
think it's just this thing of refinement
and it's more just that's the nice part
of just having a soundboard like just as
a fellow founder that's building similar
type stuff just to go okay this is what
I've seen work and this is what I'm
doing now and given where you're at like
this is what helped pull me from you had
some clarity but you're so foggy with
some stuff here's the next level of
clarity to kind of help you out
definitely I know along my journey when
I first started I was obsessed with
exiting companies for hundreds of
millions of dollars I had dreams of
bringing being Herb public getting to a
billion. With age and a lot of
reflection, I realized that these were
goals that were imposed on me by
investors, imposed on me by what I
thought it looked like to be a
successful founder. But these goals,
these achievements, they were not my
own. When you think about the challenge
in your whether it's a mindset thing or
what you're currently experiencing,
maybe it's systems, who knows? What's
kind of that gap at a very high level?
It's probably, as I said, like more of
this identity piece because if I'm like
thinking about who do I really want to
be and and who am I and what does this
person do and how does he operate that
then informs the vision which informs
the offer and the messaging which
informs like kind of the waterfall.
There's an identity thing going on.
Yeah. It's like do I want to be the the
performance guy and have to be, you
know, into nutrition and training and
like do I want to show up and be that
person in an authoritative way all the
time? because I've done that for five
years, man. Like, it's it can get
taxing. Do I really want to be that
person? Like, is that what the business
is all about? Um, so it feels like
there's a piece of that that on a
personal level is the identity. And then
how does that translate to like the
branding? Correct. Of like how you show
up. Correct. As like a personal brand
and as a authority in this space.
Correct. Exactly. So that kind of like
translates a little bit into branding.
Exactly. For me, I realized I dreamed of
running a business that I could work
from anywhere on whatever I want, work
on cool [\h__\h] with cool people, build
something that would make a big impact,
but it wasn't some big exit. It wasn't
some massive billion dollar valuation
that was going to make me happy at the
end of the day. I could be perfectly
happy at, you know, $5 million profit a
year, working with dope people on a
problem that I love, with customers that
I love, and just having fun. That's my
story. I encourage you to reflect on
know what do you actually want? Not what
your parents want, not what your
girlfriend or your partner wants. What
do you want? I think that's the most
important question you can ask yourself.
I think you're more of a guide and less
of like an authority. Yeah. Right. It's
like you're you're coming on. I've been
through this journey. I've now like a
decade into this journey all the way
from like burnout, collapse to recovery.
I'm just bringing you on this journey
and I'm to help guide you. And a lot of
this stuff like I know from experience.
A lot of it I know the people that know
from my experience and I've hand
selected the people that have helped me.
The cream of the crop. Yeah. And I'm
giving you access to True. Yeah. I'm
curating the plan. I'm curating the
experiences. I'm curating the onetoone
coach you get access to. I selected this
guy out of 50 people. So true, man. You
You're spot on with this. Like that's
it's a really good reframe. Yeah.
These things it feels like are kind of
like all like interrelated in a way and
you have some clarity but there's a
little bit of murkiness around each of
the individual pieces and then also like
the connectedness. You have this offer
that you like the fact that you're
meeting people where they are and you're
able to like customize like the protocol
based on them. You have noticed though
from doing this a lot that while there's
no like one stream, there are
similarities between people and there is
a probably a desire to kind of tighten
that up and have like it a little more
streamlined while also leaving it nicely
expansive as well. So you're not just
giving someone just a pure template, but
it is rather systemized and simple to
deliver on like a balance there a bit.
Definitely 100%. So Lincoln starting his
business very similar to the same way I
started my business. It was just me
helping founders onetoone and I didn't
quite yet understand the magic of it
all. I didn't know which parts of it
were repeatable, scalable and that could
grow beyond me. It got me thinking at
that point. I needed to understand what
was the core mechanism that I was
delivering on so that I could go and
package that magic and then be able to
replicate it not with just one, two, or
10 founders but be able to help
thousands of founders through a
repeatable mechanism which is like the
secret sauce. So with Lincoln, but now
that he's looking to get from 20K to
100K a month, it's important that he
actually packages what he does into a
core mechanism. There's like a core,
like what I would call like a core
mechanism like what what is this for
real that people are coming for? Yeah.
And how do I brand that? How do I speak
to it and stay focused on that and feel
confident and proud of that and
energized by it where it's like, okay,
yeah, this is what I do versus just
doing anything for anyone. Every time he
does something, it's customized. that's
different. Obviously, that's not
scalable. If he does that at 100K, he's
basically destined to burn out. And so,
with a core mechanism in place, he'll
identify exactly what it is that he does
with his core customer every time and
starts to process and systemize that
aspect so that anything new he does is
on top of that. But each time there's a
much more repeatable aspect to what he's
doing. Positioning is freaking hard,
right? Like to give you reassurance like
I struggled with this for a long long
time. You kind of have a thesis on a
space or a thing and then you distill
that thesis down to maybe three core
elements and then you have your
mechanism that delivers those three
things. So to give you a quick example
here, right, my thesis at founder OS
would be that the future of online
businesses will be run by founder
brands. The second part now is that to
build an amazing founder brand, you need
it to be beautiful, systemized, and you
want it all to be profitable. And then
the third piece of that then is in order
to have a beautiful systemized and
profitable founder brand you need to
have a content GPS sorted out and that's
what we do at Founder OS. And that's
kind of the positioning statement.
That's really good. What I think we can
do is just work together right now to
get that for you. Again, the pattern
there is what's your p point of view on
the space for me? Like it's about energy
management as as a means to success.
like each person has like a unique
energy system that provides sustainable
success. So I don't know how that makes
sense. So let's just maybe workshop it
with something like best leaders and
I'll just underline that cuz it's like
you could replace that with like real
estate or performers or financial
brokers or whatever, right? It's like
whatever that person is, right? Would
you say like are athletes? That's kind
of like it. So like to be an athlete,
what's the characteristics of an
athlete? They're bloody intentional,
right? And then maybe it's like the
components of that, right? And to be an
amazing athlete, you need, you know,
exceptional say recovery was one thing
you named. Mhm. I think it seems like
one other thing is energy management.
Energy management for sure. 100%.
There's a component of energy management
which is like physiological, but you
kind of need to be tapped into like the
alignment of yourself. So I don't know
what that word is but like exceptional
self-awareness or Okay, we'll say
awareness. Awareness. Cool. And then
we're going to get into we'll call it
core mechanism. So the core mechanism
that I have at founder OS is our content
GPS which is the powerful system that
allows us to go and convert people from
our audience on YouTube, Instagram,
LinkedIn X through to our newsletter and
then drive people through strategic CTAs
to then purchasing our products. And so
that path, when it's done right, is
something that allows you to drive
enormous amounts of profit and impact
from your audience and convert them into
loyal long-term customers. And so this
is the stuff that we set up for
thousands of founders businesses across
a bunch of different industries, whether
they're coaches, consultants, SAS
founders, authors, you name it. We help
a lot of different people with this core
mechanism. My mechanism is a content
GPS. It's probably worth asking yourself
what's your mechanism and let's show how
we get link into his. What is the core
mechanism, system, playbook, blueprint
that you
have that helps leaders become athletes
by helping them with exceptional
recovery, energy management, and
awareness. It's called RIP, rapid
implementation plan. I've just literally
paid for a landing page guy to build it
all out. Is it still Can I still use
that or should I be changing the whole
messaging again? Now this RIP that is
it. You need to have a RIP. Now you get
the RIP which is just a blueprint but
there's a lot of difference between
reading a book and implementing what's
in the book. Exactly. And so yeah we'll
give you the book like take the book we
don't care but like you're going to
learn that there's a lot of components
this essentially recovery energy
management and awareness and the magic
is not just reading the book it's
implementing the stuff and that's what
we help you with. So yeah so I think
that that I would just keep again in the
interest of keeping things simple the
RIP is the mechanism. Yeah. Don't don't
have energy blueprint and like it's just
that. No. And that's Yeah. The
components of this, right, are like the
leader piece. Like we know that people's
goal is like we got to get them to think
more like athletes. Yeah. Whether it's a
real estate agent, financial broker,
whoever it is, right? We'll just call
those leaders for now. Like it's an
all-enccapsulating thing. The components
that you help people with, right, from
my understanding are exceptional
recovery, energy management, and
awareness. In my mind, what's the ch the
focus point is more actually on the
external lead generation to keep that
building. So, it's actually more
probably about like what does the
content messaging look like in order to
build growth or audience to growth,
eyeballs. Mhm. Yes. We need to have
customers, right? Like so and eyeballs
help drive customers. So, when it comes
to like the content side, the content is
just what's on here. There is no other
content. This is the content. Like the
content is exceptional recovery. It is
your energy management system. It is how
you help people become aware. All the
pieces of this thing that is the content
because people go, "Oh my god, I love
this wheel of life you do. What is
that?" That's what I help you implement
inside of what I run, you know, the
coaching program. It's not content and
this whole delivery model and this whole
blueprint. It's all this is the content
strategy. The content strategy is a mix
of what you already have here and just
talking about the problems and solving
the problems of your core customers. One
of the biggest unlocks that I went and
helped Lincoln with was really diving
into the content strategy he needed
because at first he felt like it was
just some guessing game. You know, he
goes and helps people with things like
recovery, energy management, and
self-awareness. And the founders that
he's helping, they have questions on
their mind. Questions like, "How do I
build a business without sacrificing my
soul?" or how do I go and scale myself
without depleting my energy? And inside
of these questions are amazing content
ideas because the role of content is
simply just to solve the problems of
your dream customers. It's that simple.
We went and laid out a key strategy that
I like to use to go and understand the
core questions on my dream customers
mind and then use my content to give
them maximum clarity. It became obvious
to Lincoln that, you know, content
doesn't need to be this guessing game.
But his next thing was that he feels
like he needs to come across as this
authority, this expert, that he's got to
have all the answers. And I candidly
don't think that's how you should be
looking at it. The reality is people
don't want you just to be some
authority. They want authenticity. They
want to learn from your struggles, your
challenges, and your accomplishments.
You just need to be you. Inside of your
story and journey is the little nuggets
of inspiration that your community, your
customers really yearn for. In your
story is your power in a sense. Your
story is your content strategy and it's
your conversion strategy as well. People
will go and subscribe to your journey
because they just like the fact that
you're approachable, you're relatable,
and they can see themselves in you. This
is what's worked for me over my career.
This is the essence of building a
founder brand. And I think it was a real
light bulb moment for Lincoln.
You just need to be you. And when you're
being you and in just your own zone, you
will attract people through your
authenticity. And the right people will
see you as an authority. But you don't
need to try and be an authority. I don't
necessarily feel I can be my playful
side and then also receive like the
seriousness that I'm offering as well.
It's just an interesting space that I'm
working in at the moment. It's totally
natural to feel that way. You know, like
as an example, in my own journey, when I
first started with content, I felt like
every single piece needed to be so
scripted. I would spend enormous amounts
of time agonizing over like every
freaking word in like a 3,000word script
for YouTube. I knew how many words there
are and every word in that was
intentional. And then it was put in a
teleprompter and it was read so there
would never be a mistake and I was as
authoritative as possible and it was
super perfect and super dialed over time
through like Diego's encouragement and
other people seeing maybe me do
something off the cuff and being like
that was actually good and it was like
giving myself more permission like
loosening the grip on things a bit to go
I think people are just more showing up
because of my energy and how I actually
am. I don't need to be so perfect and so
clean around the edges. Like people just
want, you know, your humanness. And I've
been reading a bunch about like the, you
know, it's like the Japanese concept of
like wobbishabi, right? Like just like
the beauty and the imperfection. And I
feel like that's also what an
authenticity is, right? It's just like
just being you, right? And suddenly I
think what people start to come for, and
I see this all the time when I ask
people like, "Why did you move forward?"
It's like, "I just like your energy. I
just like like how you show up." That's
about 60% of people. And I'm sure it'll
be the same for you. M well it's what we
preach in here like performance and and
even the money section of like success
is a transfer of confidence but it's
really a transfer of energy. Yeah. I
think as founders we often times get
lost in this idea of are we doing it
right? Are we doing it wrong? Should we
do it this way or should we do what this
other guy is saying online? And all of
these different opinions, all these
different thoughts swirl in our heads
and we quickly lose track of, you know,
which way to go. And often times I think
we default to thinking that we're doing
it the wrong way. The truth is there is
no right or wrong way. There's just your
way. I know as I've built my businesses,
there's been tons of moments of being
uncertain, of being unsure of what
direction I should go. Inevitably, I
kind of come back to my own criteria,
you know, wanting to build a business
that I love, work on problems that I
actually care about. Coming back to my
own truth and sticking to a system, a
business that is my way. That may look
like creating the offer in a way that
allows me to take a month off so I can
go and mountain bike in the Dolommites
each year. That may be systemizing my
entire business at Herb so I can just
spend 30 minutes on it cuz I've been
doing it for a decade and 30 minutes a
month sounds about right these days.
You're not going to read this in a book.
No mentor is going to tell you to set it
up that way. Inevitably, you got to kind
of curate all this advice, all these
insights you're getting and then make it
your own. Do what you want. Do what you
think is right. and be okay that you're
gonna make some mistakes, but you know,
each mistake, each wrong move is just
going to get you closer to the
inevitable right move you're supposed to
make. That's the cool thing about all
this, right, is like I find
entrepreneurship, it's like the ultimate
meditation. So, it's like gradually just
becoming comfortable in a sense like
with ourselves and as we just like
become comfortable with like yeah, like
are you the expert at all this? You're
not, right? like you have a bunch of
this figured out and you don't know a
bunch, but you have found some people
around you that can help and you do
actually have the self-awareness like
you teach to go I actually don't know
these parts and that's okay and that's
actually really honest and real and
versus being the guy that's talking out
of your ass or blowing smoke up people's
ass. You're just showing up as a real
human and people appreciate that and the
kind of people that you would want to
hang out with, they would appreciate
that part of you and the kind of people
that would expect you to be an expert in
all these, you probably don't want to
work with them. Definitely right. It's
like being in a relationship actually.
It's like a mirror, especially in a
social media game, content game, even
entrepreneurship. It's like it's
reflecting the parts of me that like I
actually need to look at. Mhm. You know,
it it has to cuz it shows up in
bottlenecks or challenges or, you know,
totally whatever it is. And for me, it's
it's it's always been about that showing
up online versus who I am and creating
both of them. So, it's a reminder, at
least for me, to step into the realm of
humility. What I've learned is like when
I was trying to be so perfect with
things, it had this like reverse effect
of sometimes feeling like untouchable or
like out of grasp, right? Cuz I'm just
making everything so polished and so
perfect on this like endless wheel of
just being as like yeah perfect as
something can be. It's just that much
more relatable, right? when there is
like that little rough edge or that
authentic thing you say when you just
don't know something or you make those
mistakes or like oh he's one of us like
oh Lincoln's just me but 5 years from
now he's not just this insane expert
that I can never be and like maybe I'm
not maybe I'm too beginner to work with
this guy like he's too advanced he's
just got it all figured out whereas like
you'll actually be probably more
attractive to people if like you don't
have it all figured out but you're just
a little bit further along as a guide
than they are and you can point them to
the right people that do have more
figured out than you. You've curated
what works for you. Really good reframe
of like the curation and the guide and
figuring things out and, you know,
finding experts and doing the market
research and testing and triing and
erroring like all of that. Yeah. You're
like the guinea pig. That's what it is.
That's actually what it is. It's like
someone's going to watch this video and
just take this whole thing and do it.
That's not the magic. The magic is the
implementation. Yeah. And only you can
do that of this, right? No, you could
tell people what this rapid
implementation protocol is. They
wouldn't know you invented it. It's in
your brain. It's not in like just
knowing 100 words around it. Since my
parents had gyms actually is when all
this actually started, which is when I
was a child. So like the lived
experience of going through personal
training to then into real estate to
then into coaching. Like there's a lot
of time spent in this space that you
can't replicate that. Yeah, you really
can't. So when Lincoln brought up the
fact that, you know, he has been so
confused without any structure, I think
this is just a common battle that we
constantly face as founders, right? We
are at one stage, we've just started, we
maybe want to scale beyond just
ourselves and build a team. And
inevitably, you need to start
systemizing, processing, streamlining
what you're already doing to get to the
next level. I know that that is why I
like having a mentor so much. In fact, I
have mentors for most areas of my
business, whether it's growth, you know,
content, sales, every core aspect. At
the end of the day, the more that you
have the right people, you know, around
you helping you understand that
structure, the more you can move from
chaos to clarity. I completely resonate
with where Lincoln's at. You know, it's
confusing. It's overwhelming. You know,
some mentor goes and unlocks the system
for you, brings you clarity. inevitably
you run with that for a bit then you're
going to hit another wall of confusion
and need to get more clarity through
more proven systems and then kind of
elevate to that next level. I think this
is oldest part of the cycle of
entrepreneurship a hack as well like if
you find documentation hard do you use
chatbt or claude or would you use okay
cool so you know on the desktop part of
it right I would just turn on the voice
side and I would say I run a business
that helps the best leaders become
athletes and to be an amazing athlete
our whole thing is that you need
exceptional recovery energy management
and awareness in order to do this we
have this rapid implementation protocol
I want you to go and create a chart that
has the following columns in it going to
have the delivery mechanism which are
balance, performance, and money. There's
then these different columns which are
the plan. There's the 30 days, the 60
days, the 90 days, the core issues that
this person has and the wins that we're
going to get them to 90 days so they
renew. I want you to go and fill in this
chart. I'm going to give you examples of
what I do for the balance person. Please
fill in the rest that's similar. Go and
complete filling this out so that I can
go and easily copy and paste this to a
mirror board and then just let it make
it,
right? And don't even build, you don't
even need to make it. and then just copy
and paste it over to the thing and then
yeah, you got to edit it. I've been
talking a lot of people this like more
recently. It's like in 2004 or whatever,
humans started changing their level of
thinking where it's like, oh, you need
to go find a good restaurant. It's like
just Google it, man. Right? Like, and
you stopped like looking in the yellow
pages or looking in books or asking for
it's like just Google the damn thing.
People's minds are not shaped yet to
what AI is supposed to do for you. It's
like the ultimate productivity tool. the
second you feel cognitive dissonance
around making something or documenting
something, just default to I'm going to
check GBT this. And so I'll go and look
at my to-do list and before I do
anything, I'll just go and be like GPT
GPT GPT. And it ends up being probably
like 70% of what I need to do just needs
to be done by GBT or by Claude. So with
this kind of stuff, it's like, oh, the
second you feel that feeling of like,
god dang, I don't want to do this thing.
It's like that means you should it need
to do this, right? Just then just talk
to it and feed it this stuff. Whether
it's a image of this or transcripts of
what you've got as founders like we
should be okay and accept the fact
sometimes that we are just like
strategically lazy. That's probably why
we are founders because you're
strategically lazy enough that when you
have a boss telling you do this, do
this, you're like, I don't want to do
this anymore. [\h__\h] yourself. I'm out.
You're strategically lazy enough that
when you're like you could do things
these messy ways, you're like there's
got to be a better way, which causes you
then to build whatever you're building.
So, same thing. It's like you're
strategically lazy enough that maybe
like documenting all this feels a little
bit cumbersome. So, you yeah, let's use
chat GBT. Let's use the stuff we've
already made to then just synthesize
that into something simple. And now you
have a bit of at least a structure by
which you can synthesize. Not a bit. I
think that's a really good structure.
Okay. I would say like viewing this more
as like the seed of something much
bigger. It's gonna just branch off from
there. I need to be careful not to get
too big though. So keep this just Yeah.
I mean, yeah, keep it simple. But the
point is that I'm just letting you know
that even for mine like it keeps on
getting more robust that there's
probably actually 15 columns now of just
things for each of these things. What
I've had to go through over the years is
80% was freestyling, 20% was structured.
But I needed to flip it on its head.
It's like 80% play within this system.
Like I've done this enough. I've helped
enough people. There are just things
that work, which is why people are
coming to me. Like play this game. And
then from that 20% freestyle from there.
There's a consistency in experience,
consistency in results, consistency in
outcomes, and like they're getting the
core of what they need. It's more
predictable. And it's just dialed, you
know, cuz you're not freestyling and
then out in no man's land where you're
like, "Oh man, this person's confused
over this and this and this." It's like,
no, no, just stick to what we know
works. Yeah. Right. And yeah, like still
add your personality, get creative, but
don't just waver entirely or else I
don't even know how to help you and you
know you're not get lost as well.
Exactly. Exactly. Or it's more Yeah.
more energy to get back to center. Okay.
That's kind of how I would look at it.
Now we we've earned enough time to burn
enough time so we can just go play
paddle. No, thanks, man. I appreciate
that. You should just take a um a photo
of it if you can. If this video sparked
something in you, well, you're not
alone. There comes a point in every
founder's journey where you really
reflect on, no, am I just trying to
build something bigger or am I trying to
build it better? I know this from
building businesses over the last 14
years that it really comes down to your
peace of mind, your calm, your clarity,
and having that freedom that we're all
really after at the end of the day. You
know, if this resonates with you and you
want some mentorship directly from me,
my team, and you want to be a part of a
community of legends, well, then you
should check out Founder OS via the link
in the description and join me. Now,
thank you so much for watching this
video. Like and subscribe, and let's win
together.