need better habits let's do it together
here are the four areas I'm focused on
habits for your mind this year I'm
blocking out 4 hours every morning for
deep work no distractions no deviations
your life is decided by your ability to
protect your time from now on I evaluate
opportunities is either a h yes or it's
a no habits for your body I do at least
60 Minutes of intense exercise a day I
take 10,000 daily steps I do yoga three
times a week and do regular ice baths
and saunas for energy recovery habits
for your business I talked to 10
customers a month I want to understand
problems find Opportunities and keep my
business evolving I'm committed to
building a personal Board of advisers
each month I talk to my mentors they
accelerate my growth in areas I don't
understand I also create content daily
with no excuses habits for your
relationships always remember birthdays
ask about family care about every person
you talk to the single greatest people
skill is a highly developed and
authentic interest in others