Most people think you need to work
harder to get richer, but every
billionaire I've studied has taught me
the opposite.
I discovered that success isn't about
[music] how many hours you work. It's
about learning the principles and
secrets from people that are miles ahead
of you. So, today I want to show you the
seven lessons I stole from [music] seven
billionaires that allowed me to build
massive wealth and a business that runs
itself. Let's get into it.
>> [music]
>> Lesson number one, you are the asset.
I got 99 problems, but a [\h__\h] ain't
one. Hit me. Let's really become in the
artist that we looked up to. Jay-Z went
from drug dealer to billionaire, and it
wasn't because he started building all
these companies. He started building his
own brand. You know, there's this line
that I love in one of his songs. It's,
you know, "I'm not a businessman,
[music] I'm a business man." You know,
there was this innate understanding
early on in his career that it was him,
you know, his own brand, [music] you
know, his own voice, his message, his
struggle, his story. That was the
ultimate moat, right? [music] That's
what allowed him to build Tidal,
alcohol, clothing, you name it, and all
these other billion-dollar brands. But,
it wasn't [music] just their logos that
caused those billion-dollar brands to
grow up. It was the fact that Jay-Z, you
know, the goat, was behind it. And
[music] so, I've experienced the same
sort of thing in my career. You know,
early on when I built my first business,
BitMaker, all of a sudden one [music]
day we were raided by the government.
Now, that's a whole other long story,
but to cut to the chase, I realized that
I needed to go and mobilize the Canadian
tech community. And so, I went and sent
3,200 emails, and within 24 hours it was
blowing up on Twitter in Canada and the
number one trending story [music] across
Canada and the US on Twitter. Sure
enough, 1 week later we got the only
exemption of its kind in Canada, [music]
and we were able to operate, and I was
able to exit this business for a
life-changing sum. And so, I've learned
over my career as well, you know, from
that date, [music] that it wasn't just
the companies I was building that was
the most impactful. It was my energy, my
story, my own grit and might that people
were attracted [music] to. You follow
people, then you follow brands. You
know, when you think about going and
trying to build a massive brand, one of
the most important things you can do is
build distribution. And Jay-Z understood
this from day one. Your face is the
funnel, your story is your [music]
strategy. So, stop hiding behind the
logo. You know, it's time to actually go
and put your own brand out there.
Telling, [music] you know, your
struggles, your wins, your challenges,
the obstacles along the way. Being
insanely generous and sharing the
blueprints you've learned, the systems,
the different strategies [music]
that you believe could have helped you 5
years ago in your journey. You know,
don't worry about being perfect [music]
out the gate. Just get going, and then
get good.
We have a chance to make these things
beautiful, and we have a chance to
communicate something.
The next lesson is extreme, but it's
essential. Raise the bar or burn the bar
down.
And it all started with just an idea.
>> [applause]
>> And we are calling it
iPhone.
People talk about Steve Jobs' genius as
if it's some polite thing, but honestly,
after reading over eight books on Steve
Jobs, that is a crock of [\h__\h] Steve was
violent when it came to his standards.
You know, it was almost like complexity
and things that, you know, were not
beautiful almost created a rip in his
soul, right? He just couldn't stand it.
You know, Steve was relentless in his
pursuit of excellence, of quality, and
of simplicity. You know, he believed
that, you know, when it came to even
marketing these products, it came down
to the values. You know, I've had to
learn this over the years myself, right?
I think early on in my career I let my
standards slip, right? I thought I
constantly had to compromise on things
like design, on beauty, on the artistry
that I wanted behind the products. At a
certain point, you know, when you hire
certain people, I think that it's quite
likely that you revert to the mean,
right? You revert to just being average
and mediocre unless you keep on
establishing the bar you have. Your
culture is essentially what you do and
[music] what you tolerate. And so, Steve
is a shining example of violently
holding up a bar and not allowing anyone
to go below it. And that's why Apple has
become one of the most beloved brands
that has ever been created. You know, an
example of this is at one point, while
building the iPhone, Jony Ive had come
to Steve Jobs, and he let Steve Jobs
know that they had finally transformed
the mobile phone. You know, while
BlackBerry at the time had a phone with
about 200 buttons on it, you know, Jony
had finally invented the iPhone, and it
had just one button. And so, he went to
Steve impressed and thought that Steve
would be elated. And when Steve saw it,
he couldn't help but think,
"Why is there one button on it? Can't we
do less?" And this is just an example of
going and making a product insanely
simple, right? One of the core values of
Apple is simplicity, and Steve was
relentless in his pursuit of these
values. You know, when you look at your
career, you know, what are the kind of
opportunities you're surrounding
yourself by and the people that you're
surrounding yourself by? Are they
raising your standard or causing it to
drop? You know, what are the habits
you're tolerating around you, right? Do
you have a high bar of standard in terms
of the daily habits you do, or are you
reverting to just a bunch of substandard
[\h__\h] that's causing you to be a low
performer? On the same side, when it
comes to, you know, the relationships
around you, are you surrounding yourself
with amazing people that you're learning
from, that you're growing from, and that
cause you to have insane ambitions? Or,
you know, when you go and you audit the
community around you, you feel like
they're just, you know, causing you to
play small? Be careful of what you
tolerate.
>> [music]
>> Now, the next lesson comes from Star
Wars, one of the most lucrative pieces
of intellectual property [music] ever
created.
Cross trackless void to unknown world.
Before releasing the first Star Wars
movie, George Lucas already had the
scripts, the characters, everything
already designed for the next three
movies, right? So, this was, I think,
one of the ultimate bets on himself. The
insane thing, too, is that when he was
making the first Star Wars movie, he
knew that he needed to create all these
worlds, right? All these planets, these
galaxies, right? But, the thing was that
special effects didn't even exist. So,
he created his own special effects
studio, right? So that he could go and
execute on this insane vision he had for
these insane worlds. The crazy thing is
that when he finally had released the
first movie, right? He already had the
next two ready to go, and that first one
ended up hitting box office records and
hitting the number one spot in history
for, you know, most ticket sales ever.
When you're going and you're building
your own worlds, I think the things that
you can do just to kind of bring this
down to ground floor is, first off,
think about your business as big as you
can. If you need to even, go and upload
your company vision and strategy to
ChatGPT, and then get it to go and make
your vision 10 times bigger. I think
just a simple exercise of going and
seeing how big your vision could be
allows you to start expanding your mind
more, right? So, that's number one.
Number two is to start going and
thinking about the different pieces of
your vision. For me, I know it's, you
know, insanely amazing systems,
unparalleled support for founders,
having epic retreats worldwide, going
and having the greatest team ever,
getting our content onto streaming
platforms, having an amazing publishing
business, right? These are the different
worlds that we're building, and when I'm
clear on those worlds, I'm able to
[music] attract top talent that wants to
come on board to help make this all come
true.
This one is hard to put into practice,
but it makes billionaires. Conviction
beats consensus. It was a success. It is
a recognized [music] success.
In the 1980s, Dior wasn't Dior, you
know, it was this wounded animal limping
around Paris, but there was one man that
saw the potential in it, Bernard
Arnault.
You know, Arnault had this vision that,
[music] you know, Dior could be a part
of this stable of luxury brands, and he
thought that over the next 50 years,
right, this, [music]
you know, luxury brand portfolio could
be something incredibly special. But,
the thing was everyone thought he was
crazy. You know, Dior was a failing
brand, and no one could understand why
Bernard even wanted this brand. And the
same thing happened when I was building
Founder OS. People told me that personal
branding was just some fad, right? That
systems aren't even sexy. But, I knew
that the future of founders would be
that, you know, every entrepreneur
should have their own media company
around them. That distribution was the
ultimate moat, that your story is the
ultimate strategy, and that more and
more founders would build founder-led
brands. The reality is is that in most
businesses' early days, what you're
working on, it's not that obvious,
right? Cuz you're oftentimes piecing
together different insights, different
sort of systems, and random secrets that
you know that the rest of the world
doesn't, which is why you're probably
building something different. You know,
be okay with working on something that
people don't understand in the early
days. Just make sure you have that
compelling 50-year vision.
I learned the next lesson from Elon
[music] Musk. Delete before you
optimize. Like, why do you want to live?
What's the point? What inspires you?
What do you love about the future? If
the future does not include being out
there among the stars, it's incredibly
depressing if that's not the future that
we're going to have. While most founders
ask, "How do I improve this?" Elon asks,
"Why the [\h__\h] does this exist?" Elon has
an algorithm that he uses across all of
his businesses, and the first part of
that algorithm is delete. Not automate,
not delegate, not add more things. It's
delete. Because the truth is, you
shouldn't automate or delegate something
that shouldn't even exist in the first
place. Now, you can imagine, right? As,
you know, you're building a rocket,
you're trying to send this thing up into
orbit. If you just keep on adding more
and more stuff, well, then you're going
to have to have more and more jet fuel
to get all that [\h__\h] up into space. And
so, the first rule is, how can we reduce
this thing to its simplest form? Like
down to first principles. And it's that
obsession around deletion. And [music]
so, for me inside of Founder OS these
days, I have one core focus. Everyone
across my entire team knows their one
critical function. And this allows us to
move with intention, with speed, and
with velocity, right? Doing the right
things and aiming at the right
direction. And so, you need to go and
ask yourself, right? Before you even
start automating or hiring anyone, what
can you delete? Now, from there, what I
like to do is implement the AED system.
I've helped thousands of founders with
this, and it's genuinely transformed
their life and business. Go and look at
your calendar, your to-do list over the
last month, and write down every single
thing that you're working [music] on.
What you can do next inside of this
Google Sheet, which I've also gone and
linked in the description below so you
can go and implement this today, is
you're then going to go and mark the
tasks that you can automate, eliminate,
and delegate. Now, aim to delete as much
as you can, and then automate, and then
delegate.
If you really [music] want to win,
the invention that sparked a revolution.
>> Lesson number six, beginner energy
builds empires.
If you really want to Well, if you're
doing things exactly the way everyone
else's, there's not going to be a really
meaningful potential [music]
breakthrough.
>> Sara Blakely built Spanx without
investors, without industry knowledge,
really without knowing what she was
doing. [music] And I think this mindset
came back from her childhood. She talks
about being at the dinner table, and one
of the key things her father would ask
her and her sister every single night at
the kitchen table was, "What did you
fail at today?" It was [music] this
question being repeated to them every
night at dinner that started to increase
her comfort level with just pushing the
envelope, and [music] 80% of the time
just falling flat on her face. So, sure
enough, when it came to building Spanx,
you know, she didn't know what she was
doing. [music] Prior to that job, she
had been selling fax machines as a
door-to-door saleswoman. Now, was she
qualified to build some clothing
business? To build some billion-dollar
empire? I mean, many would say no. But
she knew that her naiveness and her
beginner mindset were actually her
advantage. I know in my first business,
Bitmaker, I didn't have that much
technology experience. I had [music] no
experience building a boot camp, no
experience running companies, building
teams, and the list goes on. But to be
honest, it was [music] that naiveness,
that beginner vibe, that allowed me to
build that business. I just started to
think about, what is the boot camp
around tech that I would want to go
through? I would want legendary
instructors. I'd want it to [music] be
super easy for me to learn. I'd want to
be surrounded by amazing people. Um, I'd
want it to be a really amazing brand
that I can trust, and have amazing
mentors around me that would allow me to
learn, and then eventually get my dream
job at an amazing tech company. [music]
And so, that's exactly what I went and
built. I think that experience is
overrated, and if you're a beginner at
something, don't use that as an excuse
[music] to not just get after it. You
know, beginner mindset mixed with
obsession, with taste, with systems, and
[music] the right team that allow you to
blast through all these so-called
experts.
>> [music]
>> The last lesson came from Walt Disney.
Draw the dream, and then build the
machine. But there's a lot of
satisfaction in developing [music] ideas
into realities. Here's what most people
miss. You know, Disneyland didn't start
as some sketch file or start as some,
you know, pitch deck. It started as a
drawing. A simple drawing on pen and
paper. And as I've gone and dug through
the files, right? Disney's been someone
that I've been super obsessed with for
the last 20 years of my life. You know,
my mom is an avid Disney fan, and I've
probably been to Disney like 12 times
too many, okay? And so, it was natural
for me to then want to study like what
the hell was it [music] that has allowed
Disney to build such a cult following
over the last, you know, 80 years,
right? And it showed Disney not as just
some theme park, [music]
but you could see the grand vision for
what he was creating. You know, when I
talk to entrepreneurs inside of Founder
OS and over my career over the last 16
years building businesses, I think that
around 97% of founders don't take the
time to actually draw up what they're
looking to build. When I first built
Founder OS, right? I knew I wanted to
build this entire founder ecosystem.
[music]
Like a founder theme park, right? This
idea that, you know, founders needed an
aspirational brand that stood for
something greater. You know, my belief
is that most founders get into business
in the first place for freedom. [music]
Freedom to control the four W's in life.
Control where you work, control when you
work, control what you work on, and
control who you work with, right? And
so, what we've tried to create is this
this, you know, magical founder journey.
I've always thought to myself, you know,
what is it that I wish I had when I was
first getting started building
businesses when I was 20. Go and take
time for a second to be an artist,
right? I think too many founders [music]
go and lose the artistry of building,
and they pay a price. And it's really
valuable to take a step back for a
second with just a pen and paper, right?
Put on some nice music, get your nice
Americano, whatever you like to drink,
and start to just go and sketch up the
vision for what you're trying to build
over the next 20 years. And from there,
start to share it with people. You know,
I'll go and take my drawings, and I'll
go and share them on your LinkedIn, onto
X, onto Instagram. I think this is a
great part of kind of manifesting this
imagination and this vision that you
have, and going and mobilizing people
around it. I've synthesized all of the
secrets and lessons from billionaires
inside of my billionaire [music]
decision matrix, which you can go and
get right now via the link in the
description. If you want to go and learn
how I've grown my audience over 14
million people around my companies and
3.2 [music]
million people around my personal brand,
you can go and check out this next
video, and I'll see you over there. Be
sure to like and subscribe, and let's
win together.