One of the hidden benefits of building
personal brand is that you're putting
your own interests out there, your own
passions, the things that you love to do
and you end up attracting folks that are
also into those things. Now, this is
pretty effortless. We all know from
online that we all like paddle and so it
just kind of makes sense that when we're
together here in Djangu we get together
chop it up over a game again you're kind
of sharing you know the sort of stuff
that you're into your core identity and
you start attracting people with similar
values similar interests hobbies and it
just makes it that much easier to meet
up with people around the world I was
just in Tokyo met a new friendo I'm now
in Changangu met some new friends here
Lincoln Jordan wherever I go I find that
this is happening more and more and more
just keeps caling bounding. So, put
yourself out there, share what you love,
and attract people that are in the same
stuff as