Here's a brutal truth. If you can't say
the problem in one sentence, you
probably can't fix it. Problems that
people will bring up, right? Are they
things like, you know, I'm not
generating more followers or, you know,
I don't know how to come up with ideas
or I don't have enough hours in a day.
But, that's not actually what the
problem is. Your issue around followers
is probably more of an issue around your
brand identity being tight. Your issue
around ideation is probably that you
haven't empowered other people on your
team. Your issue around hours is
actually probably a prioritization
issue. You know, if you simply did a
time audit, analyzed your calendar, your
to-do list, and the core tasks you've
done over the next 60 days, and then
understand who on your team could help
you take that off your plate, you would
have more hours in the day. And so, you
just need to get your priorities right.
The key thing is going layers deeper,
right? And asking yourself why five
times. You know, you don't have enough
hours in the day? Why? Oh, because, you
know, I got too much stuff on my plate.
Why? Because, you know, I'm saying yes
to so many things. Why? Because, you
know, I haven't taken the chance to go
and ask my team for some help. Why? Uh,
because I haven't taken a step back for
a second just to actually analyze what
it is I have on my plate and then see if
I can delegate some stuff. Asking
yourself why five times gets down to the
root [music] cause of what the hell is
going on, so you can get some of the
off your plate.