Everyone thinks that making cool
that people love comes down to talent.
But the real secret has nothing to do
with talent at all. Steve Jobs couldn't
code. He couldn't design. But he did
have one thing. Taste. How do you go and
refine your taste? Say no to things that
are below your bar. Every post, every
color, every word, it all matters. And
when you stack up all of those little
details at the end of the day, that's
what makes your brand. It's holding that
bar high and maintaining the details
versus letting it go and slide. Think
about, you know, what's the design that
we want to be known for? How do I
elevate the overall quality of what we
do? And if you can go the distance and
actually make stuff that you're proud of
at the end of the day, people on the
other side can feel that craftsmanship.
So, what are you going to go do today to
raise your standard and implement your
bar for taste?