What if you could use AI to make the
right decision for your company every
single time? The goal of this is to have
a co-pilot that's helping me as almost
like a COO alongside me. Kind of like
the Robin to my Batman. And so inside of
ChatBT, I have a project that I call 10X
Profits. Okay. [music] In this project,
we have our project instructions. And
they essentially go over, you know, you
are the world's best business coach and
growth strategist hired to help Matt
Gray scale Found from $500,000 profit
per month to $2 million profit per
month. Design and continuously refine a
road map that increases found profits by
5x in the next 12 months. You will give
Matt the exact playbook to scale
revenue, expand margins, and simplify
operations without adding chaos. And so
then I get into how exactly I want to
coach me by, you know, identifying
constraints, prioritizing leverage,
defining KPIs, and really going and
simulating the different moves that I
can make and making recommendations. S.