At the point of this video, I'm 35 years
old, and if you're in your 30s or 40s,
I'm going to share 30 principles that'll
help you change your life today. Because
right now, you can either choose to
build your dreams
or live a life of regret. Number one,
the most dangerous thing in your 30s
isn't failure, it's comfort. I see
people that turn 30 or 40, have made a
good amount of money, and are just
chilling and relaxing. And all that
comfort leaves them depressed, leaves
them anxious. They're missing some
bigger purpose. You know, I think it's
important to, no matter what age you
are, to find an exciting big vision that
genuinely motivates you, that fires you
up. You know, for me, that's going and
building FounderLy into the greatest
founder community of the 21st century.
It's going and investing in a founder
retreat center in the Dolomites. It's
going and building these, you know,
movies essentially on YouTube and
laddering this up to a Netflix series
one day. And, you know, that's just
hardly scratching the surface. If you're
going to go and motivate yourself to
jump out of bed every single morning,
which is what you deserve, you need to
have a big exciting vision. And one
other example of this is really a focus
on mastery. You know, we can always find
new skills, new things we're looking to
learn. You know, right now, I'm trying
to become better at writing and have a
book on the way. You're trying to master
things like cinematography and video
creation, becoming more and more
comfortable on camera. But a big thing
with that is the mastery of it. I'm not
doing it for some outcome. I'm not doing
it to achieve anything. I'm doing it
just to fall in love with the process
itself. And so, you need to find that
thing that pushes you. Number two, your
late start is actually your advantage.
Everyone thinks starting late is a
disadvantage. The truth is, experience
and maturity give you an edge that no
25-year-old can touch. You know, Ray
Kroc started McDonald's at 52. Sam
Walton started Walmart at 44. You know,
it's never too late to start something.
At the end of the day, you know,
starting a business, as an example, is
pattern recognition. And the older you
get, the more things you've seen, the
more you're able to connect dots that
someone much younger than you probably
can't. You know, I know at the age of
31, I started FounderLy using all of the
experience that I had gone and built
through my first two companies, Herb and
Bitmaker. FounderLy would not even have
been possible to start had I not learned
the hard lessons in the first decade of
being a founder. You know, the systems,
the blueprints, the playbooks,
everything that I share inside of the
community we've built is only possible
because of all these challenges I went
through in the first decade of my
career. Number three, success kills more
dreams than failure. Most people are
terrified of failing, but the truth is,
failure isn't what stops people, success
does. Success in life should be a
checkpoint, not some destination. Now,
what I've learned over the years is, I
used to be so outcome focused. You know,
when I exit my company, then I'll be
happy. When I go and make this hire,
everything will be much more peaceful.
You know, when I go and hit 500k per
month, you know, at that point, finally,
I'll be able to just chill. The reality
is is that, you know, these big
milestones come, and you end up
realizing the next day that you're no
more happy because of it. You know, when
you go and you win on something, the
best thing you can do is go and use that
to go and jazz yourself up and
accomplish something even bigger. Use it
as fuel to, you know, give even more of
yourself to your mission. Create an even
bigger vision for yourself and for your
team. Now, what I've learned over the
years building teams of 50 plus,
multiple profitable companies, is that
the bigger the vision, the more people
you're able to inspire. And too often I
see founders with little visions, and
they're wondering why people on their
team are not motivated. The reality is
is that you have to create a company
that has a big umbrella that other
people can fit under. You know, you have
to be able to motivate a team that the
big vision that you have can encapsulate
the vision that they have for their
individual lives as well. And so, go
after that thing. You know, run past the
finish line. You know, and use each win
you get to go and propel you to further
wins. Number four, freedom is overrated,
discipline is the real goal. We all grow
up thinking freedom is the prize. But
here's the paradox, freedom without
discipline is chaos. You know, just a
few months back, I was in the coast of
California in Big Sur, reflecting on,
you know, my life and business, and
thinking about the big vision for
FounderLy, and what I needed to do every
single day to get there. It all came
down to one critical function, creating
exceptional content. Now, exceptional
content isn't going to create itself.
You know, YouTube videos, content across
X, LinkedIn, Instagram, TikTok. You
know, all of this stuff takes real
effort, real discipline. It came down to
4 hours of deep work every single day
from 7:00 a.m. till 11:00 a.m., creating
one piece of exceptional content. You
know, it's this discipline of waking up,
getting my iced Americano, doing some
writing or filming a video like this
that all eventually compounds over time.
You can have these big visions, right?
You can have these big things that you
want to accomplish at 30 or at 40. But
you also have to go and distill that
down to what is the core action that you
need to do every single day to ladder up
to that. You know, I know for me, you
know, writing, filming, they put me in
flow, right? And I think flow is that
state of enjoyment where we're just
falling in love with the task at hand.
Number five, energy beats experience.
Wrong. Wisdom beats both. We worship
youth for their energy, but energy
without wisdom burns out. You know,
wisdom is what compounds. Now, as you go
and you gain more experience over your
career, you realize that wisdom equals
leverage. You know, I think of four main
areas when I think of leverage, media,
capital, systems, and people. So, when
you go and you're building, you know,
you want to be thinking about how can
you go and maximize these four areas?
Because the more leverage, the more
freedom. You know, we have media coming
out across YouTube, X, LinkedIn, TikTok
that requires only 4 hours a month of my
time. We have over 30 people on the team
across the media area things, sales,
marketing, ops, finance, that all do
their part, and I'm able to remove
myself from the core operations and
focus mostly on strategy, high-level
partnerships, and content. You know,
lastly, you know, when I think about the
systems at FounderLy, it's really what's
given me the freedom to go and travel
the world. Currently in London, was in
Lisbon, heading to Bali soon, then off
snowboarding in Japan. And this is all
possible because I have systems in place
all throughout our company. Systems to
go and create the content, systems to
distribute it, drive people to
newsletters, to leads, to sales,
referrals, and recommendations. It's
your systems at the end of the day, when
you have these all in place, that allow
you to step back from the stuff that
kind of you probably don't even want to
be doing anymore, and be able to double
down on the parts of your business and
life that fill up your cup. Number six,
forget balance, think in seasons. The
world sells us the myth of daily
balance, but life doesn't work in
balance, it works in seasons. You know,
for me, each season of my life lasts
around 90 days. You know, I have a
personal board meeting that I do with
myself every single month and chart out
what the theme is going to be for the
next 90 days of my life and the next 30
days of my life. And I do this every
single month. You know, I chart out my
business goals, my life goals, and the
end of the month I reflect on what went
well, what didn't go well, you know, and
what did I learn. For me, not every day
looks the same, not every week looks the
same. You know, I think that like
variety is the spice of life. You know,
you don't need to worry that each day,
you know, you're just doing a copycat of
the previous day, or that you're
sticking to the same routine every
single day for the rest of your life.
The truth is, give yourself the
permission to work in seasons. Give
yourself the permission to, you know,
mix things up for 90 days. Keep things
fresh. Keep life enjoyable. You don't
need to be super rigid. You know, change
up your environment for 90 days. Put on
a different routine. Go and learn a new
skill. Right? It's these, you know, new
flavors that kind of keep life enjoyable
and keep you kind of intellectually
stimulated as you're building. Number
seven, you should fear regret more than
you fear failure. Failure may sting, but
regret will haunt you forever. I had a
good friend, Steve, go and ask me when I
was, you know, in a transition period
about 6 years ago. I was, you know,
confused. I wasn't sure what I wanted to
start next and what I wanted to give,
you know, my time towards. Steve went to
me and said, "Matt, what would you do if
you knew you would be successful?" You
know, I realized that, you know,
despite, you know, a bunch of
opportunities on the table that would
likely make me tens, if not hundreds, of
millions of dollars, that the thing that
fired me up the most was creating an
amazing founder community, helping
founders with systems, and then helping
them remove themselves from operations
the same way I had done in my previous
two companies. You know, I said no to,
you know, what everyone else was telling
me to do. I said no to even what made
the most sense, you know, financially.
And I decided to just double down on the
thing that, you know, was a whole body
yes for me. You know, my heart was
saying, "This is the thing." My mind was
like fired up, and my soul, you know,
couldn't help but think of it day and
night. And so, you know, I would
encourage you to go and ask yourself,
you know, what would you do if you knew
you would be successful? You know, go
and do that thing that you've been
thinking about for years. Go and
finally, you know, take the plunge. You
know, lean into your real passion, the
thing that's going to fire you up, that
you could spend the next decade or two
of your life really focused on. You
know, there's really, you know, two
words that, you know, I think about when
I'm just about to start something, which
is, "Fuck it." Right? You don't need to
have a whole plan baked before you go
and take the leap and do that thing.
Often times, the plan just emerges as
you're building. Number eight, your body
is a multiplier, not a side project.
Most people treat their health as an
afterthought. But in your 30s and 40s,
your body is the multiplier for
everything you do. And so, my belief is
that founders are athletes. Just like
any great athlete, you know, they have a
coach, they take rest and recovery
serious, they show up every single day
in practice. The same goes for founders.
You know, you need a coach. You need to
take your rest and recovery seriously.
You know, you need to go and focus on
the daily practice and constantly find
some way to get better and better. Now,
7 years ago, I became sober, and it
absolutely changed my life. You know,
when I was, you know, going and doing my
blood work, I realized that my
testosterone was at like 300. Because of
the levels of substances I was using, it
was affecting my sleep and affecting my
body in a big way. Finally, when I
sobered up, you know, just after just 3
months, my testosterone went to 800,
which, you know, this is the chemical in
humans that makes effort feel good. So,
now, you know, all that building, all
that effort I was putting into my dreams
was just that much more multiplied.
Number nine, you have resources, they
don't. People assume youth has an
advantage, but in your 30s and 40s, you
have resources that they would only
dream of. You know, I know when I was in
my 20s, I was looking to start up a
business, and part of it would require
me to go and acquire a random website
out of New Zealand. And, you know,
truthfully, I was broke. You know, and
so, what did I have to do? Well, I had
to go cobble together millions of
dollars from investors like the CEO and
COO of Shopify, Joe Montana, the Hall of
Fame quarterback. You know, I raised
from the founders of BuzzFeed. And, you
know, because I was in my 20s, I had to
go and put all this effort in just to go
and getting those resources. Now, fast
forward to age 31, starting Founder OS,
I knew I wanted to build something so
much differently. You know, my
experience in my 30s had taught me that
I didn't need to do it the same way I
had done it in my 20s. You know, when I
thought of starting my third business, I
had clear criteria. You know, I wanted a
business that could get to $5 million
profit a year. I wanted to go and be
able to build something that took 3
months or less to build, that I loved
the customer, loved the problem, had
distribution product fit, and that every
day it felt like play. And so, my
experience enabled me to build a lot
smarter, and be able to build something
that was completely bootstrapped. Number
10, health isn't self-care, it's
strategy. People think health is a
luxury, but in business, it's the
ultimate strategy. You know, in any
business, one thing that you got to get
right is your energy. When you go and
you're looking to build anything,
whether it's building a team, creating
content, building a media company around
yourself, you know, inevitably, the core
aspect to all of these things is you.
It's your health, it's your energy. It's
your ability to go and motivate people
around you, to wake up every day and
actually be able to focus. And you can't
focus if you're not taking care of
yourself. You know, in my 20s, I took my
health for granted. You know, I used
different substances, I oftentimes, you
know, neglected working out, neglected
simple things like meditation. And
oftentimes, I was just hard to be
around. You know, because I wasn't
taking care of myself and wasn't really
loving myself, it was hard for me to be
a great leader for others. You know,
what I've learned is that your
leadership is the cap on your success.
If you're a five out of 10 leader,
you're probably only going to be three
out of 10 successful. But, if you're a
10 out of 10 leader, you have the
opportunity to be wildly successful.
Inevitably, you know, your health truly
does pay off. Number 11, sleep is the
new equity. People brag about losing
sleep at work, but in your 30s and 40s,
sleep is one of the highest return
investments you can make. You know, at
23, I remember always being the person
that was burning the midnight oil,
staying up oftentimes till 9:00 or 10:00
p.m. working. You know, saw it as almost
a badge of honor not getting much sleep.
This is probably one of the stupidest
things I could have done, because you're
working a lot, but you're super
ineffective. And with that little amount
of sleep, you're basically drunk every
day. As I fast forward to now being 35
years old, you know, I prioritize sleep
as one of the most important aspects of
my day. And so, this involves things
like at 7:00 p.m. using the 7:00 p.m.
trigger as a time to put on red light
glasses and initiate the nighttime
routine. You know, this routine is
everything, right? Because a great
night's sleep makes me insanely
productive in the morning and makes sure
that I'm able to get that 7:00 a.m. to
11:00 a.m. deep work routine and really
push the needle forward in my
businesses. Great sleep turns average
effort into peak output. Number 12, your
content has depth. 20-somethings post
quotes, 30-plus founders post scars, and
your scars will be quotes any day. You
know, when I was building Herb, my
second business, there was one day I had
realized that we were way over our skis.
You know, we had invested far too much
in people, the head count had gone from
about eight core people to around 32.
And I realized one day that I'd have to
go and remove 23 people on our team in
one day. You know, this experience, at
the time, was super traumatizing, and
looking back, it's one of the lowest
points of my career. But, you know, I've
shared this story with founders,
pointing out the importance of number
one, having systems in their business so
they don't need to have so many people.
And number two, the importance of
sometimes just making the hard decision.
You know, sometimes things that we need
to do are incredibly uncomfortable. You
know, over, you know, my career, I've
found the more vulnerable I am, the more
I just share those things that sometimes
feel super uncomfortable to let people
know about, the more I build connection,
you know, the more people can feel the
general authenticity in my content, and
the more I've been able to build a
movement of founders around me. So, when
you go and think about your own content
and the scars that you have, think about
the playbooks that you wish you had 5
years ago, the systems, the blueprints,
the deep dives, the how-tos. You know,
think about what you would have wanted 5
years ago, and then go and use that for
the basis of the content that you create
now. It's those scars, those moments
that you've had to go and really
struggle through something, those
crucibles of leadership, that will help
go and benefit the next generation of
builders. Number 13, the trifecta of
success is assets, leverage, and
attention. When it comes to assets, it's
those things that you can build once and
sell forever. When it comes to leverage,
it comes down to the media around you,
the people, the capital, and the systems
that you build in your business. And
then, attention by building your own
personal media company around you. When
it comes to those three aspects of
building an online business, I find that
the biggest piece that people forget is
attention. You know, we live in a
totally new day and age, right? Where
attention is where the real wealth is
built. You know, being able to build
your own organic audience and not have
to rely on paid ads. Being able to go
and have a brand that's not just with
you for the next decade of your life,
but for the next 50 years. You know,
your personal brand is the most valuable
appreciating asset you can build. You
know, if you're watching this, it's that
attention piece that I'd recommend that
you double down on. You know, your 30s
and 40s are amazing opportunity for you
to create content, build an audience
around you, and control your own media.
Number 14, money buys speed, not
happiness. We think money will make us
happy, but it doesn't. In reality, it
just buys us speed. As I've gone and
built my own profitable empire of online
businesses, I always think to myself,
you know, what's my 10-year vision? And
then, how do I actually accelerate that
to get it done over the next 6 months?
Now, when I then think about money, you
know, money's not something that, you
know, is going and just helping me solve
all my problems in life, but it
certainly helps me go and attack things
a lot faster. You know, if I find
there's a certain challenge in my
business, I'm able to go deploy capital
to go maybe hire the right person there,
or go and build the right system in
place, or the right automation to go and
remove it. You know, the reality is is
that you can use money in a way that's a
tool to eliminate a lot of the problems
that come up in business, making it a
lot more smooth and helping you go and
accomplish the big vision that you have
for your life, as well as for the things
you're building. Number 15, stop
building businesses, start building
ecosystems. One business is fragile, but
when you build an ecosystem, one
business feeds everything else. When I
got into my 30s, I started viewing
myself more as an asset manager than an
entrepreneur. There was one moment that
changed everything for me as an
entrepreneur. You know, learning about
Carl Icahn, I saw this guy that actually
viewed himself as a portfolio manager,
not just a founder. And I started to
reflect on my own businesses and
realized that I'd always put my
businesses first, and I was kind of
behind the scenes. But, you know, after
learning from Carl Icahn, I started to
put myself at the top of the chain and
then be this asset manager that managed
a portfolio of different online
businesses. Now, what this caused me to
do is start building myself too in my
own presence, because no matter what, if
I exit different businesses, the thing
that will always remain true is that I
will always have my personal brand, and
it can always feed these businesses
different leads and awareness. So, when
I go and I think about my portfolio
these days, I think of it as an
ecosystem. You know, my personal brand
feeds my business brands, my business
brands feed the different cash flows to
the businesses, which allow me to go and
focus on more people, more exceptional
content, which just drives more leads to
the business, more cash flows, and
creates this founder flywheel. And so,
as you're going and creating, you know,
your own businesses, trying to create
different flywheels within them is the
key. You know, how is your organic
content feeding you leads, feeding you
cash flows, and the ability to go and
hire more amazing people to build an
amazing product, and then, you know,
perpetuating itself. And the goal is
that you have a portfolio of different
businesses so that you're more
antifragile long-term. No matter what
happens, one business may go up or down,
but because you're diversified, having a
portfolio of businesses, you're
essentially rock-solid for the next
decade, two decades, three decades of
your life. Number 16, your business
should not be your identity. The biggest
trap entrepreneurs fall into, becoming
their business. In my first business,
BitMaker, you know, I was entirely tied
to the business. My identity was the
business. If the business was doing
well, I was high as a kite. If the
business was failing, I felt like a
complete failure. I'd essentially
blocked myself off to the world, and
everything I did was focused on this one
business. I was essentially a martyr. At
the peaks and the valleys, you know, the
business was everything to me. While
that could seem like a strength, it
actually was probably one of the biggest
weaknesses. You know, what I've learned
now in my 30s is that it's really
important to have an identity outside of
my business. You know, it's important to
have different hobbies, different things
you like to do, whether it's paddle
tennis, running, you know, going and
hiking, being in nature. You know,
having hobbies outside of the business
is important, because when you're able
to detach yourself from things, you can
just see the business a lot more
clearly. Number 17, stop trying to be
original, start being repeatable. Most
people waste years chasing originality,
the masters focus on repeatability. In
my second business, Herb, you know, at
one point, we were constantly trying to
be original and create new custom things
for every single person that we worked
with. It got exhausting. All this
customization just led to chaos. I
eventually made three rules for any
product that we started. It had to be
repeatable, it had to be scalable, and
we had to be able to deliver it on time
at a high quality. Every business is
repetitive at its core. You know, you
think of Apple, a $4 trillion company,
at the end of the day, they're on iPhone
number 17. You know, this shows that by
just focusing on one core thing and
doing it right, you can create something
magical. Number 18, consistency beats
intensity. Intensity gets you started,
consistency is what compounds. When I
think about building anything amazing,
it comes down to building something over
the long term. You know, when you think
about building something not just for 5
years or 10 years, but for like 20, 30
years, you know, being able to have a
consistent system for what you need to
do is everything. Because without it,
you're going to burn out and you're
going to give up and will stop the
compounding. Number 19, perfectionism is
just procrastination in disguise. One of
the sayings that I love most is done is
better than perfect. I think often times
as founders, we can wait for the you
know, the perfect moment, the perfect
piece of content, the perfect product.
But often times, perfect never comes
around. You know, I think a lot of
people think you need to figure it out
and then launch it. But the truth is
often times, you launch it and then you
figure it out. You know, when you think
about business, I think that 97% of
success is actually correction. The
majority of the time, we're off track.
Things are not quite right and it's your
ability to then get things back on track
that'll get that product right. You
know, you'll be able to build the right
team by just getting things out there.
You know, when I thought of launching
FounderUs at first, truthfully, the
first version of the community we
launched, you know, was something that I
was even kind of embarrassed by. But
when I look back, I'm really glad that I
just launched it because what I was able
to then do is get feedback from people,
learn, you know, what do founders really
need? What are the systems that are
missing? What are the areas that I can
go and make it stronger? And from all of
that feedback, I was incredibly
motivated to then build the community
into what it is today. Number 20, if you
don't own attention, you don't own a
business. In today's world, attention
isn't optional, it's everything. There's
this quote that I love, which is that
first time founders focus on product,
second time founders focus on
distribution. Now, you can have an
amazing product, but if it never sees
the light of day, it's all for nothing.
On the other side, I've seen hundreds of
founders with a mediocre product, but
massive amounts of attention and
audience around them actually be
incredibly successful. Now, because all
that attention doesn't just drive your
first customers, but it also gives you
an enormous amount of feedback on what
the market actually wants. And so, the
future belongs to founders that are
commanding attention. And the best way
to do this is to go and build your own
personal brand and your audience around
you. Which leads me to number 21,
distribution is more important than
product. You know, when I think about,
you know, my own business and the
portfolio of online businesses I've
built, what I spend a lot of my time on
is really mastering the distribution
around the different communities and
products. When I go and think about
YouTube as an example, this platform
drives 4x more leads than the next
platforms combined. You know, going and
focusing on things like the thumbnails,
the titles, the scripts, the hooks, the
colors, everything, you know, is
incredibly valuable and is an insane
amount of leverage on my time. From one
YouTube video like this, I may go and
generate 50,000 views. You can imagine
50,000 people. That's like a massive
stadium of folks, which just shows you
how powerful distribution can be if you
go and you utilize it correctly. A great
product with no distribution dies, a
mediocre product with great distribution
thrives. Number 22, relationships are
assets. Most people treat relationships
like feelings. Smart founders treat
relationships like assets. When I was
23, my first business was raided by the
government. This was by far the most
shocking thing that had ever happened to
me to that point. But when I took a step
back and realized that everyone the
world was against me, I figured I would
go and actually use the people that I'd
met over the previous 2 years building
that business to go and help potentially
save the day. Sure enough, over the next
3 days, I emailed over 3,000 people I
had met and within 1 week, the story was
trending on Twitter in Canada. Against
all odds, we were back in business the
next week and had the only exemption of
its kind in Canada and that business
would go on to exit for a life-changing
sum. You know, it was this experience
that really taught me that relationships
are assets. These days, every single
month, I go and I reflect on, you know,
what is my personal board of advisors?
Who are the people around me in given
parts of my life and business that can
help support me and help me get to the
next level. I think about areas of
business like marketing, sales, growth,
content, people, strategy and I have the
right people in place to go and advise
me. People like my executive coach, Ryan
Begelman, who exited his last business
for $60 million bootstrapped and is now
helping me go and scale my businesses to
that same level or, you know, even
further. You know, it's inevitably
people and getting, you know, secrets
from other mentors and advisors around
you that is ultimately one of the
biggest shortcuts in entrepreneurship.
You know, you can go and learn from
other people's mistakes versus having to
go and make those mistakes yourself.
Number 23, outgrowing people is part of
the process. Not everyone can come with
you to the next level and that's okay. I
was traveling Norway with a good friend
named Jan just a couple months ago. You
know, and he was talking to me about how
a certain people in his circles that
were kind of holding him back. And often
times, you know, as founders, I see this
all the time, right? You have a circle
of people that, you know, may have
gotten you from where you were 10 years
ago to where you are now. But when you
go and you reflect on the people around
you, maybe you've outgrown them or even
worse, maybe some of these people are
holding you back. You know, it's
important that we part our own dreams
first. The reality is is that the same
circle you had in your 20s may actually
be holding you back in your 30s and 40s.
And so, it's about going and betting on
your dreams, making the tough decision
to probably cut some people off and
double down on friends that really
believe in you and that, you know, fill
up your cup, fill up your soul and are
helping propel you forward to the person
you're trying to become. Number 24, your
ego is the tax on every decision. The
more you let your ego drive decisions,
the more expensive those decisions get.
At 26 years old, I received a
life-changing offer, $50 million for my
business. This was a sum that
legitimately would change the entire
trajectory of my life. At the time, I
remember seeing, you know, different
images of folks like Zuckerberg or
Spiegel that turned down life-changing
billion-dollar offers to bet big on
their thing. And instead of really doing
a bit of soul-searching as to, you know,
what I needed in my life and what would
fill up my cup, I just kind of let my
ego take over. Sure enough, I said no to
these offers. Looking back, it was
probably the stupidest decision I ever
could have made. You know, often times,
I'll think back to that with just a
little bit of regret. You know, what was
I thinking? You know, why did I do that?
And when I look at it, I had let my ego
take over. You know, I was just, you
know, thinking that I could accomplish
the world. 50 million, what's that? Why
not 500 million, 5 billion? When the
reality that businesses in the industry
I was in were a lot different. You know,
I want to make sure that for you, right?
Don't let your ego blind you.
Inevitably, you know, stay rational, you
know, stay clear, um and try to keep
your ego in check unlike I did at 26.
Number 25, you don't need more time, you
need better seasons. Everyone says they
need more time, but the truth is, you
just need clear seasons. It's amazing
what you can accomplish in life if you
just set a deadline on things. You know,
this is what Parkinson's law is all
about. The work that you put into
something is just going to fill up the
amount of time you allot for it. You
know, when I was 22, my back was up
against the wall and I needed to raise
capital for one of my companies. I gave
myself 90 days and basically said, "By
the end of these 90 days, I am going to
raise over $4 million."
You know, sure enough, emailed over
2,000 people, had over 400
conversations, got over 384 no's to get
14 yes's and end up closing that round
from legendary investors like the CEO
and CEO of Shopify, Joe Montana the Hall
of Fame quarterback, the board of
Viacom, number eight, number 20 at
Facebook and the list goes on. All of
this would not have been possible if I
hadn't of just dedicated that season to
just raising this capital. And so, it's
amazing what you can accomplish if you
set a deadline on things and live in
seasons versus giving yourself all the
time in the world. There's a saying that
I live by, which is that pressure makes
diamonds. Feel free and be willing to go
and put a deadline on things to go and
help make the impossible possible.
Number 26, don't chase passion, chase
problems. Everyone says follow your
passion, but the real wins come from
solving massive problems. These days,
when I think of starting any business, I
like to focus on a problem that
genuinely excites me. You know, I built
FounderUs because I was looking to solve
three main problems. Number one, people
wanted to go and build amazing personal
brands, but they didn't know how. Number
two, they wanted to create systematized
organic content to scale their audience
so they didn't have to rely on paid ads.
And third, you know, just like I had in
my previous two businesses, more and
more founders wanted to remove
themselves from operations. And so, it
was these three problems that I sought
out to solve with FounderUs. You know,
what's that problem or set of problems
that really fire you up? How can you go
and focus on, you know, being the best
in the world at solving those problems
and building a business around that? You
don't need to just focus on passions,
right? Become great at solving a problem
and you'll become passionate about it.
Number 27, stop saying I should have
started earlier and start saying I
should have start right now. The best
time to start was 20 years ago, the
second best time is today. Stop wasting
time in regret. is is that we all have
the same 24 hours in the day and the
only difference is what you choose to do
with them. You know, when you think
about what you're building right now,
what is your 10-year vision that is
insanely exciting to you? Now, what do
you need to do over the next 3 years to
ladder up to that 10-year vision? Now,
from there, what do you need to do over
the next 1 year and then in the next 90
days? And then just get after it. Don't
worry about what other people are doing.
Don't worry about, "Oh, 10 years ago I
could have started this." Or, you know,
"Am I too old now?" All of that is just
a load of [\h__\h] getting in your way. The
reality is is that we can all just start
where our feet are now, right? Start
with what you've got. Start today and
just start messy. Number 28, character
is built through repetition, not
decisions. You don't decide your
character once, you decide it every day
through repetition. You know, excellence
is a daily habit. You know, you want to
be a prolific writer, write every day.
You want to be an amazing person on
camera, film every week. You know, you
want to be amazing at building teams,
focus on reading more on hiring every
day and building an amazing culture
around you. It's the repetition that's
going to create excellence in your life.
You know, excellence is a daily habit.
You know, for me as a founder, one of
the things that jazzes me up the most is
creating the greatest founder content in
the world. This is a massive goal and I
think I still have a long way to go. I
don't let this big goal paralyze me. The
reality is is that, you know, it starts
with just the daily actions, writing
every day, filming every week, you know,
building an amazing team around me,
putting in the reps, making each piece
of content 10% better than the last,
focusing on getting 1% better every
single day. It's from these tiny daily
wins that you're able to accomplish
massive things over the long term. You
know, from repetition you build the
power of compounding, which is like the
eighth wonder in the world. And so,
focus on those small things you can do
repeatedly that allow you to ladder up
to the big vision you have for yourself.
You don't decide your character once,
you build it every day through
repetition. Number 29, age is not your
enemy, experience is your advantage.
Everyone fears getting older, but in
entrepreneurship experience is your
greatest weapon. Experience is leverage
that no one can steal. You know, all
those lessons that you've learned over
the years, all those mistakes you've
made, all those challenges, those are
now, you know, the amazing leverage that
you have to go and, you know, see around
corners, to have more leadership, and
you'll be able to do things the right
way and just build smarter. You know, a
lot of the things that, you know, I do
today, it's not just the systems, the
media, the leverage that I have around
me. It's just because I put in 10,000
reps doing what I'm doing. I have
experience, I have wisdom, and I'm able
to kind of see 17 steps ahead in many of
the things I'm working on because I've
just, you know, done this so many times.
Number 30, retirement is a lie. You
don't need to design a life you need to
escape from. We're sold the dream of
retiring at 60, but that's a lie. The
real dream is building a life that you
don't need to retire from. These days I
focus on everyday retirement or EDR. You
know, I discovered this by going
completing my own ikigai. You know, your
ikigai is really what your reason for
being is. It's your calling in life and
it sits at the inner section of what
you're good at, what you can be paid
for, what the world needs, and what you
love to do. For me, that's things like
building an amazing community of
founders. It's, you know, building
systems, building distribution, going
and creating content, traveling, you
know, being in nature, backpacking.
These are the things that really fire me
up. Every day I've architected a life
that allows me to do these things every
day, every week. You know, this is what
it's all about, right? This is what you
deserve in your 30s and 40s. I hope that
you go and take the advice from this
video and go and implement it because I
can't wait to see what you create. I've
also gone and linked my own scale
yourself playbook, which is the same
playbook I've used throughout my 30s to
get to where I am today. You can go and
download it via the link in the
description. So, in this video I've
shared a lot of advice and my hope is
that you just pick three main things
that stood out and go and implement
those today to go build your own
leverage, your own assets, and your own
attention. And so, I hope you found this
video useful. I can't wait to see what
you create and welcome to the founder
freedom movement.