If you can only sell one thing, you're
leaving 80% of your income on the table.
So, here's how to fix that. Validate
demand before you build, sell it, then
create it. And once you validate, you
don't just need one offer, you need a
stack. You need three offers that ascend
people through your personal brand
universe. An entry-level offer, core
offer, and high-ticket offer. The
psychology behind all of this is people
need small wins before they trust you to
then make bigger investments. So, here's
exactly how to build your offer stack.
Step one, validate demand. Talk to 30
people in your audience and ask, "What's
[music] your biggest problem with, you
know, insert your topic?" Ask, "If I
solve that completely, what would it be
worth?" Step two, design your entry
offer. Take one specific problem and
solve it completely for someone in 7 to
14 days. Package it as a PDF, a mini
course, or a checklist. Step three,
build your core offer. This is your main
transformation. Maybe it's a curriculum,
community, coaching program. You want
the price based on the value created,
not the time spent. Step four, create a
high-ticket offer. Ask yourself, "Who
needs speed and personal access? What
would a one-to-one with you unlock?" You
want to package this as direct access,
faster results, and custom solutions.
Price should feel expensive, but obvious
to the right people. Don't
overcomplicate it. Just get clear on the
stack and you can refine as you go.