[Music]
I want you to
imagine think of someone making $1.2
million a
month what do they look like what
business do you think they run what do
you think their days are like how long
would you guess they are working most
people would say 12 maybe 14 hours a day
grinding
endlessly but what if I told you I do
the complete opposite right now I only
work 4 hours a day and with the other 20
I've been traveling through the Alps in
France mountain biking through Italy and
exploring the beauty of Japan all while
making $13.8 million this year and I
only work 4 hours a day but it wasn't
always like this when I was 22 I was
trapped in running a business that was
running me into the ground I thought I
was living the entrepreneur dream but I
was burned out and miserable fast
forward to today I built a life that I
once thought was impossible complete
Freedom traveling the world staying in
the best shape of my life and making
more money than I ever ever imagined
here's the best part I'm going to show
you how I did it step by step this is
the exact framework I use to make more
money while working less it all comes
down to mastering the three pillars of
freedom and I'll walk you through them
right now the first pillar is radical
Focus studies show that multitasking
reduces productivity by 40% your
business should have a singular Focus
for example at my company founder OS
we're focused on creating the greatest
founder community in the world our goal
is to Dazzle Founders we do this by
creating profitable personal brands for
Founders radical Focus doesn't just
apply to your company it also filters
down to your team you know if you want
to get to $10 million in Revenue a year
you need every single person on your
team to have a singular Focus the lad is
up to the overall company Focus here's
my orc chart every single person on my
team has a radical focus in their
individual area let me give you a quick
snapshot of what this looks like Claire
my chief of staff is radically focused
on hiring we have an aggressive hiring
strategy over the next year and Claire
is in charge of making sure the job
descriptions already and we are hiring
weapons next here is Hayden my Chief
Financial Officer Hayden is focused on
cash flow which is the lifeblood of our
company it's probably what you want your
CFO focused on as well next aspect here
is Don the chief technology officer
founder OS he's radically focused on
getting 500 leads per month as I like
the technology side of our business to
be tight coupled with the sales engine
Jake here the cro is focused on getting
us to $1 million in Revenue per month
and we're so close next here our
director of marketing Michael focuses on
getting us to 120 High converting pieces
of content per month and really feeding
the overall content engine that we've
been building at founder OS Thomas our
writer absolute Legend focus on two high
converting pieces of content per day to
make sure that platforms like X in
LinkedIn are loaded up and driving
people through ctas to our found R Us
newsletter on the next aspect here Sarah
the legendary video editor that puts
together so many of our amazing YouTube
videos is responsible for one
highquality video per week this allows
her to focus on quality over quantity
because quality is the ultimate pattern
interrupt next here is Jordan the brand
strategist who's our closer and
responsible for getting 40 closed deals
per month and then we have the overall
structure so you can imagine how every
single person I just went over goes and
ladders up to the overall company vision
and you want to make sure that in your
company every single person has a core
Focus the ladds up to your radical Focus
as a
company and in any given year I have one
core Focus myself this year my focus on
hitting $20 million in Revenue across my
portfolio of online businesses while
working less than 20 hours per week but
leveraging a team of weapons is only
half the battle to achieve radical Focus
you also need to strategically leverage
systems the issue in many companies is
that the founder is the only one that
ends up creating systems and it burns
you out and this becomes a single point
of failure if the founder leaves for a
few weeks or gets busy the house just
begins to collapse on a personal level
this is terrifying because everything
relies on you you feel like if you don't
continue to document every little thing
in your company things are just become a
massive mous trap with with you as the
victim how do you overcome this you need
to democratize the responsibility across
your team and Empower weapons to
systemize their rules systems equal
Freedom this is my team accountability
chart you can see that every single
person on my team is assigned a core
Focus as well as systems they own and
must have documented and kept up to date
this ensures that as we scale we stay
organized and I can sleep at night
knowing the team is growing on autopilot
and the most powerful system I've ever
created is the content GPS it drives
over a million a month to my online
businesses the content GPS system
connects your audience to monetized
offers via scroll stopping strategic
content that compounds your reach within
your Niche and Industry content GPS is
built into the third pillar of Freedom
which I'll reveal really soon for now
leverage weapons of their craft Empower
them with systems and move on to the
hardest part of the first step choosing
what to focus on to TR your focus you
will need a framework and this framework
is the one that's helped me identify
exactly what I should be focusing my
attention
[Music]
on start with figuring out your zone of
Genius ask yourself what do I naturally
excel at where do I struggle when am I
in my element from there you can fill
out this diagram for yourself and
identify the core area in the top right
that you should be most focused on in
your business to provide the maximum
amount amount of Leverage my focus early
on in building my businesses was to grow
my audience around my personal brand to
over 2 million people in one year it's
both in my zone of genius and provides
an insane amount of Leverage to my
portfolio of businesses in the last 15
months this radical focus on growing my
audience has allowed me to build an
audience of over 2.5 million people
around my personal brand once you're
clear on your zone of Genius you need to
focus on Mastery and drive it forward as
much as possible every single day now
that you're clear on what to focus on
let's focus on the next pillar deep
[Music]
work deep work is sacred time that you
have to work on stuff that only you can
do the secret to getting ahead of 99% of
people in the next 30 days is your
commitment to deep work when you can
achieve it you'll easily see how 60
Minutes of deep work does more for you
than 8 hours of shallow work stop
whatever you're doing go to your
calendar right now and block off 4 hours
daily for deep work no phone no social
media this is when your mind is freshest
and the most creative protect this time
at all costs here are 10 steps to
protect your focus this is my deep work
routine number one turn off your phone
block off 4 hours a day to be completely
free of distractions I block off from
7:00 a.m. to 11:00 a.m. daily it's just
me my I slte a kind of music set on
Soundcloud and my computer no phone no
social media two practice mindfulness
and meditate spend 10 minutes each
morning to clear your mind it primes you
for a day of focus I love this abundance
meditation by Bob Proctor three get more
sleep entrepreneurs are athletes sleep
is fuel for high performance I make sure
I'm in bed every night before 1000 p.m.
that way I'm asleep by 11:00 p.m. and
can get 7 to 8 hours of sleep every
night sleep is the ultimate product AC
it juice four take strategic breaks you
ear a machine you need to slow down you
can't be truly productive if all you do
his work get outside call a friend
explore and get into nature five connect
with
nature but step number five is connect
with nature
after doing that deep work for four
weeks consistently you need a break I
like to go and take a trip I call it a
soul trip a soul trip is a chance to
recharge and really Revitalize yourself
because that bucket list isn't meant
just to stay on a list it's meant to
actually check off I've taken trips to
Yus traveled all the way through to
Japan and here we're just watching a
Mexican volcano explode
holy Bro all right film for me it
helps me on a deeper level I view it as
a tool that helps me to get clear boost
my creativity get the juices and the
Mojo flowing again really reduce things
like burnout I'd recommend that right
now you look say 3 4 weeks out and you
decide on what is your soul trip going
to be what's that thing that you're
going to do to disconnect from the deep
work and go and actually live life go
block off your calendar go book that
trip let's
go six exercise
[Music]
daily energy plus motion equals emotion
exercise boost testosterone increases
energy and focus and raises your overall
mood and wellbeing early in my
entrepreneural career I neglected my
health and I paid a price and found
myself in a pit of burnout depression
and despair movement is medicine if you
can push yourself daily real magic
happens seven listen to
music Here's my current Spotify playlist
the right music can help you get into a
flow State and drown out any
distractions I have a dedicated deep
work playlist with instrumental tracks
that put me in the zone some of my
favorite tracks are on Soundcloud from
Legends like Nora Ure Tim Green and Lee
Burge number eight eat well here's my
daily Health protocol and diet that I
received from my health coach stie who
is an absolute Superwoman and I couldn't
recommend highly enough number nine have
fun we've all been there working on a
task that is just killing us boring
irritated and we just want to move on
when you feel stuck ask yourself what
would this look like if it were fun and
the anchor for all of your deep work
number 10 have a compelling Mission my
mission is to help 100 million
entrepreneurs accomplish their dreams
through proven systems write down your
mission and the goal of what you want to
do in the next 990 days make your goals
smart where they're specific measurable
actionable realistic and time down now
that you have your 4 hours of deep
workor scheduled in your calendar let's
move on to the next pillar number three
your personal Media Company whether you
know it or not you have a personal brand
the question is are you intentionally
growing it the future belongs to folks
building a media company around
themselves this is the future of
Entrepreneurship you are the media
company you own a community of Raving
fans and you control your distribution
not Zuck not musk a personal Media
Company grows everything around you by
completing three functions one it drives
attention to your products and companies
two it brings you a flood of customers
and cash flow and three it attracts top
talent so you no longer need to chase
new hires taking the first step boils
down to two core actions assembling
weapons and calibrating your content
GPS number one is to assemble weapons
but I'm not talking about this weapon
I'm talking about an obsessed individual
who when brought onto a company has the
ability to 10x their area they go above
and beyond to fulfill the mission hire
more weapons just like them and Elevate
the culture in speed of innovation here
are the areas that weapons can help you
with tech sales b-roll photos design
writing filming funnels automations
operations animations you don't need all
of these folks to get started that would
be kind of crazy here's what found
looked like just 2 years ago and then 4
months later I recruited my first three
weapons with cash flows I had grown for
my audience within a year I was making
over $200,000 in Revenue a month fast
forward to today and this is what my
company looks like this rapid growth
with is all possible because I leverage
the most powerful system I've ever
discovered which leads me to step two
step two in kickstarting your personal
Media company is to calibrate your
content GPS the content GPS has helped
me pull in over $20 million to my
businesses over the last 5 years I've
done this while traveling the world and
building an audience of over 2.5 million
people around my personal brand and all
of this while only working 4 hours a day
the content GPS has three core
components number one grow your audience
across social media using proven
audience growth systems number two
create a compounding Loop by owning your
audience in your email list and number
three monetize your audience with offer
systems most people mess this up they
create random content with no systems
that's the recipe for Burnout and giving
up to drive all three components of your
content system you need to First focus
on the next three steps one you must
have unique Creator positioning I am
known online as the systems guy when it
comes to growing an online business when
people think of me they think of systems
what do you want to be known for online
two scroll stopping content establish
four content categories mine are
personal stories personal branding
monetization systems and audience growth
systems what are your four content
categories next you need to populate
these categories with content ideas that
are going to go and compel people to
follow you engage with you and buy from
you and since we're entrepreneurs and
not influencers I've created a system so
you never hit writer block when thinking
of what content to make I call it the
founder OS content idea machine you must
use this framework to come up with 30
amazing content ideas in just 30 minutes
you can steal it via the link in the
description all of this content then
flows through the last part of the
content GPS equation the content funnel
I'm on Instagram YouTube X LinkedIn and
Tik Tok driving thousands of leads to my
businesses daily I leverage my content
waterfall system to make one piece of
content and then distribute it over 30
pieces of content across all platforms I
do this with a small team and with the
powerful systems that we've built and
this is the key ingredient to making all
of that content put money in your
pocket intentionally play ctas ctas are
links to your newsletter or product or
service I use all the social platforms
to drive my audience on social media to
my convert kit newsletter my newsletter
is a centralized place where I nurture
my audience I've created the best
newsletter in the world for proven
systems to grow your profitable personal
brand every single week I give away a
free system to help you go and build
your personal brand at record speed all
of these ctas are attached to every
single piece of content on a daily basis
across all five platforms maximizing the
monetary return from my content if you
want to book a call with my team to see
if you're a good fit for us to install a
100% custom version of the content GPS
into your business for you you can check
it out via the link in the description