One hour flow is worth 10 hours of
distracted work. Here's how to lock it
in. Every morning, I start my day with
what I call my momentum hour. This is
from 6:00 a.m. to 7:00 a.m. I drink
water, take vitamins, get sunlight in my
eye for 30 minutes, and then go for a
walk. So, then from 7:00 a.m. [music] to
11:00 a.m., I am locking in because it's
time for founder flow. This is my deep
work time. No phone, no distractions, no
inputs. The only thing that exists is me
and the work that I've got to do. I'm
writing, I'm building systems, creating
content, designing strategies. [music]
Founder flow is different, right? It's
protected. It's sacred. It's the time
when you actually [music] build your
future instead of just maintaining your
present. So, tomorrow morning, turn off
your phone, work only on tasks that are
in your zone of genius. Do this for 30
days straight [music] and watch your
output explode.