When I first started FounderOS,
it was started
with this inspirational question that I
got
from one of my good friends, Steve, the
founder of Pray.com. He goes to me, he
goes, "Matt, what would you do
if you knew you would be successful?"
And it hit me, you know,
traveling the world, helping founders,
viewing entrepreneurship as this soulful
journey,
you know, genuinely just showing up,
giving people the systems that I had
built in the previous 16 years building
some companies.
And
boy, has it ever been a journey.
You know, looking back, that was about 5
years ago now,
and I think it's one of the most
powerful questions a friend has ever
given me. So,
what would you do if you knew you would
be successful?