How I filmed 30 days of content in just
4 hours. Okay, so
bear with me for a sec.
First things first, right? Is you want
to go and write 30 hooks. You don't need
to go and memorize every line of stuff,
right? If you're an expert and you
actually know what the hell it is that
you're talking about, I think that
what's most important is that you nail
the hook and then just go and yap about
the stuff that you're really into.
Inevitably, people resonate with people,
right? And so you want to go and just
make sure that you're sharing, you know,
the kind of stuff that you're really
into, right? Versus feeling like you
need to be perfect, make sure that
you're not putting on some performance,
just show up as you are and the right
people will connect with you and then
screw the rest, right? On the next
aspect here then, you're just going to
go and film them all back-to-back. I
think that you know, when I think about
this, it's like the identity is being a
founder athlete, right? And creating
content like this, it's athletic, let me
tell you. But I'd much rather go and
batch everything in one go versus having
to go
and create a little bit of content every
single day. Screw that, right? The big
wins in life happen from batching the
tasks that you got going so you get into
a flow, you can dial it in, ship it, and
then forget it for a bit and get back to
business, all right? Things like AI
edits, things like Descript and such can
be really useful. I know Memo on my
team, an absolute legend, went and set
up a clip engine that we had built off
Cloud Code, which now runs our in second
Matt Gray business YouTube channel,
right? So AI is pretty insane. So the
rules here, right? No editing stuff
yourself unless it's like, you know,
videos like this that don't need any
edits. Keep
it fun, okay? Tell yourself, "I'm not
here to perform, I'm not here to impress
anyone, I'm here just to give value to
people, you know, just give them
myself." That's it, nothing more,
nothing less, right? I like to do this
stuff in my morning when I'm just fresh,
ready to go, and
your audience, remember, they want real
you, right? Not some fake performance.
And so just show up as you are, have
some fun with it, and realize too that
you're in this kind of forever game. And
so the game is just getting 1% better
each time you do it, you know, if you
get 10% better every month, you're like
13,800 times better in a year with this
stuff, right? So just get on that train
of self-improvement. You got this.