Everyone talks about finding your niche,
but no one talks about choosing your
identity, and that's the real unlock.
You want to go and think about your do's
and don'ts, the kind of stuff that you
want to lean into on the platform, and
the stuff that you want to avoid. Flush
out five do's, five don'ts, and then
just get going with this as your initial
guidelines. From there, you really want
to go and start writing 10 posts as if
you're just going and talking to a
friend. That allows me to speak in my
authentic voice, so we're not trying to
use a bunch of industry jargon or
verbose Right, just talk,
basically. [music] And start attracting
people based on that authentic voice you
have.