Most people are creating content on hard
mode. And if you're watching this, let
me save you here. Here's how to do it on
easy mode. This is the content
waterfall. My system starts with content
creation, one long-form video, and then
I turn that into one deep newsletter
essay. I record different coaching
calls, which are also content goldmines,
and then distribute that. Each editor is
able to generally pull a bunch of the
best moments from these long-form pieces
of content, and then distribute that in
places like YouTube Shorts, Instagram
Reels, and TikTok videos. On the
Instagram side, we typically use
carousels, and it's my designer that
goes and takes our core frameworks and
puts them over there. From there, my
copywriter can turn scripts into
different long-form content for
platforms like LinkedIn as an example.
We also will typically go and take my
raw writing, which I have in different
journals or I'm sharing right now on X
articles, and then they take that and
cut that up into 20-plus other pieces of
content. And so, what you want to do is
take those winners and then waterfall
them. When you waterfall content, you
multiply it.