Stop renting your audience to Zuckerberg
and start owning it. Because here's the
math. Instead of just showing up that
one time, when you own someone's email
on Instagram, you're then able to go
market to that person for the next year,
2 years, 3 years, you're severely
limited by the algorithm. And I don't
think many people realize this. When you
go and you, you know, grow your account
to 10,000, 50,000 followers. Your posts
are not reaching that many people. your
posts are likely only going to show up
to 10% of your followers max on any
given post. That said, when you go and
own these people in an email list, you
know, every post that you put out is
going to be sent to 100% of those emails
that you've collected. The key thing
here is to think about actually owning
that audience instead of simply renting
it from Zuckerberg.