Most people build a business and then
try to build their life around it. I did
the opposite. I built a business that
runs on systems so I could be the actual
CEO of that business versus being some
day-to-day manager. I'm not in meetings
all day. I'm not stuck in Slack messages
and I'm not being consulted with every
decision. This video is a deep dive into
the eight systems that make this all
possible. No fluff, no BS, just the real
systems that help me go and remove
myself from operations without
everything falling apart. Let's get into
it. System number one is the decision
architecture. Now, every single day as
CEOs, we get hit up with tons of
different things that we could be making
the decision around. Should I go and
sign this invoice? Should we approve
this refund? Should we go and post this
piece of content? Should we hire this
person? Should we fire this person? As
founders, as CEOs, you only have so much
decision-making ability in a given day.
The solution isn't making decisions
faster. It's making fewer decisions.
Here's how the decision architecture
works. First off, for every decision
that hits your desk in a given week, go
and write them down. Then, we're going
to go and categorize them into type A,
B, or C decisions. Type A decisions are
decisions that only you can make. Type B
decisions are the kind of decisions that
you're currently making, but that
someone else could probably make as
good, if not better than you. Type C
decisions are the kind of decisions that
no one should even be making. We could
just automate these decisions. So for
type A decisions, you're going to keep
these decisions, right? These are CEO
level decisions that only you can make.
For type B decisions, we're going to
create something called decision trees.
We're going to go and make sure that
there's a framework by which someone can
easily go and make this decision without
even needing you. For type C decisions,
these are decisions that you're
currently making that you could likely
just automate. You know, I have one
client that was able to go and implement
some of these automations in their
business and move from about 200 per
week decisions that were in this type C
bucket to just 15 that were left for
them at the end of it. Pretty insane.
This allowed them to get over 10 hours
back a week. a week that they could then
go and spend whether it's with their
family or friends and enjoy more freedom
in their lives or double down on the
stuff that's in their zone of brilliance
to go and help their business grow that
much faster. System number two, your
communication firewall. This is
genuinely going to save your sanity. I
talk to CEOs all the time that in any
given day are just being inundated with
communication from all directions. The
goal is to have a comm company,
something that runs on proven systems
that you're able to remove yourself from
most of the operations of it and it just
runs on autopilot. Now, you're a CEO.
You're not some glorified switchboard
operator. Here's the structure. We're
going to go through level one, level
two, level three, and level four. Level
one is emergencies only. And I get it
right now. It may feel like there's a
fire going off every few hours in your
business. What I like to get to pretty
quickly in any business I'm running is
rule number one. There are no
emergencies. You need to have people in
place like a chief of staff, a COO, a
CTO that are going and blocking and
tackling your time and being your first
line of defense against any of these
emergencies. Level two is then same day
response. This is things like Slack
messages, emails, and all of that. One
key thing you can start putting in place
is a chief of staff. Someone to go and
help you with all this internal
communication so that you don't need to
be in all of that. And they can just
bubble up the core communication that
you actually need to worry about, which
if they're doing their job right,
hopefully is less than three or so a
day. Level three is your weekly batch.
In my teams, we have a leadership
meeting every single week. whether it's
leaders trying to get answers from me on
core things or me trying to get
responses from them. When in doubt, I'm
generally going and just pulling all of
my requests into that meeting so they
can all get answered in one go over an
hourong meeting and then we can split,
move along and I can get back to my
focus regimen and they can get to theirs
as well. And then we just go and divide
and conquer. And as questions or
challenges or opportunities come up,
boom, that's what our Tuesday leadership
meeting is for. Not sporadic emails, not
pointless Slack messages. Leave it for
the leadership meeting. Level four is
your monthly strategic meetings. And so
this is things like bigger team
planning, bigger questions, you know,
bigger initiatives that we want to make
sure everyone's updated on. What I've
seen work best for a lot of this stuff
is to have a team jam every single
month. And what we simply do is give a
bit of a recap of the big wins of the
month. We then jam around the vision for
the company and how that ladders into
what we're looking to accomplish the
next month. And then we open up the
floor for a team brainstorm and how we
can go and create things like
exceptional content for you the founder.
All right, so you've got your
communication firewall in place, but now
it's time to actually get an amazing
delegation framework into your business.
So system number three, the delegation
framework. Most founders neglect this.
And what ends up happening is they've
got amazing people on their team, but
they're not actually leveraging these
humans to their fullest of their
capabilities. I know many of you have
asked me for delegation help and this is
exactly my system for doing it. It has
three parts. Let's get into it. Part
number one is the brain dump. You've got
to go and audit your calendar and your
to-do list for every single task that
you've worked on over the last month. Go
and document every single task you've
done. Number two, the quality filter. At
this point, what you want to go and do
is go and mark every single one of those
tasks that you probably should not be
doing any longer and that you could
better give to someone on your team that
can do it as good or better than you.
So, you've gone and you've listed all
the tasks. You've now assigned it to
someone on your team. Here is where the
magic comes in. We want to go and make
sure that there's a Google Doc system
for that given thing that allows people
to go and simply execute that system and
do it as well as us. And then the second
thing we're going to do is make sure
that there's a Loom video for every
single thing we're delegating. Now, I
get it. You could be thinking, "Matt,
that's crazy. That's so much work." You
know what's more work than that? You
doing it. So, part number three is the
feedback loop. You've now gone and
handed off that system and the Loom
video to someone on your team so they
could be the systems owner going
forward. The key thing now is that they
feel comfortable with that, that they
feel like they know the ropes and
they're able to implement it correctly.
So, what you're going to do is when you
go and hand that off and that person's
now owning it, you're going to check in
with them a week later and say, "What is
your confidence level with this on a
scale of 1 to 10?" The key thing is
implementing each of these three parts
to go and make sure that you have the
right delegation system in place in your
company. To go and get the most of the
structure you're building, you need the
great systems and people trained on
them. And this is exactly what the
delegation framework's going to help you
do. System number four, the approval
matrix. This is where it's all about
determining what sort of decisions
people are allowed to be making,
especially as it pertains to money. I
like to think of it generally like
there's three different rungs here,
right? You have your individual
contributors, you have your team leads,
and you have executives. When it comes
to level one, your individual
contributors, right? This is people, you
know, that are maybe writers on your
team, right? Or maybe it's someone on a
sales squad. Inevitably, what you may
say is they're allowed to make decisions
that are $2,000 or less. They're welcome
to go and suggest a new piece of
software and pull the trigger on it.
They are welcome to go and run certain
discounts or promotions on your stuff,
assuming it's no more than $2,000. But
anything more than that leads to level
two. This is where the team leads come
in. So team leads, you may deem that
these people are the ones that need to
make decisions between $2 and $30,000.
So they can go and approve a new hire.
They can go and implement a little team
dinner or you know retreat. They must be
consulted though with any decision
between 2 and 30k. That leads us then to
the next level, right? Any decisions
over $30,000. This is where it must go
by an executive. It's when we're making
bigger decisions and strategic decisions
that are going to influence the company
direction in a big way. you know, we're
going to make sure that we bring those
to the executives on the team because
they are the ones that have the approval
to make those kinds of decisions. Set
thresholds based on what you can afford
to lose, not what just makes you
comfortable. I'd much rather my team
make 50 small decisions and make some
mistakes along the way than me
micromanaging every little decision
along the way. System number five, the
information dashboard. The truth is, you
need data to run your business, but you
don't need to be buried in it. I see
some founders that are tracking like 60
metrics across their business and I
think it's just information overload.
Most businesses can be run off of an
acronym that is ACDC just like that rock
band. AC/DC stands for attract, convert,
deliver, collect. Attract is your
ability to go and attract people that
you can sell to. Convert is your ability
to then convert those people to your
product or service. deliver is your
ability to go and give people an amazing
customer experience and then collect is
your ability to actually go and collect
the cash that is owed to you. What I
like to do is across these four
categories to come up with three key
metrics that determine the success of
that given area. So then I go and I put
each of these metrics into a Google
sheet and be able to track it on a
weekly basis. So on each of those
leadership meetings, we can see how
we're doing across these 12 core key
metrics that are across attract,
convert, deliver, and collect. Now, I've
gone and made a template that you can go
and download via the link in the
description. So you can go and implement
this with your team today. So now your
team's rocking and rolling. They've got
their scoreboard and you think things
are going to go well, but inevitably
some problem comes up. And that's where
system number six comes in. The
escalation protocol has three different
levels. So level one are decisions that
your team could just handle. And this is
about 80% of things that are escalated.
You know, adding a user to Slack, adding
someone to Gmail, you know, these are
simple decisions. Now, level two are
manager escalations. These are about 15%
of escalations, right? Maybe someone's
underperforming, not doing what they
should be doing. Maybe someone needs to
be fired or there's potentially a new
hiring request, right? These are things
that your manager can generally handle,
leaving the rest, level three, as
founder level escalations, which should
just be 5%. This is a new strategic
change in the direction of the company,
or maybe you're fundraising, or you
know, you're looking to make some
massive new product. Either way, these
should be limited. And the reality is is
that most decisions should be filtered
down to level one or level two, leaving
only 5% at level three, so the founder
can focus. I like to use what I call the
10 10 10 rule. I'm going to ask myself,
is this thing going to matter in 10
minutes, 10 months, or 10 years? If it's
not going to matter in 10 minutes, my
team can just go and answer it. If it's
something that's going to matter in 10
months that we need to answer on, a
manager can handle it. If it's something
that we're not sure about that's going
to impact us in 10 years, yeah, that's
something that I'm happy to help with.
Now, let's get to system number seven,
the automation stack. Now, most founders
think about automation wrong, right?
they try to just suddenly go and start
automating everything. I think you want
to go and indicate different tiers of
automations and start banging them out
one by one but in this order. Tier one
are administrative decisions. You know,
invoicing, payment processing, some of
the nitty-gritty stuff that really no
one on your team should be handling out
the gate. Tier two is then marketing
automation. Inside of Founder US, as an
example, we use HubSpot for all of our
marketing needs. And so when we're going
and onboarding a new customer, we're
printing the invoice for that person.
We're then upselling them and we're
tracking our analytics from our actual
payments to our traffic and
understanding which pieces of content
are performing best. Everything is held
in a HubSpot dashboard in one spot. So
we can track the effectiveness of our
marketing and I don't even need to hire
anyone around analytics because HubSpot
just shows me. Tier three are operations
automation. And so when you're going and
thinking about what to automate next,
you want to be thinking about the tasks
that are going and taking up the
majority of your time that are probably
the easiest to automate and just getting
those lowhanging fruit off your plate as
fast as possible. From there, over time,
you're moving from admin tasks to more
marketing automations to more of your
operational automations, right? But
tackle them generally in that order.
I've seen clients go and implement this,
be able to save 20 hours a week of their
time, which inevitably just helps them
grow their brand that much faster
because they're investing their time on
the decisions that only they can do.
System number eight is the replacement
test. What this all comes down to is can
you go and walk away from your business
for 4 weeks and come back to a business
that's stronger than when you left? It
doesn't matter what happens, you have
escalation protocols in place. It
doesn't matter what happens. You have
decision frameworks in place and the
right person has been delegated given
tasks. This allows you to walk away from
your business and experience peace of
mind. You can sleep at night knowing
you're no longer essential to your
business anymore. The team has got it
handled. I know when I first experienced
this around a decade ago in my second
business, it blew my mind. Now, I had
been running Herb from the inside for so
many years and finally was able to get
myself out of it and watch it run even
better without me. It was pure magic. It
made me feel so inspired and it actually
helped me go and invent new things for
the business that completely transformed
the trajectory of that business. We were
able to go invent new dashboards, new
analytics tools because I finally had
the opportunity to just think and ponder
and strategize and scheme and plot the
important things that so many of us
founders get no time to do. Now, here's
the critical part, right? You can't
implement all eight of these systems all
at once. And that's why I've gone and
created the 30-day CEO transformation
via the link in the description. I went
and spent about 12 hours with my team to
go and put this together so you had a
clear action plan on how to actually go
and implement all eight systems that I
went over in this video. So go and check
that out via the link in the
description. This is your
transformation, your business, your
life. You have the choice to make. You
can not implement these systems and keep
going how you're going, working 70our
weeks, constantly dealing with fires, or
you can go and implement these eight
systems in your business and transform
where you are and become the CEO you
were destined to be. Thanks for watching
and I'll see you in the next