Most people try to hustle their way to
making millions. I spent the last 16
years learning the five levels of
business, and now I can work where I
want, when I want, and my portfolio of
online businesses makes me $13 million a
year. Most people fail not because
they're lazy, but because they try to
bring level one behaviors into [music] a
level five business. But the truth is,
each level requires a death, a death of
old identity, old systems, old habits
that are keeping [music] you back. So,
in this video, I'm breaking down the
five levels of business, what's going to
break at each stage, and what you need
to implement to scale seamlessly. Let's
get into it. Level one, the scrapper. At
this level, most people overthink
everything and then never start. But the
ones who make it, they master one skill
that has nothing to do with strategy.
[music] When I started BitMaker at 20, I
had no idea what I was doing. This is my
first business, I was broke, I had
[music] hardly any experience, fresh out
of business school, and I was
delusional. While this was a strength,
it also led me to a ton of mistakes.
Marketing [music] came down to me. Sales
came down to me.
Finance, me. Operations, me. Legal, me.
And sleep?
Never.
And that had a knock-on effect. You
know, the amount of times I thought I
just wanted to give up must have been
60, 70 times. I think we glorify the
founder journey, but at this stage, you
guys know it. can get hard, like
real hard. You know, at this stage,
really I think the key thing [music] is
to focus on just getting your first
customers that love your product.
[music] Whether that means outreaching
to a thousand people, whether that means
creating my personal brand, putting
organic content out there, going and
hiring great people, whatever it takes,
I'm going to commit to making this idea
a success. I'm saying this just to be
real with you guys, right? For those of
you guys
>> [music]
>> going through this, I get it. One thing
I also come back to is this essay from
Paul Graham, which is do [music] things
that don't scale. You see all these
businesses that are going in raising a
hundred billion dollars or being valued
at five hundred million dollars or
whatever, right? But the reality is that
a lot of these big businesses that you
admire started off with humble
beginnings. You know, Airbnb was just
some random email from Joe Gebbia and
Brian Chesky [music] saying, "Hey, you
know, maybe we should go and try putting
a mattress in the spare bedroom I have
for South by Southwest in Austin this
weekend." You know, same thing with
Shopify. Started as just an online store
for snowboards slapped together by Tobi
Lütke. Fast forward [music] 15 years
later, hundred billion dollar company.
Be okay with doing things that don't
scale early on. Focus on building
something that people genuinely love.
So, if you want to master this level,
sell a simple offer. Get outside the
building and making sure you're talking
to at least 30 customers. [music]
Incorporate their feedback in terms of
their dreams, their desires back into
the product to build something that is
irresistible. I strongly suggest you
also go and are building your personal
brand, putting content out there because
at the end of the day,
>> [music]
>> distribution is your moat. Next level,
the operator. Most people get stuck here
for years. [music] They're making money,
but dying inside. And there's generally
one thing they're doing wrong. At Earn
My Degree, we were making 30 to 50k per
month, but I was working like an
absolute psychopath, really scaling
something that at this [music] point was
starting to break. Now, the issue was
that our product it was not repeatable,
it [music] was not scalable, and we
weren't able to deliver it on time each
month. And so, what started to happen
was that the cash flows of the company
got super clunky. What I realized I
needed to do was start getting
>> [music]
>> super serious about the people that I
had on board and about our product as
well. You know, it was important that
anything [music] that we sold was
scalable, repeatable, and could be
delivered on time. Now, beyond just the
product, there was also issues in how I
was hiring, right? At this stage, my
hiring processes were anything but
rigorous. Google's Project Oxygen found
that the number one trait of
high-performing managers isn't charisma,
it's systems. This [music] means that
the right decisions matters more than
just being liked. Now, when you think
about going and actually scaling your
business, I think the things that start
to really matter are things like your
systems, [music] your taste, your team,
and the overall culture of the company.
You mix that as well with having your
own founder-led brand so that you're
owning your distribution long-term, and
you've got the [music] system set up for
success. So, if you want to move on to
the next level, go and document five
recurring tasks that you have on your
plate. Document them in a Google Doc, go
and [music] film yourself doing them in
a Loom, go and determine the person on
your team that can then take that off
your plate,
>> [music]
>> and make sure that they are owning it
now going forward. Now, you're ready to
go and move on to the next level. Your
job at level two is to stop being the
bottleneck. And if you want my scaling
roadmap that breaks down each of these
levels and the core checklists that are
required to scale seamlessly to the next
stage, go and check it out via the link
in the description. Level three is one
of the most exciting, the CEO. [music]
You've built something real, but now you
have a new problem. Something that's
either going to make you or break you
over the next 12 months. When my second
business, Urgency, started crossing 150k
per month, I had to go from doing
everything to building a machine.
[music] I think at this stage, right,
you start to become a chief detail
officer, trying to work more on the
business than in the business by having
the right people in place, the right
systems in place, so it doesn't all come
down to you. Making sure that [music]
you're pushing decisions in your company
down, so that they don't need to all go
and get bubbled up to you by saying, you
know, "What do you think we should do?"
And then gradually [music] coaching
people and empowering them to go and use
their judgment, their intuition, and
data [music] to make those decisions, so
that you can focus on the decisions that
only you can make. So, you're probably
wondering, [music] as a CEO, with so
many things going on, what do you need
to focus on? Well, I think it comes down
to three things: [music]
Numbers, people, and culture. Getting
into the first, numbers. This is where I
see 97% [music]
of founders completely fail. I'll ask
them things like, you know, what's your
profit margin, your cash collected, you
know, what was your profit last month,
[music] what's the total cost of your
team in a given month? And they stare at
me blankly [music] almost as if their
eyes are glazing over, right? That is
your first mistake if you're looking to
be CEO because you need to have an
intricate understanding [music] of how
every decision you make impacts the
numbers. The second aspect obviously is
your people. You know, no matter what
company you're building, you are in
[music] the people business, the
business of going and bringing on A
players that believe in a vision and are
willing to do [music] whatever it takes
to get there. And the third aspect is
your culture. Your culture
>> [music]
>> eats strategy for breakfast. If you have
a great culture, a people that are
willing to do what it takes, [music]
they're hungry, they're coachable, they
obsess around quality and the customer
experience, [music]
you know, you've likely built something
that's set up for success. Here's how
you finally become the CEO of your
business and your life. First, you're
going to want to go and build an org
chart for your next 12 months and start
to figure out where your gaps are right
now and start to fill those with A
players.
>> [music]
>> Second is you probably want to start
building a dashboard and even something
simple like Google Sheets [music] that
has like the 12 core metrics across your
business on a week-by-week basis so you
can make sure that you're tracking these
things and growing them every single
month. From there, you want to make sure
that you have the right meeting rhythm
in place inside of your company likely
[music] running leadership meetings
every single week and then core
department meetings as well at the same
cadence. This meeting rhythm essentially
becomes the heartbeat of your company
and will ensure you have continuous
momentum into the future. Your job at
level three is to become a real CEO.
Level four, the empire builder. At 250k
per month, you've won, but there's a
ceiling that most people hit that stops
them from reaching seven figures
monthly. You know, I remember going and
talking to a mentor named Justin and I
wanted to grow the audience as big as
possible. In just a few words from
Justin, you know, it transformed my
thinking. He said, "Matt, if you're
looking to do that, you need to set your
audience on fire." [music]
And so, sure enough, I started to go and
analyze our presence on platforms like
X, LinkedIn, YouTube, Instagram, and go
and try to think about, you know, what
was every piece of content we were
putting out, and how could we go and
make it a hundred times better? [music]
You know, it was from looking at the
details in our videos, the sound, the
script, the lighting, the overall kind
of concepts that we're putting forth,
the titles, the thumbnails, the team,
the workflows, right? It was looking on
the writing side about the subjects we
were putting out. How could we transform
all of this to make the most exceptional
founder content in the world? It's
important to know your math, not just so
that you're building a hyper-profitable
business long-term, but also so that you
have what I believe is the most valuable
metric, peace of mind. You know, we want
to make sure that you're able to sleep
at night knowing that you have a
business that's continuing to compound
cash flows, and not compound stress. So,
your action steps here are to make sure
that you have an unbelievable CFO in
place. And from there, I like to make
sure I'm getting a CEO scorecard every
single Friday, which show me the 12 core
metrics across my entire business. The
next thing then is you want to make sure
that you have an amazing leadership team
in place. Because at this level, you
can't be making all the decisions,
right? You need to empower leaders
around you that can hire other amazing
leaders, right? [music] And can push
your business forward in your absence.
And at this stage, too, you want to make
sure that you're really dialed into what
is your zone of brilliance. Your job at
level four is to scale without losing
your soul. Level five is the icon. Most
people will never get here, but the ones
who do make this one small shift. When
George Lucas was building the Star Wars
saga back in the 1970s, before he had
even released the first [music] movie,
he had already made the scripts for all
three. He had planned out the universes,
the planets, the galaxies, the actors,
had it all lined up. Sure enough, he
released the [music] first movie, and
And was a box office success, and he
already had the next two lined up. And
it's not just George Lucas. You rewind
even Walt Disney. In the early days of
Disney, he went and drew out the entire
universe he was building. It wasn't just
the characters, but it was the animation
studio, it was the theme parks, it was
the, you know, merchandise and the
[music] figurines. He had it all planned
out. And this is the same pattern that
I've taken in my last three businesses
[music]
that has made them a success, right?
It's having this master plan, [music]
having this universe that you're
building out, right? For me, it's making
sure that I'm serving founders through
epic retreats, [music]
not just the ones we've done in Bali,
Sedona, and Mexico City, but going and
actually buying a retreat center in the
Dolomites where I can have peak
experiences with the best founders in
the world. It's going and taking these
YouTube videos to Netflix, traveling the
world, giving back, helping famous
founders across the world go and scale
to new levels, helping creators become
better business people, helping amazing
business folks become founder-led
brands, and really
>> [music]
>> sitting at that intersection of business
and the creator economy. People don't
buy what you do, they buy who they
become by doing it. They're not buying a
program, they're buying the
transformation that you're providing
them by actually going and giving
[music] the service you do. You know,
oftentimes we forget that when we're
building a brand, a brand is more of an
emotional experience than anything,
[music] right? It's a feeling you get
when you think of a certain logo or
think of a certain person. For Apple,
[music] it's creativity. For Nike, it's
victory. For Founder OS, it's freedom.
Oftentimes, it's making sure that you're
communicating that aspirational [music]
identity and vision for the brand
because inevitably, that's what people
are really buying into.
>> [music]
>> So, refine your vision into a 10-year
roadmap. Think about your brand in all
the areas you want it to exist. What's
[music] the big vision there? You know,
when you think about your team and your
org chart, how's that going to need to
evolve over the next 10 [music] years?
How does your offer and your product
suite need to evolve? If you have
trouble thinking big in this department,
leverage AI to help you think 10x
[music] bigger. It's by charting out
this vision and then making sure that
you put it into a visual presentation
for your team,
>> [music]
>> include it in all your onboarding
materials, and make sure that you go and
upload it to a given 10X
>> [music]
>> project inside of chat GPT that's going
to help you go and continue to march
towards this ambitious vision every
single day. Your job at level five is to
create a business that becomes a
household name. If you want to go and
get my five levels of scaling road map,
you can go and check it out via the link
in the description. All right, so as you
can see, these five levels, they're a
bit complicated, right? And I
understand, this ain't easy. So, if
you're scaling your business and you're
trying to go from one level to the next
and [music] you want support, you want
systems, and you want access to me so
that I'm literally in your corner
helping you move through these levels
seamlessly,
>> [music]
>> you should go and apply to Founderwise
via the link in the description. Go and
book a call, we'll understand what level
you're at, and understand where you're
really trying to go, and [music] we'll
see if we can help. And if you want to
learn the psychology behind creating a
magnetic brand, go and check out this
video right now, and we'll get into the
details there. Be sure to like and
subscribe, and welcome to the Founder
Freedom Movement.