If your business breaks every time you
grow, if things start slipping through
the cracks, if every time you add more
revenue, you also add more chaos, this
video is for you. Because what most
founders think is a scaling problem is
really a systems problem in disguise.
I'm Matt Gray. I build companies that
scale without me. Because I had to learn
the hard way that hustle doesn't equal
freedom. Today, I help founders replace
chaos with systems and scale personal
brands that sell while they sleep. I can
tell you this, most people don't scale
broken systems. They scale brokenness
and it gets expensive fast. I know
because my first business nearly killed
me. I was making more money than ever
and was completely miserable, working
15our days, sleeping on office couches,
missing every important moment in my
life. This is the video I wish that
someone had given me when I was stuck at
100K per month, spending all of my time
putting out fires. Let's fix that for
you. Here's the dirty secret most
founders doing 100k per month never talk
about. You're not scaling, you're
surviving. Your business is duct taped
together. You're the head of content,
the chief operator, the head of sales,
the emotional support line for your
entire team. The bottleneck of
everything. And every time you grow, it
just gets worse. The crack widens, the
stress deepens, and your calendar fills
up with junk you never wanted in the
first place. I was there with Herb in
2017. We had just raised $4.1 million in
funding. Revenue was exploding and from
the outside, we were killing it, but
inside it was total chaos. I remember
one particular Tuesday, I was on a call
with a potential customer that was going
to pay us 600 grand. My Slack was
blowing up. Three team members were
outside my office with urgent questions.
And my calendar had 14 meetings
scheduled. And in the middle of that
pitch, our website crashed. The client
said, "I'm going to give you a bit of
time to sort that out." And then they
hung up. We never heard from them again.
600 grand gone because we didn't have
the systems in place to handle the
growth. Let me give you a mental model
here, right? It's like you're building a
skyscraper on a foundation made of sand.
It works for a little while, but the
second you get to 120K, 150K, 200K per
month, the whole thing just shakes
because you never installed real
systems. You just kept hustling harder.
And hustling harder is the fastest way
to build a business that just eats your
life. Here's how broken systems are
born. Step one, you figure things out
scrappily. Step two, you get traction.
Step three, you bolt on new hires and
tools, and then you just try to keep up.
And step four, suddenly you've built a
monster with no map. The whole business
is built around your muscle instead of
your machine. At Bitmaker, my coding
boot camp, we were scaling fast, doing
200K in monthly revenue. We had no
systems, no content systems, no
delegation flows, no dashboard, no
nothing. I was drowning. It was just me
brute forcing everything. I remember one
night, it was 3:00 a.m. I was alone in
the office answering support tickets
from students. My eyes were burning. My
back was in knots. And I realized
something. I had built a prison. I
hadn't built a business, right? I'd
built a job that I couldn't escape. I
was making great money, but I had no
time to actually spend it on things I
love. I had success, but couldn't enjoy
it. And when we sold the company, you
know what I felt? It wasn't joy. It
wasn't pride, just relief that finally
that prison sentence was over. That's
what happens when you build without
systems. You don't get freedom. You get
golden handcuffs. Here's the truth.
Growth doesn't fix broken systems.
Growth is just going to expose them. If
you're feeling more overwhelmed as you
grow, it doesn't mean that something's
wrong. It means you are finally hitting
the edge of the systems that you never
built. I learned this the hard way when
hitting 300K per month at Herb.
Suddenly, you know, our content team,
they couldn't keep up. Our analytics
were a mess. Our hiring was reactive,
not strategic. And I was juggling
multiple things and honestly just
dropping the ball everywhere. I remember
things vividly. You I was in Italy. I
was hanging out with my girlfriend, but
instead of actually enjoying the
beautiful sights, I spent 12 hours a day
in my laptop in the hotel room. And and
instead of just exploring the city, I
just had to leave her alone. One of the
last days, she sat down with me and said
something that I'll never forget. Are
you building a business that's actually
just stealing your life? What is this
all for? That question hit me like a
sledgehammer. After that Italy trip, I
came home and I realized that I dreaded
opening my laptop every morning. I'd
fallen out of love with that business.
That's what happens when you build a
business that works because of you
instead of one that works without you.
You just end up being the bottleneck of
it and you pay the ultimate price. Most
founders live in what I call the scaling
fantasy. You know, if I just make more
money, I'll be able to, you know, hire
more people. I'll be able to have more
time, more freedom, more peace. But if
you scale chaos, you just get more
expensive chaos. You know, I've
consulted with founders doing a million
a month who have less freedom than when
they were doing 100k per month because
they just scaled the wrong things. They
hired people without systems. They added
complexity without clarity. They grew
revenue without actually growing their
infrastructure. One founder I work with
was doing a million a month but working
80our weeks. He had 32 employees and
zero systems. He was making more money
but was more miserable than ever. Within
90 days of installing proper systems, he
was able to take his first two-week
vacation in 5 years while the business
was able to finally run without him.
This is a beautiful picture, but the
truth is you need to install systems
that can scale ahead of the curve. You
don't wait until the airplane is 35,000
ft in the air to start then building the
engine. But that's exactly what most
founders do in their business. Let me
show you five systems that help me scale
peacefully. These are systems that don't
break when you grow. Number one, the
content GPS, which is really your media
system. Your business will only grow to
the level your personal brand allows.
This system is going to help you create
beautiful, systemized content every
week. It's going to drive eager buyers
to your sales team's calendars and turn
your brand into an inbound lead magnet.
You know, when I implemented the content
GPS at Herb, our leads increased
immediately. We went from chasing
clients to then having to turn them
away. One piece of content we created,
which was an interview with an NBA
player, it cost us $20,000 to produce.
My finance team thought this was crazy,
right? My CFO almost had a heart attack.
That single piece of content generated
$700,000 in revenue over the following
year. Because it wasn't just random
content, right? It was strategically
positioned within our content GPS to
attract exactly the highvalued
partnerships that we needed. It's your
growth engine. It's how you stop relying
on referrals. It's how you build trust
before people even come to you. If your
content isn't built to scale, your
pipeline isn't either. The second system
is your CEO dashboard. Every week I run
the business off a single dashboard. It
has my one domino focus, top offunnel
metrics, social growth metrics, close
rate, show rate, cash collected, cash
and bank. These metrics really help me
determine know the health of my
business. So I don't need to have 17 tab
opens. I don't need Slack, email, ASA,
notion, Google Sheets, HubSpot. It's
just one spot where everything is in
focus. I'd spend the first hour of each
day figuring out what to focus on.
Before I had this, but now, you know, I
have one dashboard to see exactly what
matters. I implemented this for a
founder I know named Michelle. She was
an agency founder doing 50K per month,
but working 60hour weeks. After
installing this CEO dashboard in her
business, she told me her stress levels
dropped by 80% in just the first week.
Why? Because she finally had clarity.
One tab, one rhythm, one view of the
business. You know, if you're juggling
17 tools, 45 Slack threads, you're not
running a business. You're babysitting a
machine that you forgot to build. The
third system is the comm calendar
system. I split my calendar into four
blocks. Build, where I have focus and
creativity time. Sell, where I'm able to
go and drive conversions. and then
thinking time where I'm banking big CEO
moves and then I also have some rest
time as well. Before implementing it, my
calendar looked like a game of Tetris
gone wrong. 15minute meetings scattered
throughout the day, no focus time, no
recovery time. I was just constantly
task switching. It was exhausting. When
I implemented this system at Founder OS,
my team's output increased by 34% in the
first month while our working hours
decreased by 22%. I was finally able to
do the big leverage stuff that would
move the needle forward. We were doing
more with less. This system makes sure
that every week you're feeling
intentional and energized. No more
reactive chaos, just clear lanes. System
four is the $2 million team triangle.
Every business that's scaling to around
200k per month needs three core roles.
An operator that's going to run the
backend, a closer that turns leads into
profit, and then a content manager that
fuels the content machine. That's it.
Those three roles unlock 80% of your
freedom. Stop hiring based on immediate
fires and start hiring based on this
strategic framework. Less people, more
revenue, more freedom. System number
five is the founder OS playbook. Every
recurring task should become a system.
Every system gets documented and every
documented task gets delegated. You go
from I need to do this to this gets done
without me. When I started documenting
our systems at Herb, my team thought I
was crazy. you know, why are we spending
all of this time writing down this much
stuff? You know, we could just actually
do the work. But six months later, when
we were able to onboard new team members
in days instead of weeks, they
understood why I was able to take that 4
weeks to Japan without the business
missing a beat. They became believers.
Systems aren't sexy. They're what allow
you to build a business that serves you
instead of something that just consumes
you. At the end of the day, this is how
you go and pass the one month test.
being able to build a business that you
could leave for a month and come back to
it knowing that it's a lot more strong
and more scalable without you. This is
the beauty of building a systemized
empire. If you're watching this and
thinking, "Damn, I've just been scaling
with duct tape." Well, good. At least
now you realize, and this is hopefully
your wakeup call, because the solution
isn't to burn it all down, it's to
rebuild it, right? I remember sitting in
a cafe in San Francisco in 2018,
completely burnt out from scaling herb.
I was journaling, trying to figure out
why I felt so exhausted despite all of
our success. I wrote down a question
that changed everything for me. What if
the goal isn't to work harder, but to
actually build better? That simple
shift, right? From effort to design
transformed how I built my businesses.
Here's the mindset shift. You're not a
hustler. You're a systems architect.
Hustlers burn out. Architects build
things that last. Build the systems
first and the scale will follow. If your
business feels fragile right now, if it
feels like you're one mistake away from
collapse, that's not a growth issue.
It's a systems issue. And I know because
I've lived it. If this video hit you, if
you're tired of juggling chaos, and
ready to scale a brand that's beautiful,
systemized, and peaceful, we build these
systems for you inside of Founder OS
Plus. And it's probably what you need
next. You can go and apply to Founder OS
via the link in the description. Like
and subscribe. Welcome to the Founder
Freedom Movement and I'll see you in the
next video.