Copy this content strategy, it'll blow
up your business. Okay. There's this
concept that I learned from Rick Rubin,
which is like producers versus reducers.
Producers are constantly adding more
platforms, adding more offers, adding
more teammates. And sometimes this is
can just cause you to build some big
bloated empire that you probably didn't
even want to build in the first place.
Reducers, right, are all about deletion,
removing until you get to the core
essential frequency, energy, sound, and
the kind of stuff that you actually want
to be doing. Now, I'll be honest, I find
reducing insanely hard. Deletion, it
ain't easy, right? Because you build up
all these darlings, and it's so hard
cutting them. But this is the real work.
You know, I know I've been in deletion
season for the last 6 months. I've cut
four product lines, six people, got my
margin above 70%. Let me tell you, it's
been hard, but it's a beautiful thing,
right? Suddenly now, you know, I've got
a lean team of core weapons, a core,
nice, simple, easy, profitable profit
product line that really brings me joy.
Um and what I've learned over the years
building businesses now for 18 years is
that building really is probably more
about deletion than it is creation. It's
more about saying no than saying yes,
right? Because focus is your scarcest
resource as a founder.