All right, how to be the CEO of your own
life. I entered 2026 and the theme of
this year was to be an architect, right?
Architecting my dream life, my dream
home here in Bali, architecting my dream
business. And so, from there, it's
really about controlling the four W's in
your life, right? Controlling where you
work,
when you work, what you work on, and who
you work with, right? Make sure that
you're working with people that fill up
your cup. Make sure that you're working
on something that feels like it's
aligned with your soul, right? You don't
want to show up every day to work that
you hate, cuz that's not a business,
right? You've just built yourself a
cage. From there, think about creating a
frustrations list every Sunday in your
journal, things that are maybe pissing
you off, and gradually make an effort to
delete,
delegate, and automate these things, so
that more of what you're spending your
time on is things that you actually
love, because you deserve it. Run your
founder scorecard weekly, right? What
are the seven core metrics across your
business that matter the most? Focus on
those things, make sure that each one
has a core owner, and that your CFO is
sending you the status of these metrics
every single Friday. And then, make an
effort to pursue joy, right? If you're
not laughing daily, what the hell are we
even doing here, y'all, right? So, joy
is what it's all about. Joyful
entrepreneurship is the movement we
should be creating here as a community,
right? Cuz we want to measure our life
by if we're really living, right? Not
just the business.