This cloud prompt generates me thousands
of emails that generate me thousands in
revenue. So, if you're looking to go and
scale up a business or even start it,
one thing that you should definitely
have in place is a 5day email miniourse
compiled with a 5-day FOMO series, which
stands for fear of missing out. That's
going to go and sell people more on
exactly what you do and convert them
into customers. Let me go and show you
how to go and create this for your
business. What I've gone and created
here is a Claude project called email
courses. Inside of the instructions, you
can see I've created this master prompt
and we're off and going. Now, keep in
mind in the project knowledge inside of
Claude as well, I've put all of the core
documentation across Founder OS and my
personal brand so that Claude's not just
reinventing the wheel or using some
generic BS. It's actually using real
words, systems, frameworks, and
blueprints that I've invented. So all of
that heavy lifting is being done without
me, which saves me hours of