All right, this is how to grow your
business to $5 million this year. One
offer, one promise, one path, right? One
badass offer that's simple, it's
repeatable, it's highly profitable with
one core promise and one path, meaning
maybe you're going from YouTube or
Instagram to a link to that maybe a VSL
and a call and a close. You master that
process, you make it as pristine and
dialed as possible
and you're destined for 5 million.
Build distribution before your head
count. I don't know about you, but I'm
much more into having a 12-person lean,
mean, mighty team than some 100-person
bloated thing, right? Head count is a
vanity metric. Keep it small and focus
on distribution, right? First-time
founders focus on tech, second-time
founders focus on distribution. So, go
and pick one or two platforms, start
making organic content and building your
brand today, right? 12 people, 70%
margin, that's what we're after, right?
From there, install your four pillars,
right? Audit things like your brand.
How's it showing up? How's the money
going in the company, right? How's your
cash flow year over year, month over
month? What's your margin at?
How are your systems going? Do you have
systems for
your content, sales, marketing, finance,
ops? And how are you doing, right? How's
that energy? How you feeling? From
there, understand that you are your
greatest asset. Getting to $5 million
means you've got to be healthy, you've
got to be feeling good.