The best time to start a YouTube channel
was in 2012. The second best time though
is right now. I get it. You're probably
fearing that people are going to judge
you, perfectionism, or you know, you're
not even sure if you're good on camera.
Well, the truth is [music] that you're
probably not right. A lot of this just
takes practice. When you publish videos,
you get your own style, you learn your
voice, and you get more confident. You
don't have it all figured out and then
launch your YouTube channel. you launch
your YouTube channel and then gradually
video by video you figure [music] it
out. And so what you need to be
comfortable with is just shipping it
messy, right? Start with where you're at
with what you've got, the equipment in
front of you, might just be your iPhone,
and [music] just get going. I would
encourage you to remove the
perfectionist mindset and just go and
embrace experimentation.