Here's why you need to treat your
personal brand like it's your
reputation. If everything disappeared,
if your whole brand, all your followers,
all went away, how would people feel
about you? Your personal brand is your
digital reputation. You know, we don't
live in an age of business cards
anymore. People go and look at your
LinkedIn, they look at your ex, they
look at your Instagram, your YouTube,
and it's not your followers that they're
looking at. They're looking at, is this
person trustworthy? Are they legit?
Because over the last 6 years, as I
leaned into my personal brand, not only
have I grown this audience to 3 million
people, but I've met people all around
the world. It's opened doors to insane
opportunities with people like Lar
Hamilton, Horoszi, Olly Abdal, you name
it. And so I recommend that you go and
you pick one platform. Decide, are you a
more pen first creator or camera first?
If pen first, X and LinkedIn. If camera
first, YouTube, Instagram, and Tik Tok.
People follow people then they follow
brands.