Most people lose their audience in the
first 10 seconds. Here's the psychology
trick that keeps them watching. In my
how to work less and earn more video, I
opened up with if you thought of someone
making $730,000
per month, how long would you guess
they're working? Most would guess 12 to
14 hours a day. I'm doing [music] the
complete opposite. I didn't explain how
until several minutes in. And the
result, [music] people couldn't click
away. Your brain genuinely hates
unfinished business. Once [music] you
open a loop in someone's mind, their
nervous system craves that closure. You
literally can't stop thinking about it
until it's resolved. [music] When you're
thinking, say about a YouTube thumbnail,
intrigue is going to go and drive the
click. [music] But once someone's in the
video, it's tension that you want to go
and create. And in order to do that, you
want to go and open up different loops
and [music] then go and create that
tension and don't close it for a few
minutes later in the video. You wouldn't
believe what happened next or this
nearly killed my business or [music]
this was crazy, but nothing yet compared
to what happened next. These kinds
[music] of questions keep people diving
in.