If you're someone, you know, following
this channel, you probably follow this
for the idea that we can have it all as
founders, right? We can have a vibrant
life and a vibrant business. We can be
like Zen at times and be intense
[\h__\h] We can want to build a
beautiful calm business while also
wanting to win our category and get the
[\h__\h] after it. We can, you know, want
to, you know, be able to remove
ourselves from the business for 3 weeks
and come back to a business that's
stronger than when we left. Well, also
when we're in the business and there
with the team wanting to push it, right?
And evolve and dominate. What makes
founders special, right? Is this ability
to kind of straddle two seemingly
disparate worlds, right? And uh, you
know, sometimes I think you may see that
one world of the Zen calm systems dude,
right? Um, but yeah, do not be mistaken,
right? There is a crazy [\h__\h]
also behind the scenes and I think this
is, you know, what I, you know, see uh,
founders inside of Founder OS, you know,
getting a taste of, you know, that uh,
that David Goggins um, side of things.
That's uh, you know, pushing the needle,
trying to help folks win, um, really
helping people,
um, you know, bring a new level of
caliber, um, and expectations to how
they operate and how their team
operates. And it's by setting those high
standards for myself as well that I've
been able to be, you know, successful
over the years. And so, yeah. That's
kind of a vibe.