Pick the wrong niche and you'll burn out
before you make a dollar. Pick the right
one and money becomes inevitable. When I
started thinking about my personal
brand, I wasn't clear on what to focus
on. This is where most people mess up.
They pick something that sounds good on
paper, but doesn't light them up. But
here's what I've learned. If what you're
talking about fires you up, you're going
to stick with it. And like all things in
life, you're going to see the most
returns over the long term. So, grab a
pen and paper right now. Draw three
overlapping circles, what I love, what
makes you money, and what customers
want. Fill each circle honestly, not
what sounds impressive, but what's
actually true. Then build your entire
brand around the center where all three
overlap.