here's how you can tell the difference
between fakers and makers in just 5
seconds if you tell someone an idea that
you have and they say great idea but you
should not listen to whatever comes next
these are the overthinkers of the world
the underdo they wait too long think too
much criticize too easily and take very
little action of their own instead
listen to people who say and great idea
and they are adding to your idea
refining it challenging you to think
bigger and push further these are the
people that you should surround yourself
with they dream big believe big and
encourage you to do the same ditch but
people find and people