Do you want to get unstuck in life? All
you need is one small win a day. This is
because of the compound effect. Jerry
Seinfeld focused on one small win,
writing one joke every single day. Fast
forward 10 years later, 20 years later,
Jerry Seinfeld is worth over $1.1
billion. And the Seinfeld show is worth
over 7.6 billion. Insane. Many people
just get paralyzed going, "Where the
hell do I start?" It starts in your
daily actions. There's so much power to
be unlocked from just taking simple
actions and making things easy and
digestible so you can just take action
today. Ask yourself, what's one small
win I can generate today? Write it down.
Make it specific, measurable,
actionable, realistic, and time bound.
As Les Brown said, you don't have to be
great to get started, but you have to
get started to be