one of the biggest mistakes you can make
as a course creator is not monetizing
your audience as fast as possible do
this to make $1 million as a course
creator don't give away everything for
free give value but keep your most
amazing value behind a pay wall train
followers to buy don't attract dopamine
Seekers set expectations that success is
found through hard work if you say it's
easy they'll blame you when they fail
don't optimize just for sales optimize
for results this way your past customers
become your Salesforce don't wait until
you get to 100,000 followers you don't
need it promote your course from day one
do this and you'll get to a million
dollars before anyone else