before May 6th 1954 it was universally
accepted that the human body simply
could not run a mile in less than 4
minutes but then Roger banister a
25-year-old medical student made history
by running a mile in 3 minutes and 59
seconds then within a span of just a few
years numerous other athletes broke the
4-minute barrier as well not just a
record was broken by Roger banister
Sprint but a psychological barrier as
well and suddenly The Impossible became
possible we all have our own 4minute
mile the thing that feels impossible
until we see someone else do it this is
why it's so important to surround
ourselves with others who are ahead of
us befriend other people who are
succeeding at the things that you want
to succeed at and suddenly The
Impossible feels possible