You can conquer negative thinking once
and for all if you have the right
systems. I used to wake up with negative
thoughts constantly. You should have
been further by now. Thoughts that just
paralyzed me every day. But now I wake
up rested and I've created four
successful companies that have impacted
over 14 million people. And finally, for
once, my external success reflects my
internal state. So in this video, I'm
giving you the seven core frameworks
that I use to rewire my thinking and
become a successful entrepreneur. The
first framework helps with chronic
overthinking. I call it the one domino
decision. Your mental spiral can be
stopped with just one domino. Before I
learned this trick, you know, I'd find
myself in these crazy spirals. I would
start to feel super anxious, really
depressed, and it would go on for weeks
and months, and I wouldn't even take the
time to step back for a second and ask
myself, what's that one domino that if I
just did that one thing, it would make
everything else in my life easier or
unnecessary? And oftentimes there's a
one domino for each area of your life.
You know, my one domino for health is
getting my 6 am workout in every single
day. My one domino for my professional
career is really making sure I get 4
hours of founder flow uninterrupted
every morning from around 8:00 a.m. till
noon. It's these one dominoes that allow
me to go and finally get out of the
spiral of overthinking, overanalyzing,
and not knowing what to do next. This
breaks the loop because of something
called the ziggarnic effect.
Essentially, just doing one thing, one
that just moves you forward ever so
slightly can oftenimes set up a chain
reaction that helps you start building
the momentum, getting your confidence,
and getting out of whatever's leading
you to those negative thoughts. It's
often times the tiniest action that can
just get you started on a path that
helps you start feeling like yourself
again. So, here's how to go and find
your one big domino. Go and write down
the answers to these questions that come
into your mind. What thought is taking
up most of my mental space right now?
What actions would make this thought
lose its power? If I only had 10
minutes, what would I do first? You want
to think about that next big move that
you can make that when you do that
thing, it topples over many of the next
dominoes in line. The one domino is your
ticket out of analysis paralysis and
into action. The second framework is
called chop wood, carry water. This is
for anyone dealing with self-shaming.
The problem isn't that you hate
yourself, it's that you think about
yourself too much. A few weeks back, I
was on a founder hike here in London and
I had a few founders come up to me and
say, you know, the thing that they liked
most about, you know, kind of what made
me different online was this mix of sort
of business and spirituality. Up until
that point, sometimes I wondered if some
of the spiritual aspects of what I may
share with you guys, you know, is a
little bit woowoo or, you know, if it
maybe even detracts people from just
enjoying and getting value from what I
do. I'm sometimes super hard on myself
and really just beat myself up. I think
it's sometimes just part of that high
achiever sort of mental condition. You
know, self-shaming actually just maybe
moves you further from actually what
makes you different. It's actually your
uniqueness, your difference that's going
to actually attract people to what
you're doing and help you be successful.
Self-shame is that little voice in your
head that causes you to stress over
every gray hair, every wrinkle that
comes up, every time you've made a
mistake or that past failure that you've
had. To get over this, I always remember
the Buddhist mantra, chop wood, carry
water. every single day, you just
probably have three to seven core tasks
that you need to do that will get you
where you are now to where you need to
go. If you can just put blinders on and
focus on those three to seven things and
get them done, no excuses, you're going
to gradually make the progress that you
really seek here in life. So, if you
catch yourself going and self-shaming
yourself, you know, break the pattern.
Just do something for someone else. You
know what I often times find useful is,
you know, maybe I'll go to my team in
Slack and someone's done a good job and
I'll go and congratulate them on that
and go and give them some specific
praise. You know, maybe I go for a walk
and just give myself some love by just
being out in nature and just kind of
switching the program in my brain. The
reality is is that we all have so much
to be grateful for and gratitude can
oftenimes just be the anecdote to those
negative feelings that can come up. So
the next time you need a reset, just
repeat the mantra, chop wood, carry
water. Focus on what's right in front of
you, do it with love, and focus on
what's next. The third framework is
called the personal board meeting, which
is my go-to framework. Whenever I feel
overwhelmed, whenever I feel buried in
stress, I do what I call a personal
board meeting with myself. I'll take
some time, generally about an hour
around the end of a month, to go and
really get outside of my environment.
I'll often times go to my favorite cafe
in a given city. I'll go and do some
reflection. I'll go and think about, you
know, over the past 30 days, what were
the things that I loved the most? What
are the things that I learned the most?
And what do I need to go and focus on to
make the next month the best month of my
life? And so from there, what I like to
do is then go and plan out my business
goals, my personal goals, and make sure
I'm clear on also my own personal board
of adviserss, the kind of people in both
my personal life and professional life.
they're going to help me get to where
I'm looking to go. Whenever you're
looking to do anything big, it's a
multi-player game. You need a good
support system around you if you want to
be successful. And I often times find
that, you know, my mentors, coaches,
therapists kind of serve as these
bumpers that make sure that no matter
where I go in life, I don't get too far
off course. If you want my personal
board meeting template, you can go and
check it out via the link in the
description. Go and reflect on your
previous month. you know, what went
well, what didn't go well, and what can
you do better, and then go and plan out
your business and professional goals as
well as your personal goals. I have
board meetings from like a decade ago,
which is a pretty awesome experience to
be able to go back to 2015 and go and
look at, you know, where was I then?
What was I currently thinking about? The
board meeting serves as this awesome
anchor, right? That keeps you grounded.
It also serves as this amazing
lighthouse that kind of shows you the
way. And when you give yourself time to
actually do this exercise, I think
you're giving yourself an amazing amount
of time to level up as a leader and
leave those negative thoughts behind
you. The fourth framework is external
OS. This is what I use to deal with
intrusive thoughts. You can't stop
intrusive thoughts, but you can
neutralize them with the right
environment. I think as humans often
times that we think that, you know, we
are designers of our environment, but
the truth is our environment also
heavily influences us. And some of my
lowest points in life when I look back,
I wish I was just able to tell myself,
you know what, just organize your life a
bit. Organize your environment. Go and
make the spaces that you spend the most
time in that much more inspiring. Most
people try to solve mental spirals by
going internal, right? But often times
it's, you know, going and taking a look
at that external environment that can
change everything. You I know for me,
beyond just the environment I'm in, it's
also who I'm surrounding myself with. as
an example, you know, making sure that I
have, you know, my parents that I'm
reaching out to every single weekend to
kind of go and ground myself regularly,
you know, staying in contact with, you
know, childhood friends and university
friends just to make sure that overall,
you know, you have a good community,
good social life, your external
environment is feeling solid, which then
just helps you feel good, you know, as a
high performer. Here's how to install
your external OS. Number one, go and
audit your environment. Go and remove
the things that are causing clutter,
disorganization or are kind of low
energy and go and give yourself finally
some space by deleting all the noise.
Two is remove one piece of outdated
code. Again, we don't need to solve
everything all at once. Just take that
one thing right now that it's in your
environment and you feel like it's some
way somehow bringing you down. Three,
add one cue for clarity. That's a nice
vision board where I work. It's a nice,
you know, piece of paper where I have
three mantras written out. Your mind
performs best when your environment is
fine-tuned and simplified to execute
your true goals. Upgrade your external
OS and your thoughts will follow. The
fifth framework is called seek the
sweat. This is how I tackle anxiety.
Anxiety isn't just in your head. It's
energy in your body that's waiting to be
burned. When I was younger, I worked out
3 to four days a week with rest days in
between. But the issue was is that those
rest days turned into rest weeks. You
know, in my first business, I got it all
wrong. There'd be weeks that I wouldn't
work out. And I was a son of a to
be around. Fast forward today, running
Founder OS every single morning, 6:00
a.m. on the dot, I'm out there doing
some sort of HIT workout, breaking a
sweat, so that the rest of my day is
peaceful. It's calm. I'm a much better
leader. I learned that anxiety is just
energy in your body that's waiting to be
processed. There are studies from
Harvard University that show just 20
minutes of physical activity a day can
be better than any anti-depressant
actually helping you feel better. Do
whatever goes and suits you, but just
make sure that you do it every day. It
should be a non-negotiable. When you
sweat daily, you don't just feel more
calm, you also sleep better. You're
going to be a better leader. You're
going to just feel a lot less anxious in
your day-to-day life. Think of anxiety
as just a pipe that's just building up
with pressure. You know, if you don't go
and break a sweat and work that off, it
just builds and builds and builds and
eventually it just breaks you. In your
career, you're working with other
people. You're closing deals. If you're
not feeling great, these things don't go
great. You know, in your relationships,
it's important that you're present,
you're able to listen, you're able to
work through different things.
Everything involves being around others.
And to be someone that others want to be
around, you got to be feeling good. So
the next time you feel anxious, move
your body. Seek the sweat. The sixth
framework is called strategic stillness.
Here's a controversial take. Doing
nothing is the most productive thing you
do. Now, we've all been there. You know,
just feeling completely burnt out. You
know, I know that if I'm not being
careful because I'm just so obsessed
with building great things, amazing
teams, creating awesome content, and
living a vibrant life that sometimes I
get so obsessed that I just run myself
into the ground. I think we all do that
from time to time. But hopefully as we
get older, we start seeing more of the
signals that kind of signal to us that
it's probably just time to slow down a
little bit and find some strategic
stillness in our lives. You know, for
me, I know that when I'm, you know,
working and starting to kind of feel a
level of brain fog, I start to look at
tasks that I know I genuinely love, but
they start to feel more like chores or I
just find myself getting a little
agitated for no reason, right? It's
probably time for me just to take a step
back, chill out, and go do what I call a
soul trip. You know, I like to take a
soul trip about every 6 weeks. It's a
spontaneous trip for around 4 to 7 days
out into nature. You know, I've been to
Joshua Tree, Sequoia National Park,
Yeusede, all over the world doing these
soul trips. They're a chance to
disconnect, you know, recharge, get away
from my phone, get away from meetings,
and just be able to kind of reset
myself. Neuroscience shows that your
brain has two major modes. One is that
take action mode when you're getting
things done, getting after it, and
really just building something
impactful. But the truth is that part of
your brain can run dry, which leads to
the second mode, your default mode. This
is when you're at rest, you're chilled
out, and this is what allows you to
overall recharge and make sure that
you're not just running yourself into
the ground. You know, we've all been
there. You know, at the end of a busy
day, you go take a break and you go for
a nice shower, the warm water hits you,
and all of a sudden, you have some
epiphany idea, that big breakthrough
that you were waiting for all day. Well,
why did that happen? It's because you
finally gave yourself some stillness to
let your nervous system downregulate. As
author and activist Annne Lamont says,
almost everything will work again if you
unplug it for a few minutes, including
you. Strategic stillness is the only
solution to burnout that actually works.
The seventh framework is externalize,
don't internalize. 9 years ago, I was
going through a really rough time in my
life. I was burnt out. I didn't know
what to do. And I called my dad super
distressed in a hotel room that I was
staying at in LA and I told him, you
know, I needed some help. One thing led
to another. I ended up going to a brain
clinic in LA, discovering that because
of a series of concussions I had playing
hockey when I was younger, there were
some issues going on. I was in this sort
of constant state of fight or flight
because of this kind of undiagnosed
condition. I would have never discovered
what the hell was going on had I not
just made the call. And the reality is
is that this happens to all of us in
small ways and big ways all the time.
You know, for me these days, what I've
learned is to externalize, not
internalize. For me, that's like having
things like a therapist that I speak to
every 3 weeks, being able to
constructively deal with the different
emotions that come up. You know,
similarly, it's having a coach. You
know, I have a coach, Ryan, I've worked
with for the last 7 years, and he helps
me in so many ways. He exited his last
business for about $60 million and is
able to help show me the ropes in terms
of how to build a beautiful, peaceful,
bootstrapped company. The reality is is
that there's so many times that I'm
thinking that there's something wrong
with me. Am I really a good leader? Is
there a way that I could be better?
There's got to be a system to solve
something. There's got to be, you know,
something I'm doing wrong. But the
reality is I'll have a call with Ryan
and realize, you know what, you're
actually doing a lot of things right.
and there's just maybe a small piece
that's missing or one new hire I need to
make. Research shows that externalizing
reduces ruminations by about 30%. You
know, that means less paranoia, less
stress, less depression, less anxiety
when you just go and reach out and get
help for the problems that are going on.
The reality is that we all have so many
people around us that can help us get
over those struggles in life. And
sometimes it just means taking that
first step. All right, so think about
tomorrow morning, right? You wake up and
maybe there's something that's bugging
you. It's nagging at you. The first
thing you can do is go and write down a
list of five people that you know or
maybe would love to know that could help
you with that thing. Then go and take
the next step, whether it's an email,
it's a text message, it's a phone call
to those five people to go and get help
today. This one habit can help you go
and begin to externalize things versus
getting stuck internalizing. If you like
this video, don't forget to hit
subscribe and go and watch this video on
I'm 35. If you're in your 20s or 30s, go
watch this. Trust me, you're going to
love it. and I'll see you in the next
one.