how do you know how to make something
for a million people I don't know where
to start but if I pick one person in the
audience and I study you and I take your
journey and say how do we improve this
part of the journey how do we improve
that part of the journey you can
actually do something really personal
and if you design something keep
iterating till they love it and don't
stop improving until that one person
loves it and you're not allowed to get
the second person till the first person
loves it and then you get the second
person and you keep itting till they
love it and then the third person and
what ends up happening is when people
love your service they become your
marketing department they tell other
people if you can design something
really amazing and you use the
handcrafted part of your brain to create
that perfect experience then you can
reverse engineer how to industrialize
this Millions times over and what
happens is people love your product and
they tell everyone else about your
product