Views don't equal cash. When I look at
my own YouTube as an example, the number
one cash generating video is like our
42nd most popular video. And that video
has driven us 100K plus of cash
collected. Today, we're building a
social media machine for a $7 million
roofing entrepreneur. We're going to go
and help him go and develop more of a
portfolio mindset, helping him see not
just how to go and scale that
construction business, but also how to
build a whole new business off the backs
of it.
>> Oh, this all makes sense.
This is tricky stuff that took me years
to understand. So even if you're just
getting going in business, maybe you're
looking to go and scale your own
business and are not sure how a founder
brand pieces with it, be sure to lock
in. So let's [music] get into it. So
Zach, I'm from Sydney, Australia, a
high-end architectural cladding and
roofing company in the trades and
construction based. Biggest constraint
is probably me, not so much stuck in the
weeds, but my whole identity is just
attached to that one business. I'm an
entrepreneur and I love business itself
and I've sort of just I'm struggling to
find a way to like sit on top of that
instead of that sit on top of me. So,
you know, if I have the ability to sit
on top of that, I can build other
businesses that also align with, you
know, what I want to do in life and not
be attached to that one business at the
moment.
>> You find yourself kind of Yeah. stuck
under this and it's zeta major roofing
right now, right? And you're trying to
kind of expand beyond that. You have
other ideas and so talk more about what
are these other ideas and what you're
really trying to do long
>> term. Yeah, obviously I got into into
the construction industry when I was 16.
Um, and I sort of just like left school
and and and I hated you hated school and
learning and stuff like that. And so the
only place you can really go and work,
it it sort of just took off, you know. I
sort of I took I've always had like a
high attention to detail and I've been
always very creative. And I just sort of
took that same mindset that I had into
that industry which was so blue collar
and everyone just did things quickly and
it was no value. And um so I really I
really you know pushed hard on you know
we're doing nearly eight figures. Yeah.
But now and I know I want to do more and
that's you know obviously where this um
you know what you would call it like
community mentoring sort of thing. Um, I
didn't really like the word mentor and I
was just like give back, you know, um,
educate back and and and sort of like
take all the lessons and I've lost so
much money along the way. Probably lost
myself along the way too, you know,
going learning leadership and hard
skills, soft skills, hiring skills. And
in the industry, in our industry, it it
no one talks about it's very it's very
secretive, you know, no one talks about
how to quote or how to do this. And the
only people that are making money right
now are just the big big companies. And
and I feel like the I want to give back
to, you know, the guy that I once was.
you have obviously the construction side
and you're looking to go and stand up
this education side,
>> but first also kind of mapping out the
flywheel of how all these things exist.
>> So essentially like what we mean by
flywheel is like just like a series of
different parts of the business that
each part benefits the next one and so
forth, right? So, as an example with
yours, you've built up this amazing, you
know, reputation
>> on the Z MH, right? Construction, right?
And so, when it comes to mind, like on
the reputation side and what you're
known for there, what are like the three
sort of like unique value props?
>> Sounds like attention to detail.
>> Attention to detail, it would be also,
you know, we're probably one of the
biggest companies. So, we
serviceability, craftsmanship.
>> Yeah, craftsmanship for sure.
>> Cool. So, we can leave that for a sec.
Okay. And so we essentially have this
like you know current entity right now
and then the question is like how do we
connect that like with the education
piece.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. And so obviously as you share
more of you know the attention to detail
that went into this the journey that
went into creating this.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. That inevitably is going to go
you know and spread awareness and
attract more people.
>> Okay. Yeah.
>> Right. To the we'll call it ZMH
education.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. Cuz these guys that are getting
going.
>> Yeah.
>> Like the things that matter to them the
most, right? Are you know your
reputation.
>> Yeah.
>> Like what have you even done, right? And
you have proof that you've built this $7
million roofing business.
>> Yeah.
>> And they want to learn like how have you
done this? And I think you also have a
unique Yeah. Just like background and
voice with it all too. Like just like a
regular guy. They can see themselves in
you. You're also just trying to speak to
the
>> 10 year ago version of yourself. So,
they're going to resonate with that
versus some like older guy that's a bit
out of touch.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. I think also like the nice thing
is like they're going to resonate with
the craftsmanship,
>> right? This isn't just about you can
make great money by just making great
products.
>> Yeah. Sure.
>> What else do you think?
>> Yeah. As I said before, relatable,
>> right?
>> You know.
>> Yeah. So, we got the relatability. I
think there's a few interesting things
that happen too, right? So, as we go and
we share more of this education, right?
you're going to then have like the
actual conversions.
>> Yeah.
>> To like the education side of things,
right? So now we've, you know, gone and
had people join the same mentorship.
>> Yeah.
>> And like education.
>> Right. So here's where things get
monetized there.
>> Yeah.
>> We have folks that have converted into
this, right? They're likely going to,
you know, let's just say some of them
get jobs.
>> Yeah.
>> Like in the crafts.
>> Yeah. Some of them like you may even
hire.
>> Yeah, of course. Yeah. Or you know even
you know buy parts of like in the in our
industry it's like they really have no
idea you know so [\h__\h] like equity
deals and and and try and brand off with
them you know like sort of solve their
problems with my systems and my
processes and my leaderships and like
yeah take they might have a crew of
three but hey you wear a ZMH dumper you
take all my systems and I lead you and I
have a certain percentage of your
business.
>> Yeah that's great too. So when you're
going and getting them jobs or helping
them with growth, let's just say, so
they're even getting jobs somewhere
else, they're starting their own thing,
>> correct? Yeah.
>> Right. So they're building their own say
venture.
>> Yeah.
>> On the venture side, right? This could
be monetized.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. Like you just said, you're
getting a percentage, you know,
licensing your systems, let's say.
>> Here it's just like now you're putting
more of your ZMH grads into great
>> construction businesses. Yeah,
>> that may need
>> over here as well. It's an example of
where you know this kind of gets fed
back into here.
>> Correct. Yeah.
>> Right. And helps obviously you over
time. I mean the biggest thing that
we've talked about is in this business.
I think the thing that leads to great
attention to detail, serviceability,
craftsmanship is your recruiting your
amazing talent like being able to build
great people.
>> So essentially this is not only helping
monetize you know the venture arm.
>> Yeah. It's not only helping monetize
like just through the education itself,
>> but helping you also source the best
talent
>> to feed back into the construction
business, which obviously is a money
maker.
>> Yeah.
>> And so essentially, it's like this whole
sort of flywheel, right, is like it's
one part like a talent flywheel for you.
It's also to as you're doing all this
too, you're also going to be attracting
customers to both Yeah. ZMH on the you
know construction side and on the
education side and the beautiful thing
is that as this all goes right the whole
kind of cycle right is generating you
right you generate cash
>> right you can use that cash to invest in
more great content
>> right to then grow the audience and
those just kind of keep on
>> ripping
>> yeah the content around like my content
at the moment in ZMH has just been like
high attention to detail like reals and
and photos and the brand sort of just
sold itself. It's a little bit like
Apple. Do you know what I mean? Apple
don't jump on and say, "Hey, buy the
phone." They just you walk past the
billboard and it's just a photo of a new
just a photo of the new Apple,
>> the new phone. So, you know, I haven't
done any face to face content, no
founder stories. It's just literally
clean sharp wellresented photos. But I
know the market's sort of shifting in
the way of the content brand. I guess,
you know, do I start telling my story
more on the ZMH founderled story, you
know, go back and and really strip back
all the onion layers and be like, "Hey,
listen, you know, I was just a one kid
one day and and sort of just built
this." Um, would it be like storytelling
would be involved? Yeah. The thing that
I'm really big on that I've seen
transform my businesses, my life, right,
is building a much more founder-ledd
brand. And so infusing it much more with
your narrative, right? your story, your
values, your origin story, the crucibles
of leadership you've been through, the
struggles, the mistakes, the lessons
that you've learned, right? I think, you
know, when folks are buying
construction, right? The number one
thing that they're often times like
scared of is like, is this person from
charlatan?
>> Yeah, can I trust this person? Right?
Are they just some scam artist? Or, you
know, what are their reviews and things
like that? Suddenly being able to see
your actual face, what you're all about,
seeing you speak, seeing the way that,
oh, no, this person's different. like
even being vulnerable about some of the
things that he has screwed up but the
lessons that he's learned it's like
there's no one really in these more old
school markets that does that right I
think bringing that sort of founder
brand to these sorts of markets is
actually a way bigger opportunity than
your traditional
>> sort of marketing area and any of these
sorts of businesses and we've helped
thousands at founder OS the number one
thing I always see from the data is that
people convert because of the energy of
the founder
>> right they want to go and get to know
the person what they're all about. They
like the way they think. They like the
way that they convey themselves. They
like the lifestyle that they've built
and the way that they're currently
building their things. So essentially,
it comes down to like your, you know,
>> Yeah. your character as well as your
point of view.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. Like you have a nuanced point of
view. Like in an example, like the thing
I resonate with is like, you know, in my
own world, I'm trying to build like an
apple for founders and you're trying to
build like this apple for construction
workers, right? like be able to take
this whole new spin on the trades. Be
able to actually show it as a really
beautiful thing, a really valuable
career path, something that like
actually involves craftsmanship,
involves, you know, a high level of
service. It's something that's like
you're saying too like anti- AI proof is
like an amazing career path for folks,
but maybe to some extent over like the
past 50 years has gradually gotten like
degraded and degraded more and just not
come across as some clean, beautiful
thing. But there's an opportunity to put
a new face to it and a new brand and a
new aesthetic to it that actually makes
it a really attractive thing for so many
people. So whenever you're going and
growing online, what most people don't
have is the right social media machine.
And this is everything that we install
inside of founder OS, right? It consists
of your ideation for the right
platforms, the right contextual call to
actions that lead to lead magnets and
then drive people to actual
monetization. Without this social media
machine in place, you find yourself
spinning your tires putting out a bunch
of content that never actually
monetizes. And when that's the case, you
don't end up building a flywheel around
what you're doing. What you want to have
is a seamless slope, right? From people
going from attention through to
nurturing folks and then getting them to
convert. So, you can both reinvest an
amazing product and content and just
have an amazing life where all that cash
flow you're going and making, you just
reinvest into the kind of things you
love to do. We can go into like kind of
on the content side, right? Map out like
the platforms.
>> Yeah.
>> And then talk about sort of the ideas
and then the right CTAs.
>> Yeah.
>> Meaning call to actions, right? That we
can drive people then to actually go
convert and monetize. This is where I
see a lot of people get stuck, right?
They like have now flywheel. They
understand like the importance of
building a founder brand. They're
getting going with it, but then they
don't have like clarity on like what
platforms they should be on. They think
that they hear from Gary Vee or they see
from Hormosi or myself that we're on all
these platforms and then they're
thinking, "Oh my god, I think I need to
be on everything at once. One thing
leads to another and then they just
start feeling overwhelmed because it's
like way too much all at once when like
first things first, there's other ways
to do it." on the ideation side, like
they're just kind of spraying and
praying with like a bunch of different
ideas, not knowing where's that nice
middle ground between stuff that's going
to perform well in terms of awareness,
but also actually drive monetization so
that that flywheel can actually pump,
right? Cuz we're not just looking to
drive views on the CTAs is essentially
the infrastructure now between really
your content awareness and actually
monetizing folks. And without this layer
in place, it's kind of all for nothing
cuz it's impossible to then
>> connect content with money. And so we'll
go and map out the best way to get that
done. And then obviously with
monetization, my approach just with all
of this in general, especially there, is
just to keep things as insanely simple
as possible. Not over complicate it.
Maybe a couple directions people go
based on like the couple archetypes that
we're talking about. Because on one side
we're talking about you're probably
going to be creating a lot of great
content that's going to attract people
that want to go and get construction
work with you. So they want a path that
they can go. Yeah. And then they're
gonna have a bunch of people that are
like, "Oh my god, I want to work with
this guy and learn from him through his
mentorship and then there's a path they
go and that's it.
>> That's it. Into the business or into
me."
>> Yeah. Exactly. So when you think about
the platforms you're looking to go on
Yeah. But when I look at my own
business, like my journey started on
Twitter, then going to LinkedIn, then
going to short form video, then to
YouTube. So that's kind of been my
journey over the last 5 years at my
founder brand. When it comes now to the
business and where we're driving most
profit, we drive around 40% of our leads
and profit from YouTube, 40% from
LinkedIn, and then the rest from like
Instagram, Tik Tok, etc. Yeah,
>> as you're starting to think about your
platforms, often times early on, I
encourage folks to figure out whether
they want to be more camera first or
more pen first, picking just like one of
those directions to start. Obviously, if
you're going more camera first, you're
probably going to think about going onto
a platform like maybe YouTube or
Instagram, getting there. Or, you know,
if you're going more writing first,
that's where you go like X and LinkedIn.
>> Where do you feel like
>> Definitely camera first, which I've
already sort of started.
>> All right. Awesome. And where have you
started so far?
>> On my on my just personal brand sort of
YouTube. I released my first YouTube
channel yesterday. Uh sorry, not
yesterday, a couple of months ago. And
then I went and filmed after the other
session, my first one. Yeah.
>> So would you film right after it? So you
just we just met a couple days ago. We
had the mastermind. We went over. I was
like just for those of you that are
getting going on any of these platforms,
take action right away. And so it sounds
like you did.
>> Yeah. Like as I said to before, the
biggest thing I got out of out of what
we sat down the other day, I feel like I
come into this with like a what strategy
am I going to get? And you know what?
And it's like you just said, "Fuck it.
You're going to die." And I was like, I
sort of been sitting on the fence of
like, you know, should I tell the story
or should I do this? And it's like, man,
like why why would I not, you know? So I
went home and pulled my camera out, sat
in front of the chair, and just ripped
it off half an hour.
>> So on the YouTube side of things, right,
we got that going. So say we've got long
form.
>> Yeah. And we've got um shorts.
>> Yeah.
>> And then on Instagram, right, we've got
reals
>> and carousels.
>> Yeah.
>> And I don't mind like, you know, um I
sort of like on the plane, I just wrote,
you know, a few things in my notes and
and sort of just chopped that up and and
threw it up there.
>> Nice. I talk a lot about like I think
there's this transition going on with
content right now where this like raw
real rant kind of style is like coming
really in, right? everyone bought like
fancy cameras and color grades and all
this [\h__\h] during co and then you know we
got on the other side of that I think
more and more people now just want to
get to know like the real you. Yeah.
>> I'm often times like when I know I'm
looking at even some of the greats
whether it's like Steve Jobs or Virgil
Abau or whoever I often times like to
see just like what's like on their desk
like it's cool to see even like what
they've got pinned around their stuff as
inspo you know or letters they've
written to someone else right and so I
often times think that just yeah that
little handwritten note you're writing
on a plane or whatever make just such
great content it doesn't need to be
polished people just want to see that
like raw
>> and I feel like that's what I've done
like really well. Like I just, you know,
I had an old Instagram and I deleted
that because it was just a highlight
reel of me over overseas and I just
like, you know, obviously I got a deep
story behind where I am right now and I
just jumped on there and just started
owning it and it sort of just took off,
you know, and and which has been so cool
because it was the only thing holding me
back like my actual true story was the
one thing holding me back to actually
being my true self. So going through
that journey of like finding my true
self and and then doing a lot of inner
work. I just talk a lot about that on my
Instagram and on YouTube which makes me
relatable but then also I run a [\h__\h]
sick business.
>> Yeah.
>> You know. Yeah. So the other format too
on Instagram as you know obviously is
stories right? So this is a great
opportunity as well when people follow
you to kind of think about running
through like an intentional flow
>> over say one or two weeks like sharing
stories a bit on the behind the scenes a
little bit on your story then sort of
like what you do
>> and then a couple CTAs leading people to
like hey if you're looking to work
through the construction side check out
this lead magnet maybe then maybe on day
seven it's kind of driving driving
people more to the education side right
so making sure that yeah stories are a
great obviously opportunity as 100% be
sharing also some of the behind the
scenes.
>> For sure. Yeah. Last night I was like up
till 1 in the morning coding. I just put
a story up on that, you know, down.
>> That sounds great.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So, let's talk about a little bit
of the ideas here. So, in terms of like
just like the way that we want to help
Yeah. build this brand essentially. I
think
>> I really again resonate with this idea
of building this like apple of
construction in a way, right? Like what
would Steve Jobs do if he was building a
business like this? Yeah.
>> And so when we think about some of the
ideas, I think a lot of the great stuff
to like lean into is howto content.
>> Yes.
>> Right. Which we can maybe talk about
some ideas there.
>> Yeah.
>> We can talk about like how I
>> which is [snorts] like now getting a
little more personal.
>> Yeah.
>> And then we can just talk about some of
like the kind of core stories that you
have and then any other like you know,
we'll just call it like wild card ideas
that you have.
>> Yeah. as well just for background like
typically when I'm going and creating
content right we have like enormous
amounts of data on what has worked and
about 70% of the time we're just
doubling down on the kind of topics that
we know work as an example I know if I
create a video on how to build a
profitable personal brand or any
rendition of that it's going to blow up
cuz that's why people are coming to me
that's what they know me for proof and
you know enormous experience doing that
stuff and so we can rinse that kind of
idea a thousand in different ways and
just keep becoming this kind of category
leader in that kind of founder brand,
personal brand, executive brand
verticals.
>> Yeah.
>> Then about 30% of the time roughly,
right, is when we may just like try
different [\h__\h]
>> Yeah.
>> Right. So we're just trying out wild
card stuff that we're interested in.
Maybe it's a random vlog in the
Doommites or just random creative [\h__\h]
right? And it's like allowing us to just
test new stuff. Sometimes those things
really work and we enjoy them and we'll
incorporate those back in. The other
side to this that I'm always just aware
of as well as I'm making ideas is that
you know views don't equal cash, right?
So when I look at my own YouTube as an
example, you know, the number one cash
generating video is like our 402nd most
popular video. It's like copy this
content strategy, it'll blow up your
business. And that video has driven us
100K plus
>> education
>> of cash collected. Yeah. always
education based and it's also doing a
great job of being obsessed with the
actual end customer and incorporating
the kind of things that they care about
in our content which might not be and
probably isn't with like just the broad
audience cares about but you don't care
about that because it's more about you
know this niche.
>> So we think about how to content as an
example.
>> Is there stuff that comes to mind for
that?
>> I guess I'm really big on soul first
business second. So like a lot of the
content that I talk about at the moment
isn't really much about like numbers and
and it's it's all about like you know
getting yourself right. So like how to
you know how to you know self-regulate
in the morning before you you know like
those those those early morning routine
things.
>> Cool.
>> How to start your day as a seven figure
founder.
>> Cool. So it's like some we got some like
one sort of topic is like kind of
mindset.
>> Yeah.
>> Cool. So yeah, we're going to have a
bunch of different ideas around that.
>> Yeah.
>> Now I think we could have one around
like the actual crack. Yeah.
>> Right. Because that's something that
both the people that will work with you
on the construction side and the
education side will care about.
>> Yeah. So it be like you know how to I
guess I'm sort of in this period now
which I really want to do which no one
else does. So to learn the stuff that we
do it's very European based not much of
it in Australia. It's all in France,
Germany and so I did a lot of research
like four or five years ago going super
deep into old you know craftsmanships
back from you know 80 90 years ago and
and and and bringing that to Australia.
That's the [\h__\h] dude. Have you suck
with this? I'm like, that [\h__\h] sounds
insane.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And you know, I've
traveled I went and traveled, you know,
France and and and I was like, man, I
took so many photos. I was walking
around taking photos of like their
finished details and stuff cuz they our
craft started uh back when, you know,
they used to make armor for for knights
to go to, you know, to go into into
battle. That's really where our our
craft started started from.
>> Like, yeah. how I learned this technique
to say it's almost like a placeholder
like you could show like that whole
journey and so similar here right we can
take these same sort of pillars mindset
craft and business
>> right and just take them to like how I
>> right so you had said like how I
>> you know
>> on board
>> yeah or yeah one thing you had said on
the mindset side was kind of like uh how
I like uh run my morning routine that
>> right and then yeah like you were just
saying with on the business side, yeah,
how you onboard people, how I onboard
new employees. So on the CTA side,
right, you can then see how these
different categories, right, really
specifically just kind of like mindset,
craft, and business, we can then go and
create CTAs around these different
areas. So we have mindset, say, craft,
and business. When I'm going and
creating CTAs, I talk a lot about how
you want to first off make them
contextual. Yeah.
>> Right. So, we don't want to have CTAs.
It's like, "Hey, if you enjoyed this
piece of content, join my newsletter."
We do want to have CTAs that are like,
"Oh, if you just enjoyed this video on
how to go and self-regulate as a leader,
I've gone and created a 10-minute daily
routine I use in the morning to
self-regulate and a 10-minute routine I
use after a stressful situation. Get it
via the link in my
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Sick. So basically right we have
first off every CTA is going to be
contextual to the piece of content
>> it's in. Now the next principle too is
that we want to be like insanely
generous.
>> You already have that as like a brand
which is similar to how I build it's
like we want to go and like give to the
next generation and give to people and
just the more you give like the most
powerful the most powerful force out
there is like reciprocity right? So you
just said get it back. And so we want to
make like with say any of these, right?
Like we look at self-regulation or your
morning routine like what would be the
most generous thing you think you give
away?
>> Yeah, self-regulation for sure. I think
it's it's so important for a person that
comes from, you know, the way of life
that I sort of live and and and a lot of
my my buyers are not self-regulated, you
know, and in survival mode,
>> right? So yeah, some self-regulation
routine or maybe it's a system.
>> Yeah.
>> But that they can go and use.
>> Yeah. Then the key thing, right, is
these CTAs lead to these sort of lead
magnets that simply can be built
initially just like in a Google doc.
>> Yeah.
>> And inside of that Google doc, right,
you just have an a link.
>> Yeah.
>> Where they can go and take basically one
of two paths.
>> Okay.
>> And so when we look at the monetization
side,
>> [\h__\h] this. I don't make sense. There's
really only two paths and issues that I
think you need to worry about. There's
one that's like kind of let's just say
it's work with me [snorts] directly
let's say which is like let's just say
that was the education side. Yeah.
>> You know and then it's like ones like
get what is it like get us to build your
dream house or
>> as in like client base it be like get in
touch like yeah like um yeah so uh get a
you know say quote to work with me or
something like that something like that.
to think about that one a little more.
But basically, you have a core CTA
that's for the mentorship and then one
that is for, you know, the actual
building side of things. And so because
of those the two paths you're monetizing
folks inside of any given lead magnet,
right, there's that option to go there
and the option to go there.
>> Yeah.
>> On these pages, so these are just on the
same zmh.com or whatever website.
>> Yeah. Mhm.
>> These pages have obviously like a
headline.
>> Yeah.
>> A VSSL like a video sales letter.
>> And then a actual like say tight form
link initially.
>> Yeah.
>> And then if the person is qualified to
work with you here or same thing down
here then you proceed with like the next
step.
>> Yeah.
>> It's likely either way probably a sales
call. And that is sort of the process.
So basically everything you just saw
that's here with Zach is only about 2%
of what we do inside of Founder OS. And
we do it all for you. I'm talking CTAs,
lead magnets, landing pages, you name
it, we do it for you and build your
social media machine inside of Founder
OS. So that's interesting. Go and check
it out via the link in the description.
We'll get on a call and get you started.
Where am I making this content on? Cuz
I've obviously got ZMH like roofing like
that's the business and then I've got
like Zack Hansen which is my personal
page. Yeah,
>> it's like what am I
s
I be should I be like installing a
flashing should that obviously be on ZMH
roofing or how much of it is founder le
like cuz Zach Hansen is the founder.
>> Yeah. You know, so when I'm building it
all, I would recommend that you have as
with my brands, right? It's like every
company has its own brand page. Yeah.
Right. the majority of where the growth
is coming from, the leads are coming
from, is from my actual personal page.
Yeah. Right. Because people follow
people, then they follow. So, now that
Zach has the entire social media machine
mapped out for him, he's going to be
able to now go and take his $7 million
roofing business and turn this into an
actual conglomerate where he's got the
education piece and the construction
piece all under one roof, all being
driven by his founder brand. Now, if you
want to go and get this implemented for
you in your business, be sure to go and
check out Founder OS. Thank you so much
for watching. Be sure to like and
subscribe and I'll see you in the next
one over here where I dive deep into the
psychology behind building a founder
brand.