want to turn your content into a 247
Sales Machine here's how I did it while
only working 4 hours a day leads are the
lifeblood of your business but filling
your pipeline doesn't come from spamming
C DMS or wasting money on ads it comes
from building a standout online presence
with a profitable personal brand here's
the three-part framework to transform
your content into a lead generating
machine one unique Creator positioning
what do you want to be known for I'm
known as the systems Guy online find
your word and build out your brand
around it two scroll stopping content
create four content categories mine are
personal stories personal branding
monetization systems and audience growth
systems I then go and create all of my
content ideas inside of these buckets
three content funnel turn one post into
30 across all platforms and then add
ctas to your newsletter or your offer
it's how you speak to your customers
directly and it's going to help you
build trust and create a business that
grows while you sleep