want to become a better salesperson stop
what you're doing and read these four
books Never split the difference by
Chris Voss the author is a former FBI
negotiator he'll teach you how to
negotiate like your life depends on it
start with no by Jim Camp learn why the
fastest path to yes is through no and
how to get to know faster so you can
move on to yes to sell is Human by
Daniel pink this book will give you
super practical strategies you need to
sell naturally without feeling like it's
forced How to Win Friends and Influence
People by Dale Carnegie a Timeless
classic this book is all about
psychology you'll learn how people are
influenced and how to influence them