Imagine you could get advice from the
same guy that coached the Google
founders Jeff Bezos and Steve Jobs for
free. This is Chat GBT Pulse. What it's
essentially doing is it's able to go and
be fed [music]
specific projects from within my Chat
GBT Pro account and then every single
day I basically get a custom [music]
newsletter and report sent to me with
multiple things that are going to go and
help me accelerate [music] my path to
progress. In my case, I've gone and
uploaded my profit project [music]
and Pulse is going and sending me custom
updates. Things like how to go and
expand my revenue retention and grow my
margins. [music] It's giving me
different channel and sales conversion
strategies. When I go and click into
this, what it's giving me as an example
is [music] how to go and optimize my
channel mix. These are ideas that say
I'm in the back of an Uber and scrolling
[music] Instagram mindlessly. Instead, I
can just go and open up ChatGBT Pulse
and basically just get fed [music]
really high quality information that's
going to help me go and accelerate my
goals. This is like the ultimate
business coach [music] in your pocket.