If it takes you hours to make a post,
you're not a perfectionist. You're using
the wrong system. Let's get into how to
go and use AI as a brainstorming partner
here. Now, to be clear, you know, I
don't recommend that you just go and
publish AI content typically, just
because number one, it doesn't perform
all that well with the different
algorithms. And number two is that, you
know, people always need that kind of
human element, right? To really
gravitate to your own authenticity and
your energy, which is your uniqueness.
And so what you're seeing here is this
page prompt project. Just take whatever
you've got and upload that to the
project knowledge so that Claude can
start writing like you speak. And so
what I'm able to do here is essentially
use Claude as this sparring and
brainstorming partner, helping me come
up with things like, you know, the
different structures of the video,
helping me research the stuff that would
probably be most retentive, the stuff
that you guys really need, so that I can
jam-pack each video with the highest
value per second possible to make sure
I'm being as generous as possible
[music] in every single video we put out
every Tuesday and every Friday.