here's how to build a business that
prints money while you sleep one create
something people want this is the most
important part if people want it it will
be easy to sell do research dig deep
find the hidden gaps in your Niche two
build a selling system organic content
referrals Affiliates your social network
create a system that makes sales on
autopilot three automate delivery don't
be the bottleneck on people getting
started with your product or service
automate delivery so your customers can
dive in right away four use the 4% rule
what is the 4% of work in your business
that drives 64% of the revenue lean into
that delegate and automate everything
else