All right, here's the million-dollar
question.
Are you running a
magnetic business
or one that's just draining you?
When you go and you think about this,
right?
Is your business one that you're
intentionally architecting or
is it draining you because you have to
be the engine at the center of every
single decision?
Now, are you able to go and focus on
maybe
two or three core things that make you
different?
Or do you have one of these businesses
that you need to do 20 things and it
just becomes this house of cards that's
solely just sucking your soul?
Now, is it something where
you have systems that run without you?
Or it just requires
your constant involvement because if
you're not there, nothing runs right.
Inevitably,
is it something that you have you know,
consistent magnetizing content that's
attracting folks to you? Or is it one of
these businesses that you have to
constantly push with things like paid
ads, with outreach
hoping that that leads to new business?
You know, inevitably what we're trying
to do here is create a business that
makes us feel alive versus one that we
just feel like we're a cog in a machine.