Founders not everything needs your
immediate attention in fact here are
three things you should completely
ignore non-customer opinions if someone
isn't buying from you then you don't
need to listen to their opinion they
very well might not even be in your
target market unhelpful negative
feedback some negative feedback is
Meaningful and has something to teach
you but some is just angry don't sweat
it carry on anything outside of your
control if it's something you control
listen and iterate if it's something
completely out of your control then
either adapt or continue with business
as usual don't get wrapped up trying to
get the universe to do what you want it
to do