Stop scrolling. Start creating and put
down that damn phone. Look at your
screen time right now. No, really. Like,
go and look at your screen time. Isn't
it crazy to see the amount of time that
you are wasting on scrolling time that
you could have been spending on selling,
on building, on creating? In this video,
I'm going to break down how you can move
from being just some consumer to a
creator, building more friction and
space in your life so that you can stop
scrolling, start selling, and create
systems around you to make your dreams
come
true. Now, I'm not talking about totally
ditching social media for the rest of
your life. We're not going to go over
any extreme implementation tactics here.
I'm going to give you a sense of a few
really simple, easy systems that you can
implement today. So, let's get into it.
The first one is create don't
consume. Now whether you know it or not
you're a creator. The question is are
you consciously creating out there? So
on your journey now to become a creator
and not just consuming all the time. I
think a big part of this is curating.
You know the best creators are the best
curators. I want to give you a
behind-the-scenes look at how I go and
curate amazing ideas and also get help
with references for things like
animations, titles, editing,
inspiration, color grading, and a lot
more. So, here you can see my YouTube
playlist. Right inside of here, I have
playlists for animations, intros,
lighting, POV, outros. I have a bunch of
different playlists all set up where
when I go and see content that inspires
me, say it's a great thumbnail, great
title, I'll go and save that to the
thumbnail playlist I've made in YouTube
or to the title playlist that I've made
in YouTube. And the better the
references I can find are, the more that
I can become inspired and the better I
become as a creator. So an example here
is when I go into say lighting, these
are a bunch of videos that have inspired
me from a lighting standpoint. For me,
you know, again, as the chief detail
officer of Founder OS and of my personal
brand, the details matter, right? So,
you know, this video as an example, I
love the color grading in this video and
it inspires me with my FX3 to then work
with my team to be able to achieve this
sort of look. And it's not just this
video I've saved, you know, there's a
whole bunch more here. You know, here's
an example from one of my favorite up
and cominging creatives, Alex CE.
Amazing color grade here. This video is
absolutely gorgeous. The shots he's
getting are insane. I think I also saved
this video to my editing inspo playlist
as well. Great shots, cool cinematic
vibe. This is what I aspire to really
create inside of like the founder niche.
I think that there's an awesome
opportunity to give founders the deep
systems that they're after while also
giving them those cinematic beautiful
vibes to create this aspirational brand
that I would like to see in the world.
That's some examples from YouTube. Let's
move on to Instagram. So on Instagram,
some of the best places to curate are
your Instagram collections. You can see
my collections here. I got, you know, an
Instagram collection, my brand, copy,
hustle, health, movement, and
discipline, YouTube style. So when I'm
going and finding stuff that I love, I'm
saving it to the respective folders. So,
say I'm looking to go and make amazing
short form videos. I can go to my short
form video folder. And inside of here, I
have a bunch of different references all
saved for videos that really inspire me.
You know, I'm not copying these videos.
I'm just using them as a reference to
say, you know, maybe I like the way they
made their copy appear um and how it
constantly is changing uh every 1 and a
half seconds in this video. I want to go
and have short form videos that have
that snappiness to them that really
hooks the viewers attention um and then
drives them to becoming a part of the
founder west community as an example.
You know, similarly, you know, the
lighting in this video and the use of
text really inspire me. You know, John,
someone I've come on my radar really
recently and I'm really inspired by the
way he uses his fonts, his text to
really hook the viewer. Um, and just
it's just awesome creativity more than
anything, right? These just get my
creative juices flowing, right? They get
me pumped up to go and create my next
video, to create my next pieces of
content because I'm just like, "Wow,
these guys are setting the bar." And so,
the cool thing is now when I want to go
and come up with some inspiration for my
own short form videos, I got an endless
list of them. Now, let's move on to X.
Right on the bookmarks tab of X, this is
an excellent area to then be able to go
and save content that really inspires
you. This is an amazing graphic that I
saw from the legend Sean Pur that really
goes over the five levels of hiring.
tons of different things that inspire
me. I'm constantly going and saving them
so that I can go and reference these
things later. Different visual styles,
graphics, different sort of imagery,
copy. You know, my belief is that X is
really like a gym for copywriting. And
the best copywriters in the world,
they're on X. A lot of the time, the
best ideas that you see later on
platform like YouTube actually
originated originally on X. I use it
often to kind of just source really cool
ideas and then be able to kind of remix
those or adapt those to what I'm
building in any given week. Similarly,
Pinterest is an amazing spot. So, I was
actually just using Pinterest this week
because I wanted to set the bar for our
graphic design efforts at Founder OS. I
just went and hired another graphic
designer that's now three on our team.
And what I did was create a graphic
design board in Pinterest where I'm
going and saving all these references
that to me really encapsulate the vibe,
the energy, the copy, the look, the
photos, the imagery of Founder OS and
what I'm looking to build. I don't just
go and bring on a graphic designer and
say, you know what, go figure it out.
No, no, no, no, no, no. I go and I
actually synthesize exactly the kind of
references that I love. And then when
I'm now looking to have that person go
design a deck, have them design a
landing page, have them design a social
graphic, a story for Instagram, I can go
and use this Pinterest board that I've
gone and created to go then and
reference specific examples of designs
that I love that I want them to kind of
use as a reference for what we're about
to create. I may actually give them a
few references and say kind of combine
these vibes along with our brand
identity and our brand guidelines to
create something that's hard-hitting,
inspiring, and makes each person that
sees this thing want to share it with
five friends. The next tool that I love
that's a hidden gem that most people
don't know about, but now you do, is
called my mind. My mind is like a
database for your creativity. And so in
here I have spaces for copy, web design,
my upcoming book, sentences, I love
offers, storytelling, short form videos,
and so I can then doubleclick into say a
section which is like the founder us
brand identity. And these are a bunch of
different graphics I've saved across the
internet to my mind that allow me to
kind of go and become inspired.
Similarly, I may go and save a bunch of
stuff around different copy that I love
out there, right? So that when I'm going
and looking to come up with different
copywriting for X, for LinkedIn, for my
upcoming book, I have no shortage of
ideas. When I'm inspired, the key thing
is I don't just scroll past it. I'm not
just mindlessly wasting my life away.
I'm not just scrolling anymore. I'm not
just consuming. I'm curating and then
I'm creating. And when you do this, you
build leverage. When you do this, you
build an audience. When you do this, you
stop scrolling and you start selling.
You sell your ideas. you sell your
message and you can sell a lot of
products doing this too. These are tools
I love. Go and use these today and I
can't wait to see what you
[Music]
create. Taking this approach allowed me
to quickly go from being a consumer to a
curator to then a creator. Instead of
just going and scrolling mindlessly all
day, go and slow down for a sec and pay
attention to the things that are
inspiring you. And then use that
inspiration. Save those things. And next
time you find yourself going and writing
online or the next time you find
yourself maybe making a video that you
want to share, go and pull up those as
references. When you're just consuming
all day, that is just energy that you
are pouring into a platform and
receiving zero benefit, zero leverage,
zero ability to change anything you got
going on right now. On the other side,
when you create, you build. When you
create, you scale. When you create, you
learn. You fail. You make mistakes. But
as you keep creating, everything starts
to transform. So the next principle here
is to use friction tactically for habit
[Music]
moderation. One of my favorite purchases
over the last 2 years is a little device
called a brick. When you go and you tap
this physical device with your phone,
it's going to go and it's going to
essentially block all of the core social
media apps. So, I'll go and tap the
brick, say around 11:00 a.m., and then
from around 11:00 a.m. till 8:00 p.m. my
social media is blocked. The benefit
here is that it really leaves me with a
few options throughout my day. I can go
and I can meet new people or hang out
with, you know, existing people that I
love. I can create or I can go and work
out, go for a walk. My ability to
actually just go and block these things
to add friction really makes it more
effortless to create and not consume.
Another thing that you can use for this
is just using your phone settings to go
and set limits on the different apps on
your phone. By setting these limits, you
know, you start to go and create more
space in your life and become more
conscious of your scrolling habits,
right? So that you can get out of that
dopamine cycle you're on of just getting
notifications and newsfeed updates and
comparing yourself to others. All these
things that are really destructive to
your creative flow. But all that space,
you know, using it to write, to build,
to work out, to lift, to reach out to
mentors, to learn, to really level up.
The same version that's just sitting on
your ass all day scrolling is not the
same person that's going to help you
achieve the dreams that you're after.
Something's got to give here. First off,
you got to give yourself space to become
that new version of yourself. You know,
saying no is one of the most powerful
things you can do. My year here in 2025,
I'm very dedicated to keeping things
insanely simple. Simplicity isn't just
something I made up, right? This is the
same sort of thinking that Steve Jobs
put into the iPhone. Over my travels
over the summer, you know, I was really
inspired by Steve Jobs. You know,
someone that not only had revolutionized
so many industries, but created products
that we still love today. It's
incredible then to go and study Steve
and understand, okay, well, what was it
that was so special about Steve? And it
all comes down to simplicity. And when
you think about simplicity, it really
comes down to saying no more often.
Steve had the principle of saying no,
which is why the iPhone is so beautiful.
It's void of all of the distractions
that plagued products like Blackberry,
which are now dust. As I've continued to
develop this concept of being insanely
simple, reading Steve Jobs biography,
from reading the book Insanely Simple,
which I highly recommend, from reading
the presentation secrets of Steve Jobs,
innovation secrets of Steve Jobs. You
can't tell I'm a little obsessed because
I've eliminated all these distractions
in my life. I now have so much time to
create. Over the past 10 days, as an
example, I filmed over seven YouTube
videos, over 20 Instagram reels, and you
can imagine all of that content now and
the ripple effect that that's going to
create. It's going to help me go and
build the movement behind Founder OS.
It's going to help me get the message
out there that there's a different way
to build businesses. You don't need to
sacrifice your freedom to build a great
business. You know, you can build a
business that actually gives you freedom
as a founder. You can build a business
around abundance versus suffering. I've
essentially gone and reallocated all of
that scrolling time past all that time
now that I have through the lens of
being insanely simple and being insanely
focused. And now that's what's opened up
my ability to go and create all of this
content. So now I'm going and putting my
message out there versus being this
person that all I do all day is scroll
through other people's stuff. So we
talked a lot about lowering the friction
to consumption. Let's also talk about
lowering the friction to creation. When
you're going and deciding that you're
actually going to start creating now,
you may actually start selling. Maybe
it's just selling your ideas initially,
but later on maybe it's actually selling
a product. It doesn't matter what you're
selling, right? It all starts as
probably just selling an idea. And when
you decide that you're going to start
creating content around your ideas, an
important place to start is lowering the
friction to creation. First off, you
want to make it as easy as possible to
go and create. If you're a writer, that
may mean going and having a pen and a
notebook in your backpack while you're
ripping around all the day. If you are
someone that's into creating videos, it
might mean actually having a consistent
setup, your lighting, your camera,
wherever you are, so that it reduces
that mental strain that's involved with
actually going and getting in front of
the camera, pressing play, and putting
your ideas into visuals. And I also keep
things super simple on the ideation side
with my content. Most of my content
ideas are all stored in Apple notes. Not
some fancy notion doc, not some crazy
Pinterest boards. They're simply just
all jotted down in an Apple note. Go and
create an Apple notes list. Okay? Create
one for your writing content. Create
another for short form videos and create
another list in your Apple Notes for
long- form videos for YouTube. From
there, start to populate these things.
Right? When you have different ideas, be
sure to go and enter those ideas into
the respective list. So the next time
you want to go and get into creation
mode, it's easy. It's effortless. It's
[Music]
frictionless. So now you've gone and
you've reduced your screen time. You've
increase the friction to actually going
and consuming and you have reduced the
friction to creating. Well, now let's
move on to the next principle here,
which is create content systems that run
on
[Music]
autopilot. As I went and started
building my personal brand, I realized
that even being a creator at times can
be super exhausting. Without the right
systems, you can easily find yourself on
the content hamster wheel. This is why
so many creators burn out. Well, how do
you actually stay in the game as a
founder brand and not just fall off the
face of the earth? Well, the big thing
here is through systems. Systems equal
freedom. If you want to live your
dreams, build systems. If you want to
work 4 hours a day on a business that
you love, build systems. If you want to
travel the world, work on things that
you enjoy, build systems. Systems give
you the ability to go and create
repeatable processes for the parts of
your business or your own creation
process that you don't want to do
anymore because it feels like there's
friction. An example of this is I went
and recently created a whole document on
how to create a viral YouTube video. It
was a 15page document on all of the
learnings that we've had on YouTube in
terms of what works and what doesn't. I
went and documented all this stuff so
that when we're coming up with new
ideas, when we're editing content, when
we're distributing content, I don't need
to be involved in all these details any
longer because there's a system. There
is a repeatable process. We have
repeatable processes for short form
videos. We have repeatable processes for
long- form video distribution. We have
repeatable processes for how we make
Instagram stories, Instagram carousels,
long form LinkedIn posts, long- form
LinkedIn infographics. All of these
systems, every minute detail, I document
it in a Google doc. I'll then go and
film myself generally on five minutes or
less in a Loom video actually doing the
thing that I'm trying to delegate. And
then I'll make sure that I have the
right person in place. Someone that has
high intelligence, high energy, is a
down [\h__\h] is hungry, is
coachable, and has a proven track
record. I get that person to go and take
my proven system and then go and run
with it. Now, initially where I see a
lot of people screw up when they
implement these systems is they delegate
it and then they just say Levie. I go
and I make sure that I'm closely
monitoring the implementation of that
system over time so that I essentially
move from being the person that's always
in the weeds to being almost the chief
detail officer across my business. I'm
looking at the details, you know, I'm
going and reviewing a video before it
goes out. I'm looking at our motion
graphic guidelines. I'm looking at the
different design templates we're
creating in Figma. I'm looking at the
different content that's being written
to make sure that all of it is on brand.
My goal is to create the best founder
content in the world to inspire millions
of you to go and to create the
businesses of your dreams to inspire you
to achieve freedom in life. You know,
time freedom, location freedom, mental
freedom, financial freedom. Freedom is
what it's all about. And I think that
content is an amazing vehicle to inspire
people just like you. But I want to live
this myself, right? I don't want to be
creating all this content and find
myself on a content hamster wheel. So,
I've shifted from just being some
personal brand to being a personal media
company. I am the CEO of a media company
with a team of amazing people around me,
social managers, editors, writers,
newsletter writers, and together we form
this entire media company that helps
founders achieve freedom. First off, you
need to have a succinct brand strategy.
So, we have a really solid brand
identity and brand guidelines for my
personal brand as well as Founder OS.
That allows us to go and bring on new
people, but they all have the same brand
guidelines because I believe that great
brands should feel like they're
basically coming from one person. A
unified brand, you know, guideline
identity is essential. The next aspect
here is that you need to have knowledge
of what great content looks like. I talk
often about, you know, taste is the
ultimate competitive advantage. making
sure that you go and set the bar for
others on your team in terms of, hey,
this is the best content we've ever
created. If you're going to go and
create, you know, a short form video for
us, make sure it's better than this. If
you're going to go and create a YouTube
video and edit it, make sure it's better
than this one that we made that got over
500,000 views. You know, in life, you
get what you tolerate. And I think when
you're building a personal media
company, it's important that you set
that bar and set it high. All of you
have a dream. You have content. You have
brands that inspire you. Don't put off
going and hitting that bar. Set that
today. The same way that I encourage
people to go and have a 10ear, 3year,
one-year vision in their personal lives
and in their business. You should have
creative references for the kind of
brand you're looking to create. That
brand ain't going to make itself. You
need to be the chief detail officer and
you need to detail out the references
that are going to allow you to hit that
bar. and the combination of those
references from my stuff, from others,
from just my own vibe and what I want to
put out there, it all mixes up to create
something that is uniquely me. And I
think that people inevitably gravitate
to you. And so when it comes to then
actually creating content, you can make
it really easy by leveraging this
founder OS content idea machine. What
you want to do is you want to go and you
want to think of what are your content
categories. So for me, my content
categories are things like systems,
personal stories, audience growth
systems, monetization systems. Those are
my categories. I'd encourage you to go
write down what your categories are. And
it could be anything, right? Just the
kind of categories that you want to
speak about. Go and take a sec and jot
down the ideas that exist around those
categories. You can create lists,
playbooks, you can create tools,
roundups. You can shout out the best
entrepreneurs in those categories. You
can shout out the best references, the
things that are inspiring you there, the
mistakes you've made. You know, again,
the list goes on. You get the categories
that you want to go and create stuff
around. Then you double click into that
and come up with your content ideas. And
then from there, you just go and get
busy. If I'm going and making content
for X, I use Hype Fury to go and
schedule out my content for months to
come so I can get off the content
hamster wheel. On LinkedIn, I post
directly because I see that the
algorithm favors that the most. on
YouTube. We go and we aim to batch our
content on YouTube. So, we'll go film
say four or five videos in a few days
and then load up YouTube for a couple
months so that we can kind of take a
step back and then get back to ideation
creation and not feel like we're got to
kind of keep up with the pace. On
Instagram, I have a social media
manager. Same with Tik Tok and a lot of
the other platforms, right? So that I
don't need to actually go and post all
this content. I think a social media
manager is probably the most underrated
hire when you're building a personal
media company. It's that person that's
going to allow you to go and delegate
the distribution of that content. I
think of a social media manager kind of
like your chief distribution officer.
That person that's in charge of helping
expand your reach, helping you get in
front of more people. And if they're
doing their job right, they're coming up
with ideas. They're helping you
understand what's working and what's not
working. My social media manager, Nick,
big shout out to Nick, is an absolute
legend. And this is someone that's, you
know, making sure that 7 days a week
that content is going out. It's spicy.
It's hitting hard. and it's providing a
lot of value to people just like you.
Finding a social media manager early on
in your business, I think, is one of the
most important hires that you can make
if you're serious about selling, you're
serious about growing an audience, and
you're serious about really transforming
your
business. So, here's my challenge to
you. After this video, you can keep on
scrolling or you can start selling. Go
and choose two things from this video
that you can go and implement right now.
along the way. If you want some help
building your brand online, be sure to
apply to Founder Os via the link below.
Welcome to the Founder Freedom Movement.