what if I told you everything you want
this year is behind 1 hour of planning
you be working 4 hours a day have
everything run on autopilot and enjoy
the freedom to work when you want where
you want with whoever you want today
I'll show you the master plan for my
business and my brand that I will use
this year to achieve all of those and
hit eight figures consistently it's the
same blueprint that worked for me the
last 3 years and has worked with
hundreds of other Founders in our
community who successfully scaled their
businesses to seven and eight figures
while living their dream life here's how
we're going to break it down first we'll
set the vision then we're going to map
out every critical system then we'll
assemble the Dream Team to bring it all
to life and finally I'm going to walk
you through a comprehensive
implementation strategy to make it all
happen let's get into it a few years ago
I was drowning working 15 hours every
day with no systems and no Clarity the
truth was I wasn't running my business
my business was running me into the
ground fast forward to now my businesses
generate over $13.8 million a year and I
only work 4 hours a day wherever I want
so what allowed me to break out of that
vicious cycle I set a Clear Vision this
is the first step to creating your
biggest year yet now vision isn't some
lofty and loose concept it's the
backbone of the motivation that's going
to drive you to success here's how I
make my vision actionable think about it
right now where do you want to be in 365
days write it down for example my vision
for 2025 is for founder West to be the
world's leading Community for
founder-led Brands empowering on laurs
to build automated scalable and
impactful businesses to achieve this
through unparalleled content audience
growth impr proven systems and to scale
to $20 million Revenue a year now this
isn't just about the money your vision
needs to include your ideal lifestyle
too for me that means building a calm
automated company that lets me travel
create connect and pursue what truly
matters to me without getting burned out
now before you write down yours let's
zoom out first begin with the end in
mind this means that the system for
designing your goals for this year
begins with designing your goals for the
next 10 years base your one-year goals
on your 10year goals here's what my
10-year Vision looks like at the top
left here you can see the company values
of insanely simple quality results
founder first and having fun these
Define everything that we do and they
determine what we say yes to inside of
the business as well as with the brand
and then most importantly what we can
quickly say no to you can then see the
vision of going and impacting 100
million Founders the mission then of
going and helping them achieve their
dreams and Achieve true freedom and our
Niche being $5 million founder systems
helping Founders achieve $5 million
profit a year with the proven systems
for audience brand and revenue growth
from there then I go and engineer our
10e goals they're smart meaning that
they're specific measurable actionable
realistic and time Bound in three years
then I reverse engineer those 10year
goals I recommend setting a maximum of
five ambitious 10-year goals they should
be related to what gets you out of bed
and what really fire fires you up and
matters to you from your 10-year Vision
extract your three-year Vision I suggest
setting five to seven goals there as
well and then once you have your
three-year Vision reverse engineer it
again to solidify what your one-year
goal should be you should end up with
something like this here are my one-year
goals when it comes down to then the
oneyear 90day plans I go and just kind
of back into the three-year to the
oneyear then on the next 990 days what I
then have here is then finalizing those
book edits to make sure that the book is
ready to go pre ordering and pre-selling
the 100,000 copies of it having 5,000
Founders on our monthly workshops
selling a certain amount of spots of
founder OS per month going and making
sure that we're going and getting
different applications and high quality
Founders into the Mastermind as well as
OS plus and continue to scale up all
social platforms like YouTube you know
the newsletter X LinkedIn so there's a
bunch of opportunities too that I see
across things like people product and
process which really involve just going
and hiring absolute Killers onboarding
them right making sure that we're
elevating the team and the culture as
much as possible on the product side
hosting some epic founder Retreats
throughout this year and on the
processes side making sure we have a
unified dashboard for the entire company
which I'll show you in one second and
then making sure that we have all core
metrics being sent to me every single
Friday so I can keep a good pulse on the
company this is the vision go and make
yours your goals are useless without a
powerful Vision to drive them into
reality here's how to crystallize your
vision even further when you define your
vision think of the who what and why who
are you impacting what are you creating
and why are you pushing for these goals
for me I want to create systems to help
seven figure Founders build a systemized
hyper profitable and scalable personal
brand using organic content help
Founders free up their time and drive
predictable Revenue without all the
headaches heavy lifting and relying on
ads that I see so many other Founders
have to deal with you know my mission is
to help 100 million Founders achieve
their dreams unlock their potential and
Achieve true Freedom now it's your turn
ask yourself where do I want to be by
the end of 2025 write it down if your
vision doesn't make you feel scared
excited well then you're not stretching
yourself enough once you've brought your
vision into Focus you now need something
that will guide every decision you will
make this is where it we'll develop your
core values to bring your vision to life
you need to make the right decisions and
make them consistently that's exactly
why your core values matter they help
you make decisions fast fter and with
more confidence I use my core values as
my North Star here's mine insanely
simple quality results founder first and
have fun don't treat this like a
marketing exercise use your values as
your filter for every decision you're
going to make this year everything we
build at founder centers on our core
value of being founder first while other
people are just selling courses we're
building an entirely new category a
comprehensive system that helps Founders
achieve true Freedom we're not just
teaching Theory we're implementing
proven systems that have helped Founders
like Sammy scale from 0 to $30,000 in
monthly recurring Revenue in just 3
months we're all about transforming
Founders Journeys from being overwhelmed
and chaotic to systemized success
nothing that isn't aligned with our core
values of being founder first takes up
my time or anyone on my team's time to
ensure that we're all hyperfocused and
moving in the right direction with
maximum momentum take out your notebook
and write down three to five values that
you absolutely will not compromise on
these are your guiding principles keep
them visible and use them daily to guide
every decision that you make now that
you've got the why in Focus let's now
focus on the how the difference between
six-figure businesses that run you into
the ground and an eight fig business
that runs itself is not more hustle it's
better systems and this is where most
Founders get stuck they have the vision
their values are locked in but their
business is a prison because they lack
the right systems these are the five key
systems that will allow you in your
business to find success this year and
we're going to break them down for you
one by one audience growth monetization
operations content creation and
Community Building lead generation is
the lifeblood of any business and that's
why audience growth is vital in 2025 I'm
scaling my audience to 5 million across
six platforms using what I call the
content GPS this system is built on
maximizing each piece of content and to
do that you must leverage the content
waterfall system this is how I take one
piece of content and turn it into 30
other pieces of content across all
platforms let me show you how when I
create a thread on X it becomes three
Instagram reals three YouTube shorts
three Tik Tok videos three x videos 10
more tweets one newsletter one instagram
Carousel one LinkedIn post and one long
form YouTube video not only has the
content been multiplied but so has the
reach of my offer since they all connect
back to course ctas don't think of
building mere followers these people are
your potential future customers
teammates and partners having a growing
audience is great it's amazing but
turning that attention into revenue is
where you really need these monetization
systems in place my goal for 2025 is $20
million in Revenue but how am I going to
generate it the plan is to get there
with three core streams High ticket
offers recurring revenue and strategic
Partnerships quickly identify your core
revenue streams and then place them
within this offer stack template an
offer stack is the series of offers that
you present to your dream customer as
they move through your content funnel
this is what it may look like for you
you know your social media bio on
Instagram is an offer for people to go
and follow you your CTA under a given
post on Instagram is an offer for people
to then visit your newsletter landing
page your newsletter landing page copy
then leads people through a lead magnet
which is an offer for people to then
join your newsletter and your newsletter
copy then contains an offer for people
to join a sales call with your team your
sales call presents an offer for people
to then go and work with you well here's
what my offer stack looks like I have an
irresistible social media profile that
drives 20% of my profile visitors to
become followers that's 40x the average
I have a newsletter landing page that
converts 80% of page visitors to
subscribers and then I have a monthly
Workshop that converts $200,000 of new
business to my company every month I
have low ticket offers between $29 and
$149 to give people my most powerful
systems and then present them with an
offer to join my exclusive communities
and experience es I have founder OS
which helps Founders go from six figures
to seven figures using proven systems I
have found plus which helps them get to
$5 million profit a year by installing
the content GPS in your business for you
and I have founder s Mastermind which is
an invite only community of Founders
that are on average generating over
eight figures in Revenue a year and I
offer Boutique content funnels for large
scale Founders for a million dollars a
year if they really want to have me and
my team work Hands-On in their business
to train their team now that money is
part of the equip
we can walk you through how to automate
these operations to maximize your
freedom as a Founder this is where
everything changes most Founders become
the bottleneck in their own business
they try to do everything themselves
control everything and it kills their
growth I learned this the hard way that
it was the wrong way now I use what I
call the AED system automate what you do
repeatedly eliminate the unessential and
delegate what others can do write down
every task you are doing right now in
your business and measure its impact on
your energy then decide whether it's
something you should automate eliminate
or delegate this is what it looks like
for me so what I've done here is in this
First Column I've listed out all of the
core tasks as well as items in my
calendar over the last month from there
I'm going to go and indicate whether a
task gives me energy is neutral or
drains my energy and from there I can go
and indicate whether I want to delegate
it eliminate it or automate it and if
I'm delegating it to who on my team or
who I need to hire now the benefits of
this is that you then go and you get
really conscious about what it is that
you're spending your time on and most
importantly what actually gives you a
lot of energy so you can eliminate all
the stuff that just weighs you down and
double down on the stuff that fires you
up what I'll do then is then use all of
the tasks that I no longer want on my
plate to then go and backload those into
job descriptions for new roles I'm going
to go higher for or the existing people
that I already have on my team so go and
complete your time audit system now is a
great time to get it done and go into
the new year absolutely cranking on task
that you genuinely love to do I repeat
this process quarterly to ensure that my
time is being spent on the stuff that
really gives me energy and drives me
closer to my goals you can download this
exact AED template in the description
below and get started right after
finishing this video after automating
eliminating and delegating your tasks
it's time for you to create a system
that not only generates leads on
autopilot but also helps you more
importantly compound your growth without
you working 12 hours a day or burning
out and you can only achieve that if you
systemize your content creation here's
where we break you off the content
hamster wheel with the content machine
this is the exact one that I've set up
that lets me go and publish repurpose
and distribute highquality content
across all platforms without lifting a
finger most days we already covered how
to maximize single pieces of content
using the content waterfall system but
now we're going to go and maximize your
ability to go and generate ideas for
each strategic piece of content I
designed this chat gbt prompt and I call
it my content idea machine because it
will generate over 30 content ideas in
just 30 seconds and it's not just going
to create those ideas but align them
with your brand pillars and your Niche
this prompt works like this so the
template is you are a viral content
expert I need your help to generate
compelling content ideas take
inspiration from viral YouTube video
titles and viral Twitter threads with
over 5 million views make the
copywriting impeccable and memorable
replace the info below with an overview
and mission of your brand I'm a Founder
creating content to help Founders reach
$5 million through every year through
proven systems for audience brand and
Community growth our mission is to help
a 100 million Founders automate their
business and hit $5 million profit a
year with proven systems I want you to
generate viral content ideas by creating
a table the yaxis has has content
categories to be matched with the x-axis
the x-axis has content groups formatted
the following way name so select your
content groups from below educational
which are lists best ofs tools facts
guides systems summaries and Frameworks
emotional are going to drive some type
of emotion and get the reader to feel
some type of way that causes them to
share with five friends Deep dive which
is stuff like data math reasons Trends
expert quotes research and Industry
breakdowns edutainment which is creating
content with amazing storytelling
practical value that is captivating
compelling and makes people want to
share it with five friends lists which
provide useful lessons steps systems
processes tools and resources about the
content category and comparisons
Alternatives pros and cons this verse
that then we have feature comparisons
budget vers premium case studies client
results process breakdowns real world
applications industry specific results
problem solution and then Q&A FAQ common
questions audience concerns specific
Solutions step-by-step Guidance
clarifications the Y AIS contains the
content categories write out a table and
write out a viral content idea for each
cell of the X and Y AIS pair each
content category with a Content group
for example a viral content idea pairing
with content group educational with the
content category educational would
generate the viral content idea seven
tools to help you grow Community from
zero to 1 million if you want a copy of
that prompt in my content idea machine
template you can get it for free via the
link in the description with this in
your systems Arsenal it's simply a
process of repeating these three steps
when you need a fresh take on your
content strategy create content in three
categories helpful personal stories and
deep Dives repurpose these then and you
can turn one video into 10 plus assets
schedule everything you're not
scrambling it's time to reveal how to
transform all of this content into
movement of real people at found R Us
we're not just building an audience
we're creating something much more
powerful a thriving founder community
that drives sustainable growth our plan
for 2025 is to invest in a dedicated
Retreat Center this is a transformative
space in the dolm mites designed
specifically for founder Retreats we're
also systemizing what we call founder
hikes creating opportunities for deep
connection through shared experiences in
nature our goal is to grow our community
to 50,000 active members but we're not
just focusing on numbers we're creating
exclusive residency experiences that
turn casual connections into lasting
relationships how can you bring your
audience together this could be through
things like webinars regular meetups
live q&as or even small in-person events
remember when you build true belonging
you create something that algorithms
can't replicate a self-sustaining
ecosystem that grows your business while
you focus on what matters most impact
and freedom building a movement around
your brand is one of the best ways to
build a business that serves your life
not not the other way around with all
systems in place we need the last
element of your success this year the
team that's going to bring your vision
to life a well-built team is the
difference between an exhausting grind
and a powerful growth fueled engine
here's the team I built in 2024 some of
you may not be starting out with a team
this big but don't worry use these four
stages to guide the sustainable growth
of your team no matter what stage you
are in your founder Journey let me give
you an inner glimpse of the different
stages that I used while scaling founder
OS so phase one was ideation at this
phase it's just me doing everything as
the chief everything officer I was on X
LinkedIn with an audience of 40,000 and
had just launched the first iteration of
founder OS spinning plates but the
systems that I was putting in place
allowed me to do a lot with very little
the next aspect here was then Phase 2
validation at this point we're
generating over $50,000 a month and I
started to go and use those cash flows
to go and make some key hires across the
tech side of things finance and
copyrighting as we scale the phase 3
monetization I started to scale up more
of the team delegating some of the sales
aspects going and hiring some creative
weapons on board and scaling the company
to over
$200,000 in monthly Revenue the cool
thing is throughout all these stages I
kept the tech super simple using
platforms like kajabi to go and sell
different programs school for the
community and stripe for all payments so
there's a lot of people coming on board
at this point but the good thing is is
that we've got great systems in place so
everything's scaling super smoothly as
we move on to phase 4 we're starting to
scale things out to over
$400,000 of monthly Revenue I'm really
focused on staying disciplined and
systemizing everything and not just me
but actually having systems owners in
the business so that I'm democratizing
the growth of the business and not
everything is reliant on me now phase
five is Mastery this is the phase that
we're currently at as we go and get to a
million dollar in monthly Revenue so
I've gone and built out my own
leadership team across sales Finance
customer success and I've removed myself
from as much as possible so I can focus
on the stuff that really fires me up
things like product creative and
creating the best founder experience in
the world so no matter what stage you're
at go and take a look at kind of The
Insider tips I've just shown you and
let's take some Massive Action looking
at this year I'm focusing on adding
three critical new hires to my team one
a sales director two a customer success
director to drive sustainable growth
three High Caliber closers to join our
Revenue team when I look for new team
members I'm not just hiring for skills
we're looking for weapons a weapon is an
obsessed individual who can 10x their
area of responsibility and Elevate the
culture and speed of innovation hire
weapons who align with your values and
your vision but here's something
critical I learned the hard way you need
systems before you bring on your team so
document everything in your company
every process every standard every
expectation that goes into your company
Wiki your company Wiki is a hub for all
the information resources systems and
processes that fuel the success of each
role in your company the more detailed
your company Wiki the more efficient
you're going to be at scaling your
business with less stress this way when
you find your weapons they can hit the
ground running and leverage the wiki to
monitor success use those systems to
then scale out your business and to
monitor all the systems in this video
you're going to need the ultimate tool
your company dashboard this is how I
track every metric every goal and every
win across our entire team to keep us
aligned and on track this year and every
year so that we win big so systems are
great and all but as the founder you
need to make sure those systems are
actually impacting the metrics of the
business and that's where the founder OS
dashboard template comes in so this is
the dashboard across one of my
businesses you can see that we're
tracking the full funnel all the way
from social media growth to newsletter
to vssl conversions applications our
Revenue mix across all of our different
products as well as things like our
Workshop conversion rate and outbound
now I'm tracking these metrics every
single Friday so they're being updated
from the week I can then go and track
those Trends across you know the entire
year see which weeks we were really
strong and then go and correlate those
with you know what content did we put
out U maybe we made a new hire at a
certain juncture or we tried out some
new method or tactic um that we can go
and double down on and so the the more
you have visibility into the specific
metrics across your business the more
you can understand what people what
products what systems are working best
and which changes that you're
implementing your business are actually
making an impact so go and Implement
your dashboard make sure it covers your
entire funnel all the way from awareness
through to transaction so you can go and
discover the constraints in your
business and attack them with your time
and resources this dashboard lets me
manage a multi-million dollar operation
and just a few hours a week and gives me
all the control with none of the chaos
now let's turn this plan into reality
with this 90day framework to Kickstart
your year the right way Phase One
Foundation Days 1 to 30 you're going to
clarify the vision and values and you're
get the platform setup initial systems
implemented phase two growth days 31 to
60 it's all about content acceleration
audience building and newsletter growth
phase three is all about monetization so
days 61 to 90 it's offer creation
systems launch and then we're going to
scale the implementation stay
disciplined to these stages and watch
your year transform into your dream and
as a thank you for making it this far
here's all the technology and tools that
I use to implement all these systems
across my portfolio of eight figure
businesses for Content distribution and
analytics here's our exact setup hyp
Fury handles all our X content
scheduling we use twex to find trending
content ideas for x and then X analytics
gives us realtime performance data and
then I use Tapo X to help help us spot
the best LinkedIn content ideas for our
community and Sales Systems HubSpot
Powers our newsletter this is crucial
because your email list is going to be
one of the best ways to connect with
your audience School hosts our entire
founder us Community stripe processes
all of our payments we built our website
on webflow although we did start it on
kajabi but either one will work
testimonial. helps us collect and
showcase hundreds of real results from
Founders in our community and for
internal systems at founder OS we use
notion as our company Wiki and this
houses every single system all Loom
videos every process that we've got that
makes our business run on autopilot
Google Drive for all our media assets
Google docs for system documentation and
then auna for all of our different
projects zapier is what we use then to
go and automate all the repetitive tasks
across the business for our creative and
communication stack figma handles all of
our design work we use loom for screen
recording this has cut our meetings in
half and then type form for all
applications and as well as founder
feedback each tool removes tasks from my
plate automates processes and helps my
team operate a lot more efficiently
whether I'm there or not every single
system covered in this video is
customized and personally implemented
for the change makers who decide to join
founder OS if you want to go deeper join
me inside founder OS where we'll work
together to go and Implement these exact
systems in your business for you explore
this opportunity further using the link
in the description below you now have
the exact blueprint I use to build
multi-million dollar businesses that run
on autopilot this isn't just Theory this
is the same system that's allowed me to
build a community of over 14 million
people generate $13.8 million in annual
revenue and work just 4 hours a day
while I travel the world and my
businesses grow an autopilot I look
forward to seeing what you do this year
with these systems like And subscribe
and welcome to the founder Freedom
Movement