most people's evenings are killing their
success here are the five things I do
after 700 p.m. that help me build a $13
million business working just 4 hours a
day first magnesium at 7:00 p.m. sharp
it relaxes your muscles and regulates
stress game changer for deep sleep
second no screens after 7:00 p.m. I used
to scroll until midnight now I'm up at
5:00 a.m. crushing deep work while
others sleep third plan tomorrow in 5
minutes write down three needle moving
tasks out of your mind on to paper
fourth read for 30 minutes it calms your
mind and helps you disconnect from the
chaos of building finally and this is
the key Lights Out by 10 p.m.
non-negotiable this system transformed
my life from working 15-hour days to
making $1.2 million a month on 4our days
your evening routine either builds your
Empire or it destroys it Choose Wisely