what you want is not what you want and
that's why it's so damn hard every
result has a cause to figure out what
you actually want you need to look at
the cause not the result everyone wants
more money a better job a bigger house
results are always desirable but if you
only desire the result you'll never do
what it takes or you'll sacrifice things
that truly matter to you in order to
achieve that result the key is to find
the cause that you desire where the work
itself is Meaningful if you desire the
cause then you're running downhill
toward the result because you don't only
want to reach the Finish Line you want
to take every step required to get there