There's one thing Kim Kardashian
understands about business that most
founders ignore and it's making her
billions. People buy into Kim's story,
her journey, her obsession with
shapewear because of the insane outfit
she wears. That's the moat generic
brands can't copy. For me, sharing one
of my worst periods of my life had the
same effect. I'd gone through business
school and felt like the whole
investment was a complete waste of time.
You know, this was the genesis of why I
went and created BitMaker, my first
company. Seven months in, crushing it
and then two agents walk in. They tell
me that we got to shut down because they
think that I'm operating an unregistered
private career college. I could go to
jail for a year, fined up to a million
dollars and the main thing that I know
to do in that moment was tell the story
to as many humans as possible. Fast
forward one year later, we trained over
2,000 software engineers and [music] the
business was acquired for a
life-changing sum. That story did more
for my credibility than any credential.
It wasn't polished, it was my actual
life story.