[Music]
imagine having four systems that allow
you to travel the world build your dream
life and scale your business
effortlessly every single month while
controlling who you work with and what
you work on I'm about to break down all
four systems in detail in this video
Let's dive
[Music]
in the systems I'm about to show you are
about 15 years in the making over the
last 15 years I've traveled and worked
in countries like Bali Sedona Arizona
Mexico City New Zealand it didn't always
look this way though when starting my
first business bit me maker I was
building in a snowy cold winter in
Toronto Ontario Canada it was a
brick-and mortar business and I had no
ability to travel the world in some
senses I just felt stuck I was
overwhelmed and had no ability to travel
a couple years later I was able to sell
bitmaker to General Assembly and
realized that it was finally time to
double down on freedom having the
ability to travel wherever I want
whenever I want work with whoever I want
on whatever I want as Founders we really
really got into business to have freedom
in life so I'm going to break down the
first system that will help you achieve
this Freedom so you can travel the world
it's all around controlling where you
work now there's two parts of this first
is determining where do you even want to
work and then secondly how do you work
from anywhere it's important that when
you're thinking about where you want to
work that you really hone in on what I
call your location radar all right so
I'm a lot better at showing you than
just telling you so let's into the
location radar on the left side here
I've got and listed how I judge any
location in the world my seven core
criteria are you know how is it for
opportunity Wi-Fi it's got to have
amazing access to Nature I need to have
amazing Founders around me an amazing
community business friendliness and
access to an airport so I can just Jet
Set whenever I want so what I've gone
here is and I've listed five of my
favorite locations you can see here
Sedona Dubai Mexico City dolomites and
Bali but you could put any location
there across The Columns from there you
go and rank each location from 1 to 10
one if it's absolute garbage 10 if it
hits that criteria out of the park for
Sedona as an example opportunity there
probably like a five realistically it's
kind of out in the country Wi-Fi 10
Founders are probably like a three there
but nature is a 10 Community I mean I
like the community there eight business
friendliness we'll give it a six access
to airport like a eight when it comes to
say Mexico City which is actually where
I've recently set up a home base
opportunity give it a nine Wi-Fi 10
access nature is actually pretty damn
solid Founders solid Community amazing
business friendliness love it access to
airport Banger when I go and I tally all
this up we get a score of at a 70 across
these seven criteria of 69 not bad when
we look at Sedona as an example here we
get a score of 50 so pretty good but
somewhere I'd only drop into maybe like
a month of the year when I may be
writing my book I'll go and do this for
each location that I'm considering that
will kind of give a bit of an objective
measure as to where I should be located
in the world this is all good but some
of you may not even know which locations
to even consider let's get on to the
location radar prompt we have a prompt
here that says you an expert at advising
Founders on where to live in the world
to have the most Freedom adventure fun
and success you help people live the
most fulfilling lives possible and get
the most out of life here are mat seven
criteria on where to live in the world
opportunity Wi-Fi nature Founders
community business friendliness and
access to airport come up with 20 of the
best locations in the world for Matt
based on these criteria in two sentences
on what makes it the best rank the
locations from best to worse let's just
see what Mr jet gbt comes up with so
here's my rank list well look at that
number one who would have guessed it
Mexico City Mexico so about the same
ranking as I just found out myself right
thriving hub for found Founders which I
agree with exceptional Wi-Fi hell yeah
welcoming community of creators and
Founders definitely love it for that
reason number two Lisbon Portugal three
three Dubai which was also on the list
four Bali which was on my list five is
Singapore medine Barcelona Austin Cape
Town Vancouver Bangkok Berlin go and
take this location radar GPT prompt
first spin yourself if you're having
troubles of figuring out even where the
hell you travel in the world now you
figured out where you're going to go
work but now you need to figure out how
you can actually get the freedom to work
from anywhere there are business models
that are easy mode and then there are
business models that are hard mode for
traveling the world hard mode business
models are like brick mortar
manufacturing businesses anything that
keeps you stuck in one spot on the other
side businesses like courses digital
products masterminds anything online and
you're good to go a lot of Founders make
the mistake when they're first picking
their business they pick the wrong kind
of business that's not going to be
conducive to being able to travel the
world when I went and built founder OS I
conceived a business that was built
around my calling in life things like
proven systems building communities
helping founders with distribution
helping Founders scale their businesses
and Lifestyles I doubled down on those
things and built it all online for the
community we built it on school for our
newsletter we built it on convert kit
for the sales engine of things we built
it on stripe all of my content is
scheduled via hype Fury we have all the
right Tools in place to run this online
business on autopilot that allow myself
to remove myself from operations and be
able to travel the world and enjoy the
beauty of the sites when I'm in
different
locations now we've talked about where
and how how you can just have the
freedom to go anywhere in the world
let's talk about what to work
on the next system you want to think
about is really being able to focus on
your zone of genius and then
understanding the math to delegation
when you're going and thinking about
traveling you should be making sure that
you are positioned as close to revenue
generating activities as possible
anything that does not fulfill your
hourly rate you should delegate automate
or eliminate you may go and find
yourself going and scheduling a bunch of
content on social media and when you
think about hiring someone for this role
it's about a $7,000 monthly role if
going and hiring that social media
manager saves you 10 hours a week or 40
hours a month it's worth doing this
delegation math to make sense of the ROI
for making that hire we talked about how
much time you're going to save from a
new hire so as just say you're hiring a
social media manager okay and that
person's going to save you 10 hours a
week or 40 hours a month as a CEO and
your hourly rate let's just say is
$2,000 now the cost of a new social
media manager is likely say $7,000 per
month month and your profit margin let's
just say was 80% okay so here we can see
that with the time Save times your
hourly rate we get to 880,000 okay so 40
* 2K $80,000 in revenue generated for
that save time that you've gotten back
because of this higher at a profit
margin of 80% your profit from that
reallocated time now is $644,000 so 64k
minus 7K is 57k you made an 8X Roi on
this hire from hiring a social media
manager Getting Back 40 hours of your
time back every month you get an 8X Roi
assuming you make $2,000 per hour now
you've got the delegation math right and
this is going to allow you to remove
yourself from of your business and build
an Empire of weapons around you have
people like a social media manager a
writer having someone on the tech side
the finance side having a cro to manage
a whole sales team essentially being
able to remove yourself from all the
stuff you hate so all you're left with
are the tasks that you love to do in a
location that develops an amazing amount
of awe every single day this math is
lifechanging because when you get it
right you remove yourself when working
in your business and give yourself the
freedom to work on your business this
makes all the difference because there's
no sense going and traveling somewhere
beautiful like Indonesia when you can't
actually go and enjoy those waterfalls
or traveling the dolomites and just
getting stuck behind a computer instead
of being able to RI down Hills on a
mountain bike now we've gone and got
what to work on let's talk about when to
work when you think about working in any
given location
anywhere in the world what I see people
make the mistake in is when they travel
the world they start to get on all these
different routines while it can look
sexy from the outside on the inside if
you're not able to stick to a consistent
routine no matter where you are in the
world it's going to break you I like to
stick to the same routine no matter
where I am the location may change the
routine stays the same a strong founder
is built on strong systems making sure
that you have a strong daily routine for
when you work when you explore is going
to give you a certain level of stability
no matter where you are in the world now
that we've got where you're going to
work what you're going to work on and
when you're going to work let's talk
about who you're going to work
with strong businesses are built by
weapons weapons are people that you can
bring on your team they're able to go
and Elevate the culture they take
extreme ownership they're down
with a proven track record
the key thing here is to make sure when
you're interviewing people you have the
right hiring process to make sure that
you're being surrounded by a team of
Avengers the truth is to get to $10
million and Beyond a year you need an
amazing closer you need an amazing
operator an amazing designer amazing
Tech person and likely a chief of staff
how do you actually go and find these
people first rule of finding the best
possible people to work with is to go
and ask 30 a players you know if they
know any amazing people for the given
roles you're looking to bring on now
once you've recruited those people in
the interview process you want to make
sure that you're clear on the three
values of your company so for me it's
that they need to have a pro track
record take extreme ownership and be a
down and then I'm going to
have three to four interview questions
that go through each of those three
values so I'm going to ask people you
know would you ever want to be a CEO do
you enjoy taking responsibility tell me
about a time that you dealt with a
difficult situation and how you
spearheaded that what's the moment that
you're most proud of in your life what
are you most embarrassed of what's a
moment where you had to go and take a
project from nothing through to a
million dollars a year in profit I want
to go and dig deep and understand are
they able to actually go and relieve me
of the workload so I can enjoy my time
while I'm traveling the number one thing
that I want to make sure that any
person's doing Beyond helping us get to
10 million a year they're bringing me
peace of mind so I can sleep at night
knowing the business is safe and I can
actually enjoy my life versus being
stressed burnt out and overwhelmed the
next aspect then is making sure you have
them complete a challenge generally
going to be around five questions that
are going to give people a task that I
actually would want from that role over
the next couple months I'm not just
hoping that they pan out when they get
started I'm virtually guaranteed te that
they're an amazing hire so say I'm going
and hiring a cro to go and manage my
sales team I'm going to go and ask this
person in the interview process things
like I want you to come up with your
90-day goals and break down your plan to
go and execute these number two I want
you to go and come up with a sales quota
for the three sales people on my team
and then an incentive structure to go
and make sure they hit 120% of Koda I'm
going to go and make sure this person is
not able to just do the job but excel at
the job I often talk to Founders that
have scaled up their team and before you
know it they've scaled up their own
prison and they are the prisoner they've
built a team of mediocrity people aren't
actually doing their roles it's a big
playground of people screwing around and
they're trying to get the freedom to
travel and just enjoy life but before
you know it they're down depressed and
screwed over the key thing is to make
sure that you're bringing on the right
people and putting them in the right
seats with the right interview process
the right rigor and the right onboarding
when you get these things right you
build a team that is high performing it
has a high IQ high energy High work
ethic and you can accomplish high
standards 15 years ago I promised myself
that when I discovered these four
systems I would share it with as many
Founders as possible this is your chance
you owe it to yourself Implement these
four systems so you can have the most
epic year of your life travel the world
and make more money than you imagined
let's go
[Music]