All right, I'm curious if this video
makes it out there and if there are
other people experiencing similar
things.
As I continue to kind of build
businesses, I think a lot about my not
to do list, right? The things that I'm
just unwilling to trade off.
Things like,
you know,
no meetings on Wednesdays, Thursdays,
and Fridays.
Things like no working with B players.
No,
you know, working late into the
evenings.
No
weekends full of non-stop work.
You know, no working with clients that
um I wouldn't consider
you know, a friend.
And no working
with teammates that cause me more stress
than they do peace of mind.
I think it's important to have these
kind of like not to do lists as you're
building because if you're not strict
about this stuff,
sure enough, you eventually
find yourself one thing after the other
working on things that just are killing
you. So, let me know, what are your
not to do's, right? The things that you
are unwilling to trade off.
I'd love to hear from you.