This is the tech stack for my million a
month business. So, first things first,
my lover, Claude code. So, Claude code
is an absolute beast. I spend a few
hours in this every single day. If
you're going to get going on it, first
step is go and hook up all the
connectors to it. Probably things like
your HubSpot, maybe even tools you're
using like your QuickBooks and things
like that to make sure that HubSpot is
able to speak to Claude code, and then
you're able to run a bunch of cool
automation. So, yeah, next thing is
HubSpot.
It's a CRM that we use. If you're
looking to save money though, you may
use things like close.io. Vercel is what
I use to publish a lot of our web pages
for, so different tools that we make and
such. I'm publishing it to Vercel first,
and then being able to hand off those
Vercel, you know, kind of files to my
engineer if we're going to go and then
actually push them to the founder us.com
website. Superbase is what we use to go
and create a lot of things super fast.
And it end is for a lot of the workflow
automation that we use, so different
tools can interact with other tools.
Fathom, all calls are recorded, and the
cool thing is that Fathom interacts
nicely with Mr. Claude code over here.
And the beautiful thing there is any
call that I'm on with my team, I
instantly go and take the Fathom
recording afterwards, I plug it into
Claude code, and I say, "Go and action
every single thing that we just went
over on that call, and I want you to be
smarter than Jeff Bezos, Elon Musk,
Jensen Huang, Warren Buffett, and
Charlie Munger combined and go and move
this forward. Enter plan mode, go and
get that done. Come up with a plan, I'll
approve it, and then we'll go get those
things going by interacting with these
other tools here." So, call me a little
bit weird, but this is how I operate.
Slack, I mean, kind of self-explanatory,
you know, but you got to make sure that
you have things like scheduled tasks
hooked up from Claude code into Slack to
eliminate all the accountability that
you got to do as a business owner. You
know, nothing's more tiring than having
to remind people, right? And the
beautiful thing is when you've hooked up
Claude code correctly into your Slack,
people are getting those Monday
reminders through Claude as to what they
need to get done that week, and then
it's able to monitor all of the meetings
that happen in Mr. Fathom over here to
make sure that Mr. Claude is making sure
that Mr. HubSpot's happy with the
revenue growth, and making sure that
these folks in Slack are staying super
dialed. On the Calendly side, we're
booking sales calls, closing revenue,
making sure that Mr. HubSpot's happy.
So, that is the tech stack. You know,
we're talking like roughly 2K per month
here, but who's checking if the cash is
flowing, these costs ain't mattering
much, all right?