[music]
Every CEO that I meet is dealing with a
fury of stuff on their plate. You know,
hiring people, firing, making that next
decision, a new tool, you name it. And
it gets exhausting. But here's the deal.
Being a CEO doesn't need to be so hard.
It actually can be pretty simple. And it
really all comes down to three things.
And when you get these things right, you
build a successful company. But when you
get them wrong, you're building a
business that is insanely fragile and
probably going to die. Over the last 17
years, I built four profitable,
successful companies. And I've learned
this three-part framework for going and
being an effective CEO. I'm going to go
and break down this framework in a
private room here of 25 high growth CEOs
helping them go and scale their founder
brands and remove themselves from
operations here in Bali, Indonesia. This
was a private invite only event, but I
figured why not just bring you into the
room with me. Let's get into it.
I talked to a lot of founders and I
think a lot of you guys are looking to
go from kind of chaos to clarity, right?
And go from sort of overwhelmed
operators uh to CEOs. And at the end of
the day, there's really only three
things that a CEO should be worried
about as you scale up. And that's
probably kind of crazy to some of you.
You're like, only three things? I feel
like I'm doing like operations and
content and audience growth and I'm
hiring people and delegating and I got
to fire someone next week. Like what the
hell are you talking about? Three
things. I got like at least 300 on my
plate, Matt. So, what the hell are these
three things I'm speaking about right
now? The three things are numbers,
people,
and culture. Numbers. A lot of time I
talk to founders, they're doing like say
over $200,000 a month. They've hired
someone. They've put another person on a
certain commission. They have, you know,
another person, they've worked this
intricate base salary plus a tiered
system as to what they're getting paid.
And then I'll ask that founder, you
know, so what profit are you doing per
month? And what are you hoping to get to
by the end of 2026? And after kind of
stirring on it and they start blushing a
little bit, they're like, I don't know.
I think that can be a kind of a scary
place to be, honestly. And I say that as
someone that's been in that position
because at the end of the day it's kind
of terrifying building something and
working as hard as a lot of you guys do.
If you know when you look a year from
now you actually don't even know where
you're trying to get to. The second
piece is the people. I know there's a
lot of different kind of niches here and
different business models that you guys
are running. Although there's also a lot
of similarities as well. The reality is
it doesn't matter what business model
you're in and what industry you're in.
You guys are all and so myself included.
We're in the people business right?
We're managing people. We're serving
people. And the better we are at that,
right, in terms of like hiring amazing
people, getting really good at
delegation, getting clear on
expectations and scorecards and
promotions and incentives, the better
that sort of people apparatus of your
company is going to be. And, you know,
the more you're able to tap into like
the full potential of that like team
you've got. A lot of founders I speak
with, they don't really think about this
that much. They don't have a systemized
way of looking at the kind of people
aspect of their business. And sure
enough, when you kind of dig into it a
bit, it becomes pretty obvious that
they're only tapping into their
company's like potential up to like say
30 40%. And there's so much more they
could be doing there if they just
started unlocking different aspects of
it. Proper delegation, proper
incentives, all that good stuff. The
third aspect is the culture. I'm not
talking about like ping pong tables or
random field trips with the team. I'm
talking about like what your values are.
um and how you make sure that the values
are part of like everyday life in terms
of how you reward people in the company,
how you give praise, also how you give
feedback if things are not going well.
Inevitably, your values are kind of the
code of your culture. And if you're not
clear on those, what can happen is as
you scale, you kind of revert to the
mean, meaning your company over time
just becomes kind of mediocre, which is
the default if you don't get this right.
So, we're going to get into numbers,
people, and culture. When I think about
the numbers aspect of a business, the
first hire that I made when I started
founder OS four years ago, talked about
how initially it's called soulful
entrepreneur. This cohort-based course
about 30 people in any given cohort, it
went for 6 weeks. I did two of those,
ended up rebranding it to founder OS,
making it more evergreen, moving it to
school, you know, kept on compounding to
four years later, here we are now. The
first hire that I made at Soulflur way
back then was a guy named Georgie who's
actually the longest running founder OS
employee, he was running all of the
books, all of the accounting, all the
invoicing, all the modeling. What I've
learned from building businesses for
like 15 years is like if you don't get
the finance piece right, you're very
much flying blind. If you're watching
this video, you likely could use a
simple checklist to help you go and
implement all of the core tactics I'm
going through across numbers, people,
and culture. And so what I've gone and
prepared here is a CEO dashboard
checklist for you. All the core things
that I think about when it comes to
cash, profit, my growth engine,
audience, you can go and get all of this
via the link in the description. Just go
enter in your email and I'll go email
this over to you so you've got it and
you can go and implement this with your
team right now. I give you things like
how I hire people, my ownership tests,
and then how I go and establish a high
performance culture across my team,
including how I also go and run all my
meetings. And so you can go and get the
numbers, people, culture checklist via
the link in the description. Go and
download that right now and go and
implement it your team this week. Let's
talk about how I at least I view the
differences between like a bookkeeper
and a fractional CFO for a second, but
then we'll just talk about what you
really need in your business. Okay? So,
a bookkeeper is typically the person
that's doing all like the accounting,
the invoicing, making sure you have like
a profit and loss statement, you have a
balance sheet, all the numbers are
organized, and you're paying people on
time, you know, kind of the cash inflows
and outflows, and everything's like
clean from a financial standpoint. A
fractional CFO oftentimes will work with
your bookkeeper and then take those
numbers and be the kind of person that
can work directly with you to then sort
of discern the implications of these
numbers which is what really matters in
your business. You know you may have
something like you know Michael brought
up seasonality. You may be looking at
say January, February, March of 2026 and
trying to figure out what proper
performance is going to be, what kind of
goals you should be setting so you can
figure out maybe sales bonuses for your
sales team or you can go and project how
many people you want to go and onboard
into your new offer or program. Well,
that's the person that's going to
understand, okay, well, this is what we
did Jan, Feb, March of 2025, what we did
in January, February, March of 2024, and
then be able to give you kind of, okay,
well, this is what we grew
year-over-year last year. what do we
think is realistic to grow
year-over-year in this next quarter, you
know, Q1, and kind of be that sparring
partner with the numbers so that you're
actively making sure that decisions that
you make inside your business are driven
off of like what you've previously done
and that they're basically based in like
sound financial knowledge versus just
kind of like licking your finger to the
wind and going like, I think in Q1 we
can do 500k. It's like you can still
lick your finger to the wind and kind of
like come up with that, but then it's
good to have someone you can kind of
stress test that with and go, "Okay,
yeah, yeah, maybe that's crazy. Last
year we did 300K in that period. The
year before we did 250,000. Let's try to
get to like 375,000,
right? That feels like a nice step up."
And then I can set maybe realistic goals
with my team and build trust with my
team that these numbers are actually
based on a level of realism versus just
some pipe dreams. Regardless though of
whether you have a CFO as the title or
you have a bookkeeper, the main thing
that I think all of you guys should be
looking at, especially as you're scaling
from 30K to 50K a month to 100K a month
to 200K a month, is you want to have
someone that you can have those kinds of
conversations with. You know, when we
think about building a business, right,
there's like a few forms of leverage,
right? You have, you know, your media
around you, which all of us are building
because we're all building founder
brands. You have, you know, your people,
you have your tech, but you also have
your capital. And as you start to get
more cash in bank, it's like you can go
and make certain investments in your
year that will maybe quadruple the cash
in bank or you can make investments that
even cause you to lose money because you
don't think through it right. So it's
kind of making sure that you have that
kind of steward there that's helping you
make really sound proper investments cuz
as you keep scaling I think you're
actually more of an investor than you
are an entrepreneur. And so having that
right partner there to help you make
good investments with your cash flows is
super key. to change your mindset with
this a little bit. When I first got
doing this sort of [\h__\h] like 15 years
ago, it was super intimidating. Despite
going to business school, my eyes glazed
over in accounting classes. I hate that
[\h__\h] I started to kind of look at my
rubric, you know, and the classes I
could go and be part of in uh in
university, you get all these electives.
I was like the as many finance ones as I
could delete out, we deleted those. as
many ones on like leadership, public
speaking, motivating people, whatever.
We added those ones in and kind of got a
little more creative and got out of the
numbers. When I started to have to kind
of get into this aspect of business and
really start to round out my thinking
there cuz I could no longer just elect
to get out of finances, I started to
view it as like you get your own kind of
custom MBA on your own business every
month. So like really trying to learn to
like study your business like enjoy it
as if it's like a course you're going
through on the your own thing you're
building and just become a little
obsessed around just the intricacies of
it and even if you don't understand it a
CFO if you have a good relationship with
them can almost be like this like
professor of your own finances helping
you just gradually get a better and more
intricate understanding and it's just
this constant journey of like every week
just trying to get the financial
infrastructure of your business 10%
stronger collecting cash faster delaying
payables longer, making sure that you're
collecting more cash upfront, less
payment plans, these sorts of things
that just gradually ever so slightly
increase the financial health of your
business. Let's go on the people side of
things where I see a lot of founders
things get a little uh messy, right? Is
they've got like all these people that
start joining their team. They don't
have clear roles set out for them.
There's not a clear onboarding set out.
They don't have clear kind of metrics as
to like what success looks like for this
person every week, every month, every
quarter, every year. And sure enough,
they end up with a team of say 8 to nine
people. It's chaotic. It's all over the
place. And they quickly start looking
around and when they thought someone
would be helping them actually drive
marketing qualified leads, they thought
someone would actually be helping them
close deals, they're still the one
panicking every night that they're not
even sure where their business is going
to grow next week. And a bunch of these
people that they brought on to bring
them peace of mind are sleeping soundly
at night while you're kind of having
night teares. And so I think what's
really important first off with the
people on your team, number one is that
like you're getting clear beforehand on
you know the KPIs for each role. Like
what are the you know say three core
metrics that you're going to use to
judge that person's success. What I like
like to make sure of is like out of
those I generally pick the one thing
that's like actually the most important.
Right? So let's just say I was bringing
on someone for social media. The most
important thing for me would be, okay,
this person is driving us qualified
inbound sales calls. If that person, I
don't care whether they're growing our
Instagram to, you know, 100,000 a month
or 20,000 followers a month, although
that's maybe one of the KPIs is
Instagram growth. The one thing I
actually care about is that they're
setting my sales team up with inbound
calls booked that my sales team can then
close deals. If that's actually
happening, I can sleep at night. We've
got the KPIs. We've got the one thing.
We then need to make sure that their
onboarding is nailed down. Where I see
too many people screw up is that their
onboarding is way too lax. And this idea
that you're bringing on people to your
company to give you peace of mind to go
from overwhelm to clarity, from chaos to
a level of peace. I think my own
approach here is for it to be a bit of
like they're going through kind of an
internal company university. You have
all the core docs inside of your
company, right? Over time, you're
building things like your different
offers. You've got maybe a one-year plan
or strategy of roughly where you're
looking to go. Maybe you've got, you
know, your overall company org chart and
the different kind of people on your
team, what those people are responsible
for, the decisions that they make. You
want to make sure they can kind of get
that lay of the land in the first couple
weeks, be a student of your business,
and kind of get up to speed as to like,
okay, this is what we operate. This is
how things work around here. This is the
different players in the company. These
are our offers. This is the community.
And for many of you that are running
different communities and have actual
courses and programs, they should be
going through those in the first couple
weeks. They should understand your
product and they should understand the
community. you know, for some of the
roles, especially if it's like customer
success, marketing, sales, and by
default, even just anyone should even
just get on a few calls with customers,
introduce themselves, get to know them a
little bit just to develop like a a bit
of an awareness as to like who these
people actually are cuz at the end of
the day, it doesn't matter what role
they're in in the company, they're there
to serve your core customer. And amidst
like the day and age we live in where
things are changing faster than ever, AI
is taking over all this kind of [\h__\h]
The one thing that will be true today
that'll be true in 10 years and 50 years
and 100 years is that you'll always win
if your customers obsessed. Preferences
are always going to change. But they're
always going to want things like speed,
convenience, quality, and if your team
can all be obsessed with just
understanding these people's needs,
their wants, their desires, their
dreams, their fears, all things
considered, you know, you're going to be
okay. On the onboarding side, I think
you then want to nail things like your
meeting rhythms with these people. So
depending on the department, meeting
rhythms may be a bit different. An
example meeting rhythm on a sales team
would be three sales meetings a week,
Monday, Wednesday, Friday, going over
wins, going over projections, covering
any issues that they're currently
encountering, running through different
objections that they're having troubles
getting over, and making sure they're
properly coached. On your creative or
content team, you're probably having a
weekly session with them covering kind
of what's working, what's not working,
and what needs to improve. On your
leadership team, you're probably having
a Tuesday meeting each week primarily
focused around, okay, how are metrics
doing? Are there any issues or
opportunities that come up? And then
let's solve those things. If you're
looking for just a meeting structure, no
matter what, just that's like the
simplest meeting structure for any of
these department meetings, whether it's
a leadership meeting all the way through
to a marketing meeting or a sales
meeting. The way to structure a meeting,
one hour. Start with wins. So, it starts
off with good vibes and kind of getting
people all jazzed up. Then start getting
into the metrics, reviewing how that
department or the leadership team's
metrics have been doing. And you cover
that for 5 to 10 minutes. Primarily
focused on the metrics that are broken.
So, something's off track, you want to
kind of name it and then work through
that in the remainder of the meeting.
Let's just say we were expecting to get
a certain amount of marketing qualified
leads or sales calls in a given week and
I'm on that leadership meeting and we're
off the mark by 40%. We want to note
that and then in the remaining basically
45 minutes of that meeting we want to
identify, okay, that's an issue. Is
there any other issues we're currently
dealing with? Everyone just goes and
names all the issues, then go and rank
the issues. What's the most important
[\h__\h] we should deal with here? All
right. Yeah, that qualified leads thing.
That's a big [\h__\h] issue. Let's do
that number one. All right. What else?
All right. Let's move this one number
two. So quickly rank them so that you
deal with the most important thing first
and go work down the list. And then for
the remaining 40 minutes of that
meeting, you're just knocking down those
issues one by one, developing solutions
as a team and then to-do list for
people. Ideally documenting that to-do
list and then each week just kind of
keeping that rhythm going, making sure
that every week the things that people
commit to are complete. And then the
next week, same deal. reviewing wins,
reviewing metrics, what are the issues,
opportunities, working through those as
a team, creating a to-do list, next
week, did you get all the things done?
You just keep repeating that. So that
becomes an overall company meeting
rhythm for the overall leadership team.
And then you would have that for sales,
for marketing, for content, for finance.
That meeting rhythm is like going to
allow you to avoid 80% of the issues
from just having a simple check-in like
that across the team. So then you know
on the people side too some things to
think about over time also are like
incentives. Humans are incentive
machines. So just thinking over time
what are you trying to get to as a
company? Let's just say one of your main
goals is like we want to hit 500k profit
a month or 200k cash collected. Maybe
there's different bonuses or incentives
you can create on the team for when you
hit those core metrics. Or maybe you
want your customer success team to get
to eight trust pilot reviews in a month.
Or maybe you want your sales team to get
to an individual basis, each closer to
get to 170k cash collected a month. Now
that you have an understanding of your
numbers, can you be using that now
financial awareness to go and be able to
confidently go and incentivize people
and feel confident that like, okay,
yeah, you're going to make your $80,000
a year base, but you know, on a
quarterly basis, if we cross this
threshold, I'll give you $10,000 every
quarter. So starting to create these
like aligned incentives across the
business that when you win the people
win as well. So the culture side when I
was running Herb in like 2015
it was about uh a year and a half um
after starting running things I had gone
through a pretty massive hiring spree.
Had hired in the previous year let's
just say 20 people. I was around 25
years old. We had scaled the team up.
Companies were raising like crazy.
Canopy Growth had just crossed a billion
valuation. Aurora and some other large
companies had just crossed, you know,
billions. They were going to look to
market with us at like, you know, a $3
million contract that was about to
close, a $2 million contract that was
about to close. The Canadian market on
October 5th of that year went and
legalized and everything kind of went
downhill after Canadian legalization.
Instead of the market just blowing up,
it actually didn't end up being as big
as people had thought and it didn't
actually become that big of a thing. And
so the whole industry just started
cratering. The contracts that I thought
were coming in for five million bucks
evaporated. And here I was with like 20
people too many in the office. Not to
mention too when I looked over like the
previous four months of even building
this thing, I could feel the kind of
pressure building. I knew things were
getting kind of dicey. And when I would
go to the team and when I looked over
like to the left or to the right when I
was in meetings, these people were
[\h__\h] oblivious. And not because, you
know, I was definitely talking and
saying, "Hey, we got to figure some
stuff out here." But they did not embody
like a level of extreme ownership. They
didn't actually care. I thought because
they were chill good people that they'd
make a good team member. And I didn't
really care too much about this. Often
times in a first interview, if someone
like seemed really cool and, you know,
seemed legit and like a person I would
hang out with, they were on. And I
wasn't that strict with hiring and I
wasn't that firm in terms of like my
real values. I actually didn't even take
that much time to think about the values
that I had. that ended up being
surrounded by a bunch of strangers in
these dark moments versus being
surrounded by a bunch of [\h__\h]
warriors that could get through these
kinds of moments. And so the only thing
that I was left to do once it became
this kind of dark month of October 10
years ago was one by one to go and fire
20 people one after the other that day.
And it was probably at that point in my
life like the hardest professional thing
um I had to go through. That moment left
some insane scars that I'm grateful for.
And it taught me the importance of
really being strict um with the kind of
culture and company you're looking to
build. And so your culture is
essentially just like the code of how
you operate. More simply, it's like what
you're going to tolerate in your
company. And I think when you get this
right, the goal that I always have in
any company I'm building is that the
culture self self-governs itself. If
someone comes on the team and they
didn't embody the kind of cultural vibe
that we all have, the values that we
have, it wouldn't even take me pointing
out that that person's not a fit. We
would almost like cut them out as a
company pretty quick and go like, hey,
like that guy over there, like that's
not going to work. And ideally, again,
the culture can kind of self-govern. I
could be taking a few weeks off and
there's some hires being made and I
could trust that my team's going to go
and find people that embody those values
and bring them on versus bringing on
people that you know are subpar. One
thing on this that uh has inspired me is
uh Mark Benoff in the book like into the
cloud talks about uh one of the big
breakthroughs he had when he was
building Salesforce was he created a
little card almost like the size of a
business card. It had the company's
mission. It had their five core values
and what we do. It was just that and it
was on a card. He printed it off, gave
it to every single person in his
company. I think that a core part of you
know your values is first off like you
got to write these things down. So even
at Founder OS like as part of the
onboarding we have a Founder OS
onepager. It has our internal mission,
our external mission, our vision, it has
our values. Everyone goes through this
as part of the onboarding. Now the
question then becomes okay well how do
we kind of make it compelling? I think
there's like two ways to make things
compelling. There's like really make it
motivating to do the things and then
make it like hurt to not do the things
or whatever other word pain or whatever
there. So on the good side it's like
which is most of the time right there's
people doing a lot of good things in
your company all the time. You got to
kind of slow down for a second, I think,
as the founder and CEO. And when you
give praise to someone or you talk about
something you're proud of in the
company, relate it to a core value and
bring it back to the mission. This is
going to feel [\h__\h] weird to start
off, right? Cuz it's like, oh my god, I
just want to say so and so did a good
job and now I'm saying, hey, really love
the fact that you cook it insanely
simple today. like this is just like
made given me so much peace of mind the
level of like complexity you've
eliminated and for just kind of like
dumbing things down so that we could all
understand it. I appreciate it. It's
like it's maybe it feels more
long-winded. Maybe it feels a little bit
mechanical to say it like that. But the
thing is like when you say it like that,
number one, you're embodying that and
being a role model of the values that
you've set. Number two is that obviously
there's a lot of people on your team
that are like they want praise, right?
Everybody wants to feel like what
they're doing is contributing to the
broader mission of the company. And they
also just want to make sure that you're
taking care of as the founder. They're
probably that's probably part part of
the reason why they work with you,
right? Is that they care about you.
Whether it's the person you're actually
giving praise to or the others that are
witnessing that praise, whether it's in
Slack or in a meeting, everyone else is
picking up on that signal you're
setting. And if you're saying, "Hey,
this was really good because it was
insanely simple." Then everyone's
thinking, "Oh, Matt values things that
are insanely simple." Or if I'm going
and saying, "Hey, you know, I really
love the fact that like that was a
pretty big problem, but I appreciate you
bringing a solution to it." They're
going to think, "Oh, Matt really values
bringing solutions, not just problems."
Or if I'm like, "Man, I really love the
fact that you went the distance with
that video. Those animations were
[\h__\h] insane. Such like elevated
design, and I can tell you really went
the distance." And like, "Did you spend
tonight working on that?" Like, "Yeah,
yeah." It's like, man, the obsession
around quality is like nuts there. Well,
what do people think that Matt values?
Elevated design and obsessing over
quality, right? which all the four
things I just mentioned are the values
of founder OS. And so it's taking a
second to wrap the praise that you give
people as an example around the values.
So people start to kind of hear this
constantly. They start to know that
that's what you value as a leader. They
understand that that's what the culture
values and sure enough like everyone
starts kind of embodying those things
because that's kind of like how we do
things. Now, the other side to that too
is like maybe you've had to let someone
go or just on a more chill basis like
there's some feedback that needs to be
given. Same way that you'd wrap praise
around a value, you should also wrap
feedback around some values, right? So,
hey, like one big thing we're big on
here is bringing solutions, not
problems. It's all good. You're new.
You're just getting to know the company
here, but that said, you've just brought
up a whack of problems. I need you to
make this way more simple. So, what's
the solution here? and like they're
starting to see, okay, [\h__\h] I shouldn't
just bring problems to this guy. I have
to bring solutions by constantly kind of
sometimes repeating yourself there. I've
heard Evan Spiegel, the founder of
Snapchat, state this in a good way. He's
like, your job as the CEO is actually
the chief context officer. Constantly
giving people context as to like how you
operate because people by nature aren't
going to know that, right? Because often
times your company values are unique
like a personality and people aren't yet
used to the personality of your team. So
you have to educate them on that
personality so that they gradually start
to understand it. Ideally, you're also
testing them in the interview process
around these values. So the interview
process, you're really looking for like
three things. Proven track record,
alignment around your values, and that
they embody the competencies you need
for that role. Proven track record,
alignment around the values, and the
competencies that you're looking for in
the role. like you're going to try and
kind of test people on these things to
make sure that you're bringing on people
that innately have a similar DNA to what
you're looking to build your company off
of. Appreciate it. And uh we'll just
keep uh keep rocking here. Cool. Thanks,
guys.