somewhere along the way, I think in
entrepreneurship, so many folks have
just been led astray, right? Running
bloated teams, you know, getting lost in
a web of confusion, overwhelm, night
after night, wondering like, "What the
hell am I even doing? How did my
business end up like this?" No, I'm just
here to say like, there's definitely a
better way because I was just like that.
I'll be honest like even these days, I
find at some points, you know, I think
it's kind of the default state of where
your business is always by nature kind
of pulling itself, right? It's kind of
pulling itself to chaos, pulling itself
to entropy, right? And you constantly
have to kind of be conscious of that to
make sure that it stays on the path
that's kind of like your true north.
True north for people, I think, that are
as part of this channel, right? Is, you
know, a business um that's systematized
is a small lean team of weapons, a
business that actually fires you up, is,
you know, working with customers you
actually love, and saying no to ones
that are not a good fit. I think true
north is being able to charge proper
prices so you can have healthy margins
and be able to also build a brand and
build like, you know, your business as
this kind of work of art. And true
north, I think, is being able to build
amazing content around your business so
that leads are coming organically. Um
you don't need to go and get on some ads
treadmill. Um you don't need to just
rely on referrals or wonder where your
next leads are coming from. You know,
you've got a powerful organic social
media machine, owning your distribution,
so that you really control your destiny
as a founder.