What if I told you that chatbt can 10x
your output with four simple systems?
Sam Alman, the CEO of OpenAI, said the
first billion dollar solo business is
coming and it's going to be powered by
AI. We're living through the David
versus Goliath moment of our generation
where one person with AI can do far more
than 50, 100, or even 500 people. So
today, I want to show you four ChatB
systems that you can go and leverage to
make real money in the new era of AI.
Let's get into it. System number one,
use ChatGBT pulse as your trillion
dollar coach. This is ChatGBT Pulse.
What it's essentially doing is it's able
to go and be fed specific projects from
within my Chat GBT Pro account and then
every single day I basically get a
custom newsletter and report with
multiple things that are going to go and
help me accelerate my path to progress.
Now, let me go and show you how I
actually go and configure ChatGBT pulse
so that it's feeding me these ideas
every morning and I'm able to
incorporate these into my daily
deepwork. Here is my chat GBT desktop
app. You can see I've gone and set up
this project called PennX Profits.
Inside of the instructions, which is
essentially the prompt for this project,
you can see I've gone and prompted it
with the following prompt, which you can
go and get via the link in the
description. I've created a chat GBT
prompt and template for you. Go and get
that right now. The prompt is
essentially, "You are the world's best
business coach and growth strategist
hired by Matt Gray to scale Founder O
from $500,000 profit to $2 million
profit per month. You advise the
greatest entrepreneurs in the world like
Larry Ellison, Elon Musk, and Jeff
Bezos, and are a 10x better coach than
Bill Campbell, the trillion dollar
coach." You don't know who Bill Campbell
is? He's the legendary coach that
coached folks like Steve Jobs, Jeff
Bezos, and the Google founders. It gets
into then you have deep expertise in
things like system design, financial
strategy, team architecture, AI
leverage, audience growth, high ticket
coaching and consulting models, organic
content, compounding, and clarity. The
objective here then is to go and design
and continuously refine a road map
that's going to increase the founder
profits by 5x in the next 12 months.
You're going to give Matt the exact
playbook to scale revenue, expand
margins, and simplify operations without
adding any more chaos. What I can then
do is then go and upload some of the
core documents that we have here at
Founder OS for each business. This is
going to be different, okay? But what I
can show you are some of the core
documents that I think that you should
probably go and replicate for your
business and then go and feed to your
own 10x profit project. Let me give you
a sense of those right now. Inside my
kind of company systems wiki, we have
things like our brand positioning. The
founder's brand positioning goes and
details out our core thesis on the fact
that we think that the future of online
businesses will be built by founders
with personal brands and that to build a
personal brand, you need to be beautiful
and systemized. And that the best way to
do this is with a content GPS system,
which is what we specialize in inside of
Founder OS. All right, so you're
probably wondering, how do you go and
set up a Chat GBT project? And then how
do you actually go and hook that into
Pulse? You simply just go in your pro
account, go to new project, and give it
a name. So in this case, we're making it
10x profits. And so what you're then
going to do is go and give it the chat
GBT 10X template, which I put via the
link in the description. Add that to the
project instructions. And then you're
going to go and just add a bunch of
files to it. In this case, what I
typically do is on my desktop, um I have
a folder called prompts. Inside of that
folder, I have one called 10x profit and
it has all the core uh folders and
documents um that I want to go and
upload to this project. So boom, they're
all in there. My customer avatar, my
offer docs, um you know, all the core
systems to found are all given to this
so that it has an abundance of context
to work its magic. And now you probably
want to go and hook this up to pulse.
And chatbt pulse is only available on
your mobile device. And I think you have
to have a pro account as well for
chatbt. Inside of this, you simply go to
pulse. You'll see um that you can go and
configure it, which is pretty cool. You
can curate the knowledge. Right now, I
have mine focused on helping me scale
profit systems and leadership. um it can
see that you know I've mentioned that I
want to 10x my profit stepping away from
operations and really develop more
transformational leadership and make
sure that everything I'm doing is
connected to systems AI automation and
building a high leveraged team for
growth. It's saying well hey is there
anything I missed? I can go and put in
here well you know one goal I'm working
on is scaling um our YouTube to 1
million subscribers by the end of Q1.
give me tactics and scalable playbooks
for that as well. Now, what's happening
is it's also getting fed that goal of
mine to make sure that that's being
incorporated into the kind of
recommendations it gives me on a daily
basis. So, here you can see it says,
"Got it. I've noted your goal of hitting
a million YouTube subscribers by the end
of Q1 and your interest in tactics and
scalable playbooks to get there. Thanks
for sharing that direction." It also
will show you the history of the
different sort of recommendations it's
given you and you know oftentimes you
know I'm using these to kind of go and
design different parts of my
organization. So here you can see things
like org design and delegation ladders
SOP systems cadence and automations new
metrics basically um that I could be
tracking as the CEO of the company to
make sure that over the next 30 60 90
days I am driving at an aggressive pace
towards my goals. System number two, use
ChatB to help you reach your 10-year
goals in 6 months. You know, every
single month I have something called the
personal board meeting, which is
something I do with myself to go and
basically understand my 30-day business
goals, my personal goals, and how these
ladder up to my 1 year, threeyear, and
10-year vision for where I'm both trying
to take my personal life as well as my
businesses. All right. So, what we have
here is my board meeting for November
2025. Okay. Inside of this board
meeting, I've gone and taken some time
to unplug. I take about a couple hours
to go and think about my personal 30-day
goals. Things like lifting every single
week, doing yoga three times a week
while I'm here in Ubud, Bali, you know,
being able to meditate, hiring a 10x
engineer, and finishing a life design
for myself. On the business side, the
goal is to get founder OS to a million
dollars of monthly cash collected.
There's some core things we need to do.
We need to hire a 10x engineer. I need
to get my book finished up and
published. We need to get a dashboard
completely upgraded to go and integrate
all the different departments that we
have. You know, we've got something
we've been working on for a couple years
now. But like most things, it's a game
of constant iteration. Inside of this as
well, I then go and synthesize my
founder vision, right? Over the next 90
days, 1 year, and then how that gets us
to where we're looking to go over the
next 3 years and 10 year. Now from here
what I can go and do is go to file
download all this put it into a PDF form
and then go to that 10x profit project I
had made and simply go and upload and
put it inside. What I'm able to go and
do is go and prompt catcht all right you
have my November board meeting inside of
the project files. I want you to go and
look at that whole document and then go
and synthesize the top 20 projects
ranked from best and most important to
the ones that's least important that I
should be focused on to finish 2025
strong. My goal here in the remainder of
2025 is to get more done than most
people get done in 10 years and compress
time into just a few months. We can then
go and let Chat GBT go and analyze the
board meeting as well as the 25 other
core project files that I've given it.
So, I've uploaded that 2025 personal
board meeting. And then the beautiful
thing here is it's taking that board
meeting as well as all the other core
documents that I have here inside of
this project, and it's able to
synthesize that to let me know, you
know, the core projects that I should be
most focused on. What this is allowing
me to do is simply go and spend my time
most focused on getting my vision clear.
And then as long as I'm prompting the
right sort of project with enough
context, um, I can use it to then help
set priorities not just for me, but for
my whole team. System number three, the
revenue to content flywheel. This is how
I use AI to turn customer purchases into
an endless stream of high converting
content ideas. Right here, I have a full
doc that is all of our paid full deals
over the last month. We've gone and
simply pulled these transcripts from
Fathom AI, gone and copied these into a
Google doc. I can then go and download
this doc and upload it to a voice of
customer project that I've created
inside of chatbt. This voice of customer
doc has a project instruction to it that
says you know to transform real customer
language from surveys, interviews and
testimonials into high converting
marketing copy for all the found offers
for found velocity our mastermind offer
as well as found program. It's going to
essentially be this customer language
analyst and go and be a copy strategist
helping synthesize the best stuff from
core responses we've gotten from
customers and then use that to extract
our voice of customer. From there I can
use it to create things like headlines
for my website, CTA lines for different
calls or workshops, email subject lines
as well as social and video hooks for
platforms like Instagram and on X. I
take this whole instruction here and
then I can also go and add different
survey responses. So over here I have a
type form survey that I went and sent
every single customer inside of founder
OS. All our founders helped by filling
out this survey and in this I asked them
things like what has been your most
valuable learning or insight from
founder OS? What additional resources,
features or support would make your
founder journey even more valuable? you
know what's your current business
challenge and if solved would create the
biggest impact on your revenue and
profitability and then I can simply go
to the results here and then go to
download get these all into a CSV file
by simply going and downloading it over
there. So this gets downloaded to my
desktop added all of these different
files. Now from there as you can see
here I can go and ask it go and give me
the top 10 founder challenges that my
audience experiences people are most
willing to pay for. What you can see
here is it's synthesized these into
these core challenges based on the
analysis from that survey data. What I
can do here then is tap into those
emotions using my actual customer
language to go and evolve the overall
copy infrastructure behind founder OS
and make sure that we're attracting
these kind of dream customers by using
their words. System number four, how to
persuade anyone with AI. Let me go and
show you how I tool this up. So first
off, you likely want to have an org
chart for your company. This is what my
org chart looks like right now. We've
got, you know, a legendary team across
finance, sales, founder, success,
distribution, video, and tech. What I go
and do is typically have it both in this
visual form so I can see the general
structure of the team, but I also like
to go and put it into a Google sheet.
This Google sheet has every single
function throughout the company. It has
each person as well as their core
metric, incentive, and responsibilities.
Now, what you can do is actually go and
get this sheet, which I've given you via
the link in the description in the 10X
playbook. What we're doing here
essentially is going and uploading the
org chart to the 10X profit project.
We've gone and taken it from my desktop.
We've added it into the different
projects that we're going to use that
for. And then what I'm going to go and
ask you to do is go create a Excel
document that has each function in my
company, every single owner of that
given function, their core goal, um, and
make it one goal, and then the one core
incentive that we're going to put in
place when they achieve that goal by the
end of Q1. What I've got here is I've
gone and uploaded that org chart to this
project. Okay. And then what it's going
to do is go and synthesize the core
team. So it's going to ask me, okay,
what exactly do you want for this? And I
confirm that I do want the columns of
function name, ro title, the core goal,
core metric, incentive, and their direct
manager. Okay, what you can see here is
now we can go and download this whole
Excel sheet and this is the V1 of this
whole sort of team incentive model. What
I would then go and do is take all of
this, copy it, and then bring this over
to this org chart inside of Google
Sheets. So here we have it. I've gone
and simply taken every single person in
the company and then gone and tied in a
core metric I want to see from them and
then an incentive structure that if they
hit those goals um they will be given
the bonus. So essentially just what
you're doing is trying to just aim every
single person in your company at a core
goal that helps move your mission
forward and ensure they're incentivized
and aligned with the company's success.
So depending on where you're at right
now, there are two potential paths for
you. If you're just getting started, you
can go down to the first link in the
description, get my 10X Chat GBT
playbook, and go and start implementing
the different prompts and templates in
your life today. If you're a founder and
you're looking to really level up and
start to go and accelerate the growth of
your business, you can go check out the
second link below and go and get on a
15minute systems audit with my team.
Thanks so much for watching this video.
I appreciate you being a part of the
founder freedom movement. Be sure to
like and subscribe and go and watch this
next video on how to go and get ahead of
99% of people with AI.