I generated $1.7 million from a single
workshop that took me two hours to
create. And in this video, I'm going to
give you the indepth systems, slides,
and scripts that I use to construct a
workshop in just a matter of a couple
hours. And I do this without coming
across as salesy. The workshop that I'm
about to show you converted over 23% of
attendees to high ticket clients.
Candidly, I've never shared this
publicly before. So, let's get into it.
So this is how to create a killer
workshop that converts. The perfect
workshop formula consists of first off a
storydriven hook. Secondly, valuepacked
content, third, a strategic pitch, a
follow-up sequence, an automation
system. Okay? And so we need to nail
those five parts to really make sure
that you have the right workshop system,
and you can go and implement this for
yourself. And so your first five minutes
are everything. You want to make sure
that you have an amazing title of your
workshop that captures people from
social. And so how things work on my
side is that one week of the month, we
do a 7-day countdown that leads up to
this workshop. And so we're promoting
that across my Instagram, across X and
LinkedIn, driving people to a workshop
link at founder
OS.com/workshop and getting people to
register. Now, the cool thing is there's
a bit of a growth hack going on there
that when they register to the workshop,
they also get piped in to my email list
in HubSpot. So, I'm both getting
workshop attendees and email list
subscribers that I can market to for the
next decade. So, it's a real big hack
that way. In addition to that, beyond
the pattern interrupt, right? So, you
want to start with an amazing story when
you get going here. Okay. From there,
you're going to really address a big
pain point that your audience has. And
I'm going to show you an example here in
a minute from my own workshop. You're
again going to paint the dream outcome
for people and then create an aha
moment, right? You want to make sure
that people are instantly captured. Very
similar to how on YouTube, your first 30
seconds are imperative to your success.
Well, the same thing goes for a
workshop. I do a freaking really high
impact story that really gets people
hyped. And then we move at a solid clip
going through value. I tell them to get
their pen and paper out so they're ready
to go. and we just drop knowledge. My
goal in these things is basically to
have an insane value per second so
people are like, "Wow, I am so grateful
I showed up to this." I always want to
make sure too that I'm competing on
generosity. And so we give people some
free resources at the end of the
workshop that rewards them for sticking
around. And I'll show you here exactly
those free resources so you can go and
copy them for yourself. I simply use
notion and me and my team will go and
cook up some cool template that we think
would be really useful to people. So
right here you can see our 90-day growth
checklist. This 90-day checklist goes
and contains the 90-day action plan that
I think people need to go and implement
if they want to go and scale their
audience themselves without my help. So
I'm just again trying to be generous,
help people out, giving them a resource
that I know will provide insane value to
them. And inside of this resource, we're
giving people a checklist week by week
of what they need to accomplish to go
and start developing warm leads from
their organic content. And so I'm just
overd delivering on the promise of the
workshop to make sure again that people
are fired up, they feel the generosity,
they feel the energy, and they are
motivated to take action. Because
whether or not founders work with me, I
just want to make sure that founders
have the tools that they need um to make
a massive impact in their company, in
their community, with their team. um and
achieve their visions, right? This is
what fires me up. That's candidly why I
get out of bed every single day. So, you
want to get those first four to five
slides of your workshop and those first
five minutes dialed in. Practice makes
perfect. So, make sure that when you
show up to the workshop, you know,
you're not just winging it. Practicing
your workshop a few times also going to
help you nail things. So, when it comes
to the content delivery, there are
really three core secrets that I like to
go give people. You can't give everyone
in like an hour or a 90minute workshop.
So you got to choose your most frothy
systems, right? So I'll choose things
maybe like helping people build their
personal media company, helping them
with their content waterfall system, and
then also learn the content GPS to
convert people from their organic
audience to paying high ticket clients.
So that's the kind of systems that all
go drop. You want to go think about what
are your most powerful systems,
playbooks, tips, tricks, whatever that
you can give people so that regardless
of whether they buy for you or not,
you're creating an insane amount of
goodwill. Again, compete on generosity.
Give people the behind the scenes,
right? Show them how it all works. When
I go and I show up to these workshops, I
go and think to myself, you know, how
can I just be as generous as possible
for people going and being a part of
this movement that I'm creating across
social? you know, I'm really just
putting myself in this vibe, this energy
of extreme generosity. You know, my
belief is that there's so much noise out
there online. And when you can go and
really connect with people's hearts,
when you can show up in a way that they
can feel the love, right, it creates a
massive impact. And when I go and look
at surveys of why people decided to join
Founder OS, about 62% of people say that
it was my energy, my vibe was the reason
that they converted because they felt
that they could trust me. they could
relate to me. As much as I'm about to
show you all the systems behind these
workshops, I don't want you to lose
track of the fact that your energy, your
own vibe, your founder energy, right? It
matters. And when you can really lean
into you and your uniqueness, your edge,
I think that is ultimately your
superpower. From there, you want to make
sure that people also get concrete
action steps. And I'm going to show you
how I think about concrete action steps
throughout this video so you can go and
implement this stuff. Give them wins
that they can implement today. Cuz if we
can help the attendees feel momentum
now, they're going to trust that
whatever is behind, you know, the paid
service or product that you're selling,
it must be indicative of the same value
that you're dropping on the workshop.
And so when it comes to then the perfect
pitch framework, you want to have value
plus a solution plus a bridge plus an
offer. You want to make sure that you're
not only delivering a high-v value
workshop, but that you have an insane
follow-up machine after. Because around
60% of your sales are going to happen
after the workshop, not even on it.
Okay? Because people will go and look at
those follow-up emails, and then they're
going to pull the trigger, go to your
CTA link, and then actually book a call
with your team or convert directly
depending on how you're doing it in your
business. I like to go and give them the
immediate replay the next day. 24 hours
later, I give them all the bonuses that
I'd shared, right? From there, 48 hours
later, I'm sharing different case
studies. Okay? And then we're giving
them a final offer within 72 hours. So,
what's happening is is that they're
getting an email right after, right,
thanking them for showing up, an email
the next day, giving them the replay and
a bonus. The next day after that,
they're getting a case study. And then
the final day, which is about 3 days
after the workshop, they're getting a
last, best, and final offer. that you're
essentially going and taking all the
attendees that you had for your workshop
and driving as many of them to hot leads
and paying customers of your company,
but doing it in a way that's leading
with generosity, leading with just a
good energy to help again build this
good vibe and goodwill with your
audience. You know, I look at a lot of
founders and they're building things
with cold ads and they're coming across
as salesy. And while that may cause a
quick spike in sales, it it's not how
you build a brand. I set out to build
Founder OS because I wanted to build
something that was like what Apple did
for creatives in the 70s, what Nike has
done for athletes in the 80s. I'm trying
to do with founders in the 20s. Creating
a brand that's aspirational and I'm
looking to build this for the next 70
years, not the next 7 months. So for me,
brand is everything, right? And the
goodwill and the relationships we have
with founders is everything. If you
really subscribe to this approach, I
think you're going to love the way that
we deliver workshops and using this for
your own product or service. Because the
key thing here, right, is that once you
build out this workshop, it can go and
be something that you use month after
month. What I generally advise founders
to do is, you know, create a workshop
you're really proud of and then go and
each month change the title of it and
maybe change the initial story you have,
but you can keep the same value there
for a second. So, some founders will
ask, you know, so I've done this
workshop once or twice. I'm just gonna
now record this and have an auto
webinar, an auto workshop running. I
don't advise that. You know, I've been
running workshops live for two years. No
recordings of it, right? No auto
webinars. I just deliver live value.
Now, I know this is a bit controversial,
but the truth is I think even if you're
going to go and record your workshop
eventually, you should wait until you
have perfected that stuff. I like to go
and think of at least committing to six
months of delivering these workshops
once per month to your audience so you
can really refine it. Get comfortable
with it, make tweaks to it because the
truth is that each time you're probably
going to make your workshop at least 30%
better. Put in those reps, right?
Because good things happen when you just
keep at it versus trying to get some
quick, you know, buck or just a quick
shortcut. Um, and you know, I think
quality really matters. Once you start
going right, you want to go and start
putting your workshop on autopilot. So,
you're going to have a registration page
like the one I'll show you. We have ours
at
founderwest.com/workshop. In addition
there, you're going to have email
sequences gone and built out so that
you're promoting the workshop leading up
to it. These are the exact workshop
templates that I use to drive people to
the workshop and attend live prior. And
then also the workshop series that I
send to people after. I'm going to give
you the templates and some examples that
we actually used over the course of the
last couple years. So, here I'm going to
give you something that's probably worth
like $10,000. Here you can see
pre-workshop email number one. You can
see right when people register, we're
going and thanking them for joining,
letting them know they can share this on
X or on Twitter, which creates this
flywheel so they're telling more of
their friends that they joined and
thereby more of their friends now
joined. And these kind of viral loops
are something that we're very big on
teaching and giving founders inside of
Founder OS. We're letting them know that
when they attend live, there is a
special surprise giveaway that we're
giving them, so they're not going to
want to miss it. From there, we have a
number of other pre-workshop emails that
go and really get them bought in. We're
helping them understand the different
pain points that people have and the
things that we're going to be delivering
in terms of the value on the workshop.
again building this hype, making sure
that they've got their calendar marked
because we are about to drop some
knowledge. Now, inside of this as well,
workshop email number three, we're
showing them different testimonials from
our community, what people have been
saying about the workshops and about
Founder OS to really get them hyped so
that they're already coming in the right
frame of mind. They got their pen, their
paper, they're excited, they're ready to
go, and they're not just showing up
there kind of like, "What the heck is
this? What do you even do?" No, they
should already be in the right frame of
mind before they even join the workshop.
So then the pre-workshop email number
four is letting them know, hey, 3 hours,
we're going live here. So let's buckle
up, get ready, we're about to make this
thing happen. Then you're sending them
likely an email 1 hour before, maybe
even one 30 minutes before. It depends
on how you want to do things. But this
is just again making sure that people do
not miss it because you've put in all
this work. You've marketed this thing
across social. We need to make sure that
people are now actually showing up
because the main goal here is live
attendees. And so you can just go and
what I'd recommend is taking these
templates but then making them your own.
Okay? So these serve as a good
structure. Uh but again everything that
you send people especially when it comes
to marketing for me it's about coming
across as non-salesy using stories using
your vibe using the way that you speak
to convey your energy to your audience.
I think that's really what separates
great founders from just all right
founders. You can go and get all these
templates via the link below. And if you
want me or my team to help you go and
implement this system for you in your
business, well then go and book a call
because we'd love to chat with you.
It'll either be me or someone on my team
to go and learn more about what you've
got going on and help you get onboarded
to Founder O so we can go and make an
impact in your business. So you're
getting as much people that have signed
up aware that this is going on and
encouraging them to come live to the
workshop. And that's key. You don't just
want people going and sticking around to
get a replay. You want to encourage
people to come live because when they're
live, they're there. They're in the
energy. They get the free bonuses that
you share on the live to the live people
and they're able to ask questions. And I
think there's just a bigger sort of
conversion rate, candidly, when people
actually attend it live versus watching
it on their own, maybe skipping through
it or getting distracted in the
recording. And so live attendees is
everything. Those are your highest
converting folks. In addition to that,
you want to make sure you have a simple
text stack set up, and I'll show you
mine here in a second. When it comes to
the tech stack, too many people over
complicate things. I at first thought
you needed to use insane tools like
webinar jam and all this crazy stuff to
go and deliver these workshops. That's
actually not the case. On the delivery
side, I just use Zoom and I keep it
super simple. In terms of the emails, we
use HubSpot, but you can use whatever
email service provider that you use. On
the design side, we use Figma. And then
on the checkout side, we use Stripe.
Okay? So, just keeping it all super
simple. And then each of the workshops,
we give away a free system. And how this
works is when someone goes and joins the
workshop, I let them know, hey, at the
end of this hour, I'm going to go and
give those of you that stick around a
free system that me and the team have
spent a couple hours going and creating
that encourages people then to stick
around for the whole bit of value,
including the offer made at the end so
that they learn from me, they're
engaged, and then they get this free
system at the end that blows their mind.
It really shows them the amount of
generosity that we have and how willing
I am to show up to founders and really
help them. And then make sure that
you're utilizing your entire content
waterfall. For us, that looks like going
and promoting the workshop in our
featured section and at the end of every
post on LinkedIn. We're posting it as
well in our X link in bio and then at
the end of different X threads and posts
to promote it. In addition to that, we
also have it on YouTube. We have it in
Instagram posts that are hooked up to
Manyhat. So I am arming my entire fleet
of organic audience and CTAs to drive
people to this core workshop, right? So
we get the maximum amount of live
attendees. So when you look at it,
right, you want to be aiming for a
registration rate of around 40% of
people that hit the workshop page you
create converting to actual attendees.
Okay. From there, you want to be aiming
on the sales conversion side to about
10% of live attendees converting to the
product or service that you go and
pitch. In addition to that, you want to
make sure that your show up rate, people
that go and confirm for the workshop, at
least 40 25% of those people you want
actually showing up. And then ideally,
you're getting to about a 300% ROI from
your time and the investment that you've
put into this. Right now, workshops,
like anything, right? They may take a
couple reps to get right. You know, I
remember my first one, I think I had
like 30 attendees, right? But I stuck
with it and I kept putting in the reps.
And these days, we get at least 600 live
attendees on most of our workshops
because it just keeps compounding. And
at even conservative conversion rates,
you know, we're making hundreds of
thousands of dollars each month that we
run these. Um, in many cases, a lot more
than that. Workshop killers though that
I want you to avoid are the following.
First off, information overload. Keep
your slides to like 60 max. Okay? You
don't want to overload your audience. In
addition to that, a weak hook.
Storytelling wins. So, make sure that
when you're starting a workshop, you
lead with an engaging story. In addition
to that, poor transitions, right? You
want to make sure it flows, right? And
it's not just one piece of value over
here and then some other disperate piece
of value over there, right? You want
people to get captivated, to settle in,
relax, get their pen and paper out, and
to be actively engaged and learning
because again, you're giving them a
taste of what they can expect in your
paid product. So, you want this to be an
absolute banger so they're like, "Damn,
I really want to learn from this human."
versus it feeling kind of choppy. You
need to make sure that your follow-up
game is immaculate, and I'm going to
give you my exact templates here. We
also have these postworkshop emails as
well. Post workshop email number one
which is going to be sent 30 minutes
after. It's like thanks so much for
joining me. It's awesome to have you. At
the end of our time together, I invited
you to apply to, you know, founder OS or
whatever it was. These calls are
specifically targeted to insert your
target market who are serious about
specific goal. If that's you, I highly
recommend you apply for a call before
the spots are filled. I owe a lot of my
success to, you know, taking action,
making things happen. And so, I want to
encourage you to take action yourself.
You may have a few more testimonials and
then get people to book a call or you
could get them to directly go and
purchase your product depending on how
exactly you sell things. In my case, I
get people to book a call and they get
on a call with my team of brand
strategists that help them out. In some
people's cases, they sell directly from
a workshop to a product link. Either one
can work. I prefer getting people on a
call. If it's a product that you're
selling that's above $2,000. If you're
selling something that's below $2,000,
you could be selling that directly via a
product link in your workshop. Okay? So,
it just depends on the pricing that you
have. From there, the next morning, I'll
send an email like this subject line,
your workshop replay. You know,
yesterday's workshop was awesome. At the
end of our time together, I invited you
to apply for a specific, you know, call
with me and my team. Here's the link. If
you missed any part of the workshop,
here is the replay for you where I'll
link the replay, which is just simply
the Zoom recording. I may leave a few
more testimonials and then just say, you
know, if you're ready to take action,
then book a call with me or my team via
the link here. And so these are the
mistakes that you want to avoid. And
trust me, I've made a lot of these
mistakes, right? Having run these for a
couple years, I had no idea what I was
doing when I started, right? This was
all new to me, but I put in the reps. I
stuck with it. I was consistent. And I
committed. And when you commit to
something, you know, I think good things
happen. You know, at first I wasn't
really sure how to do the stories to
start them. I had decks that were like
120 slides long and I was just flipping
through them like a rapid man, right?
The truth is I learned that over time
you want to give yourself time to
breathe, to tell stories, to actually be
able to go and convey your energy to the
audience versus feeling like you just
got to rush through it. People want to
genuinely connect with you. So beyond
just the value you're providing, you
want to give yourself time to slow down
to really connect with folks um so that
they really enjoy it. Um and if they're
having fun, they're going to convert. In
terms of your own implementation
guideline here, week one, you know, you
probably want to go and design your
workshop. So start creating the content
and then putting it into either Canva or
into Figma. I think you want to take the
time to actually have something that
looks great because the quality of it is
indicative of the quality of your
product and brand. Week two then start
creating all your content and your
organic content funnel around your
workshop. And this is the stuff that we
give people inside of found us is the
exact playbooks, the exact content that
we use, but I'm going to give you a
taste of that here. In addition, you
want to get your whole marketing system
set up week three. And then week four,
start to build the automations. So you
don't need to do this all manually. So
this is your four-week execution guide.
And when you execute each piece of this,
I think you have a workshop that is
ready and primed to go. Are you ready to
build your workshop? Well, if you want
help with the complete workshop system,
you want my help, my team's help,
actually going and constructing this
with you, helping you formulate the
whole thing and being there every step
of the way to help you construct
something that makes a massive impact,
not just in your business, but in your
community and the movement and the
impact you're looking to make. Well,
then go and apply to Founder OS via the
link below. You can go and apply, get on
a call with either me or my team, and
we'd love to help you. Let's win
together. Please like and subscribe and
welcome to the founder freedom movement.