All right, this is the 4-3-2-1 content
formula. I'm going to keep it simple for
you guys cuz I see a lot of you guys
wanting to make content but sitting on
the sidelines here. So, let's just break
it down. First off, pick four content
pillars. For me, that may be things
like, you know, organic content,
personal branding, founder freedom, and
then just sharing some personal stories.
And those are then going to be the
pillars that I just focus on with all my
content. Don't overthink it, just get
started. You can always evolve these
things over time. From there, what are
your three signature phrases? What are
the things that you commonly talk about?
I know for me, it's things like, you
know, founder freedom or the four W's.
These are formats and phrases that I
come back to. So, you know, just go and
pick your phrases because they kind of
become those things that make you unique
online. From there, pick two formats.
All right, so if you're pen first, you
may go and pick, you know, long-form
LinkedIn posts and X posts as your first
two formats. If you're more camera
first, you may pick, you know, Instagram
Reels and long-form YouTube videos to
start with. Just pick two, keep it
simple. The best content strategy is the
one you can stick with. From there, if
you're just getting going,
you might just start with one platform
to keep it that much more simple. I see
people trying to overcomplicate things
early, and then they give up. So, you
know, if YouTube excites you, get
started there and just keep it simple.
The less surface area that you start
with, the better because you can go
deeper versus focus on just trying to do
everything. So, this is how I'd approach
it if you're getting going. 4-3-2-1
beats doing everything at once.