I used to spend weekends making SOPs.
Now I just record myself once and it
trains people for months. Say that I
want someone on my team to be able to
evolve our offers and help me go and
create different offer stacks for the
things that we're building. Okay. Well,
here you can see I've gone and created
this overall deck that gives people an
understanding of how our offer pyramid
works at Founder OS. Having an entry-
level offer, core offer, and high ticket
offer. Once I've gone and recorded this
5-minute Loom video, I can then go to
generate and in the settings of Loom,
you can go and click SOP here. What I
love about this is it's giving the key
steps. And what it's doing is providing
an image for each as well as a few core
bullet points so that it's very easy for
someone to then go and execute this
stuff. And you can just record yourself
doing these things and then have Loom
take care of all the systems around this
so you can move faster, stay organized,
and build leverage across your