All right, I've been reflecting a little
bit on the difference [music] between a
magnetic business and a drained business
model. One that fills up your cup or one
that just slowly destroys you. When I
think about a magnetic business, I think
about one
where you're really paid to be you,
right? To pursue your curiosity, your
joy, where you get to focus on what you
actually love to do. And you have a team
that is supportive, also small and
mighty, not bloated. [music]
They're supporting your vision for where
you want to go and understand that
honestly one of their core roles is just
to make your life easier. It's a
business where you have systems so you
can remove yourself from the operations
of the business,
>> [music]
>> not be caught in the weeds, and thereby
be able to pass the one-month test,
right? Be able to have a business where
you can leave for one month and come
back to it stronger than when you
[music] left. You know, it's a business
where, you know, you built an amazing
community around it, right? And
you're able to take
>> [music]
>> a week in nature every month, just like
I am here
in Bali, enjoying a solo trip here, but
a week [music] posted up in the middle
of nowhere, off-grid, some time to
reflect, journal, [music] and really
just enjoy life. Now, I think
a magnetic business is one that
recognizes that your
really big strength [music] is being a
reducer, right? It's reducing the amount
of things that you do. It's about
deleting stuff, right? And not getting
caught in just doing more and more and
more, that you need to actually simplify
the business at the end of the day.
And it's about, you know, success
[music] being time wealth, right?
Abundance, love, right? Not getting
stuck in fear, anxiety, frustration,
confusion. No, a magnetic business is
one that pays you to be in flow all day,
Right? Versus feeling tense, feeling a
burden on your shoulders. Right? Feeling
like
you're constantly battling different
fires. Because you know, a drained
business,
>> [music]
>> you know, it's constant meetings,
constant feeling like you need to do
more. The business is just running off
of your grit.
And you just constantly got to produce
because you're essentially the engine of
your business, [music]
doing 20 plus things, relying on
referrals and a paid ad hamster wheel,
and [music] feeling like you can just
never slow down. On the other side of
things,
I think
>> [music]
>> that a magnetic business rewards you
for being an architect. Right? For
really having [music]
two or three areas of core focus. You
know, for me, that might mean, you know,
hiring core core roles, uh being
involved on the content side and
building amazing content, maybe like
this video, depending on how you feel
about it, and scheming and plotting,
basically. Right? Whether that's new
offers, or that's even just deleting
different areas of the business to keep
it super simple. [music]
It's building a business
that again doesn't require your constant
involvement. You've got real leaders
around you, and [music]
you've got content that really
magnetizes people. Right? Because when
you've got consistent content going out
there, and you've got an organic content
funnel,
and
your team is running on the core three,
which I see as
>> [music]
>> core velocity meetings, where our team
and each department is running tight
meetings so that they're working towards
core goals.
>> [music]
>> Secondly, they have quarterly targets
they're moving through that don't
require your micromanagement.
And
three,
you've got a founder scorecard, which
are the core metrics across your
business that your team is aiming for,
and [music] those metrics have core
owners. When you have that, you can kind
of let the ship run knowing that, you
know, everyone is aligned around what
they need to do. Now, in a magnetic
business, people come to you because
they can feel your energy. They resonate
with you, right? They like your overall
lifestyle and they want to be a part of
whatever it is you have going on.
On the other side, a drained business
[music]
is one where the founder is just cooked.
Like just completely fried,
right?
And the founder very much just feels
like this cog in a machine, right? This
like cow that's been endlessly milked
and is just run dry.
Sorry for the visual there. And so,
[music] whereas a magnetic business,
your energy is attracting folks,
you know, in a drained business, people
are just staying the hell away. Cuz at
the end of the day, to be bit magnetic,
I think one thing that doesn't get
talked enough about is that you need a
personal board of advisers, right? You
need people around you to help you with
things like growth in sales and
marketing and content and finance and
strategy, right? To help you get to
where you're looking to go because you
and I both know, right? That the number
one cheat code in entrepreneurship is
finding folks that are a few steps ahead
of where you are and then learning from
their way of doing things so that you
don't need to make the same mistakes
that they were making. Similarly, folks
know that are building a magnetic
business that with each hire you make,
it's kind of just more stress. So, being
conscious of you hire and trying to keep
your team no more than 12 with 70% plus
profit margins
so that it's lean, it's mean, and
inevitably, it's peaceful, [music] it's
purposeful, and it's profitable, right?
And seriously cash flowing so that it
can fund, you know, an amazing product,
an amazing brand, but also you just
living your life. I think folks that are
running magnetic businesses understand
that growing an audience and your own
personal brand is the most valuable
asset you can build. [music]
When I look at folks that are drained,
it's because they're stuck on paid ads
being their entire model or relying on
referrals and wondering where their next
lead is going to come from. And they
don't have that content [music] just
compounding without them. And they're
basically just a ghost online. I learned
a long time ago that that was not the
way to go. You know, when I was building
Herb, my second business, I grew that
business to 14 million people in eight
figures and [music] you know, the
largest community and audience in its
niche all organically without a dime
spent on ads. But there was something
telling me that I should start building
my own founder-led brand. And I started
[music] that just about six years ago
getting going on X, then moving over to
LinkedIn, growing the audience there now
to over 900,000 followers all
organically,
>> [music]
>> moving on to YouTube and to Instagram,
where we've now grown this amazing
audience and founder freedom movement to
over 3 million people. Now, beyond
growing my business and cash flows and
net worth and all those kinds of
metrics, the most magical part of
building this founder-led brand
>> [music]
>> is the people, the serendipity, the
opportunities that it's opened up. You
know, meetings with folks like Taki
Moore, Alex Hormozi, Ali Abdaal, Leila
Hormozi, Gary V, Mark Cuban,
you know, so many others,
>> [music]
>> right? My personal brand basically
precedes me in any room, persuades
people, pre-sells people. And so,
honestly, just building a business is
just a lot less work.
And obviously just a lot more fun, too.
You know, I think that magnetic
businesses are one where the founder is
very much a pioneer, right? You
recognize that you're in this new
frontier,
>> [music]
>> right? And you're building something
that really is like unique to you, that
fires you up around your calling, you're
building a brand around it, [music] and
you're just sharing this mission and
your values and what you're big on with
people because you're passionate about
it, right? And people [music]
can feel the energy. They can feel the
vibe. Whereas in a drained business,
>> [music]
>> it's a mess. It's constant chaos. You
have no time to even build a brand,
right? [music] Things feel complex, and
because you have low margins,
you're kind of just treading water,
right? You got this outbound growth
engine versus having some personal brand
founder-led brand growth engine.
>> [music]
>> Everything kind of feels like a push
instead of being able to pull in
the your dream customer because they're
essentially just magnetized to you. You
know, an organic content funnel converts
people while you sleep, right? They see
your content, which is like a
salesperson that never sleeps. They go
and they arrive on a landing page. They
convert maybe based of a VSL to an
application to a call, or maybe you're
even running a salesless model in
a magnet magnet a magnetic business
where you don't even need sales people.
People just simply go and see an offer
doc. They're so magnetized to you,
they're like,
I like this guy. [music] Or I like this
woman.
And bam, before you know it, they're in,
and you don't even need sales people.
What a dream, right? Well, this is
exactly what's possible
>> [music]
>> in a magnetic business. Now, I think the
most important part is this part right
here.
Beyond business, beyond all the magic
tricks and all this, I think the
ultimate thing when you're building a
business, right, is your own nervous
system, right? How do you feel when
you're building? In a magnetic business,
right, your nervous system is regulated.
In a drained business, which [music] I
know my first business, BitMaker, was
definitely this.
You're stressed out constantly. You're
wondering why you're even doing what
you're doing. You're wondering when it's
going to get better. You wake up with a
sense of dread. You go to sleep with a
sense of anxiety, [music]
and it just doesn't seem to quit. You
can't get it off your mind. You can't
[music] relax. So, the question then
becomes, how do you build
>> [music]
>> a magnetic business? Well,
first off, you've got to get real
on what you really want. I think that
all founders, we're renegades, we're
rebels, we're inventors, we're dreamers.
We can create any future we want.
If you truly want a more magnetic
business, then the first step is
deciding well, that's what you want, and
that you're not going to put up with
these aspects that are draining you.
The second thing is adopting the
identity
of a reducer, not a producer, and
deleting the that's draining you.
The third is adopting the identity of an
architect, [music]
not the engine, and not allowing
yourself to get pulled into
that is just sucking the life out of
you. Now, I'm not saying that that's
going to happen overnight, but decision
by decision, move by move, you can
gradually get one step closer, right,
[music] to this more magnetic feeling in
your business. Now,
the fourth thing, right,
>> [music]
>> is this understanding that when you
start to share your journey, when you
start to share what you're passionate
about, you start to magnetize people to
you. And this has many benefits cuz you
don't need to chase folks anymore,
right? You attract your tribe. You
attract the kind of customers that if
you were to see your customer on the
other side of the street, you would want
to cross the street and say hello to
them, because they're a good friend of
yours, versus bringing people into
whatever business it is you're running,
and those customers are the ones that,
you know, you just dread. [music]
You don't want to get on calls with
them. You don't enjoy serving them.
And they're [music] part of the issue
that's causing you to feel so sacked.
Now, from there, I think it's really
deciding to [music] start really
reinventing your overall business model.
Now, if you're watching this, you may be
a coach or [music] a consultant or
service provider SaaS company, I don't
know what. Could be any model, right?
And I think that this magnetic
philosophy of building a business can
work for anyone. And I think it's about
auditing your business. [music]
Auditing your team. Who do you
absolutely need and who can you cut?
Auditing your time. What stuff
is giving you energy and what is
draining your energy and cutting the
Auditing your business model
and your offer. What are the one to two
core things you want to be known for?
What's your unfair advantage? And what's
a bunch of the stuff that's just kind of
noise that's gotten kind of tacked on to
your business over time that it's time
to reduce, cut, and delete. From there,
you know, I think most folks generally
end up deciding to go and pursue [music]
things like organic content around their
brand. To have an online brand that's
this [music] beacon for the kind of
people they're looking to attract. So,
they don't need to chase folks
and they can really build, you know, a
niche of one online and be kind of the
most referred to expert in their area.
So, that folks know to come to them for
what exactly they're doing.
And
they just really get paid to be
themselves, to be on this journey, to be
curious, [music] to be magnetic, and to
really just continue to innovate in
their narrow niche and stay focused.
[music]
Stay happy. Stay joyous. Right? This is
what joyful entrepreneurship looks like,
I think.
Now, I'm not here to tell you that I got
it all figured out. I'm certainly
learning
just like you are.
Right? I think that this magnetic
business philosophy is one that
is a North Star. Right? A true North.
One where
you know that physically [music]
it invigorates you, that mentally
it's something you definitely want,
spiritually it feels like something that
fills up your cup way more, [music] and
emotionally is something that will leave
you excited. And
I don't think there's a specific end
point in mind. It's kind of this
infinite journey of gradually optimizing
what it is you have going on. Optimizing
your business for peace, optimizing it
for purpose, optimizing it for profit,
optimizing it
>> [music]
>> for a nervous system that makes you feel
good, optimizing it for a product you're
excited by, a team you love, customers
you love, a margin of 70%, a lean team
of 12,
>> [music]
>> right? But I think it's a worthy
journey. So, if this sort of
magnetic business [music] model
philosophy resonates with you, well,
that's what this channel's all about.
[music] Thanks so much for watching.
Maybe you want more videos like this,
let me know in the comments below.
Be sure to like and subscribe.
>> [music]
>> And if you want to, you can go and check
out
this next video, um which is all around
the content strategy that I've used to
go [music] and sort of blow up these
kinds of magnetic businesses. So, go and
check that one out, and I'll see you in
the next one.