what if I told you there's a 14-page
master plan that could transform your
business health and your happiness in
2025 it's the exact system I've used to
grow multiple seven and eight figure
businesses avoid burnout and design a
life I love and today I'm giving it to
you I'll reveal the exact strategies
lessons Frameworks and mindsets I use
every year to increase my profits
improve my health and find fulfillment
all in one document and the best part
you can download the exact template and
start building your own 2025 Playbook
right now I'm sharing this guide with
you all because I know how we as
Founders tend to overestimate what we
can get done in a year the problem isn't
our lack of ambition it's the lack of
the systems to bring that Vision to life
this 14-page framework is my solution
it's a proven actionable system that's
helped me thrive in business and life
and now it's yours fair warning though
things will get personal if you think
you know me you might be surprised let's
dive in so around every December I go
and I write down my annual review it
consists of going and reflecting on the
best moments experiences and people from
the year the biggest mistakes I've made
and reflecting on what I've learned I'm
going to go and break this down for you
step by step my mission is to really
unlock Humanity's creative potential and
live the most fulfilling and inspiring
life imaginable for me this year is all
about peace plus profit plus purpose my
purpose is really to go and help 100,000
Founders in 2025 achieve a million
dollars plus Revenue per year through
proven systems to grow Their audience
their brand and their monetization and
we do this at founder OS by giving
people the exact systems I've used to
build multiple seven figure and eight
fig businesses when I drill down and
look at my core Focus for the year it's
as follows right obsessing over quality
doing fewer things and saying no by
default being a world-class manager and
leader working at a natural pace and
just having fun I'm actually currently
in Dubai heading out to Bali next week
for a month just to relax rejuvenate and
start the year in just a peaceful place
I really want to go and lean into the
Artistry of everything when I first
started building businesses I was really
obsessed with the business side of
things right always just driving things
forward hustling as I've gotten older
I've really tried to lean into the
Artistry behind building a business the
creativity The Taste the quality I'm
doing things just because love it 2025
is going to be no different for me and
so I really want to go and lean into
really unlocking my creative potential
making amazing YouTube videos like this
one really leaning into design making
sure that the brand of founder OSS
really comes to life and reaches its
full creative potential and I also need
to be a smart investor not just you know
of my time but of my money and in the
people that I'm investing in inside of
my companies as I approach 2025 insanely
simple as the theme insanely simple
experience experiences insanely simple
operations insanely simple systems
insanely simple design insanely simple
culture and insanely simple lifestyle
insanely simple to me means drilling
down into the core parts of our
operations of the business of my life
that are bringing me the greatest
returns and saying no by default the
more things I can say no to the more I'm
doubling down and going deep on the
things that truly matter to me to the
business and will make a big impact in
my life and the life of others as I
reflect on 2024 question is well how
could I have been better I could have
been more patient you know I get caught
up in all of the busyness of the
day-to-day sometimes going and rushing
to the next thing and I need to go and
pause more and enjoy the moment I could
be more present I could be a better
active listener and only doing things
that are really a hell yes this was a
big theme for my era there was too many
things at times often times people that
I had around me um that didn't feel
aligned and so I want to be more
selective this upcoming year um and only
saying yes to things that in my head in
my heart and in my gut feel aligned and
feel right I have a lot to improve
myself I think I can also though improve
kind of making sure that I'm setting the
right boundaries with people around me
to make sure that I'm surrounding myself
with people that have similar values to
me that I really want to work with for
the next decade there were some
difficult times with new hires I think
hiring is one of the most important jobs
as a founder and CEO I also think it's
the most difficult job it's a lot easier
said than done done we actually had the
team get pretty large this year working
with a bunch of different people
different contractors and I want to kind
of trim things down a bit keep that team
lean and this kind of doubles down on
that idea of keeping things peaceful in
2025 on the health side you know I
really thought I had some great health
wins this year I went and worked with a
woman named Sadie who implemented a new
health protocol for me um which helped
get my testosterone above 800
testosterone is the chemical in men that
makes effort feel good and I think as a
Founder you want to make sure you have
optim hormone levels to really be able
to drive through different walls and be
able to give every morcel of your being
towards your mission on the wealth side
you know had some big wins investing
consistently on a monthly basis you know
recording record profits across my
portfolio of businesses and working with
a financial adviser just to invest in a
diversified portfolio every single month
that makes me feel kind of financially
unbreakable on the business side we
served over 18,000 Founders across the
various products at founder OS one of
the most rewarding things this year is I
brought on my sister Claire to be the
chief of staff of founder us which has
been an absolute dream you know I was a
little bit nervous at first working with
a family member I was like ah I don't
know if this is a good idea but it
turned out to be one of the best
decisions I made all year we hosted two
epic founder Retreats one in Mexico City
um with about 60 Founders and then
another one in Sedona Arizona with about
70 Founders there and these were
mindblowing I had to pinch myself at the
amazing community that we're building
not just online with founder OS but
these epic in-person experiences where
we do different founder hikes different
Jam sessions deep Dives and intensives
around different parts of people's
businesses helping them solve their
greatest bottleneck and move forward
their business at record speed on the
audience growth side we hit over 100,000
people here on YouTube so shout out to
you for being part of this community
over 500,000 views on a single video
garnered over 750,000 followers on
LinkedIn 170,000 newsletter subscribers
we crossed 300K on x and over 800,000
Instagram followers you know I think
building an audience is one of the best
decisions that you can make it's an
appreciating asset that you have for the
rest of your life and my belief is that
the future of brands are founder-led I
really want to live that example to
Founders inside of found us and show
them what's possible when you build an
amazing personal brand the amount of
impact leverage opportunities
connections amazing highes that all
become possible because of this amazing
community that you're building online
now let's get into the personal Vision
side for 2025 I think it's important
that you really get clear on your values
going into any year so my values are
things like Inner Harmony Freedom
Community creativity and nature these
help me determine what to say hell yes
to and then the things in my life that I
should say no to if I have the
opportunity to go live in a city for 10
months of the year I'm probably going to
say no because nature is a big value of
mine and I'm going to prioritize things
like mountain biking in the dolomites OR
exploring the jungles and Bali so on the
personal goals side on the romance
family side you know things like weekly
date nights weekend getaways and making
sure I'm doing quarterly epic
spontaneous adventures in nature are
things that are important to me on the
health and wellness side daily lifts
daily meditation on the personal growth
side I'm looking to read 24 books this
year here you can see um all of the
books that I've read in 2024 currently
reading autobiography of a yogi over the
holidays which I'm looking forward to
it's the book that Steve Jobs read every
single year um and at his funeral um he
gave that book to every single attendees
we got two more epic founder Retreats
happening one in April in Austin Texas
and another one in October in Bali I'm
looking to also attend some highlevel
masterminds myself I think that it's
important as a Founder to constantly be
surrounding yourself with amazing
Community these sort of Investments are
responsible for about 80% of My Success
because the best investment you can make
in your life is in yourself as we go and
look at the vision for founder OS you
know it really is predicated on this
thesis right that number one brands are
founder Le which is the importance and
why so many people should be building
their personal brand the second aspect
is my belief that every brand is a media
company thirdly creators are the future
I'm passionate about merging amazing
founders with the best design video
capabilities taste quality that creators
like Casey neistat Emma Chamberlain life
of Rizza Daniel dalan these sorts of
creators really embody and I think it's
important that as founders you have a
beautiful systemized and Hyper
profitable brand and content the way
that we deliver on this inside of
foundos is with the content GPS which is
the most powerful system I've ever
invented and it's really the only way to
build a hyper profitable personal brand
driving people from your social media
audience to your newsletter to an
irresistible offer and doing that as
quickly and as smoothly as possible so
it's kind of like a slippery slope going
from your audience to revenue my big
vision for foundos is to create a
community of a 100 million Founders
right that are changing the world my
belief is that the future belongs to the
builders to the dreamers The Taste
makers the creators just like you here
at founder us we're dedicated um to
creating this founder Freedom Movement
people that are united around using
proven systems to create true freedom in
Life Time Freedom location freedom and
Financial Freedom as we look to the next
10 years you know I'm looking to build
this community of 100 million and we're
looking to go and create a ret stre
Center in the dolomites which I'll show
you here just in a sec over the next 3
years then to reverse engineer those
10year goals we're going to go and grow
the audience to 50 million get the
newsletter to over 5 million subscribers
The Mastermind that we're running to
over a thousand high growth Founders
going and serving over a million people
with founder OS and then opening this
Retreat Center in the dolomites which is
going to be just the most epic thing
ever as we then look to the one-year
side of things right I kind of am
reverse engineering the 10-year the
three-year into my one year and my
90-day goals in 2025 by December 31st
mark my words we're going to grow the
audience over 9 million people 2 million
on IG 2 million on x 2 million on
LinkedIn a million on YouTube and 2
million on Tik Tok reaching a million
newsletter subscribers graduating over
2,000 Founders through founder OS
selling a million copies of my book
that's coming out soon getting the
Mastermind to a th000 and hitting a
th000 Founders inside of os+ so the next
90 days they are going to be B busy
because my belief is that in the first
90 days of the year it's about going and
eliminating all distractions that take
you away from really going and nailing
your goals being hyperfocused as I look
to the next 90 days I'm finalizing the
book we're going and getting you know
founder OS growing getting more Founders
served helping install the content GPS
in hundreds of Founders businesses and
then reaching over 500,000 YouTube
subscribers is a big goal so we're going
to start publishing videos every single
week starting in the next couple months
the big opportunities I see across
people product and process over the next
90 days you know really just leveling up
my team continuing to build this kind of
culture of extreme ownership continuing
to kind of lean into a full funnel
dashboard that we've created at founder
identifying bottlenecks every single
week and then going and eliminating them
week by week getting 1% better every day
which will help make the company 37
times better in a year when I think
about this year my priorities are things
like finding a home so got one set up
here in Dubai currently going and
investigating if Bali makes sense to go
and set up a place there as well making
sure I'm infusing my year with a lot of
fun adventure and play again
prioritizing peace because to me that's
just one of my greatest values I want
nice Harmony and good sleep at night
Building Systems writing creating
content building vibrant communities
being out in nature traveling and
coaching high growth Founders along the
way too my big focuses are leaning into
high converting copy creating
irresistible offers doubling down on the
founder community that we're creating at
founder OS both online and in person um
and just leaning into just creating the
greatest founder content in the world so
this is just a glimpse of how we
approach content at founder OS our main
goal when we're creating content is to
Dazzle Founders right to just blow your
mind with the level of love care and
attention to detail that we put into
every single piece of it my belief is
that I'm like the chief detail officer
making sure that every piece of content
really embodies our mission our goal is
to really create the best founder
content in the world this is what we're
constantly striving to do with every
single YouTube video every xread every
LinkedIn post is just to move the needle
forward in a big way and Inspire
Founders so as I go and think about the
kind of content we're creating this year
I want to make sure that when people
think of these sorts of words like
systems travel Adventure the dolomites
you know organic content deep systems
scaling delegating that they think of
founder OS and the way we do this is
prioritizing the amount of value people
get per second of our content back to
the plan here as I reflect on the year
some of my best of lists that I thought
would be useful to share with you is the
following so the best book I read 2024
was psychology of money the second
runner up was slow productivity by Cal
Newport you can go check those out on
the event side the two founder Retreats
that we ran at founder West were Epic on
the article side my favorite article was
this one called founder mode by Paul
Graham all about how as a Founder you
know you need to be in the details you
need to be in the operations involved in
the product as a Founder we are the
chief detail officers it's up to us to
make sure the product is done right on
the podcast side I love this podcast by
Founders called house steeve jobs kept
things simple the best purchase of the
year was my Sony fx3 my best habit was
my incredible Health protocol you can
see here this health protocol that I
went and followed throughout the year
that absolutely changed my life on the
meditation side um I'm big on
experimenting with different meditations
but one I've come back to almost daily
for the last decade is this meditation
by the legendary Bobby Proctor um it's
an abundance meditation that's about 22
minutes long super peaceful and just set
me up for really great thinking through
the day let's get into some of the Big
Dreams I have uh for this year right so
when I look at 2025 Some Dream collabs
are with Legends like Mr Beast Elon Musk
Rick Ruben Tim Ferris Tony Robbins Casey
neistat nval rant and Andrew huberman
you know I have dreams of being able to
collaborate with them in different
pieces of content here on YouTube um to
help them with their audience growth
help them install the content GPS in
their businesses on the dream Community
side um like I mentioned I'm really
dreaming of launching this founder
potential Center in the dolomites so
setting myself up for that throughout
this year is going to be a big theme U
let me give you just a quick taste of
what we have planned there the vision of
okay is to create this Retreat Center in
the dolomites designed to ignite the
most profound Transformations for
creators dreamers and Builders the
founder potential Center offers the peak
experience of a lifetime to the founders
inside of founder OS so this isn't just
some retreat center right it's a
movement a place for True transformation
and I really want to empower Founders to
experience moments 10 times more
powerful than their greatest personal
Milestones ever so creating these sort
of peak experiences giving people a
chance to escape the grind to be able to
tap into the deepest versions of
themselves and Elevate their lives
beyond levels they ever thought possible
Founders can get to know one another on
a deep level be able to transform both
their life and their business be able to
meet one another go for epic mountain
bikes hikes Adventures the founder
Freedom Movement is all about freedom
and a big part of that is epic
experiences this experience that we're
putting together in the dolomites is
going to be this home base for the
founder Freedom Movement
and you are invited now I've given you a
bit of a glimpse of my plan for 2025 I
hope it's inspired you to go and reflect
on your year and the highlights of it to
also go and plan out the intricate
aspects of your personal goals and your
business goals for 2025 let's get after
it as a global community of Founders and
welcome to the founder Freedom Movement
Like And subscribe let's go