We're here in London and we're blending
the new school scaling tactics for media
companies with an old school dinosaur
industry. Today we're meeting with a
wealth management company with $750
million of assets under management and
they need help setting up a media
company in their organization. So how do
we do that but still maintain that point
of quality. So we're going to go get
into three systems that will help them
go and transform their business. We're
going to get into their LinkedIn OS,
their content waterfall, and then their
org chart. Let's dive in. you guys want
to just like maybe start off where you
guys are currently at in terms of like
your social platforms, how you're
marketing on them, and maybe any gaps
that you're currently seeing.
>> A big big challenge in this industry is
brand recognition with the view that
design has a cultural connection to
clients. Like if they can feel the brand
is more than just financial services.
It's more than just the P&L that we're
going to be able to carry them through
kind of the highs and lows, but also
attract them. But we really also know
how to create amazing design like Johnny
Iva Apple, Norman Foster in
architecture. We want to bring this
design high quality. We want to bring
the culture of like being open and
democratic. And then we want to look
through the lens of our clients. We are
entrepreneurs. We set this up with risk.
We didn't have to do this. We're in a
very conservative industry. So it takes
longer. So everything around now
LinkedIn, you know, the big conundrum
for me is how do we get into Instagram?
How do we get into YouTube? like what is
that? It doesn't feel naturally the
right place. But again, our industry is
really like dinosaur like in terms of
moving into this space. So, how do we do
that but still maintain all that those
that that point of quality. When a
company like Hundle wants to do content,
it really needs to have the right
definition. You need to make sure that
you're organizing the operating system
of this so that it's simple and there's
a clear structure. Let's talk a little
bit about like just to start with like
LinkedIn and like the funnel there just
so you guys understand like the
mechanics. First off, like we have like
you're going to have the different
content pieces go out say like once per
day, right? So I'd recommend that this
starts going seven days per week. From
here, how this works is you're going to
have content and in that content there's
going to be a call to action, okay? Or a
CTA. Now that CTA, how we think about it
is you're probably going to have like
say four different like categories of
content that you put out there. You
talked about things like helping people
like with their investments. There's tax
stuff. there's like new growth
opportunities and this nextg. So we got
like nextg, we got like investment type
stuff, we've got tax and then maybe
we've got stuff around like the values
that you talked about which are like
design, quality and delivery. On the CTA
side, essentially you have this content
going out every day and what you're
probably going to want to have is like a
CTA at the end that's curated to the
category. Okay. So, as an example, if I
go and put out a piece around like new
tax strategies for 2026 that UK
residents should be aware of, a lot of
people moving to Dubai these days, is it
is it your time to move or does it is it
worth you staying? This has probably
been on your mind. We're going to dive
into it. The post then gets into that.
And then the CTA could be, hey, you
know, are you looking to go and discover
like the best like tax strategy for you?
We've laid out all 40 of the top regions
that British folks are moving to and
given you the procons list of all of it.
Go and click the link here and you can
get it for free. So there's four
different kinds of CTAs which are going
to go and lead people to four different
landing pages. From there they get the
lead magnet. When they get this lead
magnet, let's just like go and say it's
like this 40 next trends thing. And my
goal when I create create these guides
is that I want someone to go and share
that in their entire company in their
company Slack. So now everyone's
digesting it. Some guy that is just a
lower level person that saw it on
LinkedIn is now sharing the Slack and
the CFO is like what the [\h__\h] is this?
Right? He's opening it up like who are
these guys? We're getting charged by
Barclays 10K for this information. Who
prepared this? It's like oh these guys
over here you know Hundle like this is
like the kind of stuff they give away
just for free. And so now they've got
the lead magnet. But the most important
part here is now you've got them in your
newsletter. The place where most people
in this industry in these kind of boring
industries or archaic ones like they
screw up is I think like when you really
think about the goats in this space,
right? Content was actually a pillar of
what they did. Jeff Bezos's shareholder
letters are like epic. Warren Buffett's
shareholder epic. That's what your
newsletter should be. And the CTA is now
in the newsletter. And there's a this is
a key distinction. If the CTAs that you
put on social are constantly like work
with us, work with us, you sound like
Barclays. And the issue too is that you
sound salesy and nobody wants to listen
to you very long and they just like mute
you, unfollow you, whatever. And then
when you're in the newsletter, you have
their email now. Now you can CTA them
to, hey, if you want to get on an
individualized session with us, we'd be
happy to accommodate to you. We have a
concierge service. Just book a call with
us here. we'll have our financial
concierge on a call with you and we
can't wait to speak with you. There you
can now go and start laying up the
actual like sale. And the thing is too,
if you go and create say one of these,
you know, you create these lead magnets
as an example, right? Each one of these,
let's say they're 30 pages each, you got
like 120 pages. I mean, each one of
those pages arguably could be an email.
Maybe there's just like, hey, one week
we do a deep dive on one core thing that
we're kind of interested in, and then
the next week we do a little bit of a
roundup of like what we're reading these
days. an interesting like take on
personal finances or investments or
whatever that we think you should
consider mix of like deep dives and
curation. The trouble will not be coming
up with like more categories and more
that yeah it's the depth. When I think
about doing this, you know, we talked
about LinkedIn right now, right? But you
guys have been talking about like
Instagram and YouTube and and the
newsletter. There's a lot of work to do
here. You have to get all these made in
terms of like the landing pages and the
lead magnets. You got to have someone
that's you trust making the newsletter.
You're probably going to want to bring
on a writer. This is like nuanced like
novel, non-obvious information. Like to
go and train someone up and go, we talk
about these 10 things and these 10 kind
of like ways we go with it. It's like
you'd much rather just be like, hey, you
just need to like nail these things.
Yeah. Exactly. Exactly. When you're in
the newsletter, right,
>> that's the point where that person has
signed up being like, I want to hear
from you. Right. And the difference to
point out that I don't think a lot of
people understand is like when you post
this content over here, it's seen to
about 10% of your LinkedIn audience,
right? But over here, 100% of those
people get it. And so this is where it's
best to drive your leads. What you guys
need to have is a like work with us
form. This is very important. inside of
this, right? You may have a drop down of
like your different needs, potentially
like the stage they're at, their
location, just some initial info that
takes them 1 minute to fill out that
allows you to qualify these people. This
form serves as a router. You're going to
be able to see that $100 million person
come in. That person gets routed to
Andy, right? You're going to be able to
see that person come in that's good for
the 1% product you're releasing that
goes to say, oh, the handle as an
example, right? you're going to see a
lot of other stuff that's just like just
not qualified. And then that just goes
to like a free resource just like hey
like you should check this out. Here's
some videos that we have out there like
great to have you in the community in
the audience like and then just like a
little bit about the firm saying like
hey we're just this really like
>> you know highle thing. Um but if you are
you know any friends or whatever you
know kind of vibe like we'd love to work
with people and thanks for being a part
of this and we hope to you know really
help you learn more about your own
future through our free content. I would
be trying to get on a call with those
people within an hour. Yeah.
>> So, they filled this out.
>> It's like boom,
>> right? And now they're on a call and
they're like, "Wow, this is different."
If you're building a media company, the
truth is you want to get started on the
platform that's just easiest and makes
the most sense for where your dream
customer is currently operating and
active. With Hundle, they're already on
LinkedIn. their customers are on
LinkedIn and so it makes sense for them
to go deep on that one platform versus
spreading themselves too thin too fast
and just trying to be omniresent. We'll
get into like the actual like LinkedIn
kind of content strategy. Now first off
like we have like the topics and then
that sort of like brings up like what
are the formats which is kind of what
you're asking.
>> Yeah. like length and all that stuff,
>> you know, we've got the actual like
topics for the lead magnets and then say
your newsletters. When it comes to on
LinkedIn, the best type of content is
going to be like longer form content.
Essentially, the thing that LinkedIn
measures is like time on post, just like
YouTube looks at like watch time.
>> LinkedIn's looking at, okay, you get
this little hook as a preview. Does
someone click read more? Then it goes
and populates a long post. They scroll
through that long post. Then they also
see maybe like a dense image. They look
at the image. Maybe the image is like an
infographic of like 20 countries as an
example and which in their friendliness
score
>> for Brits. I'm just saying as an
example. So then they look at that.
Yeah. Then they look at that too and
then they're like [\h__\h] Oh wow. And then
on you know if I click this link I can
get a free resource to go even deeper
here. LinkedIn's like wow there's a lot
of signal there. Like these people were
like opening this spending a couple
minutes on it. They then went and
reposted this because it was so
valuable. Then they took that link
structure and shared it in their company
Slack. All that signal is what causes
these posts to do well. In terms of like
the topics themselves, what's most
important is that you have like a point
of view. So like I'll illustrate like as
an example like a three-part sort of
like positioning statement, right? Like
with founder OS, my whole thing would be
like the future of online businesses
will be founderled. In order to build a
founder business, you need to be
systemized, profitable, and beautiful.
And then the best way to build a
systemized, beautiful, and profitable
founder brand is with a content GPS,
which is what we help you with at
Founder OS. So that's kind of like my
point of view. What I generally like to
do is think about the best topics often
times to talk about are what are the
people that are paying you the most
money or like the most loyal customers
like your dream customers. What are
their core questions? Why did they start
working with you? then being thought
leaders around that stuff to attract
more people like them and their friends.
And that's where the magic is. That's
what other people won't do. It's like we
have this stable of 500 clients. No one
knows this pool better than we do, which
is basically the brand stance. No one
serves them on a deeper level and cares
more than we do. Here's the things
they've brought up. And that's your
content strategy for you guys. is like
given the fact I think you have an
opportunity to like just whiteboard all
of these kinds of topics that have been
coming up over the last few months.
Yeah. Is the 3% worth it? Lazy investor
versus smart investor. All this like
nuanced stuff that then becomes like the
actual content you're going to put out.
The good news for you too is that also
becomes amazing onboarding material for
the team you're going to be starting up
cuz now they're like reading all this
stuff and they're like this is our
stance. So a client asks you this,
respond with this. Like if they ask you
like is the 3% worth it? This is how we
speak to that. So I think like when you
think about the topics right it's like
these insider questions it's like the
why kind of questions you've brought up
right and then a lot of education around
like you know is it an asset manager
versus a wealth manager asset manager or
an investment banker or
>> you know deep dives into like you know
for these kind of folks like I think you
know there's a million deep dives
different kinds of products different
kinds of markets how to also structure
their overall like team when they think
about this like people know they need
like a great accountant, a great lawyer,
but what do they need in this whole
area?
>> So then on the format side, I think it's
a lot of like kind of deep dives, right?
Just like getting into these things in a
thorough way. I think there's a lot of
like surface level stuff out there,
right? It's like actually going deep
into these different like why questions.
You know, some of these can be also like
how-tos, how to structure your team, how
to uh you know exit a certain place, how
to um decide on an asset manager. And
one thing with this too that you can do,
right, is like if you make a really
detailed document on like your core
client avatar or even two, right? So you
have like your 01% person, you have like
your 1% person. What's like their pain
points? What are their dreams? Where do
they live? What are they into? What do
they read? Just like I could think about
a two-pager brainstorm for each of these
avatars. upload those to chatbt and then
ask it to go and just just upload this
photo that we've just made and say just
flush this out for me now based on the
core stuff we pointed out. So go and
create like 100 deep dives that are
ranked from best to worst. Go and create
a 100 how-tos that are ranked from best
to worst and then you guys are armed
with like
>> you can have this done by tomorrow
>> and by your Monday research meeting cuz
it's Yeah. So yeah, in a week from now
>> that's amazing what charge can actually
if you put this in.
>> So we're not living in 2018 anymore.
It's 2025 and chat GBT should be your
best friend. But most people are using
it the wrong way. They got basic
prompts. They give it no context and
then they wonder why they're still doing
all this grunt work. And so what we get
into here is the 10 10 formula.
Essentially making sure that you have 10
references on a given platform for the
best type of content that inspires you.
10 references from inside of your
industry of the best content that you've
saved or bookmarked that you're like,
"One day I hope my brand is that good
and then 10 references for what your
brand is all about." You take those 30
pieces of content, you feed that into a
chat GBT project, and now you're
standing on the shoulders of giants.
From there, as we'll get into here, it's
where the real magic happens. So, you
set up like your Chat GBT project here,
right? And kind of follow like a 10 10
rule with it. I would go and find 10
LinkedIn posts that you think are like
the best ever in your given niche or
like in overall, right? Put those all
into a dock. Then go and find 10 pieces
that are the best ever ever reference
pieces from others just in this niche.
It doesn't have to be on LinkedIn. It's
like this is like, you know, you've you
probably know those 10. You know what I
mean? So, you're like feeding, hey,
these are 10 articles or pieces or
whatever that I saw that like I couldn't
stop thinking about that I shared with
everyone. put that into a doc and then
have like a brand reference 10 brand
references. So this is like maybe your
landing page copy. This is uh you know a
bunch of these letters that you've been
writing to your um existing audience and
uh insiders that like they've been
loving. Like what are like the best
eight of those?
>> Yeah. I thought
>> Right. And so now you've got this
project in GPT that's got all of these
amazing LinkedIn docs.
>> Yeah. all of the references from amazing
people and it's got this, right? And now
starting to use that to brainstorm
things like the best deep dives ever and
like the best how-tos cuz essentially
now what it's doing is like standing on
the shoulders of giants and it's fed
enough that it can really start coming
up with some breakthrough stuff. On the
lead magnet side, it's the same thing,
right? You can come up with all these
topics. If we want to like get more like
AI about it, what you could end up doing
is you have like say 60 topics right
over here that you've come up with on
like your Monday brainstorm and then you
can go okay these are the 60 topics that
we're going to come up with. What are
like the four lead magnets that we need
that would be like you know cover the
gambit and be like the right thing to
then lead people from these topics on
LinkedIn to these lead magnets. So from
here basically like you have your
newsletter and again it doesn't need to
be every week. you have these topics
going out, you have these lead magnets,
like you could just dive into those
slightly more and that's a newsletter.
And it comes down to too like early on
to how quick are you looking to scale
things and monetize all this? Well,
every time you send a newsletter, right,
it's got the CTA to the work with us
page. And so if you're looking to get
things going, that's your trigger,
right? Cuz all these people are now in
that, all these people you've been
talking about, you're talking with all
through your travels, all the people
that are on LinkedIn that have been
getting into the newsletter there,
that's your database. you know, you're
gonna have like a bunch of coffee in the
newsletter doing its thing.
>> And then you may describe like like an
organic little blurb that leads to like,
oh, by the way, like we've been seeing a
lot of our clients like asking us for
this like if you're curious about how
we'd work with people just like, you
know, click this link and then it will
get into a little bit more coffee and
then like kind of maybe have like a sign
off Harry and then just say like by the
way like want to want to work with us in
some way, get on a call with me or my
team. Yeah, just last couple things you
guys have brought up like, okay,
LinkedIn's good, but what about all
these other platforms? And then kind of
like the orc chart you would need on a
media team. Let's first just talk about
like back and napkin how to think about
the actual content, right? So you have
these like LinkedIn long form post going
out, right? Your best LinkedIn long form
post can inspire like a newsletter as an
example. The same thing you would take
your best LinkedIn post after 2 months.
So just focus there for now, right? But
you're actually getting your YouTube
content strategy done at the same time
because your best LinkedIn stuff is
going to give you data on, you know,
what do people really care about, what
drives clients, and that becomes your
YouTube videos down the road. Similarly,
if you start posting on X, right, these
long form posts, you could literally
just take the exact same content and
probably just put it right on X.
Similarly, you know, as you start moving
to like IG, these LinkedIn long form
posts probably have an image in them.
And those images can go into things
like, you know, IG posts and cut downs
of your YouTube
>> could be like, you know, YouTube shorts
and the same stuff could become like IG
reels. In a sense, like the quickest way
to build this omniresent strategy is to
first just focus on like the minimum
viable, which is like LinkedIn and
newsletter. you get that right. You're
you actually are doing all this other
stuff,
>> you know,
>> and what's the production cost? Because
that's what I've always thought like if
we if we need to do that well,
>> we got to do it well. If we're going to
do it, we got to do it really well. And
I want it to be professional.
>> Blog versus media company. Most people
want to go and build up a media company,
but quickly find themselves building
some rinky dink blog. And I think one
thing that people get stuck with there
is the org chart that's required to
build an actual media company. We're not
talking about hiring people on Fiverr.
We're talking about going and finding
people that can help you build a
Ferrari. And the truth is, when you're
building that out, you need to view
people as investments versus expenses.
If you go and try to hire the cheapest
person, yeah, you're going to find
yourself running some rinky dink blog.
But you start going and actually valuing
people for their skill set, the real
additive skills they can go and add to
your organization. Going and looking at
people as real investments, people that
you know they can go and produce, say,
30 pieces of content for you in a given
month. and you know that from those 30
pieces of content, you're going to go
and finally get five dream clients. So,
they're not just some cost center for
your business. These are people that are
going to drive real cash flows and
profit to you. You know, the question
is, are you looking to build a media
company or just some blog? When you're
building an omniresent team, you're
likely going to have basically like a a
content manager.
>> Yeah.
>> Similarly, you are going to want like a
creative director for the brand. That
could be you know you Harry as an
example but I could see you being the
you're the CEO from my understanding and
the creative director is going to be
that brand team you mentioned now as you
go and start thinking about the
different platforms. I think the obvious
way to think about it would be like
there's video and a video department and
then you have content like written kind
of department and then you'd have copy
over here which we'll talk about over
here like more like your newsletter
area. These are kind of like your
different areas. So you're going to have
likely basically like a CEO of the
newsletter who's going to be some like
badass writer. So on the content side,
you're going to have like basically like
a social writer. Typically, you want
someone different than the newsletter
writer, okay? Because like this is the
person that's doing stuff for X and for
LinkedIn. On your video side, you're
typically going to have like an actual
like videographer and you're going to
have long form editors for YouTube and
short form editors if you do short form
content. And so the content manager is
like, you know, the one keeping this
whole squad together. The only last
piece is that you're going to want a
social manager, right? Someone to
actually go and post the content. The
next piece is that you're the content
manager right now, right?
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. But you're are you hoping to be
that for a long time?
>> Yeah. I mean, I enjoy it.
>> Yeah. And I think for this role, like
because of where it is, I you're going
to want to talk to like I would talk to
50 A players, you know, that's like, you
know, a kind of early person potentially
like we we'll just talk like in first
stage, right? First stage. We need the
writer for the newsletter. and we need a
social writer for X and LinkedIn. I
mean, mostly just LinkedIn to start
with. That's stage one. Like, it's
really that simple is the nice thing,
right? Then the next part from there is
you're probably then looking for sure
like you're going to need a social
manager. The third piece then is you're
probably then looking to move into like
video and that's where you start
building this operation out. So,
throughout this session, I get deep into
the org chart and content waterfall
system as well as my LinkedIn OS. And if
you want to follow along and go and fill
out these systems so you're almost in
the room with us, you can go and get
this entire guide via the link in the
description. So go download that and
follow along. And in terms of like the
different stages, so you know the budget
per stage, we'll talk about like just
incremental budget just to do like phase
one. So you have this writer, that
person's um going to be 8K back in
Atkin. The content manager is probably
10K and social writer back at napkin 8K.
This could be plus or minus this is
monthly
>> month.
Yeah. So you're looking at like V1 25K a
month
>> and you're like up and going with like a
pretty good like
>> with sorry with a really solid like
written publication getting stuff out
there you know getting that
sophisticated kind of content
infrastructure going out getting the
voice right getting the messaging
building like the V1 media company here.
So stage two then we're probably just
like filling some of the gaps here. So
some people are like like we want to
scale to the next level. We've noticed
like some areas are breaking. You know,
again, I think one area that's going to
break first is like social manager.
There's just be a lot of content you're
going to want to start posting soon. And
it's like, okay, we need to get some
help. That person's 10K max. You can
probably get them for like 6, 7, 8,
depending on how you want to do it. You
may also just like add a budget like I
know you guys are design forward. And
so, you probably have like potentially a
design budget just for stuff, you know,
whether it's infographics for LinkedIn,
little images you're going to put in the
newsletter, making the landing pages
look badass. Yeah, that could even be an
earlier thing, but you know, back in
Aken now you're at another incremental,
say 20k per month. And then when you
start to go the video direction, this is
where you're adding like a lead video
producer, videographer just when you're
shooting, editors when you have stuff.
Let's just say back in napkin, you got a
video producer, let's say back in napkin
for 10k. We have videographers say doing
four videos long for a month at 1,500
each, that's 6K. If they're doing say 10
to 12 short form videos at 150 each,
1,800 bucks, let's just say pack a
napkin for short form approximate like
budget here is like Yeah. 18K. That can
sound like a lot to some people, right?
45 like so 63.
>> Yeah.
>> 63K a month or a year, you know, you're
looking at like what is that? 7 720 or
some [\h__\h] Where it comes down to is
essentially when you think about that
dream customer that we were making all
this content for in the first place.
What is that person worth to you a year
or over like the life cycle that they
work with you?
>> Okay, so let's just let's put some
numbers in it.
>> Sure. A 10 million client will earn us
between 50 and 100,000 a year. So that
client is 10 million 50 basis points low
as 50. It can be as much as 1%. That's
100, you know. So let's say midpoint
75,000 comes in a year from each each 10
million.
>> Sure. So let's just let's just keep it
conservative. So, let's just say it's
actually 75, but let's just make it
30,000, okay? Just because then it's
like, okay, let's make this make sense
under like even more conservative
numbers, right? And each month under
this whole operation, right? So, you
have one YouTube video coming out per
week as an example. 12 short form videos
coming out per month. You have four
newsletters that are badass that are
written by like some Financial Times
like editor that now you've poached and
is now running your [\h__\h] You have a
monle copywriter making your [\h__\h] look
like insane. and you're building like
this apple for like the 1% kind of vibe
going. The question is like can all of
that go and drive you two clients a
month? Because if it can just drive two
clients a month, it breaks even. If
you're looking to go and scale your
media company, build out your team with
the right structure, system, support,
and mentorship from me directly, you
should definitely go and check out
Founder OS. This is the high growth
community that I've created for founders
just like you. And you can go and apply
via the link in the description. these
kind of this strategy too serves the
people that are just on the fence right
now. There's all these people just on
the fence that are like I've been
between you guys and a couple others and
this that all of this just helps get
them across the finish line.
>> Yeah.
>> Well, big prospects. I mean, even if we
got five of them, it would pay.
>> Yeah.
>> Well, that's the whole point.
>> It would pay,
>> right? So, there you have it. This is
how to go and apply these content
operating systems to go and build a
media company in your industry. If
Hundle can do it in the boring wealth
management industry, well, it will
probably work for you and your company
as well. Now, if you're interested in
seeing the whole LinkedIn system from A
to Z, you should definitely go and check
out this video. I appreciate you
watching this. Be sure to like and
subscribe, and I'll see you in the next
one.