I had a call last night with my wealth
advisor
and we were talking about retirement.
I hit my number a while ago
and I like to chop it up with Steven
just around
the philosophy around money.
And we were talking about
the idea
of you know, once you've hit a number
how your mindset should change.
This idea that if you wake up
any morning
and you don't want to go to work that
day
well then you probably just shouldn't,
right? Cuz you've already hit that
number and there's no sense just working
more
when it's not actually making you happy.
Go find something that really makes you
happy.
And also just got me thinking, well, why
the hell should you wait for retirement
for that kind of mode? Right? Why not
live every day retirement, right? Trying
your best every day
to do you want and architect your
life.