The most dangerous thing in your
business isn't a bad [music] decision.
It's a good opportunity you said yes to
at the wrong time. Saying no to a good
opportunity, I get it. It can feel
terrible. But saying yes to a bad one,
that pain is physical. As a founder, you
already know you need to train your eyes
for a good opportunity. But what most
founders forget is that you also need to
train your eye for the bad ones. The
problem is never a lack of new ideas. It
was a lack of executing the ones that
you already have. Gary Keller put it
this way. What's the one thing you could
do such that by doing it, everything
else becomes easier or unnecessary?
Here's [music] your action step. Write
out everything on your plate right now.
Then ask yourself, what is the 4% of
this list that's going to drive me 64%
[music] of the actual impact? The math
compounds in both directions. You decide
where it goes, right? Clear out the
rest, set your default answer to no, and
[music] protect the few things that
actually matter.