Okay.
So, personal board meeting. This time
every month, you do a reflection on how
you did the previous month and then go
and chart out your goals. So, I'm going
to go through my July personal board
meeting right now. So, starting off, we
got our personal board of adviserss,
right? These are the people that are
helping me go and scale out my
businesses. People across strategy,
tech, sales, AI, copywriting, everything
in between. Building an a team, design,
traveling, coaching, copywriting,
built-in distribution, day one,
automating tasks, soulful journey,
memberships, and community. My one big
domino every single day is to have an
unbeatable 4-hour deepwork system that
produces at least one highquality,
exceptional piece of high lever content
every single day. Content is the fuel
for all of my businesses. It drives
organic growth. It drives top talent to
what I'm doing. It helps propel the
movement. It drives conversions,
viewers, applications. We've been
crushing it there with consistent
exceptional content. And then I kind of
chart that out over 30 days, even over
the year, of the one thing I need to do
that will make everything else easier or
unnecessary. So on the personal 30-day
goals, we had to book a 1 week writing
week. So we got that done. It actually
ended up being here in Norway. I am in
Rafain Norway right now. Been hiking,
enjoying life, ripping it. Getting a
house in Europe. So, I am heading to
Portugal, then to North Visa, then to
Marba to go and look at homes uh and
looking to get a European home base. So,
that project is underway at the moment.
Stay tuned. And if you have any
recommendations for spots I should be
checking out, feel free to put that in
the comments below. I'll be looking. We
are well underway there. That's all
moving. Sleep hygiene's been good. We're
getting our 8 hours of sleep. So here
you can see, you know, I have, you know,
our goal, which we've crushed, of 600K
monthly cash collected in July. So I'm
charting out all the little tasks that
need to get done in July to go and make
this happen. As I go through the month,
I'm checking this about 3, four times a
week and crossing out the tasks as we
complete them. Simply just kind of
ripping through stuff here. Um, so we
set up our low ticket funnel, a whole
funnel that integrates into our HubSpot
that drives people to different low
ticket products between $29 and $149
that I sell. And we've been showing our
work daily, which has been awesome.
We'll cross that off. We optimized the
email course. We showed our work daily
here. We've been designing some magic.
Got our upsells ribbon. Good [\h__\h] So,
books to read. Hammered through this. I
read generally about two books every
week, sometimes one. So, we've crushed
through a lot of these here and are off
to the races. Generally, what I like to
do, assuming that the author is still
live and the books I'm reading, is I'll
actually go and outreach to that author
and try to set up a call just to go and
chop it up. That's the power of having a
big audience online. People actually go
and answer your DMs, which is awesome.
So, I've been doing that though my whole
life. This is how I, you know, raised,
you know, $6 million for Herb, um, is
just by reaching out to people, um, and
making a habit of trying to reach out to
a few people a day, um, just to build my
network. And so here you can see I'm
revisiting my vision every month. Right
now, you know, 10 year goals are things
like being madly in love with my wife
and having an amazing family, epic road
trip, simplicity, retired, just doing
art every day. Um, I see myself these
days as more of an artist than an
entrepreneur. So, lots of big goals
there. We're publishing the book this
year, which is going to be dropped in a
few months. currently here in Lafeton
and have a big little trip here to get a
home in Europe over the next couple
months, but then heading out to Bali for
an epic founder retreat we're hosting
there and then to Japan snowboarding for
the winter. So, some big things planned
there. So, over the next 90 days, we
are, you know, getting this book
published, continuing to, you know,
manifest this home base in Europe, which
is a big big milestone. I have plans
near the end of the year to go to India.
What I've learned with success is that
there is one key concept I've learned
from the book called the slight edge.
It's that everything is a curve. It's
either an upward curve or a downward
curve. And obviously as a successful
person, you want to ride that upward
curve. That upward curve is the
combination of every decision that you
make, right? Every touch point, every
email, every message, every call, every
move you make. And so you want to make
sure that you're making one good move
after the other, right? asking yourself,
you know, is this one thing I'm doing
right now going to help my compounding
in life, right? And compound me in a
great way. So, I like to ask myself
things like, you know, does this support
the peace in my life, the profit, the
purpose? Is this the one thing I should
be doing right now that will make
everything else easier or unnecessary?
And then sometimes I ask myself honestly
just what makes the best story. And
that's probably how I found myself here
in Norway was just figured this would be
really fun, good chance to get away. So
said, "Fuck it. Let's do it." All right.
So looking at Gondess's visions too, I
go then through the marketing calendar
and this is the most important part of
July though, right? So we're at the end
of the July. So I'm going to reflect on
what went well. Tons of hiking in. You
know, I was able to get a lot of reading
in. I loved reading. Unreasonable
hospitality. What else? Norway was epic.
Lots of creativity and design
improvements. and we finished the book
manuscript which was a huge milestone
cuz I've been going through like tons
and tons of that over the last few
years. What didn't go well? I think
there's some improvements to be made on
the team and velocity. Always trying to
increase the level of velocity on the
team. I think that you know honestly
everything's going pretty well though so
it's pretty hard to find things but I
always like to try and find some stuff
that I can improve. Um, I think we can
do a better job with our YouTube growth
engine and continue just to reinforce
it, make it better. Actually, that's it.
I think that's it. So, where did I learn
the importance? You know, always I
policy always learning this the
importance of amazing talent, right? We
made some new talent adjustments on
Founder OS and Herb did that a game
changer. So, just constantly reinvesting
in talent. learned the importance of
energy um and vibe on our sales team.
We've been leaning into the culture
there um and the vibe and it's been
amazing. Everyone's vibing on a high
level, loving their lives. We're all
learning together. It feels like every
week it's like a you know leadership
group all kind of getting together and
just upping one another's game and so
that's been something that's been an
amazing learning. I've also learned I
love Europe, hence why I want to get a
home here. Um get a home here. Yeah,
hiking freeze my mind. Yeah, I don't
know. We need a little uh little yogurt
break.
Authenticity equals sharing the real
behind these scenes moments. This is
what people really want to see from you.
I've been surveying more and more people
on Instagram and on YouTube and more and
more people like, "Dude, just show us
behind the scenes of your life, what
you're struggling with, what's going
on." Right? So, this is it a step
forward, right? Just showing you guys
how I kind of do my thing. So, here we
go. That's the July board meeting. Now,
because August is around the corner,
it's July 26th right now. We start to go
and make the August board meeting here
and make a copy of this. And then what
I'll go do is chart this thing out and
just go update it. We keep the personal
board advisor the same every single
month, unless I'm adding new people, but
right now that's solid. As I'm scaling
this YouTube growth engine, trying to
get YouTube to a million subs this year,
we have, you know, some big things
underway. We got we're adding people to
our team. I'm also part of a YouTube
mind meldd which is a YouTube
mastermind, right? And I just want to
point out to you guys the importance of
having a mastermind. If you're looking
to go and grow faster in your given area
and scale up, it's important that you
surround yourself with the right people
that are going to help you go and hit
your goals, right? You are the product
of the five people that you spend the
most time with. And so for me, if I'm
looking to go and up my YouTube game, as
an example, I'm surrounding myself with
people like Olly Abdoll, Dan Martell,
and the list goes on, right? a group of
legends inside of this mindmel that are
all going upping one another's game and
helping each other get to the next
level. So just a quick tidbit there. I
have this basically on my computer, but
I also have this on my phone right on my
Google Slides. And so I can check this
multiple times a day when I'm in an
Uber, when I'm traveling, when I'm on an
airplane. I can see it. I can envision
it. I can feel it. I can, you know,
really embody this in every decision
that I make, right? Getting that slight
edge in everything that I do. The real
part here is when it comes to my
personal 30-day goals here. So, we got a
house in Europe we're getting. We got
the mobility daily amazing sleep
hygiene. We're going to read four books.
What else are we going to do this month?
We're going to finish illustrations for
the book. So, there we go. Keep it
simple. I don't overdo it over here. So,
what I'll do is all the stuff that I did
last month. I'll just cross this stuff
off and then launch AI agent launch 21
days of profit email course. Launch new
company dashboard. Film three videos in
Lisbon. Go and see
six potential
homes in Lisbon. Then we're going to go
in Northiza. Do this again cuz I just
like to keep that there. Optimize the
email course. Send book to 10 beta
readers.
Film 20 short videos. Yeah, that's
pretty good. We're going to do make a
new goal here. So, we're going to get to
700K. Bingo. All right, new book. So,
what I generally go here is do my
reading list here. You can see all the
books that I've read this year so far.
So, things like Wobbishabi, Be Here Now
by Rahm Doss, Let Them Theory by Mel
Robbins, Perennial Seller by Ryan
Holidayiday, really good book. The next
ones that we are going to be reading
here, I'm going to read Kitchen
Confidential by Anthony Bourdain, the
legend. If you guys really want to, you
know, up your game, I think it's all
about, you know, reading regularly.
Reading is such a superpower, right? You
get to like go and learn from legends
and almost putting them on as your
mentor in a sense. Let's read some stuff
by Senica, probably. Honestly, I just
read books that interest me. I think the
most important thing is just to always
be reading. Inevitably, you just read a
lot. And every book that I read teaches
me something new in life. Um, that helps
me just take how I think, my mindset uh
to the next level. So always be reading
folks. Then I kind of revisit my vision
which stays the same. I'm just always
looking at this. So nothing changes
there. And then same thing over here.
All good. This is our marketing
calendar. So you can see in October,
November, we got Black Friday, Cyber
Monday coming around the corner. So I'll
probably start working on that. So now
that I look at it, that is kind of the
board meeting. You know, here we go.
August personal board advisor done. We
got our domino personal 30-day goals
done. Business goals done. Books we're
going to read, visions clear, calendar
done, and then I'll clear this off. So
this will be my reflection for end of
August. Nice and clean, ready to go. So
what I then do is I pull this down into
my desktop here. I just make it a so
that means August my board meeting. I
bring my July one. Now the cool thing
here y'all is like look at this MG
folder here. I go here and see I have
all these board meetings. And the
tribute part is let's go to MG and I can
go all the way back to like May. I don't
even know when this is May 2022. Oh my
god. I can rewind back to May 2022 here.
Cool thing is I still have that icky
guy. And what's changed? Well, I've
optimized this consistently now for
about 3 years. And it's trippy because
like I'm living it, right? Hiking,
mountain biking, living the dream,
coaching founders, you know, traveling
the world, living the dream, right? Like
it's all coming true. What will you do?
I'm going to set my personal brand on
fire. Back here, I said I get my Twitter
to 100K, LinkedIn to 100K, email to 50K.
Now my Twitter's at 360K, LinkedIn's at
840K, emails at 190K. Pretty insane. I
said I'd launch a soul for
entrepreneurship course. Well, now I run
something called Founder OS, helping
founders achieve their dreams through
proven systems. And you know, that's
what we're all about, right? If you're
interested in applying to Foundest, you
can go and check it out via the link in
the description. Um, definitely want to
check it out. If you're looking to get
mentorship from me directly and my team,
my seuite, over 50 live sessions with us
every single month. But you can see how
small I was starting here, right? I
wanted to have a community product that
would bring in 500k a year. Now we do
10x that. I want to get Herb to are on
autopilot. It now does that. The books
I'm going to read again. You can see I
was always just investing in books and
upping my game in personal development.
You want to go and rise in success, you
have to rise as a leader. And the way to
rise as a leader is to invest in
personal development. Personal
development is the key to your success
because you need to upgrade yourself.
I've been doing this for a long, long
time. I've actually been doing this
almost, you know, probably 8 years now.
It's been the most powerful system in my
life. So, if you're looking to go and
complete your own personal board
meeting, you should go and check out the
template I've put in the description. Go
and make sure that on the last Saturday
or Sunday of every month, you are
reflecting on your previous month and
then charting out your next month's
board meeting. And then I would
encourage you to be revisiting it every
single morning. It should be dictating
what you do that day, what your tasks
are. It should dictate how you're going
and improving not just your business,
but living a more vibrant life. And so
this is the most powerful system I've
ever created. I wanted to go and give it
to you because I want you guys to go and
be able to achieve the kind of life that
I've been able to achieve here. Um, and
be a part of this amazing founder
freedom movement. A community, a
movement of founders that are dedicated
to achieving true freedom. It's all
about action, guys. Thank you so much
for tuning in, for being a part of the
founder freedom movement, and let's win
together.