Every time Elon Musk walks into a room,
he asks one question that saves him
millions of dollars. While most founders
ask, "How do I improve this?" Elon asks,
"Why the [\h__\h] does this exist?" Elon has
an algorithm that he uses across all of
his businesses. And [music] the first
part of that algorithm is not automate,
not delegate, not add more things. It's
delete. Because [music] the truth is,
you shouldn't automate or delegate
something that shouldn't even exist in
the first [music] place. So much of the
world is going to go and kind of
brainwash you into just adding more and
more and more. But I think the real
thing you're looking to do is subtract
all of those things to the core essence
of what you need to do to be successful
in your business, which often times is
super simple.