If you're a founder growing your
business and still the one creating all
of your content, well, I get it. You're
probably burning out. You're exhausted.
You're overwhelmed, and you're looking
for some help. It took me 4 years of
trial and error to perfect this AI
content system. And in this video, I'm
going to show you three tools, my
complete system, and one secret
checklist I've never shared before
that's going to help make your content
easy leveraging AI. Let's get into it.
So, starting off here, I like to use a
tool called Poppy AI. Quick note, this
video is sponsored by them, but I've
been using Poppy for the last 6 months.
It is insanely valuable. Like I
mentioned, I've used over a 100
different AI tools, and Poppy passes my
test, and I'll show you how I use it
here in a second. But if you're
interested in using them, you can go and
check them out via the link in the
description. So, this is my Poppy AI
Goat script writing board. Now, if
you're interested in how I use this
board and how I set it up, you can go
and check out this video over here where
I get into all the details as to how I
leverage Poppy for things like my
titles, my scripts, my concepts, my
thumbnails, and overall growing my
YouTube channel. What I want to show you
here is I'm going to go and use this
board now to go and come up with ideas
for some upcoming videos on my YouTube
channel. Let's get into it. We are
looking at this board here. And what
I've gone and done here is I've added
every single one of my most popular
videos here to this popular videos board
inside of Poppy. In addition to that, I
have all of these different systems that
help me with things like title, intros,
thumbnails, scripts, all of those
systems, right? They come from this
overall board synthesizing the
transcripts of all of my most popular
content out there on YouTube. Now again,
if you want to go and learn how to set
this up, you can go and check out this
video over here. So, what we're going to
go do is we're going to go to my YouTube
channel. Now, the cool thing is I can go
and copy this link. I can paste it into
Poppy AI. Now, it's going and
synthesizing all the titles and
everything that exist on my YouTube
page. I can then go and hook up a
YouTube chat window here. So, this AI
chat, I can connect it to my YouTube
channel. Here you can see it's
synthesizing all of the different
titles, the YouTube videos that I have
and now it's connected to um this AI
chat which is hooked up to Claude for
Sonnet. So there we go. We got my
channel and now we've got this. So what
I'm going to go and do is I'm just going
to put I need you to go and leveraging
the kind of topics that I talk about on
my channel. Go and come up with 15
irresistible YouTube titles that will
help me go and convert people at a
click-through rate of above 10%. I want
you to make these for maximum intrigue,
value, being insanely generous. Make
sure that they're on brand, helping
founders go and build their own founder
brands through beautiful systemized,
sustainable systems. Now, it's going and
analyzing my channel. Okay? And it's
coming up with a bunch of different
titles here. Okay? So, you know, as with
anything with AI, right, you need to
make sure that you're actually, you
know, using your own human ingenuity
here as well, right? We're not just
taking anything as it is, right? We're
always going and adding our own spark
and creativity. What I see is like the
future with AI is that creators go from
always being the one that has to build
things from the ground up to just having
an assistant along the way with you,
right? But you still have to be that
editor, that chief detail officer, that
person that is looking at the details
and making sure that, you know, the
stuff is just right. So, we got things
like, I built a $10 million business
working 20 hours a week. Here's my exact
system. The 4-hour founder, how I
automated my entire business,
step-by-step blueprint. Why 99% of
founders burn out and the 1% who build
systems instead. You know, I replaced
myself in my own company. Here's how you
can, too. The $1 million mistake every
founder makes that keeps them trapped.
So, here it goes. I'm just looking
through these. They're looking pretty
solid. How I designed a business that
runs without me while I travel the
world. All right. So, we're going to go
with this one here. Why 99% of founders
burn out and the 1% who build systems
instead. Now I can go and take that
title idea and bring it over to my next
AI tool which I use Claude for. So
inside of Claude, people use this a lot
of different ways, but I want to show
you how I hook this up in a way that I
think is better than 99% of other
founders out there. So I go and I have
different Claude projects based on all
of the different content formats that I
use. So things like Instagram reels, um
X content, Clockwork, which is like how
I go and I remove myself from the
operations of my business. So I have a
project inside a cloud just for that. In
addition, I have YouTube concepting or
script writing. I have my Instagram
carousel stuff, email courses, the list
goes on. The key thing here, right, is
that using AI correctly is the
combination of actually going and having
an amazing prompt and then also making
sure that the project has enough context
as well. So you want to make sure that
the project knowledge is hooked up
incredibly well. Let's go to the YouTube
script writing piece. Now the another
piece I want to give you here. So, we
have the title, okay, of the video. What
I want to show you is how I go and hook
up the project knowledge. I want to show
you how I go and prompt this. And then
I'm also going to go and show you a
little bit about how I think about
filming my videos. Let's start with the
prompting here. So, here you can see my
YouTube goat prompt. Now, if you're
interested in a template of this prompt
for yourself, so you can use it to go
and scale up and hook up your own cloud
project, you can go and check it out via
the link in the description. I've gone
and given you every single piece of it
so you can go and customize it to your
brand, your channel, your content
categories, and be able to go and start
making YouTube concepts fast. Now, my
approach to this is simply to give it as
much detail as possible. Look at the
amount of detail that I put into this
prompt. Okay, this is no joke. So, I'll
give you a sense of it. You are a
YouTube script writing expert who
generates billions of views for the best
YouTube creators and entrepreneurs in
the world. Please create the YouTube
title, hook, and script with a research
from Matt below. Create a script that
uses the best YouTube retention tactics
to create an amazing hook, script with
tension, and climax that keeps the
viewer glued to the very end. Then I say
you can review, you know, refer to the
how to create a killer YouTube video to
blow up your channel, full transcript,
and a bunch of other resources there.
So, we've got that there in the
instructions inside of the project
knowledge here. Now, okay, what I have
is I have my entire book outline, my
entire book transcript of over 300,000
words. I have transcribed my six most
popular YouTube videos ever, you know,
including this one, which is 0 to 100K
followers on any platform. This one over
here, which is LinkedIn, my ultimate
guide to growth there. This video over
here, which is starting a business from
nothing, do this. And then I've also
gone and provided it with a bunch of our
curriculum. I've also gone and uploaded
all of my different offers here as well
and a lot of my core languaging. So
things like words like personal media
company, the four W's, controlling where
you work, when you work, what you work
on, who you work with, so that it has
all of my languaging. From there, I can
simply go and put in here, and I'm going
to show you another tool here in a sec I
do this with. I need you to go and
create a YouTube concept around the
title below using all of the copy and
stuff that I've created previously in my
book, in my YouTube videos, and in all
the stuff in the project knowledge.
Okay, now I paste in the title we have
there, which is why 99% of founders burn
out, and the 1% who build systems
instead. And then let it rip. So, the
key thing here, right, is that we've got
like a three-page prompt we've made. We
have gone and based this title off of my
channel using Poppy AI. We have the
project knowledge all updated with
probably around 500,000 words that I
have written. So, we're not just taking
Claude out of the box and just saying,
"Hey, rip some BS template script or
concept, right? We're actually getting
it to go and create content based on my
words." And it's essentially going and
synthesizing some of my best stuff that
I've ever made and then packaging it in
a way that fits this title. What this is
doing is just saving me time, right? So
that I don't have to go necessarily
synthesize all this myself. It helps me
just get my juices going. Almost like a
research assistant, which many larger
YouTube channels have research
assistants, have, you know, content
managers, all that. The cool thing is
that on my team, I only need myself, a
content manager, and then video editors,
right? And with that, we can go and
build my channel to 165K plus subs in
the last couple years. We can go and
build a content waterfall that allows us
to create one piece of content into 30
other pieces of content. And we're able
to do this in a lean, mean team. So,
this is the power of using Claude,
right, and using this AI stack. But
you're going to want to know the next
tool, which I'll show you in a minute as
well. So, here you can see it's gone and
flushed out the entire concept. Okay.
Now, what I often do, because I actually
don't script my videos totally, right? I
don't need it to be this scripted. So,
sometimes what I'll ask it to then go
and do, can you go and actually
synthesize this into a one-page cheat
sheet that I can use that when I'm
recording, I just have one page that
gives me a sense of the general points I
need to cover, including three different
highly engaging retentive hooks that
guarantee that the video has a 70%
retention at 1 minute. All right, so
that is ripping. Now, what I like to
sometimes do is just have, you know, a
one-pager. Okay? And so, an example of
this is sometimes I go and I get this
one pager. I then go and write and edit
it myself. I then can go and kind of
print it off so that right before I'm
recording, just similar to like a
newscaster before they're going and
delivering the news. I've kind of able
to read things, get a sense of the
general vibe I'm trying to accomplish
with the video, and then boom, we're off
to the races. And so, here you can see
I've got a recording cheat sheet. now
gone and good to go, which I generally
will go and edit this myself and then
print it off. Here we can see we've got
three different hooks for this. So 3
years ago, I was answering Slack at 2
a.m. next to my sleeping girlfriend,
million-dollar business, but it owned me
completely. The 1% who escaped this
understand something that 99% completely
miss. And I'm about to show you the
exact system they use. Even if you're
drowning right now, even if you can't
step away for 5 minutes, fair warning,
once you see how simple this is, you'll
be pissed at how long you've been doing
it the hard way. I mean, pretty damn
good. I'm going to edit that, put it in
my own words a little bit better. So,
here we go. We have this whole concept
done. So, what I would generally do is
I'll take this, copy it, bring it over
here, open up a Google doc. I can go and
open that Google doc, put that all into
it. Boom. recording cheat sheet for why
99% of founders burn out. And I will
then go and edit this. And bam, we've
got ourselves a concept. You're probably
wondering now, well, Matt, how do you do
your videos? You know, do you teleprompt
them? Do you just, you know, build a
concept, then go over them? Early on in
my days, I did teleprompt some of my
videos, okay? Because candidly, I wasn't
that confident on camera yet. I was
often times nervous. I didn't know if I
was like really that good at presenting
myself. What I've done though over the
years is realize that it's just so much
more fun speaking off the cuff, being
real, being genuine, and building that
deep resonance with you guys. And so I
do not teleprompt my videos at all
anymore. They are all just off-the- cuff
delivering the value. And that's why
these like onepage cheat sheets are
useful because they just give me a
general vibe as to the sort of stuff
that I can cover in the video based on
all of the content that I've ever made
and all of my most up-to-date systems
which I've all uploaded to Claude as
well as to Poppy. So that as I'm
creating videos, it can just help me
remember some of the key concepts that
may be relevant for this specific title
and concept. So then what I have is, you
know, my one pager good to go. Print
that off. I'm able to go and read that a
couple times, get a sense of the vibe,
kind of combine both what's in that one
pager with just what I feel like
bringing up in any given moment, right?
And then just rip it. And I'm not
looking for perfection. I'm looking to
just make something that I feel proud of
that delivers you guys value and helps
you guys go and scale up your own
founder brands. You may be wondering,
"Well, Matt, cool. I get it. you just
rip these things now off the one pager,
but you know, do you have any tips
there? You know, I hate delivering stuff
to the camera. Um, and I need some
assistance there. Well, I want to give
you one bonus here, okay? And I've
included this as well in the link in the
description. This is my filming
checklist. I have this in a note in my
phone, and often times before going and
recording a video just like this, I'll
go and read this. Now, I'm going to show
you my favorite part of this, but again,
you can get this all via the link in the
description. So, here are some filming
notes that I like to consider. Loosen
the grip, right? Don't take it so
seriously. You know, make it an activity
of play, expression, and service rather
than pressure. Right? I'm just trying to
give as much value to you guys as
possible. Help you guys out. And if in
one way or another, I'm helping evolve
your own strategy, your systems, the
simplicity in your business, and in your
life, even just 1 to 2% each video, then
I think I'm doing my job to help you
guys level up. And that's something I
can feel good about. And what I'll
remind myself of is this sort of mantra
before filming, which is this is fun.
This is easy. I'm here to share, not to
perform. Let's roll. Okay? And what I
would encourage you to do is go into the
guide that I've put in the link in the
description. Go and copy and paste that
into a note in your phone. And next time
you go to film something or, you know,
you're on a podcast or putting yourself
out there, remind yourself, this is fun.
This is easy. I'm here to share, not to
perform. Let's roll. So, that is my
filming checklist. I hope you find that
useful. Let's get into the last tool
that's going to help speed up your
content creation. One thing you probably
notice me doing in this video is often
time just talking into my computer in
many different ways. Okay, I use a tool
called Whisper Flow. Okay, the cool
thing here is that I think we live in a
day and age where you should not be
typing too often. With Whisper Flow, you
don't need to type, right? You just
speak, right? And it's like effortless
voice dictation in every application so
that you're four times faster on your
computer. This tool is cool. Right now,
what you can go and do is say I'm in
this chat window here inside of Claude.
I can go and just put know, hey, I want
you to now go and come up with 15
natural questions that I can go and
answer at the end of this video. And
then I'm going to go and provide really
organic answers to that so that when I'm
going and creating the video, it feels
as authentic, as resonant as possible.
will go and come up with 15 vulnerable
questions that I can answer to help take
things to the next level. Boom. I didn't
have to type any of that. It just goes
and synthesizes everything I just said.
You can use this in any chat window. You
can use this in, you know, Chrome. You
can use this in Slack. You can use this
in your messages. Anywhere. It doesn't
matter. Okay. So, here you go. Now,
Claude is easily just coming up with
questions that I can answer at the end
of this video so that my editor has an
abundance of me being just vulnerable,
talking about things like my darkest
moments, helping, you know, people
really connect with me in a deeper way.
What's the conversation you're most
avoiding having with someone important
to you? If you lost everything tomorrow,
what's the one thing about yourself
you'd be terrified people would
discover? What advice do you give
founders that you're still terrible at
following yourself? So, these are
examples of questions that sometimes at
the end of a given YouTube filming
session, I'll actually go and answer 15
vulnerable questions so that my editors
can go and insert that into different
moments in the videos to just create a
deeper level of connection with you, the
viewer here on my channel. All right,
guys. So, these are three AI tools that
honestly have 10xed my productivity and
helped me take my content to the next
level to make it easy. I hope you've
enjoyed this. Welcome to the Founder
Freedom Movement. Like and subscribe and
let's win