comes to customers now, you want to go
and obviously make sure that your
content that you're putting out there is
converting those leads to customers.
When you're going and actually putting
out content, you want to pay attention
first off, what are people asking you
for? Looking at the comments, looking
at, you know, different responses you're
getting from your newsletter. What are
people really resonating with? I know
that a lot of the founders that I help,
they're looking to get more of their
time back. And so, I'm going to go and
create content, whether it's here on
YouTube, Instagram, X, LinkedIn, TikTok,
you name it. We're going to create
content that gives people proven systems
to get more of their time back because
we see that as founders scale, their
real desire goes from, you know, just
making more money to actually getting
more time back, which for successful
founders is the real currency. So, we
want to see what content topics really
resonate with our audience. And you can
do this a lot of ways. One amazing way
is you can go to your best customers and
go and ask them via Typeform survey,
"What is it that you're trying to
accomplish with me? What's your biggest
challenge this year? What's keeping you
up at 2:00 a.m. at night? And if I you
could wave a magic wand, what would you
want to have accomplished over the next
year?" Then you can go and create all of
those questions into a probably a Google
Sheet or an Excel Sheet, go and upload
that as a PDF to ChatGPT, and then have
ChatGPT go and come up with 100
high-converting content ideas for you
that go and serve your core market. This
is a major hack and something that can
help you go and unlock an insane amount
of high-converting content topics based
on actual research from your existing
customers that are already paying you.
So, you can take that one right to the
bank.