I've always been a writing first [music]
thinker. But at some point, my notebook
stopped creating clarity and it started
creating clutter. And that's when I
realized something uncomfortable. My
brain had quietly become the [music]
bottleneck. Here's the idea that changed
everything. Your brain is a compass, not
a hard drive. The moment I stopped using
[music] it for storage and started using
AI as a second brain, the work didn't
disappear, but the cognitive load did.
And in this video, I'm going to show you
the three ways that I use AI to go and
[music] reh harness that lost energy and
get off the hamster wheel and start
getting real leverage in my life and
[music] in my business, not more busy
work. Let's get into it. Section one,
memory offload. Mental clutter comes
from trying to remember everything.
Here's why. Most people don't realize
this invisible cost. You're spending
energy retrieving information instead of
actually creating something new. And
inevitably, that's where your real
genius is as a founder. It's that stuff
that only you can do. Inevitably, I try
to tell myself these days, if AI can do
it, let it do that stuff so that I can
just focus my mental energy on the
uniqueness that I have. Things like
creating new offers or coming up with
innovative pieces of content, filming
videos like this, or writing my book
right now. These are things that I can
do. I built a system where nothing
important lives in my head anymore. It
starts with something I do once a month.
Once a month, I sit down and have what I
call a personal board meeting. This is
really this opportunity for me to go and
analyze, you know, what are my 10ear
goals, what are my three-year goals, my
one-year goals, and then what do I need
to get done in the next 90 days to
ladder up to this big ambitious vision
that I have. From there, at the end of
every month, I also have a reflection
period where I look at what went well,
what didn't go well, and what did I
learn so I can really go and improve the
next month. I'm also doing the same on
my desktop where I have this all
organized in a Google slides. I can
simply go and download the PDF slide
deck and then insert it into the given
AI I'm using, right, which in most cases
is chat GBT and into my 10X profit
project. All right, so let me give you a
bit of behind the scenes of how I
personalize AI inside of this 10x profit
project. Okay, so first off, 38 files in
this at any given time. I think the
limit in GBT is about 40 right now. So,
you know, I'm maximizing this as much as
I can. Okay. So, it's got things like
all of our offers. It's got even our
financial model in here, which I get
from my CFO every single month. I've got
things like, you know, transcripts for
my customer. I've got my board meeting
in here. And I've got our org chart in
here as well. So, and then you can also
see that I've got extremely detailed
instructions in here. This is where most
people fail. Too skinny the prompts,
right? And what we want to have here is
fat prompts. And so you can see here,
you know, I have clear goals to get the
business to $2 million profit per month.
I want to advise me like Larry Ellison,
Elon Musk, Charlie Mer, Warren Buffett,
and Jeff Bezos, right? And then I go
through our objectives. I go through the
constraints that we currently have and
that I want to give me core systems and
then action those systems for me. Now,
the beautiful thing is that we can go
and ask this project, right? So, you've
been going and following my progress
with Founder OS over the last year. I
want you to be brutally honest with me
around what you see as the core
strengths of what we're building and my
strengths as a leader and then also
where we're falling short as a business
and where I'm falling short as a leader.
And then I want you to go and point out
specific improvements I can make
focusing on three core things. The
beautiful thing is I can be using this
on a weekly basis in ways like this to
go and level up as a leader. And often
times, you know, I find it's going to be
10 times more honest than any executive
coach I could have. Here you can see the
core strengths. It's saying that Found
has a real point of view, right? Which
is awesome because that's what we teach
founders to build with their brands.
Product depth is legitimately unfair,
right? The 180 systems, the seuite
access, live cadence, AI tools. So,
yeah, we put a hell of a lot of work
into the product. So, that makes sense.
The brand has emotional gravity. Yeah, I
think it's based on our whole story, the
infrastructure, and then [music]
strengths as a leader. Okay, no false
modesty here. You have an elite pattern
recognition. You can name the problem
better than the customer. founder led
chaos, architect versus engine. You
know, here's where I think it's most
valuable, right? Is like really seeing
the three core improvements and just
cutting through the noise, which is what
I think this project's best for.
Building a how Matt would decide
operating system. Okay, that's cool
because it basically is trying to teach
me to get the business from where it's
at now to $2 million profit per month in
the next 6 months. And so what it's
trying to make sure is that the final
bits of our operating system that may be
dependent on me are now independent of
me and my team is trained. It wants me
to ruthlessly compress the business to
three growth levers. You know, really
making sure that we're focused, as an
example, on one primary audience growth
engine, one core ascension path, and one
flagship experience. Okay, good
reflection. And then really continuing
to define my role as a system architect,
which good news is we're already all
over that. The big theme this year that
I've been training my team on is moving
me into this architect role, focusing on
really just exceptional content all the
time. Things like YouTube videos and
writing books and removing myself from
the final little bits of operations. And
so this project is super powerful and I
can't wait to see what you create with
your own version of it. I don't have to
reconstruct my thinking, right? I just
ask ChatBT, what was it that we were
focused on in Q2? What goals did I set
that I'm not hitting right now? Right?
What's the pattern that you're seeing
from me over the last 6 months? Right?
If you were to be brutally honest with
me, where do we need to improve? The AI
will respond instantly, and it's
brutally honest. It's going to give a
great analysis on where we've been, have
we hit those goals, and what are the
core patterns that keep coming up month
after month after month. So, I built a
free assessment that shows you exactly
where you're leaving AI leverage on the
table. And this is important, right?
Because I think to really get ahead as a
founder this year, you need to be using
AI correctly and in the most leveraged
way possible. Okay? And so you can go
and check out that assessment in the
description and learn where you may have
some gaps in how you're currently using
it so you can go and become more of a
systemized founder this year. That's
just one part of the equation. The next
aspect is really going to go and
compress time in your business. Section
two, decision compression. Great lives
aren't built on more decisions, right?
They're built on making fewer decisions
better. There's this motto that I remind
myself of every single day. Less but
better. less things around me, making
less decisions, but the ones that I am
making, putting all of my judgment,
data, and intuition in those to move
things forward in my business, in my
life as fast as possible. Here's how I
go and cut my decision load by 90%.
First off, we have to come to grips with
something, right? Decision fatigue is
one of the largest productivity killers
in your life. And decision fatigue
really comes when you're just making way
too many decisions. Small decisions, big
decisions, decisions from this person on
your team, then from that person. And by
the end of the day, you're just
exhausted. But here's the thing. Most
decisions don't deserve your raw
thinking. But we treat them all like we
need to do them all. And what happens is
is that you just see founders drowning
in these decisions. Hire this person or
that person, launch this offer or wait,
take this meeting or protect your time,
right? It just never stops. And the cost
is just mental exhaustion. If we can go
and get in a habit of just reserving our
cognitive load, right, for the decisions
that most need us, this is what's going
to help you not just grow fastest, but
honestly just grow in a peaceful way.
Because if you're anything like me,
right, we know that we're going to be
successful long term, likely already are
really successful already. It's not just
about making a bunch of money, being
more successful this year. Honestly,
it's just about peace of mind, knowing
that, you know, you can focus on the
stuff that you really enjoy. you can be
in flow as much as possible in your day,
enjoying your life, enjoying the process
of creating an amazing business that's
impacting millions of lives. This is
probably one of the most beautiful and
powerful use cases for, you know, things
like CHBT. Here's what I've realized,
okay? You don't need better decisions.
You typically need fewer decisions. So,
I built an AI decision filter trained on
my principles, my context, and my life.
It's not a calculator. It's not a
strategy bot. It's a decision filter
trained on my principles, my history,
and the mentors I've learned from. We're
talking like the best founders of all
time. So, this isn't some generic AI
advice, right? It's my thinking
externalized, and I use it to filter
decisions across marketing, hiring,
operations, and finance. All right. So,
what I'm going to go and show you here
is the difference between using my 10X
profit project that's loaded up with my
project files, my prompt, and all my
memory versus just generic GPD for a
common question I may wonder in a day,
which is, "My team wants me more
available for ad hoc questions
throughout the day, but my most
productive time is 3 hours of
uninterrupted deep work in the morning
for content creation. How should I
balance being accessible versus
protecting my flow time?" Here we go.
The side byside comparison here just to
show, you know, and let's see what
happens here. So normal GBT right
quicker to the punch right is saying you
know reframe the trade-off you know it's
an important mindset shift time box your
availability you know a strong default
schedule setting a clear interrupt rule
you know example I'm heads down in the
mornings but if something is truly
urgent please slack me urgent at the
start kind of lame use async to absorb
ad hoc questions instead of live
interruptions encourage questions to be
posted in a shared channel so again this
is all just kind generic advice.
Honestly, not the kind of stuff that I
would action. It's just very basic. On
the other side here, we have the 10x
profit project, which is saying this is
a classic founder constraint and your
right to protect it deliberately. The
real problem, the team wanting more ad
hoc access isn't the issue. The issue is
that your availability has become the
system that creates two bad outcomes at
once. Your highest leverage work gets
fragmented and your team never fully
upgrades their decision-making muscle.
So, here's what you should do as a
non-negotiable. Morning equals creation.
Afternoon is collaboration, right?
Right? So getting much more specific.
Okay. The solution predictable access is
greater than content constant access.
Right? So block the deep work block.
Right? Example 8 to 11:00 a.m. Create a
decision intake s system. Right? So most
ad hoc questions should come into
predictable buckets and I can
standardize how those are asked in all
of your filters. Okay. So where I
generally get interested here, right, is
when you kind of just use generic GBT,
it kind of just ends and that's that.
Whereas these ones, right, you can be
like just, you know, go and do this for
me inside of the 10x profit project and
it will just go and start standardizing
that Matt doctrine documentation and all
of the different operating rules that
need to exist. And it's even creating
the Slack announcement that I can then
go and use and send to my team in Slack
so that I can just get this going right
here, right now. So, it's going and
giving me a message I can send to my
team in a channel. You can see, right?
just making your ability to go and
implement this stuff 10 times faster. I
don't even really need to decide
anymore. It kind of just does it all for
me. All right. So, you see the
difference here. This one is trained on
the internet. The other one is trained
on me. It has an insane amount of
context, memory, and history with me to
know what the best version of me would
do in this situation versus just some
generic advice. You know, if you're
making the right calls, but they're not
turning into repeatable systems, well,
you're not creating leverage. You're
just creating more work for yourself.
And that's what we're trying to tackle
here. You've got enough on your plate,
right? I think that being a founder,
being a builder is one of the hardest
jobs in the world. You have pressure
sometimes coming you from multiple
directions, right? You got a team and
lights you got to keep on every month.
And you've got this big hairy audacious
vision that you have for your life in
your business, a whole crew of people in
terms of your team, a community, and
customers that you're all trying to go
and rally in that direction. Truthfully,
I think you can use all the help you can
get. And that's what we're tackling
next. If you're wondering where you can
actually go and get help like this,
right, and go and implement this stuff
right now, well, I'd recommend going and
checking out the 10-minute AI readiness
assessment via the link in the
description below. You can go and simply
go through this, score yourself across
memory, decisions, and systems. And what
we typically see is most founders score
around 37% capacity. And so, they're
leaving honestly a lot of juice on the
table there. So go and download that,
score yourself and book a call if you
want to learn more about the systems
that we use inside of founder OS to
install this AI leverage directly with
you inside of your business. So now let
me go and show you the third AI lever.
This is where it all compounds. Section
three, systemization. Here's how I used
AI to turn everything that lived in my
head into repeatable, scalable
infrastructure. This is the real magic.
So, what we're always looking for are
those things that we find we're
repeatedly doing and trying to go and
systemize that stuff, document it, and
then upload it to AI so that it can
start doing that stuff as good, if not
better than us. Okay, about a year ago,
I realized something that was pretty
terrifying. There were parts of my
business that only existed in my head.
And that's not good because then it just
means that it relies on me going
forward. I'm getting hit with the same
thing over and over when someone else or
AI could do it as good, if not better,
than I can. What I started is doing is
this, right? Every time I explained
something more than twice, I recorded a
loom of me actually doing the process.
Every time I did something more than
three times in one week, I created a
clawed project for that exact task. And
so what we'll see here is I'm going to
break down each of these AI systems in
just a second. But [music] here's what
happened. Slowly, the things that lived
in my head started living in the
systems. And the crazy yet beautiful
part here is my business didn't just
scale. It got beautiful and easy to run.
Here's something insane that just became
possible. I used Loom to then go and
record the walkthroughs for my team and
then spend around 30 minutes going and
writing it up in an SOP separately. But
not anymore. This is probably the
coolest AI feature I've seen in the last
year. You can use Loom AI to now go and
take a video run through that you use to
go and walk your team through a given
task. It's going to transcribe it and
then generate a full Google Doc SOP with
timestamps, step-by-step instructions,
and section headers for you. This is a
work of art and a complete game changer.
So, you can go task by task and process
everything in your business. When you do
this, right, we're talking about
building repeatable tasks and building
systems, right? so that everything ends
up, you know, being done by your team
and leverage with AI versus being on
your to-do list three times a week.
That's a beautiful thing, right? Less
work on you, more work being done by
your team, more time for you to focus on
the stuff that you're really great at.
So, here's what I've built. YouTube
script writing, lead magnets, brand
voice, email courses, Instagram
carousels, X content, market research,
and why all separate projects? Well,
because each different task has its own
specificity. I'm not just starting from
scratch every time, which is what you
want to avoid. Now, you're building on
top of infrastructure that's already
existed and trained. But here's the
thing. Everything I've shown you so far,
whether it's memory, decisions, and
systems, all are leverage, right? But
the biggest unlock, it wasn't about
efficiency. It was about clarity. And
that's what we build inside of Founder
OS. Businesses that scale without
burning you out. being able to actually
have a business that runs peacefully,
systems that create margin, not
complexity. Because if you're doing 50k
per month, you're probably ready to go
and get help building this, right? So
that your business is AI ready. And if
you want to get a better look at how I
use AI, well, go and check out this
video where I show you how to use AI
better than 99% of people. Go check that
out. Thank you so much for watching and
let's win