My best friends know me as an intense
[\h__\h] People think I'm just this
Zen CEO guy. And honestly, it's a bit of
a lie.
Here's the deal, right? You're building
a business, things can get intense,
right? At times, they get a bit chaotic.
And the truth is, you know, my business
is no different than any business out
there in terms of this default state of
entropy. You know, whether it's your
business, my business, you know, things
come up. You know, people quit.
There's still fires that happen, right?
And
I want to just be able to be real with
you, right? That, you know, even me, you
know, at 20 years into entrepreneurship,
you know, I still struggle with this
stuff at times. And I say this to you uh
because, you know, I don't want to
convey um some person online um that
purely all the time has it like figured
out. I think that all of us,
entrepreneurs, really are just figuring
it out as we go, right? There's so many
things that I don't know, that I'm still
learning. I guess I'm just saying all
this because all of us, you know,
founders, we've got flaws. And it it
isn't all smooth sailing. And I think
that for me, when I look at my own life,
probably like many of you, right? I
straddle like many different vibes, many
different sort of personalities almost
in a way. For sure, I can be that Zen
guy when I'm, you know, taking that
3-week break in the summer to go to the
Dolomites or going snowboarding in Japan
for 3 weeks and just unplugging. But I
would actually say that a lot of my
default state is I'm pretty damn
intense. And I think it's interesting
when I meet different founders and they
get a sense for me in person, they're
like, "Holy [\h__\h] You know, this guy
This guy's really in it. And he's
[\h__\h] passionate." They would say I'm
intense.