Here's the difference between someone
making 50K and someone making 500K
online. I see people create one amazing
piece of content and then just move on.
But, that's leaving so much on the
table. For every core idea or long-form
post, you should ask how many places can
this one idea live? If the answer is
fewer than five, you're not
distributing, you're just creating
endlessly. I take stuff that crushes it
on LinkedIn, and then I adapt that for
YouTube, X, and my newsletter. The same
insight gets packaged differently for
each platform so it's native to that
platform, but that core idea now is
multiplied. Now, this isn't laziness,
right? This is how you actually scale
reach without creating 10x more content.
Because when you're going and stacking
up every piece of content, you're
building a hell of an antifragile
business.