People don't buy what you do, they buy
who they become [music] by doing it.
They're not buying a program, they're
buying the transformation that you're
providing them by actually going and
giving the service [music] you do. Often
times, we forget that when we're
building a brand, a brand is more of an
emotional experience [music] than
anything. It's a feeling you get when
you think of a certain logo or think of
a certain person, [music]
right? For Apple, it's creativity. For
Nike, it's victory. So, refine your
vision into a 10-year road map. Think
about your brand and all the areas you
want it to exist. When you think [music]
about your team and your org chart,
how's that going to need to evolve over
the next 10 years? Because you're going
to need the top talent in the world to
get to where you're [music] looking to
go. How does your offer and your product
suite need to evolve? Your job is to
create a business that becomes a
household name.