want to create a $100,000 per year
income stream here's one way to do it
let's break it down find something you
can sell for
$33,000 this is one of my favorite price
points it's high enough that your
customers will be committed and low
enough that people in medium income
markets will be able to afford it next
acquire three customers every month
that's $9,000 per month which is 108k
per year how do you acquire those
customers book 20 sales calls per month
sales calls have an average close rate
of say 20% to get three to four new
customers per month you'll need to book
20 sales calls how send 1,000 emails per
month the average appointment rate from
cold emails is around 2% you can use
gmass to send mass emails from your
Gmail account and you can use LinkedIn
sales navigator to find people in your
target market and then a tool like
seamless AI to go and get their email
addresses automate once it's built this
entire process can be automated with
just one salesperson and one VA doing
the email Outreach so what's stopping
you