Do you even understand something if you
can't draw it out on a napkin? So, I'm
going to show you a super simple example
to show you that this works no matter
what application in your life. First
things first [music] is we really need
to first prioritize sleep. From there,
we got to go and make sure that we are
moving. Now, after we think about
movement, I like to think about
nourishing myself. Now, it's time for
focus. And the key for focus for me is 4
hours of founder flow. Being able to go
and work on the stuff that only I
[music] can do. After 4 hours, the truth
is, you know, I need a break and it's
now time to go and recharge. And to me,
that just looks like going for a walk.
Once you've gone and you've recharged,
what I then like to do is I like to go
and connect with folks. That might be
connecting with a friend, maybe
connecting deeply with a colleague. And
so I actually think one of the most
important parts of my day, the
reflection. My reflection is really
going to consist of what went well
today, what didn't go well, and what are
the three to seven priorities that I
need to go and hit [music] tomorrow. Um
so that tomorrow is another epic