the world will have 40% more
millionaires by 2026 and in this video
I'm going to share an underground
strategy that myself and other Founders
have been using to tap into a new wealth
that is being created but pay close
attention because this isn't the
traditional way to achieve success by
working 880 Plus hours a week while
cutting out as many lattes and avocado
toast as you can and even if your dream
isn't to build out a massive Empire and
you just want to solid 10 to 20K and
easy monthly income that you can make
from your laptop anywhere in the world
will keep walk watching because what I'm
going to share with you in this video
will allow you to tap into the world's
new most valuable resource so you can
create the life of your dreams and
achieve the one thing that we all desire
the most Freedom the freedom to do what
we want when we want wherever we want in
the world and what I'm about to share
with you doesn't require a bunch of
previous experience or crazy rare skills
either because it leverages a unique
component that I'll reveal in just a
minute plus a proven blueprint I've used
to build multiple seven fig your
businesses and that hundreds of others
have used to generate tens of thousands
of dollars online while working less
than ever so what is this unique
million-dollar opportunity that almost
no one is taking advantage of let me use
a real life example to show you do you
know who this is this is Mr Beast he's
just a regular kid from North Carolina
except for one little thing he has one
of the world's most watch YouTube
channels with a massive following now
it's predicted that he'll be the first
ever YouTube billionaire and we're
already seeing the impact of his reach
for instance when he launched his
chocolate bar line febles he sold a
million bars in just 72 hours how was he
able to do that because he tapped into
the world's new most valuable resource
attention in today's digital age
people's attention is at a premium and
if you can capture people's attention
you can make almost any of your dreams
come true and thanks to platforms like
social media and YouTube normal people
people like you and me have the
potential to build an audience and
achieve a life of Freedom this is
exactly why I've spent 14 years millions
of dollars in thousands of hours
developing proven systems that will
allow almost anyone to tap into the
attention economy and build out a
successful online brand these systems
have also been shown to work regardless
of where you're at in your
entrepreneurial Journey whether you're a
Founder who still has a real job you've
yet to crack consistent five figure
months or even if you're well establish
and are ready to scale to a million
dollar profit and Beyond but perhaps the
most powerful part of this system is
that it works for practically any Market
it works with coaching Consulting
courses media books software digital
agencies Professional Services health
and wellness and e-commerce so if you're
in any of these markets or interested in
building your own business in one of
these markets what I'm going to share
with you will work for you leveraging
these proven systems has changed my life
and I want to help you experience the
same level of Freedom fulfillment and
success so what's the secret behind my
success I call it the founder flywheel
it's a model that's based on
productizing what brings you Joy and
leveraging the attention economy to
build at a profitable online presence
proven based on my experience building
businesses in four completely different
Industries this is the easiest most
sustainable and long-term guaranteed
method to achieve 100K per month while
maximizing your joy and accomplishing
the for W's in life work where you want
on what you want with who you want
whenever you want while also achieving
true freedom in Life Financial Freedom
location freedom and most importantly
time Freedom this will allow you to
spend time with family and friends do
what makes you happy and travel the
world it's also going to allow you to
buy things without having to care about
the prices and work four hours a day
doing what you love so let's start with
the first pillar seven figure
foundations you know building a seven
fig business isn't that hard but 80% of
success is choosing the right business
you need to do three things number one
find your Zone a genius two build a
digital product and Community around
what you love and three create a banger
offer around it that people can't live
without too many Founders are winging it
and that's the reason they can't get any
traction that leads to pillar number two
packing your pipeline but here's the
thing getting a full pipeline of leads
has very little to do with sending cold
messages or running a bunch of ads to
make it in today's industry and grab
your slice of that multi-million doll
pie you must develop a standout presence
online doing so will allow you to
enhance the value of your brand and
offer it's going to establish you as a
true leader in your area of expertise
and it's going to give you a packed
pipeline of potential clients that you
can tap into at any moment it's also
going to make you in demand and allow
you to charge more and more for your
services and build a thriving following
that will buy whatever you sell it's now
time to monetize with social funnels a
big following doesn't guarantee a big
number in your bank account you also
need the right system in place to
monetize your audience it's what I like
to call a social funnel and it allows
you to drive people from your social
media platform which I like to call your
rented audience to your owned audience
to your monetized audience the social
funnel is a literal ATM for the audience
you have created ATM stands for audience
targeted content engine and money you
control it and thereby you control your
destiny the last step is automating your
operations and growth your time is your
most valuable asset and you must guard
it at all costs as soon as possible we
want to remove you from the nitty-gritty
operations this is going to allow you to
begin really scaling your business spend
your energy on only the most important
and life-giving parts of your business
and the best part well you'll actually
get the freedom you dreamed of when you
first started your company you need to
remove yourself from operations and have
a business that runs an autopilot is
autonomous and ensure all the core tasks
are automated the attention economy is a
gold mine of opportunities and like I
said earlier it's estimated that the
world will have 40% more millionaires in
just a few years but here's the thing it
will never be easier than it is right
now because as more and more people get
clued into this opportunity to leverage
the world's most valuable resource to
grow their own Brands the competition
will only get stiffer that's exactly why
I created founder OS to help shortcut
your path to success and help you start
to see results in months not years Fest
has the exact blueprint and systems I've
used to grow two businesses to eight
figures and two businesses to seven
figures I've completely decoded these
systems they can be applied to your
business helping you get results like
people like Rob who closed 100K in new
contracts in Just 2 months and Steve who
went from 0 to 7 million per year with a
new SAS product of course in addition to
helping you make a healthy profit the
goal of founder is to remove you from
the founder grind and get you true
Freedom it's no secret that many
Founders set out to build a business
online because they want to escape the 9
to-5 but the thing is they end up
working 7 days a week 12 hours a day and
I know it because it happened with me
with my first business it nearly broke
me found Ros is all about helping you
implement systems that remove you from
your business without sacrificing your
growth or Revenue we want you to spend
more time on the parts of the business
that you love so you can start living
out your dream life if you'd like to
discover more about this opportunity and
how you can tap into the digital economy
to build the life of your dreams just
hit the button below to apply for a
Founder Clarity call with my team I've
gone above and beyond to pack everything
I possibly could into founder OS it's
going to give you the closest thing to a
copy and paste blueprint that I could
have ever created it's going to allow
you to avoid all the pitfalls and the
challenges that I faced and help you hit
your goals as fast as possible