If you open your calendar right now and
you say, "I don't have time." Or you
look at your Stripe balance and say, "I
can't afford that." Then I'm going to be
honest with you, you're not thinking
like a millionaire. You're thinking like
a prisoner. Because wealthy founders,
well, they don't ask, "How much does it
cost?" They ask, "What's the ROI if this
works?" This one shift will either set
you free or keep you stuck in a prison
disguised as a business. And when this
clicked for me, I went from working
15-hour days in a business that stole my
life to building two systemized
companies that now run with less than 4
hours of my time each day, giving me the
freedom to grow a profitable media
empire, travel the world, and never
worry about money again. And so, I'm
going to show you exactly how I did it.
I'm Matt Gray. I build companies that
scale without me because I learned the
hard way that hustle doesn't equal
freedom. Today I help founders replace
chaos with systems and scale personal
brands that sell while they sleep. Today
I run Founder OS where we install
systems for founders doing anywhere from
$30,000 to $500,000 per month. We've
worked with everyone from rising
creators to 8 figure brands helping them
scale without burning out. But this
expertise didn't come easily. It came
from hardearned lessons building and
scaling my own companies. So here's a
bit of the backstory. Back in 2015, Herb
was doing about 140K a month in revenue.
Solid business, but we'd hit a plateau.
For context, Herb is a cannabis media
company I built into the largest
cannabis media company in the world with
over 14 million followers. We create
content, have a highly engaged
community, and develop enterprise tech
to help convert cannabis consumers into
customers. I was at this founder dinner
in Los Angeles when I overheard this
conversation and someone had mentioned
that they had connections with several
NFL and NBA players who were advocates
for cannabis, especially for pain
management and recovery. A light bulb
went off. Man, I've got to meet these
people. These aren't just any athletes,
right? These are household names with
millions of followers who could
completely transform how people viewed
cannabis. The next morning, I reached
out and discovered that we could go and
get these three NFL stars for a
professional video series about their
cannabis consumption and how it helped
their journey as an athlete. The
production would be top tier, the kind
of content that looks like it belongs in
a Netflix documentary, not some YouTube
video. The price tag, 29K. When I
brought this to my chief financial
officer, he had a heart attack. Matt,
that's almost half of our monthly
revenue. Now, we can't justify that kind
of expense. What if these players back
out? You know, what if this doesn't even
convert? To be honest, his concerns were
valid. You know, we weren't flushed with
cash. Spending 29K could actually be
seen as irresponsible. But I sat with
the decision for a couple days, and I
realized that we were asking the wrong
questions. Instead of asking, can we
afford this? I started asking, "What's
the long-term value of associating our
brand with these respected athletes? How
would this change our brand positioning
in this industry? And what's the cost of
staying where we are for another 6
months?" When I reframed these
questions, the decision became obvious.
I called up the production company and I
said, "Yes, let's move forward." The day
that we released that first video, the
series was picked up by Sports
Illustrated and a dozen other massive
cannabis publications. Our social
following over that next month grew by
127,000 people. Here's where it also
gets interesting and what most founders
miss about ROI thinking. The real
return, it wasn't just traffic or sales.
It was in brand positioning. Before this
NFL series, we were just seen as another
cannabis media company. After, we were
the premium brand connecting mainstream
culture with cannabis education. Within
3 months, our monthly revenue jumped to
over
$240,000. And within 6 months, we landed
our first major deal with a company that
had been previously refusing to go and
enter the cannabis space. Their exact
words were, "No, Matt, we watched that
series with those NFL players. you've
really changed our view on how we look
at this industry and we're ready to move
forward. That 29K investment generated
over
$700,000 in direct revenue within the
first year. More importantly, it
completely repositioned our brand in the
market. I see this pattern repeating
itself time and time again with founders
that are trying to hit that 100K per
month mark. They start playing defense
with their money instead of playing
offense with their money. When I talk to
founders considering a $50,000
mastermind or a $30,000 content series,
I always ask them, you know, are you
calculating the full ROI? Not just the
immediate return, but the doors that
might open, what positioning it might
create for you, what opportunities then
become possible. Most aren't. They're
stuck in expense thinking. They're
thinking small. That's too much money
for what it is. Or, you know, I can't
afford that. But at 100K per month,
you're not paying for what it is. You're
paying for what makes it possible. That
NFL content series wasn't just videos.
It was the key that unlocked an entirely
new level for our business. The $29,000
wasn't an expense. It was the admission
price to a different league. And that's
the shift that separates founders who
stay stuck at 100K per month and those
that end up scaling to 500K per month.
So, when you're considering that next
big investment, that high ticket coach,
that mastermind, that premium content
series, and it seems too expensive, I
want you to ask yourself, what's the
real cost of staying where I am right
now? And what becomes possible if this
actually works? That question has made
me millions over the years. Let's get
into the core problem I see. Most
founders stay broke not because they
don't work hard enough, but because they
make decisions like broke people. Here's
how to tell which mindset you're in.
Expense thinking asks questions like,
"How much does it cost? Can I do this
myself? Let's wait until we're ready.
That seems too expensive." ROI thinking,
on the other side of things, asks,
"What's the upside if this works? What
does this free me up to focus on? What
would this make possible? How fast can
we test it?" Expense thinking is really
going to focus on preserving what you
have. It's that scarcity mindset. ROI
thinking focuses on multiplying what you
have. It's that abundance mindset.
Here's the kicker. Your decisions are
your destiny. If every time an
opportunity comes your way, you pause
and say, "That's too expensive." What
you're really saying is, "I don't
believe I'll get a return." Back in
2018, I was struggling with a major
decision for Herb. We were doing around
285K in monthly revenue, which sounds
impressive from the outside, but we'd
hit a serious plateau. Traffic was
stagnant, growth had flatlined, and the
cannabis industry was getting more and
more competitive every single day. I
knew we needed a complete brand
overhaul. New design, new website, new
content strategy, the works. When I got
a quote, it came in at
$78,000. At the time, this felt like a
massive expense. My immediate reaction
was pure expense thinking. It's a lot of
money for a rebrand, and we already have
a functioning website. We should just be
focusing on operations, not pure
aesthetics. I spent weeks trying to
figure out cheaper alternatives,
freelancers, templates. Could I just do
this myself maybe for half as much? Then
I had a conversation that changed
everything. I was having dinner with my
close mentor, Greg, watching the sunset
over Lake Ontario. And I asked him about
the situation. You know, Greg put down
his fork. He looked at me directly and
he said, "What's the cost of staying the
same for another year, Matt?" The
question hit me like a thunderbolt. I
started calculating. You know, my
current monthly revenue was 285K. My
projected monthly revenue with this
rebrand was 450K. And that was just a
conservative estimate. The difference
was 165K per month. The potential cost
of not doing the rebrand was about 1.9
million over a year. And suddenly that
78K investment, it looked completely
different. It wasn't an expense. It was
an investment with a potential 2500%
return in just one year. I was so caught
up in how much does this cost that I
wasn't thinking about how much will this
make us and what's the opportunity cost
of an action. This was expense thinking
versus ROI thinking and it was keeping
me small. The next day I approved the
project. Within 3 months, the rebrand
was complete. One year later, our
monthly revenue hadn't just hit that
450K mark. It had exceeded reaching
$500,000 per month. The 78K expense
ended up generating over $2 million in
additional revenue in the first year
alone. I've seen this pattern repeat
with founders time and time again. When
I was building Founder OS, I invested
$68,000 in a video production system far
earlier than most would consider
affordable for a company at our stage.
One founder in our community asked me,
"Matt, how can you justify such an
expense as big as that when you're just
starting out?" I told him it wasn't just
an expense, it was a revenue engine.
That video system generated over
$840,000 in sales in the first 90 days.
I've noticed two types of founders. You
know, when you see a 68k price tag for
joining an elite mastermind, do you
think, "Wow, like that's expensive as
hell. I can't justify that." Or if I get
just three to four new high ticket
clients from the connections and
strategies, this pays for itself many
times over. Founders in camp 1
ultimately become the bottleneck to
their own growth. Founders in camp 2, on
the other side, experience exponential
growth because they run more
experiments, pursue more opportunities
with a high potential for ROI. It's not
about being reckless with money. It's
about calculating return, not just cost.
And this mindset applies beyond business
investments. It applies to your time,
your energy, your focus. Are you
calculating the ROI on how you spend
your days, or are you just trying to
minimize expenses? The rebrand story was
my wakeup call. And since then, I've
approached every single decision through
the lens of ROI, not expense. And it's
transformed not just my businesses, but
my entire relationship with resources.
So next time you're looking at a
significant investment in your business,
whether it's hiring a new team member,
joining a mastermind, or implementing
some new system, don't just ask
yourself, how much does this cost? Ask
yourself, what's the ROI if this works?
And what's the cost if I do nothing?
That shift in thinking might be the
difference between staying where you are
right now and building your dream
business. That's the difference between
founders who scale and founders who stay
stuck. So, here's where the rubber hits
the road. Let's get tactical. Here's the
four question system I use to rewire my
brain out of expense thinking and then
into ROI thinking. Number one, what's
the money multiplier? Most people look
at a price tag and they think, can I
afford this? That's the wrong question.
The right question is, if I put a dollar
into this, how many dollars will come
back to me? Let me show you what I mean.
Last year, a founder in our community
named Sarah was debating whether to
spend $5,000 on a professional video
team for her upcoming course launch. Her
first thought was, "That's expensive. I
could just use my iPhone to film this."
Then she asked the money multiplier
question. If this $5,000 video helps me
sell just five more courses at $2,000
each, that's a $10,000 return. So, she
invested the $5,000. The result, she
sold 27 more courses than her previous
launch. That's $54,000 in additional
revenue from a $5,000 investment. That's
a 10.8x money multiplier. This isn't
about spending money. It's about seeing
opportunities where others see expenses.
View your business as if you're a
portfolio manager. Your role is to
identify high ROI investments and then
pull the trigger on them fast. Two,
what's the cost of waiting? Most
founders think delaying a decision saves
money, but it doesn't. It costs
opportunity. Every day that you wait is
a day that you're not making progress.
James, a founder friend of mine, was
hesitant about hiring a VA for $3,000 a
month. I asked him, "What's the cost of
waiting 90 days to make that hire?" And
he calculated it. 3 hours saved daily is
270 hours over 90 days. His hourly value
on sales calls is $500 an hour. So the
potential lost revenue is
$135,000. Suddenly that $9,000, which is
3 months at 3K, looked tiny compared to
the $135,000 cost of waiting. He made
the hire that week. Within 60 days, his
revenue increased by $42,000 a month.
The real cost wasn't the hire. The real
cost was waiting. Question three is,
what will this free me up to do? This is
the question that most founders never
ask. When you spend money, you're not
just buying a thing. You're buying back
your time, and that's your most valuable
resource. What you do with your time
determines everything. Another founder I
know, Michelle, was spending 15 hours
weekly on content creation for her
design business. She hesitated to hire a
content manager for $4,500 a month. So,
I asked her, "If you get these 15 hours
back each week, what would you do
instead?" Her answer was, "I'd focus on
partnership calls with bigger brands."
The math was simple. One partnership
deal equals $25,000. One deal per month
equals $300,000 per year. A cost of a
content manager is $54,000 per year. So
that's a 5.5x return just by focusing
her freed up time on high lever
activities. She'd get this insane
return. This isn't just delegation, it's
time leverage, turning average hours
into golden opportunities. Question
number four is, can I survive the worst
case? Most people focus so much on what
might go wrong that they miss what could
go right. Smart ROI thinkers ask, if
this fails completely, can I survive it?
If yes, and the upside is significant,
it's almost always worth the risk.
Another example, Mark, a founder I know,
wanted to launch a high ticket
mastermind, but was afraid to invest
$20,000 in marketing. The worst case, he
loses $20,000. The best case is he
enrolls 10 members at 25,000 each and
makes
$250,000. That's a 12.5x potential
return. Could he survive losing 20,000?
Yeah. Was a potential $250,000 worth the
risk? Absolutely. This isn't reckless.
It's calculated courage. Now, I want to
give you the most powerful shift that
changed everything for me. This isn't
about just asking better questions. It's
about becoming a different kind of
founder, a different thinker. Here's the
sentence that transformed my entire
business. Expense thinkers cut costs to
survive. ROI thinkers invest
strategically to thrive. I see the
difference every single day at Founder
OS. The founders who grow the fastest
aren't the ones with the best ideas.
They're the ones who make decisions
differently. Let me show you what this
looks like in real life. An expense
thinker says things like, "I can't
afford a team right now. Maybe when we
hit 100K per month." On the other side
of it, an ROI thinker says, "I can't
afford to not build a team." Each hire
should 3x their salary and value. An
expense thinker is going to say, "Let's
cut the software budget by 20% to
improve our margins." An ROI thinker is
going to say, "Let's invest in software
that makes us 5x more efficient and
eliminates human error." An expense
thinker is going to say, "We need to
reduce our content budget until our
revenue improves." An ROI thinker is
going to say, "Let's double down on the
organic content with the highest return
and then cut the rest." This identity
shift from expense thinking to ROI
thinking is what separates good founders
from the greatest. One sees cost, the
other sees investments. One plays
defense, the other plays offense. One
stays stuck, the other one scales. There
are two currencies in business, money
and time. Only one of them is infinite.
Every single day, founders make a fatal
mistake. They save money, but then they
spend time. They DIY their website to
save 5K, but then spend 40 hours
building it themselves. They handle
their own bookkeeping to save 5,000 a
month, but waste 6 hours a month on a
task that they hate. They write their
own content to save 5,000, but then
spend 10 hours creating something that
doesn't even convert. Money is
renewable. Your time is not. This is the
prison that you've built for yourself.
And the key to escape it isn't working
harder. It isn't even hiring more
people. It isn't even making more money.
It's changing how you think about money.
Stop asking how much does this cost.
Start asking what's the ROI if this
works. Because the real question isn't
whether you can afford to invest. It's
whether you can afford not to. If you're
tired of being the bottleneck in your
business. And if you want a business
that serves your life instead of
consuming it, well then it's time to
install systems that will think for you.
That's exactly what we do at Founder OS.
We don't just teach theory. It's no BS.
No fluff. We help founders build systems
that transform how you think, how you
work, and how you build. Now, you don't
have to choose between success and
freedom. You can have both. We have the
community, the mentorship. You'll get
direct access to me to get all your
questions answered and ensure that you
get unstuck and able to scale. If you
enjoyed this video, be sure to like and
subscribe. Apply to Founder S below.
[Music]