what if you could achieve your dream
life by following a simple step-by-step
system checking off the boxes to
organize strategic and fulfilling tasks
designed to guide you on a path to make
you realize your higher
self yeah right if it was only that easy
that clear that
simple no the reality is many of us had
no other choice but to learn the hard
way make mistakes learn make make
mistakes learn make
mistakes learn the average person makes
over 34,0 562 choices a day by the time
you're 79 A2 that's over a billion
decisions and say 35% of those are
mistakes that's over 354 million
mistakes but you don't have to learn
from your own 354 million mistakes
because there's a shortcut listen to the
people who have made the same mistakes
learn from them the easy way and avoid
the hard way way if you're ready to use
a system to design your dream life let's
dive in starting where it all begins in
the depths of
burnout when I graduated from business
school I felt completely hopeless I
realized the dreams I was working for
weren't even my own at first it felt
like I had already failed I got a boring
9 to-5 at craft foods and I hated my
life I had no Direction no purpose no
vision so I made a plan to learn as much
as I could I learned to code I learned
how to build websites and by a stroke of
luck with the help of co-founders I
built my first business bitmaker we
agreed that coding was the language of
the future and we were helping Millions
get the skills to build online this
dream became a prison of my own making
over the 3 years of running bitmaker I
faded away I smoked I drank and used
unhealthy coping mechanisms to deal with
the stress and co-founder issues I sold
bitmaker at 24 it was a massive
milestone in my life from the outside I
looked successful but inside I felt
completely lost L I knew I needed to
find a new Direction a new reality for
the first time ever I sat down and I
asked myself what do I really want
what's my dream I realized what I truly
wanted more than anything to be unrushed
so I could fully experience my life in
this world the freedom to control where
I am when I arrive what I do and with
who this was the beginning and that's
where I want to start with you Mark
Twain once said most men die at 27 we
just bury them at
72 I'm going to give you a harsh truth
here no one's going to live your life
for you and no one cares about living
your life as much as you should so what
do you need to ask yourself what really
excites you you know what do you want
your dream life to look like what are
things that you've been putting off that
you've always wanted to do now is the
time to go and get after those things
stop putting off your biggest dreams and
just telling yourself well maybe
tomorrow that's a load of BS now is the
time to go and get these things going
now is the time to press play on your
life step two assume control a mentor
once told me your life is a reflection
of the standards that you set for
yourself I was stuck in a job I hated
doing things that felt completely out of
alignment with who I was why because I
wasn't taking control I let life
happened to me you are 100% responsible
for your experience of Life frustrated
with your job who's forcing you to stay
disconnected from Friends who's stopping
you from opening up the moment you take
ownership of how you feel and what you
do you become Unstoppable in his book
The Score takes care of itself Bill
Walsh offers insights into his
Innovative approach to coaching and
Leadership a central theme of the book
is Walsh's philosophy that focusing on
the process rather than the outcome is
the key to achieving Excellence the
strategy that Walsh talks about revolves
around the concept of controlling what
is in your hands which means concent
ating on the preparation and execution
of tasks rather than the end results he
believed that if players and coaches
committed to high standards in every
aspect of their preparation and
performance the score would just take
care of itself this is rung true in my
own life by focusing on the controllable
elements I've created a culture in my
company that is second to none I've
created a self-sustaining Empire that
runs itself this approach has led me to
building a team that's not just focused
on winning games but on dominating their
individual roles which cumulatively have
led us to insane success so when faced
with obstacles ask yourself these three
questions is this essential can I
control this and what are two actions I
can take right now you are the one in
control of your actions you're never
powerless you can change things we hate
assuming responsibility for how we feel
it may seem impossible sometimes but
taking small steps creates an instant
relief you reassume control and learn
the you can fix any problems that come
up you can't control the weather you
can't control the market and you can't
control the outcomes but you can control
the inputs and at the end of the day the
score will take care of
itself step three build a habit of
reflection as Ray deio says pain plus
reflection equals progress 10 years ago
I dreamt of living a life in nature
building an online business going to
National Parks exploring
the beautiful sites of Joshua Tree yeed
flying across the world to Exotic
locations like Bali and Thailand
balancing work life and play I had
recently sold my first business bit
maker and I decided the hell with it why
was I quitting off living it was time to
sell everything I had get on a plane and
that's exactly what I did exploring some
of the most majestic sites I've ever
seen I started my first business herb
which now was the largest and most
engaged cannabis community in the world
world of over 14 million people doing
eight figures and Beyond a year then it
hit me one day I was reflecting and I
realized that there was something
missing in my life I was no longer
passionate about the business of herb I
was passionate about the mission and
passionate about the team but I realized
I needed something more I started
journaling journaling around what
excites me journaling around the things
that were draining my energy all of this
gave me the realization that the
business was no longer filling up my cup
I needed to discover what truly set my
soul on fire as I began writing it was
things like Building Systems helping
Founders traveling the world taking care
of my health from all this reflection
came the concept and the idea for
founder OS a community of Founders
globally helping one another through
proven systems scale Their audience
their brand and their revenue I want you
to kind of think about doing the same
you know reflection is one of the most
powerful things that you can do in your
life it'll give you the ability to
determine what habits give you the most
energy and what Memories do you look
back on in your life most fondly what
are the patterns of the things that
drain my energy and what are the
patterns of the things that give me
energy and what are those things that
are just bringing you down whether it's
people experiences or different tasks
that you're working on from there what
you want to do is a bit of an audit and
start to double down on the things that
are bringing you Joy and eliminate the
things that are leading to a certain
level of unhappiness in your life how
can you go and build a habit of
reflection in your own life first off I
think it involves tuning into your own
body body you know what are the things
that you're working on that make you
feel at ease what are the things that
you enjoy what are those tasks that when
you're doing them you lose track of time
and then on the other side of things
what are those things that you work on
that just drain you that make you feel
like garbage that you just can't wait
till they're over I think it's a matter
of Having the courage to then double
down and lean more into those things you
love and then looking at your given day
whether it's the people the experiences
the tasks that you're working on that
you no longer enjoy and just stopping
those things that may mean eliminating
certain friends from your life not
working with certain people waking up a
certain way eliminating certain food
from your diet who knows but the point
is to live a more intentional life you
need to take time to reflect on what's
bringing you Joy and the stuff that is
draining you when I started reflecting I
learned I was in a negative mood about
50% of the time that completely shocked
me I made changes and I started working
on things that gave me energy I was free
to move on to the next step in this
dream life system step four
visualize a couple of years ago after an
exploration through you 1 week I finally
felt it completely calm and unhurried
like I was in exactly the right place at
exactly the right time I realized I had
removed myself from the operations of my
business I was part of this amazing
community of Legends who had my back I
could take long breaks from my business
to travel the world and go on Epic
Adventures my progress was undeniable I
felt amazing
nature is not only great for recharging
it's also super helpful for getting
clear on your vision having a Clear
Vision of where you're looking to go
over the next 10 years and 3 years is
essential for both your personal and
professional success I've gone and
gotten clear on my vision to be able to
go and architect for profitable
companies over the last 12 years and
it's really been a Difference Maker not
just for helping you be successful but
for hiring amazing talent for selling
people for inspiring people your vision
board is amazing for you to get clear on
exactly where you're looking to go
inside of your vision board you want to
have your 10year goals your three-year
goals and then reverse engineer the
success of those goals by getting clear
on what you're going to do in the next
90 days and the next 30 days and then
incorporating that into your daily
schedule I'll go list my personal values
as well as my professional values these
serve as a filter as to what I say yes
to in my life and the things that I say
no to as an example my professional
values are things like keeping things
insanely simple taking extreme ownership
and having an insanely High bar of
quality on the personal side things like
Inner Harmony love and freedom go and
get clear on your vision go and write
down your 10year goals your three-year
goals and then how you're going to go
accomplish these things over the next
one year 90 days 30 days and then today
all right on to the next one step five
here we go
step five set goals when I was at
bitmaker running a team of 20 training
2,000 software Engineers I felt
something I hadn't felt before I felt
like I was creating something larger
than myself and it gave me purpose and
my days had meaning I let it light the
way as my mission to be a part of a team
that help people learn new skills and
unlock new capabilities today I run two
companies with a combined 60 people and
a community of 16 million I love helping
Founders leverage systems to create
automated Empire s this is my life's
purpose that's what setting goals is
really about figuring out how to do more
of what you really want to do and less
of the stuff you hate to figure out what
these goals should be you first need to
determine your values your mission and
your Niche then set specific measurable
actionable realistic and time bound
smart goals let's break all of it down
starting with part one your values your
personal values serve as a filter on
what you're going to allow into your
life and the stuff that you're just not
going to accept one of the biggest
mistakes I see Founders making is they
create a vision or set any goals for
that matter that are completely contrary
to their values one of the best ways to
stay motivated and show up even when
times get rough is by setting goals that
align with your values write down your
six values here are some ideas fun joy
Faith Family health peace Inner Harmony
pick six that are important to you and
use them as a compass for navigating
life part two your mission when when I
first started building my habit of
reflection I learned that I needed to
tap into my true calling in life helping
Founders leverage proven systems to
build their dreams this was my reason
for being from this calling founder OS
was born I dove deep into documenting
all of the systems around my businesses
audience growth content monetization and
structuring high performance remote
teams we've grown it to over 4,000
Founders and a team of 24 Legends and an
audience of over 2.7 million people part
three your niche in the same way that
you need to find a niche for your brand
and business I think it's also important
for us to have our own personal Niche
essentially this is how you would want
others to describe you over a dinner
conversation here's what my personal
Niche looks like and you can do this for
your company too so at foundos our Niche
is $5 million founder systems and my
personal Niche is Soulful
entrepreneurship our mission is to make
the founder Journey magical and our
vision is to build the greatest founder
community of the 21st century now how do
you design your goals themselves well
remember the vision you created a little
earlier for your life it's time to start
thinking about that big dream in terms
of the goals you'll be achieving to make
it a reality you live every day start
with your 10year goals the biggest and
the most intimidating here's what my
10year goals look like for my personal
life and founder us now that you have
your 10-year goals worked out it's time
to start making those more achievable I
know some people that make 5-year goals
but I prefer to focus 3 years out it's
still a ways out but it feels close
enough to serve as a good point to
ensure I'm on track to hit my 10-year
goals here's what my three-year goals
look like people overestimate what they
can accomplish in a week but
underestimate what they can accomplish
in a year that's the mindset I try to
have when planning out my one-year goals
next I take all my big needle mover
tasks and plan to implement them as
quickly as possible by creating 90day
goals I can then spend the remaining
portion of the Year Gathering data
optimizing and launching new things
based on what I've learned here's what
my 90-day goals look like today now
these are goals not plans you need
deeper systems for those and we'll cover
those in other videos the point is you
can't figure out a plan if you don't
have a goal that makes sense and fits
into the dream you have in mind step six
stay accountable to yourself creating
your ideal future takes effort and
action there's a system I invented 5
years ago that has been of great use to
me on my journey to doing what I needed
to do to live the life that I had
imagined I call it my personal board
meeting and it's how I stay accountable
to myself public company CEOs you know
they report to a board and this ensures
that they're accountable and doing what
they said they will do but what do we do
as one person businesses or as just one
person trying to reach their own
personal goals simple you have a board
meeting with
yourself okay not literally but just
hear me out for a sec all right so
here's an example of my personal board
meeting this is from March 2024 here you
can see the mission of founder OS this
year help a th founders Founders in 2024
achieve a million doll plus Revenue
through the proven systems that we have
for growing Their audience their brand
and their monetization our vision here
we want to create the greatest founder
community of the 21st century No small
feat I must say here you can see the
core values of what we're building
quality results founder first so every
time I open up this board meeting I am
reminded of why I'm doing what I'm doing
it just gets me a bit fired so let's
keep going here the next area like I've
talked about is really honing in on your
calling in life I talk a lot about you
know having your icky guy a reason for
being you know I practice what I preach
and so here in the center you can see my
icky guy right things like traveling
coaching Founders building proven
systems design writing art these are the
things that set my soul on fire all
right next slide now you got to get
clear on your personal 30-day goals and
so back in March 2024 these are the
things that I was focused on
implementing Brian Johnson's blueprint
protocol flawlessly getting one massage
a week because you know why not making
sure I'm taking my girlfriend on a daily
date because I love her and hiking the
doll mites because what's more epic than
the Italian Alps now we got the business
30-day goals on the revenue side you
know we've got certain goals in terms of
setting different deals and closer calls
we're hitting a certain dollar amount
1.5 million in the portfolio making sure
that we host an epic Mexico City
Mastermind and I can report back now
that was an insane event on the
operation side setting up a team
dashboard you know making sure the cro
is a killer chief of staff's a killer
this is what my 30-day business goals
look like and these are things that I'm
revisiting about three times a week just
to make sure that every move I'm making
is getting me one step closer to these
goals that lad up to my 10-year
three-year Vision so I can design my
dream life we're not done yet I actually
go and take my 10-year vision and make
sure that as part of the board meeting
and so I can see what am I doing this
all for I'm doing it you know to create
the restat center I'm looking to in the
dolomites make sure I'm creating this
epic founder community and doing all of
this because my mission in life is to
really help unlock Founders creative
potential and help people build their
dreams here on the next part you can see
then how those 10year and three-year
goals trickle down to my one-year plan
my 90day goals and I'll outline all of
the different opportunities that exist
across people product and the different
systems across my business the next
aspect here is I do the same thing on
the business side so I have my personal
vision and I have the business Vision we
trickle it down to one year 90day and
those people product and system
opportunities we get to the reflection
area of things reflection is all about
understanding first off what went well
in this month after reflection it was
things like completing my 90-day goal
lifting daily scheduling a writing week
which you know was great and that book
is coming out very very soon you know we
onboard our chief of staff and hit all
of our cash flow goals in terms of what
didn't go well like many of you I could
have done a better good job of
delegating to my executive assistant so
I'm looking to continue to offload more
of those tasks I also need to take a
little bit more time daily to be present
to meditate to slow down the last part
here is then what did I learn you know I
really learned that you know taking time
from myself in nature is really one of
the best investments that I can make I'm
doing a great job overall and should be
proud of myself and you know I ended up
reading psychology of money I learned a
lot and would highly recommend that all
of you guys go check out that book
that's it let's get it I think that
there's no room for compromising on the
system you have to do it so step seven
is take Swift action and so you've got
clear on your goals you're clear on your
vision and you're clear on your values
and so now it's just time to get your
in gear one principle I found super
useful for this is the 5-second rule by
Mel Robbins when you think of something
that you know you should do you count
down from five 4 3 2 1 and then you just
get that thing done procrastination is
the biggest killer of your dreams no
more procrastinating no more waiting to
tomorrow now is the time to move towards
your vision now now we're going to go
and we got an adventure planned I'll see
you in the next
one so step eight is to choose play fun
and
Adventure you know building a business
shouldn't be all about grinding hustling
and scaling building a business should
be fun it should be adventurous it
should be you know just like this
out here in the middle of nowhere in
Mexico an erupting volcano behind me
with my good friend Diego on an epic
adventure how do you go and incorporate
more play fun and Adventure into your
life let me give you some steps come
along seek new experiences don't do the
same Old Mundane stuff day after day mix
it
up Embrace discomfort you know the
recipe for Burnout is doing this same
thing day after day go on that road trip
go to a festival go to a concert have
some fun
already Embrace joy in life life's not
all about
Milestones it's about moments get
outside have some fun with friends go
for a cold bath sauna meditate whatever
brings you Joy think about it when was
the last time you did something just for
fun not because it was productive or had
some future payoff because it truly lit
you up inside cuz here's the kicker when
you make room for play fun and Adventure
your work
improves because people can feel your
energy and new ideas and it's contagious
so don't design a life you want to
escape from design one that you never
want to leave so choose road trips
choose nature choose Wild Adventures
choose
discomfort choose living choose to be a
kid again the freedom you want is closer
than you think like And subscribe and
welcome to the founder Freedom Movement
[Music]