I haven't done what we're about to do in
like 13 years something that I've been
kind of bit nervous on the last few days
borderline [\h__\h] my
[Music]
pants okay this [\h__\h] is out of control
I'm driving through hell and I didn't
brought snow it's shining in h and I
didn't brought glow
packed up we are over out heading to the
airport here leaving from Seattle off to
lagona beach to go see the founder OS
director of customer success Ben then I
am heading to San Diego uh for a crazy
adventure with the cro of herb and then
I'm getting on a flight we're heading to
Italy going to the dolomites and for
some Epic Ventures throughout Europe
over the next few months so I want to
take you along and uh well let's rip it
oh [\h__\h] you can't even
sing yeah just saying this s get
Somey bab I like it uh there's just
honestly so much exciting stuff going on
I've been building businesses for 15
years now um and run a portfolio of
online businesses that do $13.8 million
of Revenue a year um across a number of
them including herb which is one company
I run with a community of over 14
million people there's a team of around
36 weapons there and then I also run a
company called founder OS um where we
help Founders install organic content
engines in their businesses and build
automatic profit machines and my mission
there is to help 100 million Founders
accomplish their dreams through proven
systems and across the entire portfolio
things have been [\h__\h]
booming and you know I waited a long
time for this you know there's uh many
years where I struggled you know just
inexperience founder didn't know what I
was doing didn't know how to build you
know a healthy business didn't even know
how to build a healthy lifestyle for
myself and it feels like everything
right now though is just comeing full
circle and I'm just in the pocket you
know I'm in the zone I feel like you
know Tom Brady Michael Jordan you know
going for this sixth ring here you know
I just feel like everything is happening
um and it's
happening better than I thought it ever
could when I reflect on what is going so
well right now and why I think I've
built such a calm company in portfolio
across all these businesses it comes
down
to Great
marketing great
product in great
systems
and let's talk about the marketing side
of things my belief is that the future
of online businesses are founder Le you
know you see this with Elon Musk in
Tesla and
SpaceX you see this with jobs back in
the day in
apple people trust people and then they
trust
brand and I still think that we're
actually in the first inning of these
founder-led businesses of people using
their own personal brand to build their
business more than ever people want
compelling stories they want Founders
that are real are authentic are willing
to share the good times and the bad uh
the struggles and the
achievements and I
am I wish I could bu me spaceship
you know I had the chance
to hang out with a teammate today
and it was a real beautiful enlightening
conversation uh you know I think as a
Founder it's important to renew your
spirit and to surround yourself with
people that really help you downregulate
your nervous system you know you want to
monitor you know 30 minutes after you've
left a conversation with someone how
does your body feel you know how does
your nervous system feel do you feel
tight stressed choked
up or do you feel
Zen do you feel
calm do you feel inspired
that 30 minute test after any
interaction with
anyone is a
tell and my meeting with Ben uh the
director of customer success
today um at founder was
certainly um you know just a really
peaceful
inspiring beautiful conversation and I
feel more inspired than ever to create
the greatest founder community in the
world you know when I look back on my
entrepreneural career there have been a
lot of dark
days 72% of entrepreneurs suffer from
some sort of mental health issue it's
really like an
epidemic you know
72% that means if you had four Founders
in front of you and you
went and looked at them know you you may
actually look at them and think damn
this guy's at 10 million and be envious
and this guy over here just hit 100K per
month damn why am I not there and this
guy over here just went and hit his
first $5 million year damn it like why
am I not there and then you know when
you actually peel back the curtain the
truth of the matter is in those own
Founders minds and hearts and
souls three of those four
guys
are maybe dying inside you know crippled
under pressure under the constant
demands of a
company from the
outside they may look like they have it
all but on the
inside it ain't so sweet
and the truth is I've been there I've
been the founder that from the outside
everything looked
amazing but inside I just wanted to
die
and I've been one of those
72% founder West and what we're building
and the team and the vision it means a
lot to me I think because it really just
hits close to to my
heart as a Founder I wish I had the
support system I wish I had uh the
community
the guidance the support
the yeah just the feeling like someone's
got your back because sometimes it feels
like it's just you on an island all
alone against the
world and it may look sexy from the
outside
but on the
inside you can be at
War I guess I say all this too just to
say to those Founders out there that are
building something they truly believe
in that are giving it their all day in
day out have
conviction have a
dream I want to encourage you
to keep going but more
importantly I want to encourage
you you're worth it and you deserve to
take a
break
rest is sometimes the ultimate
productivity
hack
and you've earned a right to take a step
back and just make sure that you're
taking care of
yourself you know you don't need to be
running a business that's running you
into the the ground there's people that
care about you there's people that have
your back
and everything's going to be just
great and
remember healthy
Founders build healthy
businesses my perspective great products
are
built from obsession
you know Steve
Jobs I love the Steve Jobs quote you
know be a yard stick of quality some
people aren't used to an environment
where Excellence is
expected and you know it's the truth you
know we're filled of a world you know
just
mediocrity mediocre products mediocre
people mediocre approaches to the
day-to-day and
you know things like quality customer
service care love you know and so many
products today you can't feel it at all
they're just void empty you know you
leave that restaurant and are shocked by
how bad the service is you know
you go and buy a new pair of headphones
you've been looking forward to and
suddenly the things don't
work and you know we all experience this
weekly and so for
me Beyond
Obsession a great product is
buil from attention to
detail at everything I do across founder
OS the backbone of a lot of it is
attention to
detail
and great
taste our belief as a
team is that taste is the ultimate
competitive
advantage and to me it's about having
that
instinct that instinct for what's
beautiful what's
elegant what's simple removing all the
distractions making the experience
Pleasant for people making it delightful
you know making it something that
enchants them makes them happy with the
smile on their
face you know looking forward
I'm excited because you know B Ross has
really got all the right ingredients to
continue to lean into just a great
product and that's what really jazzes me
up you know money doesn't excite me um
you know making another $10 million
doesn't excite me um I'm not looking to
be the richest guy in the
graveyard what really excites me is
helping Founders uh making their journey
through life more
joyful you know and for us the right
ingredients are
speed
reliability and quality and
today I'm on a little rip here from
lagona out to San Diego to go meet an
absolute Savage that I work with his
name is Ian the chief Revenue officer of
er another one of my
companies and
and we have some crazy stuff planned
today that has me pretty
nervous I haven't done what we're about
to do in like 13
years uh feels a little nerve-wracking
to be honest um something that I've been
kind of bit nervous on the last few days
borderline [\h__\h] my
pants and
yeah I think the big learning there is
just to do uncomfortable stuff daily and
so
today I'm going to be really pushing
myself yet again to just send it you
know and to do something that scares me
but that I know needs to be
done uh because it's just what's best
and sometimes you just got to make those
kind of calls in life
you out easy decisions hard
life hard
decisions easy
life all right here we
go now what are you doing in this airpl
bro I have no idea uh we're definitely
not scuba diving I'll tell you that
much Fly Like a Bird spin on the first
and the third solid I'm keeping my word
can't be
yo Matt welcome back to planet Earth
saing sound on the ground all in one
piece how was that skyd brother feeling
good probably the most epic team meeting
I've ever been on ah heck yeah would you
do it again oh hell yeah what was your
favorite part today feeling the the
heart pumping you know feeling alive
hell yeah well you look like an eagle up
there put it right here boom go jump
Ocean Side let's go flee beautiful job
brother all right to say that was the
most epic business meeting I've ever
been on would be an understatement how
do you feel complete understatement oh
epic life Chang
jumping out of a plane I actually feel a
level of like calm and kind of
meditative I don't know we you no 100%
usually people are freaking out at the
door but for some reason I was calm cool
collected ready to go it's uh one of the
yeah one of the most relaxing
experiences that I know of so this is
your friendly reminder to build
businesses with crazy folks crazy folks
make the best Executives and they get
after it they don't give a [\h__\h] that's
what you need you need a team of down
[\h__\h] people that will jump jump
out of planes with you you know if they
won't jump out a plane with you you
don't want them
[Music]
period now you got a great product in
place you got your marketing dialed in
and the next big thing are your systems
you know strong systems build a strong
business and allow you to build a
business where you can leave the
business for a month at a time come back
to it and it's stronger than when you
left you know and live really the
founder dream founder Freedom be able to
leave the business you know have it run
an autopilot with strong systems you
know great people and run what I call an
automated Empire an Empire that you know
runs without you so you can have
autonomy it's on autopilot due to the
systems you have in place um and all the
automations allow it to run smoothly
without you now
herb is an automated Empire you know and
has built the largest cannabis community
in the world over 14 million people and
it's really backed by legendary strong
formidable antifragile systems and so I
could tell you a lot about them but
there's actually someone I think a lot
more suited for it and it's the guy that
actually runs her so I'll pass it off to
Yan hey everyone thank you Matt the
biggest thing that I've learned in just
helping scale companies build
organizations is it's not about what
you're building is about who you're
building with and I'm a firm belier in
that right it's making sure that you
bring the right people on that see your
view that are they see your vision that
understand what it is you're looking at
accomplishing and are bought into that
they're all in but at the same time you
have to be all in on your employees
right so if you're going out there and
you want to build out the the next
million-dollar business or you want to
travel to the world without having any
issues or or any restraints then you
have to make sure that you have the
right systems and processes in place and
that starts with bringing the right
people on your team you have to make Mak
sure that you have people that you trust
you believe in that are on a on a a good
Mission and really have something that
they want to accomplish in their life
and then and that's what I that's what
helped herb grow that's what helped ma
grow is really about fine-tuning what
your vision is what you're here to to
provide to to the universe to society
and really making that become a stable
in your uh in your reality based on the
people you surround yourself with the
people you bring into your community in
your organization so when you look at
systems and processes
you can have a million dooll funnel but
if you have the wrong systems and the
wrong people in the wrong processes not
going to make you any money so doesn't
matter about having the perfect thing
it's about creating the perfect thing
within yourself within your business we
can only do that with strong people so
yeah know and I think a big part of it
too is like yeah when you think of like
hiring right it's systems recruitment
it's systems Sales Systems right it all
comes down to you know what are those
repeatable scalable you know formidable
systems that you have in place that
people can easily follow day night so
that while you're sleeping you know
those things are just running on
autopilot um and yeah inevitably it
frees you up mentally frees you up you
know spiritually everything to be able
to focus on much bigger things like you
know the vision you talked about and big
strategic opportunities you're trying to
close you're not lost in the weeds all
the time you're able to really level up
think 10x not 2X and build some real
[\h__\h] yeah and think about this way do
you look at business through the lens of
an sop do you have an sop for every
facet of your business are you waking up
and just shooting it from the
trying to find people trying to plug the
holes when the when the the holes come
up or do you have Sops in place to make
sure that no matter what hole what
problem arises you know that it's going
to be uh implemented and orchestrated
effectively through the S so you set in
place most people that I've talked to
over the years had no idea what an sop
is or
a yeah exactly so go get those Sops
going and uh that's it guys systems when
and out build systems you want to work
four hours a week four hours a day
whatever it may be build systems you
want to build that business of your
dreams build systems want to hire
amazing people have good systems so this
is your message got a big Vision get
those systems going