Human attention is shrinking, which is
why more cuts equal more engagement and
[music] more cuts also just make things
more cinematic. Changing up the visual
hooks to make people [music] retain into
the video. Using great sound to make
sure that people can hear your voice in
[music] a rich way. Ensuring that you
use text intentionally on the videos to
make sure that people can be prompted as
to where you are in the world and what
you're saying. Whether it's subtitles,
title [music] cards, pick a right font
that actually goes and inspires people.
And make sure that your brand is tight
with a core color, core color grade, and
all the details sorted [music]
out. Add movement. Walk, hand the
camera, film with good natural light
[music] with great sound so people can
actually hear what you're saying. Add
B-roll of all the core things that you
do. You know, for me, it's meditation,
hiking, [music] working. Switch your
backgrounds. You know, go outside,
inside, in nature, you know, in a cafe.
Change angles, [music]
over the shoulder, wide shots, close
shots, cinematic drone shots. Mix it up
[music] just to show the different
settings so people can actually put
themselves into your life and routine.