It isn't enough just to go and find your
voice to get a bunch of followers. You
really need to go and study the best of
the best on the platform [music] and
start to pick up on the patterns of
success. And start bookmarking the top
posts [music] on X that when you read
that post, you can't help but save it.
And so as you start going and writing
your own ideas to share on X, make
[music] sure that they feel like they're
in the same league as that best content
ever. I'm not talking about stealing the
content. I'm not talking about stealing
the hooks. I'm talking about using it as
inspiration and using it as a bar of
quality. Doing this a little bit of
upfront homework, right, is going to
allow your writing sessions to be that
much more impactful.