In this video, I'm going to show you how
[music] to go and make your stories
addictive in the six-part framework that
turns any story into profit. So, as
you're going through this as well, I
want you to think about one story you've
already told or want to tell. And I put
together a short storytelling growth
assessment that [music] you can use
after this video to map that story and
then see whether it can actually scale
into sales. [music] Watch this verse and
then go and diagnose your story after.
Step one, make your stories addictive.
First, you need to understand how to
make your stories addictive. In my how
to work less and earn more video, which
hit over $598,000
views, I opened up with, "If you thought
of someone making $730,000 per month,
how long would you guess they're
working?" Most would guess 12 to 14
hours a day, I'm doing the complete
opposite. Then I held that tension
through the whole video. I didn't
explain how until several minutes in.
And the result, people couldn't click
away. The reason this works is a garnic
effect. Your brain genuinely hates
unfinished business. Once you open a
loop in someone's mind, their nervous
system craves that closure. You
literally can't stop thinking about it
until it's resolved. You know, when
you're going and creating any video or
maybe you're writing something, right?
The main goal here is to actually go and
retain people to the end. And when
you're thinking, say, about a YouTube
thumbnail, the core currency and emotion
you're trying to drive there is
intrigue. intrigue is going to go and
drive the click, but once someone's in
the video, it's tension that you want to
go and create. That retention is going
to be created when people are really
[music] sucked into the story. And in
order to do that, you want to go and
open up different loops and then go and
create that tension and don't close it
for, you know, a few minutes later in
the video. You wouldn't believe what
happened next. And this nearly killed my
business. This was crazy, but nothing
yet compared to what happened next.
These kinds of questions keep people
diving in. Now, their brain leans in and
it needs the answer. You know, what
you'll often see is when you use these
kind of tactics multiple times
throughout a video, you're going to make
sure that people are hooked in the story
all the way through. On the other side
of things, shitty stories basically go
and get someone hooked at the beginning,
but then the story just seems to fall
flat because there's no more curiosity
gaps. [music] And so when you're going
and getting that story dialed in, make
sure you put the right curiosity gaps
throughout it to keep the viewer
retained. Step two, use storytelling as
your growth engine. Storytelling is your
fastest path to revenue. People remember
stories 20 times more than facts.
Stories get people emotionally involved
in your brand. You know, as much as we
like to think that we're just these
rational beings, the reality is we make
emotional decisions, especially when
we're purchasing. And so your story is
an amazing opportunity to develop that
emotional resonance and that emotional
bond with your core dream [music]
customer. This explains the psychology
behind luxury brands. You know, a Birkin
bag costs $50,000. And trust me, it's
not because the leather's something
special, but because of the story, the
artisans, the waiting list, the
heritage. Someone will wait 3 years for
that story. Your story is your strategy.
But more than that, a story is a funnel.
A funnel is the path someone takes from
never hearing about you to becoming a
paying customer. Most people think it's
linear. You know, traffic leads to calls
leads to sales. But that's not actually
how humans buy. The real funnel is this.
It's attention to trust to belief to
action. Attention gets people to stop
scrolling. Trust makes them listen.
Belief makes them think. This could
[music] work for me. Action is when they
finally buy. For me, when building
founder OS, I could have said, you know,
we just teach systems. Instead, I told
the story of the 15-hour days I was
working at 22, miserable, trapped, and
depressed, and the transformation then
to building a portfolio of businesses,
doing over $13.8 million a year, all
while being able to travel the world,
and really enjoy my life. So, show
people where you are, and tell [music]
that story of that journey. The founders
with the best stories win. You know,
what are those stories that you know,
people can really get grip to around
your brand? It may be your founder
story. It may be big crucibles of
leadership you've had to overcome. Maybe
it's the best [music] stories from your
customers that have gotten amazing
results. That's how you move them from
attention [music] to action. That's how
you make profits way faster. And so now
you might be wondering, well, what if my
story isn't good enough? That's where
most people [music] are dead wrong. Step
three, your story is really your unfair
advantage. And I have proof here.
There's one thing Kim Kardashian
understands about business that most
founders ignore. Kim Kardashian skims
versus every Shopify shapewear brand.
There's some obvious things that stand
out, right? Same [music] product, same
factories, but Ski crushes them. Why?
People buy into Kim's story, her
journey, her obsession with shapewear,
because of the insane outfit she wears.
That's the moat generic brands can't
copy. For me, sharing one of my worst
periods of my life had the same effect.
I'd gone through business school and
honestly felt like the whole investment
in going to business school was a
complete [\h__\h] waste of time. You
know, this was the genesis of why I went
and created Bitmaker, my first company.
The goal there was to go and train full
stock software engineers 7 months in,
crushing it, 200k per month, and then
the government comes and raids my
business. Two agents walk in after
seeing an article in the Globe Mail and
they tell me that we got a shutdown
because they think that I'm operating an
unregistered private career college,
which [music] was pretty insane because
we weren't giving any grades. We were
certainly not a university or a college.
We were just a training program getting
people jobs at top tech companies in
Toronto like Shopify, Facebook, and
Google. I could go to jail for a year,
find up to a million dollars. [\h__\h]
insane. And the main thing that I know
to do in that moment was [music] tell
the story to as many humans as possible.
Sure enough, I went and stayed up for 48
hours straight, emailed over 3,000
people personally, and told the story of
why we had created BitMaker and the
impact it was having across the Canadian
tech community. [music] The story went
viral and within one week, the
government backed off. We got the only
exemption of its kind in Canada. Fast
forward one year later, we trained over
2,000 software engineers, and [music]
the business was acquired for a
life-changing sum. That story did more
for my credibility than any credential.
It wasn't polished. It was my actual
life story and one of the craziest
experiences I'd ever gone through. It
was the story that saved me, right?
Because when thousands of people ended
up hearing this story of what we were
going through, they couldn't help but
act. You know, Ben Horowitz famously
said, "Your story is your strategy. your
authenticity, your challenges, the
things you've overcome, the stuff that
you wish you had known 5 years ago. So
run with the five-year test. What
blueprints or challenges do you wish
someone had shown you 5 years ago? Share
the chaos that almost broke you, right?
Those moments that shifted you. Those
are the stories your audience needs
[music] right now. You have a story,
right? And what we now need to do is go
and uncover what that story is for you.
This is where the five line story
framework comes in. And the reason it
works is the same reason the biggest
movies make billions at the box office.
Joseph Campbell's The Hero with a
Thousand Faces analyzed myths all over
the world. Greek, Norse, African, and
Asian. You realize they all follow the
same structure, the hero's journey. Star
Wars, The Matrix, Harry Potter, every
story you love follows this arc. This is
why I use a fiveline framework for
business stories. Step one, the mirror,
[music] where they are right now. You
want them thinking, "Holy [\h__\h] this guy
is literally reading my mind." Example,
you're stuck in Slack all day. Message
after message, it feels impossible to
keep up. You keep feeling like you're on
this treadmill. The day ends, you look
yourself in the mirror. You're brushing
your teeth, and you can't help but think
to yourself, "How long can I keep going
like this?" Every wind still requires
you. [music] Step two, the friction.
Why? They're stuck. This is the personal
cost and not just the business problem.
So, you know, an example here might be
you keep missing your kids' birthdays,
[music] no real vacation in three years,
your partner asks when things will slow
down, and you have no good answer. Step
three, [music] the realization. This is
the epiphany no one tells them. For
example, the problem isn't your work
ethic, it's that you are the system.
Replace yourself with systems and
everything will accelerate. [music] Step
four, the shift, your transformation. I
went from 15-hour days to 4-hour days,
burnt out to energized and trapped to
free. And last, the invitation. [music]
This is the natural next step. If this
resonates, here's what to do. At this
point, most understand the framework,
but you still don't understand where
your story breaks. That's exactly why
the storytelling growth assessment
exists. It forces you to map one story
using these five lines and then shows
you which of your line is killing
scalability. If your stories aren't
converting, well, this is going to make
it obvious why people don't buy
conclusions, they buy clarity about
themselves. The mirror and friction earn
that early and then most people rush to
the solution. Don't make them feel
understood first. [music] Because if you
can describe someone's lived situation
better than they can, they're going to
trust you then to go and provide them
with the right improvement or solution
through your product or service. This
[music] becomes a skill that I find I
can pick up by actually just going and
getting outside of the room and just
talking with customers. It's from these
actual stories that I hear from your
mouths that I'm able to then go and
weave those into the different stories
that I tell on this channel and all
through Founder OS. The best copy just
exists in the words of your dream
customer. And so the same thing goes for
the best stories you can tell. All
right, [music] so you've got the
structure now, but here's one fatal
mistake people make that stops them from
making money, even with this framework,
which is why you need to understand the
right way to turn your story into sales.
If you want to sell without sounding
salesy, [music]
here's what you need to do. Where most
people go and screw this up is that they
go and have some sort of call to action
that just jolts people out of the story.
They'll go and tell this amazing story.
They'll captivate people and then
they'll say something generic as hell
like, "Hey, if you like this, go and
join my newsletter." Or, [music] you
know, if you like what I'm talking about
right now, you should go book a call,
right? Well, the thing that you really
want to focus on is making sure that the
call to action is tightly coupled
[music]
with the story itself. A good CTA is
inevitable. It's a natural next step.
The story opens up a loop and then the
lead magnet closes it. [music] An
example is if I told you about being
stuck at 22, working 13-hour days, and
then said, "If this feels like what
you're going through, go and grab this
guide [music] so you can systematically
remove yourself from operations." You
see, that's connected, right? Not
random. You want to be insanely
generous. When you give genuine value
for free, selling becomes natural.
People [music] think, "If this stuff is
free, what's inside the paid stuff?" So,
after every piece of content, ask
yourself, what loop did I open? You
know, what problem did I surface? What's
the smallest most valuable thing I can
give that starts solving it where I see
a lot of people screw up as they think
that they're just done at telling the
story. Most people I see online don't
give anything away clearly go and guide
them to the logical next step that's
going to help then solve that problem.
And the good news here is that as they
go and download that lead magnet as an
example, you're going to go and be able
to collect that email. And as you
probably know from watching this
channel, email is the most powerful way
you can sell to people. In any business,
it's typically your email list that is
your most valuable asset. So if you want
the email, make sure that you have lead
magnets that are tightly coupled to your
story. This is how you create stories
that convert. If you think everything
I've shared sounds like a lot of work,
then the good news here is you don't
need new ideas every day. Most people
are creating content on hard mode. Let
me save you here. Okay, here's how to do
it on easy mode. Now, you just need to
apply the content waterfall system.
Before this system, I was posting
randomly, inconsistent, [music]
burning out, trying to be everywhere all
the time. So, let me walk you through
it. [music] This is the content
waterfall. My system starts with content
creation, which is around 2 to four
hours a week, one long form video, and
then I turn that into one deep
newsletter essay. I record different
coaching calls, which are also content
gold mines, and then distribute that.
But that's all my team handling it,
right? Each editor is able to generally
pull a bunch of the best moments from
these long- form pieces of content and
then distribute that in places like
YouTube shorts, Instagram reels, and Tik
Tok videos. On the Instagram side, we
typically use carousels, right? And it's
my designer that goes and takes our core
frameworks and puts them over there.
From there, my copywriter can turn
scripts [music] into different long-
form content for platforms like LinkedIn
as an example. And we also will
typically go and take my raw writing
which I have in different journals or
I'm sharing right now on X articles or
[music] in my YouTube videos and then
they can go and take that and cut that
up into 20 plus other pieces of content.
To be clear, [music] we don't just do
this with everything. Okay. The kind of
way you want to view your content
system, [music] right, is that you're
putting all of these stories out there
to the world. And there's going to be
some of your stories that are either
[music] insanely important or you see
them perform extremely well. And so what
you want to go do is take those winners
and then what we do is call waterfall
them. Waterfall meaning that you take
that core story and you go and break it
up into smaller pieces and [music]
distribute those smaller pieces. When
you waterfall content, you go and you
multiply it. The dark side of building a
founder brand is the fact that it's you.
So, if you're not careful about
multiplying your content, quickly
[music] it could feel like you're on a
content hamster wheel. And this is why
it's important to have the right team in
place, editors, [music]
social managers, video producers, and
the right systems in place like this
content waterfall system. You know, you
get it right. having [music] the right
tools in place, the right people in
place and the right system to make this
way more seamless, scalable and
effortless. For me, [music] you know,
when I go and view building this story
engine in my companies, right, it's
moving from just being the creator of a
personal brand to being the CEO of a
personal media company. A personal media
company, right, is going to remove you
from a lot of the actual content
operation. It's going to build leverage
through your team and systems, and most
importantly, it's going to give you
longevity. The best storytellers stay in
the game for a long, long period of
time. And that's what we want to set you
up for. Pick one story from your
business. You know, maybe it's your
origin story, some crucible story, or
some story like, you know, this almost
killed us. Film it, write it, map it
everywhere it can live. YouTube, YouTube
shorts, Instagram, LinkedIn, email, then
repurpose it to all of these platforms.
[music]
Most people invent something new daily.
And I think that's a mistake. And
honestly, it's exhausting. And [music]
that's why most people burn out. And
most creators just give up. Go deep on
one story. You know, pour your [music]
creativity, your authenticity, your
vulnerability, your genius into that one
story. Make it undeniable. [music] Now,
let your distribution multiply it. Build
once, distribute forever. So, here's
where you go and take action. So, buckle
up. Step one, use the storytelling
growth assessment to map your story and
then identify the first line that breaks
conversion. [music] Step two, I want you
to go and book a call with me and the
team and then go and bring that
assessment to the call because [music]
we're going to go and then pair that
with our systems to see where your
stories could be driving more revenue.
Don't forget to hit subscribe and I'll
see you in this next video where I break
down how to build a profitable personal
brand in just [music] seven steps. So,
I'll see you over there and let's
continue to win