Everyone is asking if we're in an AI
bubble. So, here's my take as an 8
[music] figureure entrepreneur that uses
AI every day. We're both in a bubble and
at the cusp of probably a new
generational shift. You [music] know,
you're seeing companies raise
astronomical sums one after the other.
The reality is is that probably 90% of
these companies long term will fail,
right? But that's kind of the venture
capital model in a [music] nutshell.
That said, I think it also represents
this new platform shift, right? I think,
you know, we're moving away from Google
and using, you know, platforms like Chat
GBT or Anthropic, right? And I don't see
that being a bubble that's going to stop
anytime soon. In fact, I think it's only
going to accelerate.