Going viral is like training martial
arts. When I first started my personal
brand 5 years ago, X was my dojo. What I
started to learn on X was it was these
long-form X posts [music] combined with
great imagery as well as great video
clips that started to allow me to go and
stand out as this triple threat. I went
from virtually unknown
>> [music]
>> to one of the top 10 creators on the
entire platform. And the beautiful thing
is that from the depth on one platform,
it's not like all that content goes to
waste. Truthfully, through the content
waterfall system, I was then able to go
and take that exact [music] content on X
and bring that to LinkedIn long-form as
well as Instagram carousels. Now, when
you combine this with the right [music]
infrastructure, and what I mean by that
is not just growing your audience, but
having an email list in place and then
driving people from your rented audience
on the platform you pick to your owned
audience in an email list, you're going
to be able [music] to capture all of
this attention and then effectively
drive it to monetization leveraging what
I call the content GPS.