This is one of two YouTube plaques that
YouTube sent us for growing our YouTube
channels in 2025 and we're excited to
get these plaques from YouTube. We
believe these are just the beginning of
what God's called us to do when it comes
to the content that we're creating and
distributing through the platform of
YouTube. Cool to get a plaque for
100,000 subscribers. We think we need to
see millions of subscribers and in turn
hundreds of millions of views on our
videos if we're going to accomplish our
mission. So, we're just getting started
but I want to share what we've done to
grow as much as we did on YouTube in
2025 and what we're focusing in on as we
lean into YouTube in 2026 and beyond.
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; Hey there, if we haven't met yet, I'm
Neil Smith, VP of Marketing at
Faithdriven Movements and this is just a
series I'm doing here on my personal
YouTube channel to learn out loud as I'm
wrapping up my first year. I'm actually
recording this in the middle of the
Christmas New Year window and we're all
kind of decompressing a little bit. This
is an exercise that I often do of just
journaling and I thought, you know, let
me just turn on the camera and journal
[music] out loud. And so, you lot of
times people say this is building in
public or learning out loud. So, this is
my way of doing this and I hope that
it's helpful for you as I'm learning out
loud the things that that we have
prioritized at Faithdriven Movements,
how that might be able to help your
organization. So, YouTube has been a
critical platform for us in the last
year. It seemed like a no-brainer to me.
It's actually I think one of the main
reasons Faithdriven was drawn to hiring
me is because of my background with
social media and with YouTube. And so,
what what I knew coming into Faithdriven
Movements is they create great content.
So, they we now uh create great content,
but at that point it was they create
great video content. Like exceptional.
Should be on Netflix or on television or
what the second to none from the
content, but it doesn't always get as
many views as it should from my
perspective and it it just I think is a
matter of and it's timeless. And so I
knew, [music] you know, with more
opportunity there would be ways to drive
more traffic to this content. And
YouTube is there's so much of it is art
and good content wins, but you got to
package it right. You got to spend a lot
of time on the packaging. You can't just
put the content out there and throw it
out there and hope it goes viral. You've
got to drive some traffic. You've got to
get some get the snowball moving. And so
as we began to build the Faith Driven
Entrepreneur's snowball, we had three
channels that we were primarily
developing.
That's Faith Driven Entrepreneur,
Solving the World's Greatest Problems,
and Faith Driven Investor. Now, one of
the big shifts that we're making that
was really
helping really has helped our Faith
Driven Entrepreneur and Faith Driven
Investor channels is we took audio
podcasts that have historically been
audio and began recording those in
video. Well, that gave us new weekly
video content on these channels that we
could begin utilizing. Now, not just
utilizing for the core long-form video
podcast, but also for the clips. Now,
one of the early hires that we made is
[music] in a full-time clips editor. So,
their only job is his name is Jared.
He's an incredible editor on our team.
His only job is to take videos from
either our core content that we're
already creating our historical library
of content, but primarily [snorts] from
our new podcast content and create clips
that we can use as YouTube shorts, that
we can use as clips to post on LinkedIn,
that we can use as reels on Instagram or
Facebook, but really primarily YouTube
shorts was the platform for [music] that
content. And so a combination of really
packaging our content differently,
having regular consistent new content,
and then having clips took our YouTube
content through the roof in 2025. Let me
just share some of the stats from our
channel in 2025.
Just looking at the YouTube for the
Faith Driven Entrepreneur channel in
2025, we had 3.4
million views, 82,000 hours watched, and
144,000
new subscribers to our channel.
Incredible. Incredible growth on that a
channel, and I believe that those
numbers will probably be tripled this
year if the engagement continues, which
I have no reason to believe that it will
slow in any [music] way. And so,
incredible to see what what can happen,
but a few things that I wanted to just
share that we prioritized in that
process that has really helped us me
just go and share my screen cuz I think
that will help. Okay, when you go to our
channel, one of the things you'll see is
just a very intentional uh banner image
here, uh profile image that a a welcome
video get to know Faith Driven
Entrepreneur. Uh so, if you don't have
that welcome video uh built into your
channel, I highly recommend it. Start
here is just some of our key videos. Uh
this history I can you know, you got to
go watch these videos. So, if you
haven't watched these yet, uh these
these are key videos to the movement
with Dear Entrepreneur. Don't journey
alone, um
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; and the history uh of Faith Driven
Entrepreneurship. Uh just great videos.
Then, you'll see here our podcast, and
this is where we're doing a ton of
testing. Uh one of the things that that
we're testing uh as YouTube now makes it
available is you can do three different
titles and three different thumbnails.
And so, one of the things we're testing
with our thumbnails is even how big this
text should be. Should it be orange or
should it be white? In some videos,
we're actually finding the orange text
uh to perform better, some the white, uh
some we have a little orange even
background in the image itself. Um some
we've tested with multiple, you know, um
Hey guys, just want to interrupt myself
real quick. Get back to the video in a
minute, but want to highlight Amplify
Social Media. Amplify is the agency that
I started more than a dozen years ago. I
transitioned out, handed the company
over to Matt Williams, Darrylin, the
incredible team at Amplify. They're
continuing to help me. I'm a client now
of Amplify, still an owner, still have
an aspect of involvement, but really
focused on by work at faith-driven
movement. And so, [music] I'm so proud
of the team at Amplify, and I want to
make sure that you, as you're watching
this, if you are looking for help
amplifying your message like I am with
this video, [music] reach out to the
team at Amplify. Amplify social.media.
Talk to Matt, talk to Kelly, talk to
Farina, talk to Jerry Lynn, talk to Roy,
talk to any of the incredible team
members there at Amplify, and [music] I
know they would love to help you amplify
your message. They do everything from
social media to podcast to YouTube
videos like this to all kinds of
content, websites, anything digital.
They do not just social media, while
that is our specialty and where we
really started, our services have
expanded. So, make sure you reach out to
the team at Amplify. Doesn't cost you
anything to talk to [music] them, worth
the conversation, see what they can do
and if they can help you amplify your
message. Let's get back to the video.
The host and the guest or just the guest
in front of the the image or just the
guest closer up front on their face
performs better. So, we're testing
[music] so many different aspects of uh
what drives the better engagement rate.
And by even just [music] getting a
better thumbnail, we'll get twice the
engagement rate. So, it's taking the
time to do that. Uh if you look even
here in our short section, uh some of
these videos are getting 2,300 views,
821 views, but then some of them, this
one right here got 183,000 views. This
one got 269,000
views. So, some of these will just pop
uh more than others. And so, really need
to see and and having a diversity of a
lot of different content of how those
shorts are really driving up a lot of
that engagement, especially some of that
subscriber growth. And so, where you'll
see the 3 million views, but [music]
then
a smaller number of the uh hours watched
is because
um not all of our content is 30 minutes
or an hour long. Uh a lot of that
content that's combined with the shorts
and long form, and these shorts are all
typically about a minute long. So, you
get a much shorter time span and it
depends on if somebody's watching on a
mobile device or whether they're
watching on a computer
as to what they're going to be watching
on or you know, most what's fastest
growing on YouTube is now people
watching on their television.
And so, our hope is is that
business leaders are watching our
podcast in their board room with a team
together.
And so, that there's that that activity
and that engagement happening
within the channel.
The other thing I want to just throw out
that we've added to YouTube that people
often, you know, ask about is are you
running ads and is this growth due to
ads? The answer is yes, we're running
ads. Is the growth due to ads? Some of
it, but but I think the reality is we
wouldn't spend money on ads if we didn't
first feel confident in how we're
packaging and distributing without the
ads. And so, the ads allow us to target
in different ways. A lot of how we're
using ads is even towards retargeting of
people that are engaging with our
content to then visit our website and
visit take action around joining a group
or starting a group or attending a
conference. And so, we're using ads
creatively in that way.
But then also to build awareness and to
reach more content with a specific video
that might be performing well, we'll add
to that. And YouTube now you used to
have to go through Google Ads to set up
ads. They now have a promotion feature
in your in your YouTube studio that
makes it super easy to almost like a
boosted post on Instagram or Facebook.
Makes it super easy to just, you know,
get a little bit more traffic around
certain content or certain videos. We
like to do a little bit deeper. So, we
do primarily run ads through Google Ads,
but we we have tested through the
promotion feature and it has made it
super easy if there's certain videos
that we see are performing well that we
want to get it even extra eyes on. That
promotion feature has made it super easy
for us to integrate ads into our growth
strategy on YouTube as a platform. I
think coming back to our whole strategy
though, we say come for the content,
stay for the community. And so, we're
really trying to be intentional to use
YouTube as an awareness platform, as a
way to get our content out there. We
believe somebody's going to listen to a
30-minute podcast or listen to a few of
these, the likelihood that they're
they're then going to feel connected
enough to join a group or to sign up to
lead a group is much higher to attend
one of our conferences. And so, we
really want to take the great content we
put so much effort and energy around to
then [music] package it well, putting a
lot more energy and effort around the
packaging. And I mentioned the clips
editor, you know, it's our designers
what they're doing around the thumbnails
is is it also a significant investment
in how we're packaging that content. But
then we're retargeting those to get them
to our website. So, moving them,
building awareness through how we're
distributing and engaging people with
the content, and then retargeting,
[music] you know, based on their
engagement with our content. So, they're
watching for 3 minutes or more, we're
probably going to retarget them to take
another action. Or if they bailed after
20 seconds, we're probably said that
whatever we were messaging didn't
resonate with them. And so, we're not
necessarily going to retarget them.
And so, the algorithms build and learn
and how we're using these platforms to
to target and reach our right audience
and those that resonate with our message
and those that don't. And so that we can
continue to learn and adapt and adjust
and create better content and more
naturally flow people into our
organization and from the content into
community. So, that's how we're using
YouTube. I would love uh your thoughts
as we continue to lean into YouTube.
Video content is something we're going
to keep doubling down on, tripling down
on as an organization. And YouTube as a
platform feels clear to me that YouTube
is the platform for video distribution,
video engagement [music] into the
future. And so, while there are
different social networks and platforms
that are changing all the times, YouTube
is one of those platforms that is
changing from a feature standpoint, but
not in a tangent standpoint. And so,
when we think when we think about our
target audience and where pretty much
anyone anywhere is engaging with video
content, it is YouTube. Um and so, it
will continue to be a significant
priority for us into the new year and
has been incredibly fruitful for the
investment we've made uh so far in this
first year. I'm excited to see what's
ahead. I'm going to keep learning a lot.
I'm going to keep building in public. If
you have any questions about what we're
doing on YouTube or have any ideas or
thoughts or recommendations, drop them
in the comments. I would love to learn
and hear from what you're doing as well
as we grow and learn together. Thanks so
much for watching. We'll talk to you
again on the next video.
&gt;&gt; [music]