In this video, I'm going to talk about
all the websites we built at Faith
Driven Movements, what technology we
used, what systems we used, what
strategy we used, and where we're going
with our website infrastructure. Lean in
to this. We're going to get a little
technical, uh, but really at the core,
we all have a website that we need to
prioritize, or websites in our case. And
I want to talk about how we've
approached this, what we're doing, what
we've done, and where we're going.
Hey there. If we haven't met yet, I'm
Neil Smith, the VP of Marketing at Faith
Driven Movements. And I'm just doing
this series to learn out loud, to build
in public, uh, to share what I'm
learning in the process of leading our
marketing team, leading our marketing
efforts as we are building a rocket ship
in the air. Uh, what God is doing, uh,
through Faith Driven Movements is is
just miraculous, but also very
intentional, also very strategic. Uh,
and so a big part of that, [music]
uh, is our our our our websites. It is
our home base uh, in many ways as we as
we move people in strategically into our
organization. We will often say, "Come
for the content, stay for the
community." Uh, and so I want to talk
about how we're doing that with our
websites. And practically, I see
marketing in [music] three key buckets
of of the pathway of one is awareness,
uh, which is often done on social media
and through advertising. The other is
consideration, where you're checking
out, uh, the organization. That's
primarily done
on the website,
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; uh, and often through email, and then
conversion, which is done either through
an advertising effort or sometimes even
a conversation, an interaction, or just
a sheer transaction, uh, that's that's
happening. For us, that's often getting
somebody into a foundation group. And so
uh, we offer free community groups of
our content is free, our groups are
free. Uh, it's confusing, uh, for some,
um, and as I've shared before,
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; uh, I want to encourage you to go back
to see the other videos. Uh, we have a
value proposition that seems too good to
be true, yet it is better uh, than it is
even perceived uh, to be and that's one
of the unique marketing challenges and
opportunities uh, that we have and I
believe why we're growing as fast as we
are. So, let's talk about the websites.
When I started with Interim Movements,
one of the things that just attracted me
to the organization was just the
excellence in which I saw all of their
websites. They just looked professional,
uh, they looked beautiful, they they
were clearly very strategically designed
and built, uh, great copy and messaging
uh, on the websites. I I would say if
there's one
you know, knock I would have on the
websites is that they're cluttered and a
little crowded. I would say we still
have this challenge because the problem
is we have so much content, we have so
much stuff uh, that we want to just give
uh, to uh, those that are coming into
our organization that we have a hard
time of where do we prioritize to make a
clear, concise path for people. So, it
is a tension that we are managing uh, on
our websites of how do we include
everything and make it navi [music] you
know, where you can easily navigate uh,
but then also get people to what they
want to do. But, the first thing I had
to do uh, or that I felt as it was a
priority is that in our organization
we were in transition. The majority of
the websites had initially been built in
Squarespace and [music] were being moved
into WordPress uh, and then WordPress
more specifically we use Nexus hosting,
we use GoDaddy uh, domain management and
then we use Divi uh, as our you know,
basically theme uh, within our websites
to build on top of uh, my in the
background I'm a big fan [music] of
WordPress uh, for the last you know, I
don't know 15, 20 years
uh, so definitely not new new to
WordPress. I have primarily used
Elementor. Uh, so if you're familiar
with Elementor, Divi is very similar to
um, and works great, you know, lots of
great functionality. It is it is kind of
a best-in-class platform. Squarespace
I've always been a big fan of and I
think it was a good move for for Faith
Driven start at Squarespace because it's
I compared to Apple, it's hard to break,
but it's also hard to really customize.
And so, you can only take it so far. And
I think with our organization growing as
fast as we are with it as unique as as
we are, we needed something that could
scale with us. And so, having already
made that decision to move to WordPress
and with Divi, I think it was a wise
move that I inherited. And so, I'm glad
to be able to just take that and run
further with it.
But we we had about half of our websites
not on Divi. So, we had to really
you know, prioritize
getting everything over. Now, we're
talking hundreds of pages, things that
have been developed over, you know, the
[music] last 5 years.
And what needs to come, what needs to
stay, what needs to go. The truth is a
year later, we're still working through
this. We still have old blog content
that we need to get active. And
you know, people that have been in our
videos and and bios that that need to
get updated and revised. It is a
never-ending project. And things like
SEO that we're continuing [music] to
optimize. But one of the first steps
that we had to make and probably took us
about 4 months is to get everything from
Squarespace and out of Squarespace and
into
Divi with WordPress. And so, we were
able to prioritize that. All of our
websites are now on Divi.
And
and and are now being optimized. We've
got a great team. You know, want to
highlight Eric, [music]
Angela, Julian, John, Errol. John's
John's really been our WordPress expert
to to help us
in so many ways to to really maximize
some of the WordPress functionality. And
now we're getting more and even SEO as
we're digging deeper in the pages as we
want every page to be optimized well.
And there's some great tools out there
to help.
Help like SEMrush is a platform that
that we've used more recently. But just
to help to clean up the the way some of
your back pages work, some of your 404
pages, getting it into the weeds of it.
So, we we've really been prioritizing
the technical side
of the
website. But, what we you [music] know
and and what
I've talked about in previous videos is
that it's not necessarily what you have,
it's how you use it. We could be on
Squarespace and if we had a bad website,
it doesn't matter how well
you know, how strong it is technically,
if it doesn't message the right thing to
the right audience in the right way,
make it easy for them to take action,
it's broken.
And so, we we've really needed to
prioritize our messaging. We're
constantly testing. We're doing a lot of
AB testing.
Love some different tools out there
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; that my team knows I don't necessarily
know or can share with them and we're so
early to using them, probably not
comfortable promoting them as of yet
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; because we're still so new into some of
the AB testing that we're doing live on
the website, but excited about what that
is going to open up for our website
users. So, let me actually just go ahead
and go to one of our websites and just
show you
what it looks like and what we're
prioritizing when it comes to the
website itself.
This is our Faith-Driven Entrepreneur
website and you can see up here at the
top, we've got a lot going [music] on
here in the navigation. This is probably
our longest
first website
and so, there is years and years of
content. One of the first things you'll
see is our first process in the
navigation is
content and the foundation course, video
courses, teens course, podcast, books,
research, insights, we got an app, we
have U version, reading plans in the
Bible app.
And so, you can go through our website,
you can actually see here, these are our
key calls to action, places that you can
take action getting on our email [music]
list, signing up for our teens course.
By the way, I got two teenagers that
just we completely go through the teens
course, it's free now. So, if you're
watching this,
uh it might still uh be free. It was
$100. It'll probably go back to $100,
but uh I I'd go check it out. Um it is
incredible uh content. Um and the we
have the Table Group has partnered with
us, and
um yeah, just it's it's so cool. Um
and uh yeah, we've got our book here.
So, some other activities you can see
there here. We're featuring one of our
videos uh that you can just jump right
into
uh that that we want to highlight there.
Content, community, coaching,
connection. Uh this is what we do. Try
to inspire people to get in the game. Um
and so, here's a great video
um
that is uh David Platt uh did with us uh
called Dear Entrepreneur.
Um it just really introduces why we
exist and how uh you [music] uh can get
involved and engaged.
Um I'm even seeing right here just the
blurriness of that image. Something for
us to improve uh here on the website.
So, every day we're just looking at how
can we improve? Um
and what can we pay attention to? One of
the things I And And then practically,
what we've really identified is if
you're coming for the content and then
you're staying for the community, what
is that process for [music] one Are
people coming to our website, and are
they looking at content? So, So, we're
tracking that. And then the other is
this find a group.
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; Uh when somebody goes here, uh we they
go to find a group, and do they choose
entrepreneur or investor? And
uh and this is how they get into a group
on our our web page. And so, does our
site do a good job of getting people
into both finding a group and starting a
group? Um and [music] so, one of the
things we've really prioritized is these
pages in particular.
And so, as you think about your website,
one of the things I would encourage you
to do is to think about what is the key
action you want somebody that's visiting
your website to take. And And so, for
us, you know, the first thing we hope
they do is look at get on email list.
And so, are we providing a good value
proposition as to why they should get on
our email list? So,
the value proposition comes with is the
value you're already providing for free,
is it valuable? And so, if I give you my
email, is the additional value going to
also be valuable? If what you're already
providing isn't real valuable, I'm not
convinced that, you know, me giving you
my email address is going to all of a
sudden bring new value. And so, we we're
we're testing how can we get somebody to
sign up for our email list better? We're
testing a lot of different even pop-ups
and
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; just newsletter sign-up forms. And then
the second is is joining a group. Is is
what happens when people join a group?
And so, one of the things we're using to
really test this is we're actually
testing different language of is it join
a group or is it get in a group or is it
find a group?
So, is is there language that works
better? [music] Is the button being
orange or gold going to be better? Which
one drives more action?
And so, we're we're finding a lot of
just great insights by just doing a lot
of AB testing with some of those
messaging. And then the other thing
we're using is heat maps. So, we're
using Microsoft's Clarity platform to
heat map all of our web pages
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; and give us insights into
how are people behaving on our websites?
What actions are they taking and how can
we improve? Maybe we need to move this
call to action up. Maybe we need to
remove a whole block from a web page
where we have too much information on
that page where they're leaving after
this and they're not engaging past a
certain point on the page. And so, yeah,
we're we're putting in and doing a lot
of testing and now and I think we're
moving it from a marketing perspective
into build and into to optimize. [music]
And we're optimizing based on data and
analytics. And so, I'll get into that
further how we moved into
a really significant priority of
analytics and data in our marketing
systems and strategy. But that's where
our websites have come. So, we've gone
from focusing on the technical to then
really prioritizing the content and the
engagement and conversion on these
platforms. I just want to interrupt
myself real quick, get back to the video
in a minute, but want to highlight
Amplify Social Media. Amplify is the
agency that I started more than a dozen
years ago. I transitioned out, handed
the company over to Matt Williams,
Jerilyn, the incredible team at Amplify.
They're continuing to help me. I'm a
client now at Amplify, still an owner,
still have an aspect of involvement, but
really focused on but I work at Faith
Driven Movements. And so, I'm so proud
of the team at Amplify and I want to
make sure that you, as you're watching
this, if you are looking for help
amplifying your message like I am with
this video, reach out to the team at
Amplify. AmplifySocial.Media.
Talk to Matt, talk to Kelly, talk to
Farina, talk to Jerilyn, talk to Roy,
talk to any of the incredible team
members there at Amplify and I know they
would love to help you amplify your
message. They do everything from social
media to podcast to YouTube videos like
this to all kinds of content, websites,
anything digital. They do not just
social media, well that is our [music]
specialty, but where we really started,
our services have expanded. So, make
sure you reach out to the team at
Amplify. It doesn't cost you [music]
anything to talk to them, worth the
conversation, see what they can do and
if they can help you amplify your
message. Let's get back to the video.
And and now, I think we're going to move
into hyper engagement with that
while while also continuing to refine
what what do we need to add to our
websites? What, you know, are more pages
going to be helpful for SEO? And as we
get into more
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; chat GPT kind of SEO
functionality, what's going to be
important for that for people to find
our websites and engage with them? And
then beyond that,
it is what what are what do we need to
do to to trim our websites? Where where
have our websites gotten fatter? You
have pages that are outdated or
information that that's inaccurate or no
longer accurate or no longer represents
our organization well. We need to
constantly be refining those websites
and so,
our web pages can get very old and
outdated and people can land on old
pages and get very confused. Or one of
the things I see all the time is, you
know, the wrong date. It's 2025
uh or now, probably 2026,
uh and it still says 2022 at the bottom
of your website. Uh do you have the
right date? Uh because that can tell
people of like, "Are they even still in
business?"
Um and so, we we need to make sure uh
we're prioritizing these little things
on our website. So, uh the other last
thing I want to note when it comes to
our website
is having people that have a high
attention to detail involved in your
website process. Well, I mean, I
mentioned before that we hired a
marketing director. Uh her name is
Kristen. She has been such a great asset
uh to our organization. And one of those
things is just her high attention to
detail uh when it comes to not just not
just, you know, project management, but
really like making sure these pages uh
the copy is getting integrated with the
pages well, uh that the the design is
fitting well, that the uh that that
we're doing it in our QA processes. We
now have a
a QA person on our team that that's
their job is to QA
um primarily our web pages. Uh and so,
we're really beginning to prioritize
that that quality uh level uh when we
get to the optimization of our web
pages. So, hope that helps uh as we're
continuing to build out loud, um that's
where we're at uh with our web pages. We
have seen great progress. I think this
is probably an area uh that that you'll
see and I'll I'll continue to
uh share
our learnings. Uh but, I don't think
we're going to change a whole lot
technically in the future, but I think
we're going to take a lot of this AB
testing that we're doing, integrate
this, and so you guys see uh a lot of
just little small refinements happening
uh that we believe are going to help to
really scale our core objectives uh as
we're learning from the data that's
coming into the website and the user
behaviors into our website. So, thanks
so much for watching. If you have any
questions, don't hesitate to drop those
uh in the comments. I'd love to answer
those. Uh if you're not yet engaged with
faith driven entrepreneur solving the
world's greatest problems, faith driven
investor, we just have so many great
things going on with the faith driven
movements. I hope you'll get involved. I
think it's there's something here for
everyone. It has been such an honor for
me to lead as the VP of marketing and I
hope it's helpful for you as I'm
learning out loud here as we're building
in public. Thanks for watching. We'll
talk to you again on the next video.
&gt;&gt; [music]