Hey guys, today we're going to be
looking at HeatBit, a Bitcoin miner
that's also a heater for your house.
We're going to ask a question, can you
effectively heat your house and mine
Bitcoin at the same time? Is it worth
the price?
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; Let's take a look. I'm going to open the
box with you today and we're going to
hook it up, see how easy it is to use,
and how much Bitcoin does it actually
generate as a miner, and how warm does
it actually heat my little office here
in New York City. Let's jump into the
video.
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; Hey there, if we haven't met yet, I'm
Neil Smith. I'm actually author of a
book called Crypto for Good. I wrote
this book several years ago, probably
seven years ago now, with my friend Nick
Runyon. I believe significantly in the
power of the blockchain, the power of
Bitcoin, and the opportunities that it's
going to create and already has created
for so many. It's gone through waves. It
goes through waves
and and I think we're seeing the shift
in attention and focus as mine has
shifted to AI, but blockchain technology
is far from gone, far from being a fad
that disappeared. It is continuing to
develop [music] and this is a hardware
device that I'm pretty excited to try.
When HeatBit reached out to me, I was
very excited to try out the product, but
I was very transparent with them.
[music] You can send it to me, I'll try
it out, I'll post a video about it, but
I'm going to be honest if I like it or
not. So, I'm always glad to test out new
products, but one of the things I'm
committed to here is to be honest with
you. And you watched, if you watched my
other videos, there's a lot of software
and [music] even hardware devices that
I'm like, man, that sounded cool, but
when I actually got to using it, it
wasn't or, you know, I thought it was
going to be this and it actually is way
better. So, if you're considering this
device, I hope this video helps you
decide whether it's the right device for
you or not. So, let's get into the
video. Step one, let's get to the box.
It is a huge box. So, let's see if you
can [music] see this whole thing. So,
this just got to my office.
My office is not a
big space and so it is way bigger than I
anticipated.
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; So, yeah, know that. It's a big device,
or at least the box is big and some
weight to [music] it. So, let's get into
the box.
Okay, so here we are. I got the HeatBit.
This is the full device. It is still
very large, but you can see the big box
behind me, so it is much smaller
than the box. It also came with this
charging cable and this little piece of
cloth. I don't know what the piece of
cloth is for, but
we'll find [music] out. So, let's get
this thing plugged in and see how it
works.
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; Turn it on.
Mode select, [music] hold. Okay, so this
is mode select.
Start. 5 seconds switching heating and
air purifying. Huh, it's an air
purifier, too.
Nice.
Very cool.
All right, I think I will keep it mostly
in air purifying mode
in my office.
Yep, plus and minus to switch
temperatures.
Nice. And then this is the turboing. So,
this is turbo, [music] this is auto,
this is light when it comes to the
mining boards. And so, what's [music]
affecting here is turbo is going to be a
little louder
and then auto is going to keep the
desired temperature
and adapt the mining boards to keep
[music] the space perfectly balanced.
And then this is light, so I'll probably
keep it in this auto zone mostly. Okay,
so just like that, we've got the Bitcoin
miner, heater, air purifier all set up.
I'd say it took about 10 minutes
to unbox, connect to the Wi-Fi, turn on,
see how it works. I'll tell you, as just
a piece of hardware, it is huge. It's
it's a big piece of hardware. It just
feels legit and professional. It is
heavy duty. Puts off pretty good heat,
quick heat. [music]
Curious to see how it works as an air
purifier. I'm going to be monitoring
that in the app. But the big question is
is this worth it? Is this worth it for
you to buy? And I think the question is
is really how
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; good of an air purifier is it and
heater. And you compare that to another
and maybe that's worth $200. But the
question is as a Bitcoin miner, you
know, how effective is it? Is it loud?
Is it annoying? [music]
We'll see. Time will tell. What I'm
going to do is I'm going to take about a
week. I'm going to monitor just how much
Bitcoin is mined in that time.
I'm going to test some different
settings and then I'll come back and
I'll share my feedback. I'll do it in
this video, so you don't have to wait
till the next video.
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; Until then, I'm going to be playing with
this and yeah, we'll see. I'll be back
in a week. Well, actually a few seconds
for you, a week [music] for me.
We're back. I have been using the
HeatBit here in my New York City office
for about 2 weeks. So, I've got some
data. And and as I look at the HeatBit,
let me just give some quick updates
[music] after 2 weeks of using it. One,
the device is just really solid. You
know, I think I think if you look at it
just from a heater standpoint, a mining
miner
standpoint, a
air filter standpoint, it's just a
really solid [music]
device and it just works good, it looks
good.
Yeah, it works, you know, functions
[music] really good. The other side is
as a heater, air filter, and as a miner,
if I've used other miners, they're
really loud.
This thing is really [music] quiet. It's
about the same as any other air filter
heater that I've had, so it's really no
different. And so,
practically, you know this, this is the
core of the product is
it's [music] if you're already going to
be heating something, you can also
basically mine Bitcoin at the same time.
Now, it doesn't work, the air filter
doesn't work. I think some people have
been curious, I was curious, maybe just
the air filter work when I don't need
the heater
to to mine, it doesn't.
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; You need the heater
or, you know, when it's mining and
putting out heat [music] is when you
kind of get that dual benefit of the
two. So, here's the thing. I I think the
best part of this device is not actually
the hardware, maybe it is the hardware,
but it's the software [music]
that they built in. I've had other
devices like this, the software is
clunky, the device is, you know,
kind of rigged [music]
together. This is a professional
hardware device
and and probably what I like best about
this platform [music]
is their app. So, let's go into the app.
So, when you log in to the HeatBit app,
at the top you can see the balance.
Basically, how much [music]
Bitcoin has been mined. You can see it's
been 10,888 satoshis, satoshis $7.67.
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; I've been using this device for about 2
weeks. Only had it heating
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; for honestly because it got so warm in
my office. So, I've only had it heating
probably about [music] 6 or 7 days, 6 7,
see what I did there. That was
unintentional and you can see I've got
$7.67
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; in
USD value in the Bitcoin that has been
mined. So,
I would estimate probably about 50 cents
a day
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; in mining
returns at the current price of [music]
Bitcoin. And you can see here in the app
that current price is about $70,400.
So, yeah, you can also see if if you go
down, you can see kind of the current
state of the heater and it's currently
in [music] heating mode. If you're in my
office and I don't have any noise
cancellation turned on, you can't hear
that
it at all. And so, you'd actually be
hearing my AC if you're hearing a noise
that's louder [music] than the heater
right now. Now, I do have it set on a
lower setting
and so that's where that is, [music] but
you can see the temperature, you can see
the performance and so what
hash rate is and then the consumption
[music] of from a power standpoint.
And then you can just see, you know, how
you're heating, you know, what level I
can I can turn that up or down
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; with the directly on the device. I can't
actually control it, or at least I
didn't figure out how to control it from
the device. I can just monitor it from
this device. [music]
And then air purification, it will
actually tell me how humid my office is,
the air inside is moderate, like is it
clean or is it not? And yeah, [music]
and then I I looked at just how to
change the filters. I didn't change the
filters, it, you know, came built in,
but
really easy to do. I have another
air filter air purification air
filtration system in my [music] office
very similar to how that works. And so,
and then here within the app, you can
see the stats. So, where kind of mining
rewards are, you can see peak and so
[music]
I was running it more last week and so
then it dropped off after I came back to
my office and haven't been running it
[music] every day.
And then here's a wallet where I can
transfer
those into Coinbase or Binance. Here's a
chat. One of the things I actually loved
is
uh
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; I needed some help in the setup.
Uh I was do It was It was actually user
error. Uh but I was able to talk to a
person, a real life person,
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; uh in the app within seconds of of
logging in and getting help. Uh that is
rare. Uh as anybody knows that needs
help with technology. So, that was
[music] a a big positive. Uh and then
you can see the account. You can you can
update some things. So, all that said,
the app is [music] great. Uh and it
works great. The device is great. So,
here's the question. Do I recommend the
Heatbit? Would I Would I buy [music] it?
If I had $800 to buy this device or not?
And the answer is maybe. And And let me
just be honest with that. [music] Uh
people want to know is
am I going to get $800 in Bitcoin back?
How long would that take? Now, I would
estimate that's probably going to take
you about 2 years if you're running it
all the time or [music] or pretty
consistently, maybe a year and a half if
you're running it all the time. But it
puts out pretty significant heat, so you
got to have a place where you can,
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; you know, offset some of that heat. And
And then you got to look at the cost of
your electricity.
Um and so, realistically, if you're
looking for [music] this to become
something that is like a in the
background money printer for you,
[music] you're probably better off just
getting an actual mining miner. And that
that can put out more Bitcoin and mine
mine more uh significantly. [music]
But if you're somebody that that loves
Bitcoin, that loves the ecosystem, that
wants to be a part of the ecosystem,
that has a space, that needs a heater,
that needs air I think we all need air
purifiers [music]
in our spaces, uh then this is an
excellent device. It's going to be more
expensive, naturally, than another
heater. It's going to be more expensive
than a regular air purification, but
it's all-in-one. And you're a part of
the Bitcoin [music] ecosystem, which I
love to be a part of it. So, all that
said of yeah, I'd probably buy one
[music] because I'm pretty passionate
about Bitcoin and loving supporting it.
And it's a great
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; It It looks good in my office. I'm going
to turn it off. It's a pretty big
device. All that to say, it is going to
return some [music] money back to you in
Bitcoin. You're going to get some
returns. But But I think at the end of
the day, you're you're really supporting
the Bitcoin ecosystem. You're getting a
little return. You're getting a device
you probably already need. And so, you
add all that together, and I think it's
probably a break [music] even. So, if
you love Bitcoin and you want to be a
part of the ecosystem, great. If you're
looking for a heater that's going to
make you money
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; heating your apartment, that
that's probably not going to happen.
That's not realistic. But if you're
looking at that heater that can return
some money and uh in a cool way, [music]
and you're passionate about Bitcoin, and
you want to be on the cutting edge, uh I
would 100% get one of these, if not one
for every room in your house. [music]
This, literally, as a heater,
I'm convinced this could Now, we live in
a a two-bedroom apartment, but I'm
convinced it would it [music] would heat
our whole apartment. I probably actually
will take it home as my apartment is
bigger than my office.
Um and so, yeah, it is a cool [music]
device. I definitely recommend it for
those that are Bitcoin enthusiasts, but
I don't recommend it for those that are
looking to get financial return on
investment on [music] a Bitcoin miner.
So, I hope that helps in making your
decision. Great device, Heatbit. Thank
you for letting me be an early tester of
this technology. I will be utilizing
[music]
it. I will be testing it both at home
and continue to use it here in my
office. And so, yeah, cool device.
Excited [music] to see where Heatbit
goes. Really impressed by both the
hardware and the software.
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; Love when I get to test device and just
let you know how cool it is and the real
honest truth about it. If you have any
questions, drop them in the comments.
Happy to answer any questions you might
have, and and I'll keep you posted. I'm
guessing, based on just even how good
this device is and their software is,
that there's going to be updates along
the way. So, I'll probably do a an
update to 7 months. Maybe we'll keep it
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; at that pace for the theme of this
video. Thanks so much for watching. I
look forward to talking to you again on
the next video.
Hi.