In this video, I want to strip away the
theory of LinkedIn and get into the
practical of how we're using LinkedIn as
an organization to move people from just
seeing our content to getting engaged in
our movement to interacting with each
other and interacting with our leaders.
So, this is how we're using LinkedIn to
further our movement.
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; Hey there, if you haven't met yet, I'm
Nils Smith, VP of Marketing at Faith
Driven Movements, and I'm using this
video series to [music] to really learn
out loud help myself even process what I
in my first year of leading marketing at
Faith Driven Movements, which is a
collective you're not familiar with
Faith Driven Entrepreneur, Faith Driven
Investor, [music] a Faith Driven
Entrepreneur for teens, and probably
most significantly what people know us
best for is solving the world's greatest
problems. And so,
I want to just share what we're learning
and how we're using LinkedIn as such a
catalytic platform to help [music] us
accomplish our goals. And so, it's
actually how I found out most about the
organization. The two founders of our
organization, Henry and Justin, are very
active on LinkedIn. And so, people will
often see [music] Henry's LinkedIn
selfie videos or Justin's very
thoughtful, you know, almost like blog
articles that he posts on a daily basis.
And so, their platforms have become a
huge front door for our organization.
And one of the things that I think is so
key to understanding and why that is so
significant is because people connect to
people more naturally connect to
organizations,
period. Now, I think that's especially
the case on social media. And so, people
naturally like, you know, they they
connected Steve Jobs before they
connected with Apple. This is not new.
They they connected with Richard Branson
before they were into Virgin Airlines.
Or or what whatever that brand might be,
we so often have a connection uh to
their founders, to their CEOs, and and
it creates a a personal connection. So,
we're [music] we're no no different. And
we're just stewarding the platforms that
our founders have [music] on this
platform. Now,
the reality is is that with our
accounts, [music]
they've outgrown even our our founders'
accounts from an engagement perspective
or from a follower perspective. But we
still see organically their engagement
being much higher because it's natural
for people to engage with people more
than they connect with their
organization. So, it's not an either or.
Does our founders, our CEO, or you know,
executive team, do they use LinkedIn or
does our brand accounts We have multiple
brand accounts, and every single one of
our leaders is using LinkedIn. Let me
show you on the screen some of the what
I mean by all of this. Just want to
interrupt myself real quick. Get back to
the video in a minute, but want to
highlight Amplify Social Media. Amplify
is the agency that I started more than a
dozen years ago. I transitioned out,
handed the company over to Matt
Williams, Jerilyn, incredible team at
Amplify. They're continuing to help me.
I'm a client now at Amplify. Still an
owner, still have an aspect of
involvement, but really focused on my
work at Faith Driven Movements. And so,
I'm so proud of the team at Amplify, and
I want to make sure that you, as you're
watching this, if you are looking for
help amplifying your message like I am
with this video, reach out to the team
at Amplify.
talk to Farina, talk to Jerilyn, talk to
Roy, talk to [music] any of the
incredible team members there at
Amplify, and I know they would love to
help you amplify your message. They do
everything from social media to podcast
to YouTube videos like this to all kinds
of content, websites, anything digital.
They do not just social media, well that
is our specialty and where we really
started, our services have expanded. So,
make sure you reach out to the team at
Amplify. Doesn't cost you anything to
talk to them. Worth the conversation.
See what they can do and if they can
[music] help you amplify your message.
Let's get back to the video. So, one of
the first things you'll see as I open up
LinkedIn here on my desktop is Henry,
one of our co-founders, here doing one
of his infamous selfie videos.
Uh if I keep pulling this up, I will
pull up Justin, our other co-founder,
and you could see his account. You can
see he's got 29,000 followers. It's a
significant following on LinkedIn. You
can see even some of his posts have got
931 likes. And so, so much of what
Justin is so good at is he He's a great
writer. Uh and so, he always finds a
good image and then creates creates a
incredible hook that gets people's
attention and is getting great
engagement across his content. And then
Henry
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; uses a much different strategy of much
more personalized selfie videos that he
consistently posts on his account. Let's
go past him, but you can see some of his
posts are right here.
And the engagement that they get. Now, I
wouldn't say a lot of people are trying
to even copy that functionality. That's
Henry. That fits him well. The the
post, the blog article post that Justin
is using is probably what I would
recommend for more leaders as that works
pretty consistently across other
accounts. But you got to find the flow
that works best for you in in creating
consistent content. And then as we look
at even let's go to Faith Driven
Entrepreneur, our brand accounts.
One of the things that we're very
focused on is creating shareable
content. You see we have 48,000
followers. All of this has been driven
organically. So, we're not buying
followers. You can even one of these
other ones, you can see even the post
impressions and the new followers and
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; what that looks like in the analytics.
But you can see we use a lot of graphics
within our content. We have begun
posting more videos over the last year
as LinkedIn is prioritizing what I call
it Loop Talk, short-form vertical
videos. So, we can see one here soon.
So, yeah, a lot more of the graphics
that are for lawyers. One of those video
clips where we're primarily primarily
taking clips from our podcast and
posting those here. And so, we're
finding some of those have popped, but
it's still the graphics and the text
that are
getting the best engagement for us on
LinkedIn.
And then the other thing that I want to
note is you can see
here even [music] as people have
commented, Faith Driven Entrepreneur is
responding to the comments. And so,
leaving
links as people ask questions and being
responsive there in the comments. And
and and then the other thing that that
we did is for all of our team members,
we created banners. And so, you can see
here at the top of my banner where it
says Faith Driven Movements. And so, we
we've encouraged and offered all of our
team members to to add that to their
profile. This is Christian on our team,
and you can see she got the same banner
there on her profile. Here is Rebecca,
who is one of our key leaders and
something that we're proud of. So, she's
using that brand-specific
banner on her profile. And and so, we we
use each other platforms to engage and
interact. And [music] so, one of the
things that we have found is that having
a collective engagement strategy on
LinkedIn is what really drives the best
[music] engagement. And so, we don't
want people to just go and and follow
our leaders. We want people to kind of
follow each other and cross-engage with
our different leaders and hear different
messages and different ways to engage.
And then finding opportunities to
connect them with each other. So many of
our leaders [music] are connecting with
each other in the comments. Now, we have
tried doing things like LinkedIn groups.
We don't see great engagement there. We
have tried using some of LinkedIn
articles. Also not in great engagement.
Some have done okay. And so, it kind of
depends on what it is that you're
posting and how you use some of that
other functionality. But at the core,
it's showing up every day, five days a
week. So, we do Monday through Friday
with a post and then responding [music]
as fast as possible to the comments and
the messages that are coming in from
your account. We also find that when
it's in the first 30 minutes of a post
that the comments is what really drives
up the algorithm to showing your post to
more people. Uh so, the more comments
you can get on a post in that first 30
minutes is really important or valuable
to getting great organic reach on that
post. And every time you reply to
someone's comment, that helps it get
further reach [music] or whether
somebody else in our community So, this
is where I think us helping each other
and commenting on each other's post help
raise the collective whole.
Uh and so, that's how we're using
[music] LinkedIn. And then we don't want
to just leave people on LinkedIn. We
want to move people from LinkedIn to our
website. Typically how that's done on
social media is through advertising. And
so, when I've done this on YouTube or
[music] Meta platforms, you would then
retarget people that are engaged with
your content to visit your website. We
have tried that [music] on LinkedIn, and
we have not found great success. Our
best success has been organic on social
media. We've tried doing some outbound
engagement on LinkedIn. I think we're
going to do more of that in the future,
but so far it it also hasn't proven to
be real fruitful. What we have found to
be fruitful is just responding to the
private messages that have come in. And
that was something that we weren't
weren't doing a year ago. And so, that
alone has gone a long way of just being
responsive. [music] And And the reality
is, I know here on LinkedIn or you know
that there are so many [music] spammers
there on LinkedIn.
But mixed into the spam are some really
curious and interested people that want
to connect with you. [music] And And so,
taking the time or having somebody on
your team or an assistant that's going
to go through and and filter through the
spam to get to some of the gold, it's
worth it. And we have found it to be
very fruitful in moving people from
awareness of our organization to
connecting in community within our
organization. LinkedIn has been a core
platform to do that. [music] So, we're
going to keep leaning into LinkedIn.
We're going to keep encouraging our
leaders to lean into LinkedIn. We want
all of our leaders posting five days a
week [music] if possible. We're going to
keep posting at least once a day on our
corporate accounts. And we're going to
keep responding to people as fast as we
can as we see LinkedIn as probably at
this point the biggest front door
[music] to our organization. I I think
you could debate YouTube is maybe our
our front door, especially from a
community and a relationship standpoint,
LinkedIn has been gold for us and an
incredible platform.
And that the truth is without [music]
paying for any of the engagement, so
many of these platforms are paid to
play. LinkedIn, that's not so much the
case. It It's really been just showing
up adding value to the platform, adding
value to the conversation has has really
you maximized the platform opportunity
that we have to utilize
LinkedIn as an engagement tool for our
organization. So, that's how we're using
it. Hope that helps. If you have any
questions
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; on LinkedIn, let me know in the comments
or DM me on LinkedIn. I read all of my
DMs. Sometimes I get a little behind,
but I do read all of my DMs. Would love
to connect on LinkedIn as a platform or
even show you some of what is working
best for us.
Thank you so much for watching. If
there's anything that we can do to help
you or encourage you or answer any
questions you might have, I hope this
process of us learning out loud, of us
building a public is helpful for you and
your organization and what [music] it is
that God's called you to lead and to
build.
And we're just here learning out loud
and trying to serve entrepreneurs,
investors,
and problem solvers in creative waves
and just doing that learning out loud
here on YouTube. Thanks for watching.
We'll talk to you again on the next
video.
&gt;&gt; [music]