In this video, I'm going to talk about
my first hire at Faith Driven Movements
on our marketing team. And it might not
be what you expect, but I think it might
be a hire you might need to consider
making for your organization. Let me
explain.
Hey there, if we haven't met yet, I'm
Neil Smith, VP of marketing for Faith
Driven Movements. That's the parent
organization for Faith-driven
Entrepreneur, Faith Driven Investor. We
don't actually use the term faith-driven
movements very often, but we have a
bunch of organizations. But solving the
world's greatest problems might be the
brand that we're most familiar. [music]
uh and it has been such a journey over
the last year to lead the marketing
team, marketing efforts of the movement
and of the organization. And so I'm
doing this video series to just learn
out loud uh to take some of the things
that I have learned and share those with
others and also help myself process
[music] what I'm learning and maybe even
make some adjustments along the way as
I'm documenting this. [music] This is
something I've done in the past for the
last probably 15 years uh with other
organizations and things that I built.
actually built my own marketing agency
uh before coming back into uh from being
in the consulting world and agency world
to now being hands in the dirt building
this this rocket ship in the air and it
is so energizing and exciting and so I
hope this is helpful. So let's talk
about hired. But I think more than that,
it's the why the hire. What roles. The
first role that we actually put out
publicly to hire for is our marketing
director or we actually hire for a
marketing coordinator. Saw it as more of
a project manager in the process of of
this. And I'm I'm one of those believers
that get the right people on the bus and
find the right seats. Uh we found a
great marketing leader who was more than
a coordinator. Moved right into
director. But that wasn't my first hire.
My first hire was a a a marketing
response manager. And if you've not
heard of that, it is not a common role,
but I believe it is a role that is too
often undervalued in an organization.
Now, one of these that almost every
organization had historically was a
receptionist. You know, you would have
somebody that would be at the front desk
when people would show up to uh your
organization or they'd answer the phone
when people would call or they'd be the
first ones to get the mail and go
through the mail. when that arrived and
they were basically your first line of
defense from inbound engagement with the
organization. Well, we're an
organization that's fully remote and and
a lot of organizations are this way. We
have digital pathways that people engage
with us. But one of the biggest missed
opportunities that I see in almost every
organization is that they're not they're
they're putting out tons of content on
social media. They're sending out tons
of emails through emails, newsletters,
but they're not paying attention to the
responses they're getting in their
direct messages and in their comments
and through those email replies that
people are sending them. And and that's
those are your warm leads. Those are the
people that are most interested in
activity that's happening in ministry. I
just want to interrupt myself real
quick, get back to the video in a
minute, but want to highlight Amplify
Social Media. Amplify is the agency that
I started more than a dozen years ago.
I've transitioned out. Handed the
company over to Matt Williams, Jerlin,
incredible team at Amplify. They're
continuing to help me. I'm a client now
of Amplify, still an owner, still have
an aspect of involvement, but really
focused on. I work at Faith Driven
Movements. And so, I'm so proud of the
team at Amplify. And I want to make sure
that you, as you're watching this, if
you are looking for help amplifying your
message like I am with this video, reach
out to the team at Amplify. Amplify
media. Talk to Matt, talk to Kelly, talk
to Fina, talk to Jerry Lynn, talk to
Roy, talk to any of the incredible team
members there. Amplify and I know they
would love to help you amplify your
message. They do everything from social
media to podcast to YouTube videos like
this to all kinds of content, websites,
anything digital. They do not just
social media. While that is our
specialty and where we really started,
our services have expanded. So, make
sure you reach out to team at Amplify.
Doesn't cost you anything to talk to
them. Worth a conversation. and see what
they can do and if they can help you
amplify your message. Let's get back to
the video. Life, those are the people
that that are ready and eager to want to
be ministered to. I [music] don't think
you should be posting on social media if
you're not in a place to respond to your
DMs. I'll just say it that bluntly. And
if you're sending out email newsletters
and and you're not monitoring how people
are replying and some of the feedback
that you're getting. Now, I know a lot
of it isn't [music] fun. This is why I
often don't think it needs to be the CEO
primary leader doing this. But we need
to have a a pathway or a process for
[music] inbound engagement and
communication as we as I I shared in my
last video. If you haven't watched that,
there's a link in the description below.
I'd love for you to watch that. But but
as we're building out uh our pathway to
engagement is come for the content, stay
for the community. And so much of how
that's happening is an email, but often
how that's happening is in interactions
uh through a question in a social media
comment. Where do I go to do that? How
do I what page is this on in the
website? [music] And and so much is
happening in the DM. So we hired a lady
that that I had had the privilege of
working with for years. Katrina is her
name and she's done an incredible job of
stepping in being a response manager for
our marketing team. And so she responds
to every inbound uh direct message on
LinkedIn, on Instagram, on Facebook, on
all the platforms. And LinkedIn is our
biggest platform for all of our brands
for the most part. Um and so we we have,
you know, dozens if not hundreds of
inbound messages every single day uh on
those platforms. And so she is
monitoring those. We tried to do it
through HubSpot so that everything was
in one place. Initially, [music] I've
used a platform historically called
metrical for social media.
Unfortunately, HubSpot hasn't functioned
really well in that area for us. There's
a lot of just [music] disconnect in the
way the messages come in where they
don't all come in. So, Katrina is
[music] doing a lot of that manually
still today, a year after starting and
and it works fine. I think we'll we'll
need something as we grow that isn't
just that inbound. The other thing and
and I think the other language that is
often used for a function like this is
social listening. And so the other thing
that Katrina is doing for our team is
she's listening for what people are
saying about our organization on
LinkedIn or on Instagram [music] and and
on Facebook and then she shares it in a
Slack thread for our entire staff to
see. And sometimes she'll tag uh certain
people she thinks it's going to be
interesting for them to pay attention to
or respond to. um because we know we
want an individual persontoperson
interaction whenever possible. So she's
out listening to what people are saying
and when our organization or one of our
brands are mentioned so that she can
highlight it and then our team members
especially our key leadership team can
go and respond and interact uh with
those messages and and have those active
interactions. So, it's not just the
organizations going interactive, but the
personal platforms that that are
interacting and having somebody that is
on the front lines of listening to both
what people are saying directly to us or
indirectly on [music] their public
platforms, having that that digital
digital receptionist maybe as [music] a
title that I've used in the past, but we
we use the title of response manager in
this role. Let me show you a document
that she uses that might help you as you
build up these systems in your
organization. Okay, so this is a social
response management platform. So we just
have between these three brands, FTE,
Faith of an Entrepreneur, Faith
Investor. A little bit about our voice
and tone, uh some of those key websites
and some personalized responses is like
hi name, you know, here's an opening
response or a closing response. And so
it's almost like a call center, you
know, and and so if you have a script
for a call center, here here's what they
do. Now, one of the things we encourage
Katrina uh to [music] do is to
personalize every communication and then
every interaction she has, we encourage
her to uh add, you know, nuance to this
document. And and so as people are
responding, especially as you're seeing
repeat responses and then she can bring
it back to the leaders. And so the
reality is is about 95% of messages are
repeat messages, things that she already
knows [music] how to respond to. But
then there's about 5% that we need to
wrestle through. How do we respond to
this? And then that just continues to
now she knows how to respond in the
future. And so building out that
response system allows volunteers to be
able to step into the role with if
[music] your organization has more
volunteer engagement or other staff
members. So you're not dependent on one
person at this point in our
organization. It's one person you know
that that does this role. So if Katrina
can't do it, it's not happening. That's
something we don't want to be dependent
on long term. In the future, we hope to
have even a full team, but there are
capacity issues. Every organization
wishes [music] they had more staffing in
different areas. But what my
encouragement would be to you is one
define in your organization who is
responding to those inbound messages
that are coming in. Whether that's
email, whether that's social media, and
then two, begin to work on a document, a
simple response document of here's how
we [music] respond to our most common
responses in our DMs or public
responses. Do we [music] when somebody
responds to a a comment, do we say thank
you or do we just like it? [music] What
are our natural responses with our brand
to what people are saying about us
online? Whether that's in our private
DMs or in our public comments, but
develop that process. [music] And so
this seems like something you would do
as a phase six in development. Uh but I
saw this as as a critical, you know,
phase two or second step after setting
the foundational strategy and direction.
It was like we've got to have a system
for responding to inbound messages and
so so grateful for Katrina the progress
that's been made in this area and the
interactions that have happened uh and
been so fruitful. So that as I look back
on the decisions made the first year
that was a a great decision. I haven't
made all great decisions but bringing
Katrina in and prioritizing this aspect
of our marketing efforts has proven to
be very fruitful. So hope that helps
you. Any questions don't hesitate to to
comment below. I'd love to answer any
questions you might have as I'm going to
keep learning out loud as we're building
here in public. And if you're not yet
engaged with Faith Driven Entrepreneurs,
solving the world's greatest problems, I
encourage you go check out our websites,
go check out our brands, follow us on
social media. I think you'll be glad you
did. I hope this is helpful [music] and
we'll talk to you again on the next
video.
&gt;&gt; [music]