Welcome to the first video of building
in public with Faith-Driven Movements.
I'm the VP of marketing at Faith Driven
Movements. I just I'm coming up on my
one-year mark and I decided to do what
I've always done and this is what I used
to do with a blog and uh that I would do
with a podcast and and here on YouTube,
but I'm learning out loud. I am building
in public. And so I'm going through a
process of analyzing our first year and
the things that we prioritized and
focused on from a marketing efforts
standpoint at Faith-driven Movements.
And I want to just share out loud what
I'm doing because I think these things
can help you in your organization. If
you're an entrepreneur, if you're a
nonprofit leader, if you're a pastor, a
church leader, whatever it is that you
lead your marketing efforts, there's a
process. There's things to prioritize
and you can't do everything at once. So,
I'm going to walk you through the
process over the next series of videos
as to what I prioritized in getting
started in my role. Now, Faith
Removements has been around for about
six or seven years. I just did that 67.
I realize that I didn't mean to do that.
But it has been around and maybe by the
time you're watching this that it's like
what is that six seven thing? Yeah, I'm
too old to do that, but I have been
faith-driven movements existed before me
and so I inherited what was already
existed as a marketing plan and so I had
to jump in and learn and then lead out
of where things were to where we desired
for thing things to go. And so I'm going
to share all of those processes. I want
to honor those that came before me, what
brought them to this place. I want to
honor our team that I get to work so
closely with. I want to honor our
leadership at Faith Driven Movements as
to what we've been able to build
together. This is not something I did or
even just our marketing team did. This
is something that people that were
involved in marketing before me helped
to to shape and to build and those
holistically in our organization. And
honestly, everyone involved from a
volunteer standpoint, from just
engagement standpoint, it has been quite
a journey. And I think we're just
getting started. So, let's get into the
beginning of building out loud in this
new series with Faith-Driven Movements.
Hey, if we haven't met yet, I'm Neil
Smith, uh, VP of marketing for Faith
Driven Movements. Also founder of
Amplify Social Media. Before joining
Faith Moons, I was a consultant
essentially. I have a marketing agency.
Still owned that agency. If you want
some help, Amplify Social Media is who
is producing this video. And so, I want
to thank the Amplify team. If you need
some help with your marketing efforts,
Amplify exists to do just that. I made
the decision about a year ago that the
mission of Faith Driven Movements was so
incredible that I needed to step out of
full-time consulting a agency building
to now building this organization, this
ministry that is a collective of brands
and different objectives among each of
them, but collectively work together to
solve some of the world's greatest
problems. And so, I'm so passionate
about this mission that I went all in.
And so a as we've been building, I've
been documenting and wanting to share
some of the things that we prioritize.
So the beginning is here's what I did in
my first month as I was jumping in and I
was learning. I was looking for
documentation. I was looking for like
who does what? How what are our
processes? What are our systems? So much
of marketing is built on rhythms. What
are your rhythms when it comes to a
social media calendar, an email
calendar, a brand guide? Just what are
your core systems? And the reality is,
and it's understandable, in an
organization that was our age and stage,
there weren't a whole lot of systems. It
was just like, we just got to get out
another email. We got to get up another
social media post. We kind of know our
brand. We don't have time to slow down
and document. And so, so much of what I
needed to do in the beginning is to slow
down so that we could build some
efficiency through our rhythms and
systems. So, I want to show you what I
put together. Okay. So, I'm a Google
Slides guy. You can see here on my
screen, I just went and created a Google
Slides deck. Now, I will thank Daryl
Lynn on my team. She helps me with so
many of these things. She's part of the
team at Amplify who just has helped me
through the years create tons and tons
of Google Slides decks. So, I just
started with what is our marketing
team's objective? What are we trying to
do? And foundationally, what I had heard
as I got started and what I saw is the
designs, the websites, the social media
post, beautiful, incredible design. But
what was our what is our greatest
strength and what it continues to be our
greatest strength is we're great at
creating content that inspires video
content in particular that inspires
people to take actions inspires
entrepreneurs to take action inspires
faith-driven investors to go and apply
their faith to their investment
activities that inspires people to move
from success to significance uh through
our halftime brand that inspires
teenagers through faith through an
entrepreneur for teens to then become
entrepreneurial and the way you approach
what God is calling you to do and then
through our brand solving the world's
greatest problems to really inspire
people to take action in solving the
world's greatest problems. So these are
our brands. We have this collective of
brands and so we want to move people. We
often say come for the content stay for
the community. We know that real change
is happening in community. So we use our
incredible content to bring that to
people but with the objective from a
marketing perspective is not just to get
your eyeballs on this content but
[music] then to get you engaged in
community because as we we have found
that when people get involved in
community that's where they best take
action. So that that's our core
objective. This is our core just even
[music] how do we function as a team? Uh
it starts with strategy. You you've got
to like what what is our core strategy?
It's not just to send an email. Why do
we send an email? Why do we post on
social media? Why do we have a website?
We don't shouldn't just have those
things because Compassion International
has these things because you know Amazon
has these things. We have these things
for a reason. They have a function.
There's tactics [music] and strategies
that we have to build together to
accomplish our mission. And so it starts
with strategy development. We don't want
to just strategically fly blind. Then it
moves into marketing execution. People
often say when it comes to your
software, it's not what you've got, it's
how you use it. And I so believe in
that. When it comes to marketing, you
can get by. People often talk HubSpot or
go high level. Go high level is so much
deeper and you can do just about
anything you could ever want to do. Go
high level. While I do prefer HubSpot
personally, there's market execution is
so key in successful marketing efforts.
And that moves into analytics reporting.
I'm just one of those believers that so
so often we perceive the success of our
marketing as to one just how does it
look? How does it feel? What does our
key stakeholder say? But at the end of
the day, what action did it cause people
to take? There are so many metrics that
we can identify uh that can define
whether we're successful or not and what
adjustments do [music] we need to make
to our strategy or our execution to be
more successful. So a high priority on
analytics and then optimization when
we're looking at the data and what the
data is telling us. How do we then get
better? How do we optimize our current
structure? So that that was the core
just here's how we function as a
marketing team. So we want to move
people from content into community. We
want to have a strategic approach to how
we do that. And then this is the core
just pathway that I documented out based
on what I was experiencing and learning.
And and that was to move people from
organic social media into using digital
advertising, which we hadn't done as of
yet. I'll get to that in a future video.
The efforts we made and continue to make
in digital advertising. Moving people
into being a website visitor. This is
what I would often say is moving people
from awareness to consideration. And
then into email engagement. This is
where we perceive that somebody they
visit our website, we want to get them
on our email list. And then when they're
on email list, we want to get them and
that's where they start with the content
from social media and on our website
into community where they're taking
action to then getting into one of our
foundation groups or one of our
different community engagement
opportunities. And so moving them from
email into community engagement. And
then at the core, each step of our
process is moving people into into
action through a value equation. This is
something that I borrowed from Alex
Heroszi, but it's looking at how much
value can we drive through when somebody
first visits our website or they see a
post on social media or they get an
email is understanding our core audience
and and this really becomes in our brand
development is who are we trying to
reach? What action do we want them to
take? And so we look at a dream outcome
of of somebody that's visiting our site.
If they're a faith-driven entrepreneur,
what is their dream outcome? If they're
a faith-driven investor, what is their
dream outcome? And what is their
perceived likelihood of achievement? how
how much do they perceive that we're the
ones and how can we I'm I'm a story
brand guide story brand guy not a guide
but I uh believe that we want to be
someone's guide and how do we show that
we're a trustworthy guide to help them
go from where they are to where they
want to be and then at the end of the
day what is the time delay and the
effort and sacrifice they're going to
have to make to do that and and so
whatever our pitch is whether that's how
we're communicating on our website to
our emails when it comes from our
content and moving people in community
is how likely are we going to be to help
them achieve what they're looking to
achieve? And sometimes that's perceived,
you know, uh, value and sometimes it's
actual value. Uh, because sometimes
people think they're coming for this,
but what they actually want is um,
something different. And and so at the
core though, we want to be so
transparent up front is this is the
value we're bringing. One of the other
amazing things as I got to know this
organization is people and it's a
question I had when I was going through
the interview process is what's the
catch? Everything is free. You know,
like the course is free, the content is
free. Aren't you selling something? And
and we do have some things we put prices
on, but but that's more so that people
will actually show up, have a little
skin in the game. That is not our core
business model. And we're nonprofit
organization. Our core model is to to
raise up a million faith-driven
entrepreneurs. Our core model is to
raise up more faith-driven investors and
to get people to get in the game in
these areas and with these brands that
you see with faith driven entrepreneur,
teams, investor solving the world's
greatest problems at halftime. And so so
much of the value proposition is that
there is no catch that that we really
are providing you a ton of value for
free and [music] and it's just so that
we can accomplish the mission God's
given us to do and we accomplish our
mission when you better accomplish
yours. And it really isn't too good to
be true even though it perceives to be
that way. And then I went from this into
building on an org chart and and kind of
who's doing what getting into more SOPs
within our team and and and I would say
I [music] started very high level what
what are basically the the top five
things that everyone is doing so that we
can just kind of know who's doing what
to accomplish these things when it comes
to our email when it comes to our social
media when it comes to our websites. And
when when I started we had a team of
about five. We've grown significantly
since then and I know compared to a lot
of organizations that a marketing team
of five is significant. And so one of
the things that happens as you grow
there you move from more generalist to
specialist and so a lot of people on our
teams are moving from this you know six
sevenyear organization to you know the
next phase of development with you know
our team is now double that from when I
started a year ago and so getting more
specialist in the roles and having
definition as to who is doing what what
are those expectations okay so once I
get clarity as to here's what we're
doing the other thing that we needed
clarity around is our brands the
challenge is is We had five different
brands that had different looks and
feels, different fonts, different
colors, but they were under one
umbrella. And so we needed to figure out
how do we both differentiate these
brands [music] and define these brands.
And one of the things I I put out there,
and it's not something I've done a whole
lot of, but every organization I've been
has a brand guide. And so I was like,
guys, we we need to work on a brand
guide. So grateful to I want to just
shout out Marissa and Angela on our team
who did such an incredible job building
out many of these brand guides. Julian
as well. And uh they did a great job.
And and one of the realities is is I'm
going to show you one of our brand
guides, but what we started with isn't
what we have today. Every month, we're
looking at how can we enhance this brand
guide. How how do we create more clarity
with this brand guide so that it is a
brand resource center so that both our
team members outside of marketing have
the assets they need, but also inside of
marketing, whether it's a copywriter,
whether it's a designer, whether it's a
video editor, that they can go to that
brand guide and just almost be reminded
of this is who our target audience is.
Here's the things they like. Here's the
fonts we use. Here's the messaging that
we use and don't use. So, let me show
you one of our brand resource centers to
give you an idea of what that looks
like. [music] Okay, so this is our brand
faith-driven entrepreneur. And you can
see here when you go to the resource
center, it starts with brand name, brand
foundation. You can actually literally
click on that and it'll go to that
section. It'll literally give you the
exact colors you need. If you were going
to the colors, you can start with like
dos and don'ts. If you spin that out,
it's like [music] here's what we do and
don't do. Do we use FTE or do we not use
FTE? you know what what are some of the
things that we do and don't do with our
brand from a messaging or capitalization
standpoint. We want consistency in how
our brand is represented. And what
happens is sometimes you have different
people and contractors that come into
your organization and they just kind of
take different leeway. You want to
create some boundaries. That's helpful
for creatives that they know what
boundaries do I have to work within and
what creative freedoms uh do I also
have. So that gets into the brand voice
and the purpose and the tone. These are
the logos. So if you needed, you know,
sometimes that there's a partner that we
work with, they need a logo. We just go
to the brand resource center and get
them a logo. What size do they need? Is
it a horizontal or is it stacked? Here's
the iconography. Here's the typography,
photography that you can use. So we
literally just have stock photos and
real photos that fit. Here's our core
values integrated [music] in. Here's our
target audience that we're going after.
This persona exercise, I can't recommend
enough. Maybe I'll do a separate video
in the future, but a lot of this stuff
was already developed and I was great
for that. we just needed to put it in
one place, people that could go and
find. And some of this is also was
developed and then changed and and we're
targeting new audiences and in different
ways. Even things like the email
signature. Here's here's basically new
employees when they're coming on. Here's
the email signature that you need to add
or business cards if you needed to get
them printed, letterhead, slide decks,
and just basically Google Doc template
all right here for people to access. And
so yeah, so that's a brand resource
center. So, so yeah, we basically went
from or so in that first month really
prioritizing what is our strategy, how
do we function and then what is our
infrastructure from a brand and
messaging standpoint. The reality is we
we had conferences going on, we had
activities that we had to keep up with.
I would have loved for it to go faster.
It it's been a process I would say
that's been ongoing for the past year,
but as I look [music] back on a year,
this gave really good clarity for our
team, especially as new team members
were coming on. And so if anything, you
know, we maybe got this done in the
first quarter of last year. If anything,
I would have even put more urgency to
get this done in the first month. And
so, yeah, it really gave us though a
framework to work within. I'm eager to
dive in to our next steps as we really
get into the websites, into the social
media, into the advertising. But as
we're building out loud here and and as
we're building in public faith-driven
movements, I just wanted to share some
of the things that I'm learning from a
marketing perspective. And I hope that
it helps you. If there's ever anything I
can do to help you, drop comments. love
to answer any questions you might have
or of things that we're doing because we
want to inspire entrepreneurs. We want
to inspire leaders of all kinds. And so
if we can take from what we're building
and help you with your business or with
your ministry, your nonprofit, that is a
gift. And so I just wanted to take the
exercise of helping myself learn out
loud and go through this exercise of
documenting and looking back, but then
also take those things and hopefully
share and help you as well. So hope this
is helpful. This is the first session in
this series. We'll see how far this goes
and I'm going to start documenting more
of the journey now that I'm about a year
in. Thanks so much for [music] watching.
We'll talk to you again on the next
video.
[music]