Three days ago, I made the move from an
iPhone to an Android. And I'm going to
talk you through what the experience has
been like. So, you don't have to. Well,
you don't have to. Or you could if you
want to. It It really shouldn't be up to
this, but I'm going to share what I'm
learning in the process. So, if you're
thinking about doing this, maybe it'll
save you some time. How about that?
Let's get into the video.
Hey there. If we haven't met yet, I'm
Neil Smith. I'm the VP of marketing for
an organization called Faith Driven
Movements and the founder of a marketing
agency called Amplify Social Media. We
do digital marketing for churches,
nonprofits, small businesses. And if you
want help, reach out to the team at
amplifyocial.comdia and they would love
to help. But I want to talk through my
transition journey from this iPhone. Uh
this is an iPhone 14 to this Android.
This is a Samsung Flip 7. There's more
details in, you know, what the phones
are. I'll leave that in the show notes.
But I wanted to talk through I'm three
days in to this transition. I tried this
five years ago to be honest. So if you
followed my journey, I tried to break my
Apple addiction and I am doing it again.
I made the leap 3 days ago. I'll give
you an update again probably in 30 days.
But wanted to share fresh why I'm making
this move, what led to the move, and
what I've experienced so far cuz it's
not gone as expected as you might expect
in a move like this. It is a pain to
transition. So, let's walk through the
journey that got us here. The journey
begins with this little device right
here. This is an 8 GB iPhone. This was
not the first 4 GB phone, but this was
my first iPhone when it first came out.
Look how tiny [music] it is compared to
the iPhone 14. And this is the smaller
iPhone today. You can see them side by
side here or back to back. It It really
is uh such a smaller phone. I actually
miss how small this is, how nicely it
fit into the hand versus this is the
iPhone 14. And I stuck with this phone
because it's the smallest phone that I
could find. I [music] like a smaller
phone. And so I miss the size of this
device. I remember too when when this
had 8 GB, I was like, you know, I'm I'm
getting double cuz it was you could
either get 4 gigs or 8 gigs. I'm like,
man, I'll just never even fill up that
much closet space on my phone. Well, now
one of the biggest problems I have on my
iPhone 14 is it only has that 128 GB. I
got the lower end of memory and [music]
it's yeah, it's not enough and it keeps
filling up and I keep having to delete
stuff and that's pretty annoying. And so
yeah, so one of the [music] first
reasons I wanted to switch or needed a
new phone was because the memory kept
filling up on my iPhone. So if you get a
new iPhone, I started looking at Android
devices. But before we get to the actual
Android this device, I want to talk
about 5 years ago when I tried making
the leap and what happened and what
caused me to go back to the iPhone. So,
I was at that point I was probably 10
years into my iPhone journey. And it's
just so easy. You get a new iPhone and
it takes you about 15 minutes to just
[music] connect the two and it updates
and you use iCloud and all the things
you're supposed to use and it syncs and
it syncs to your computer so easily. The
Apple ecosystem is incredible. But about
5 years ago, I was looking at Android
phones and seeing how much more cost
effective they are and feeling like I'm
addicted to this Apple ecosystem. I
don't like being addicted to an
ecosystem. And so I tried going to a
Google Pixel phone. Now they had a it
was a great device. It was probably $300
$400. It worked really well. I did it
during the pandemic because I wasn't
traveling as much and I was like, you
know what, if there's a good time that I
don't necessarily need my phone to work
as seamlessly without being on the road,
this is a good time. So I jumped with
Google Pixel, used it for about 6 months
and the truth is it was a good device.
It worked fine. Where I had a problem is
with the Microsoft integration. At that
time I worked for an organization that
primarily used the Microsoft Office
suite [music] and that just wasn't real
compatible with the Android device.
Well, today everything I do is in Google
and so because I use Gmail, Google
Drive, Google Meet, it just feels like a
natural time that it will be more easy
to transition into the Android and
Google ecosystem. The problem I have
right now is I'm actually more concerned
that I'm fully addicted to the Google
ecosystem because I think about Google
Drive, I think about Gmail, I think
about the Android device now. I think
about YouTube. I think about [music]
YouTube TV is what we have basically our
cable subscription. I think about all of
the the Google ecosystem. I'm far more
addicted to that ecosystem than I am to
the Apple ecosystem. [music] So that
motivation of breaking that addiction
maybe not as strong now but I'll tell
you what made me [music] make the leap.
Now let me show you this other phone. So
this is the Google Flip Samsung Flip.
And the reality is my daughter got this
phone about 6 months ago. This is what
she wanted for her birthday. And we we
got a pre-owned phone. This is also a
pre-owned phone. We got hers for about
$500. I was able to get mine for about
$350. And honestly, when she got it and
I just saw the way it flipped and it's
got like a screen on the front here and
then when you open it, it's got a longer
screen [music] and she can even see it
compared to the iPhone. So, it's a
little bigger, actually a good amount
bigger, but it feels smaller because
it's not as wide. And one of the things
I like about this thinner phone is that
I can reach all the way across with my
thumb and I can type with one hand. A
few other things I really like about
this device is it's got a fingerprint
reader in the front. It does facial scan
just like the iPhone, but I like having
the fingerprint reader, too. And so,
that functionality is great. The other
thing I liked is when I was looking at
my daughter's photos, every time we'd
have family photos and be taking shots
of things, hers always looked better
than the rest of us who are on iPhones.
And so, something about the camera on
the Samsung just seems [music] to take
great photos. And then the screen is
just really sharp. And so that flip
screen, you can see a little line in the
middle if you're really looking for it,
especially if you're scrolling through
and feeling it, but for the most part,
you don't really notice it. And so as a
device, it's way cooler than just a flat
device. So basically half the price and
more functionality. So yeah, as a
device, that was a no-brainer. Let's
talk about the actual function of
changing. Now, I got this [music] device
and I was like, what do I need to begin
to transition? So I just basically
started going app by app. So, how do I
get my email connected to this or all of
my email addresses connected to this, my
Google Drive connected to this? How do I
get Uber connected to this? And and it
took me about 3 three and a half hours
to get all of the apps that I use on a
regular basis from my iPhone onto this
[music] new Samsung Flip and then get
them logged in to the accounts. And so,
look, that's sideways energy. It's not
any I'm not learning Android. I'm not
doing it. All I'm doing is downloading
an app and getting it logged in. I hate
sideways energy. Hey guys, just want to
interrupt myself real quick, get back to
the video in a minute, but want to
highlight Amplify Social Media. Amplify
is the agency that I started more than a
dozen years ago. I've transitioned out,
handed the company over to Matt
Williams, Gary Lynn, the incredible team
at Amplify. They're continuing to help
me. I'm a client now of Amplify, still
an owner, still have an aspect of
involvement, but really focused on my
work at Faith Driven Movements. And so
I'm so proud of the team at Amplify
[music] and I want to make sure that you
as you're watching this, if you are
looking for help amplifying your message
like I am with this video, reach out to
the team at Amplify. Amplify Social
media. Talk to Matt, talk to Kelly, talk
to Fina, talk to Jerlyn, talk to Rory,
talk to any of the incredible team
members there, Amplify. And I know they
would love to help you amplify your
message. They do everything from social
media [music] to podcast to YouTube
videos like this to all kinds of
content, websites, anything digital.
they do, not just social media. While
that is our specialty and where we
really started, our services have
expanded. So, make sure you reach out to
team at amplify. Doesn't cost you
anything to talk to them. [music] Worth
a conversation. See what they can do and
if they can help you amplify your
message. Let's get back to the video.
And so, look, 3 and 1 half hours. It
might might be you might use fewer apps
than I do. So, that might be less time
for you. Might be more time for you if
you don't remember your password. I use
LastPass as my password manager. So,
it's easy to get access to the
passwords. And so I think it could take
longer if I didn't have decent
organization around the password
managers and the authenticators, but
yeah, [music] took me about 3 and 1 half
hours. That's annoying to me. So, but
I've got all my apps and set up and
working within the platform. Now, the
second thing that I'm working on [music]
currently is getting my text messages
moved over. Now, this is one of the
things that makes me happy to be
breaking my Apple addiction, but also
frustrated because I've got several text
threads that people are in iMessage and
I don't know how they're in iMessage or
in a regular text message, but when I
text them from my new device, it only
replies and goes to my old phone because
they still have my iMessage as my key
contact when they reply to a message.
So, I don't really I'm going to have to
let them know, [music] hey, update my
contact in your phone so that your text
messages will start coming to my phone.
[music] That's just annoying. That's
something that Apple obviously does
intentionally. There is no major value
to iMessage, the blue text. People
always talk about the green text. That's
[music] made up garbage in my opinion.
And so, it is annoying, but Apple just
makes it unnecessarily annoying. And so,
I am happy to break that aspect of the
addiction and make the change, but it's
a pain. And it it isn't easy because
I've been doing this for 15 years
[music] in communication with people.
Getting people to make that change is
going to be a challenge. Let me share a
few other things that are a little
funky, call it, about this phone. One,
just the design is a little funky. I
love that. I love people are always like
looking at it, curious about it. I love
the flip nature of the phone. I also
love the size of the way it just fits
into my pocket so nicely and is so
small. It just it it's got a great hold
to it. But one of the things that is a
little funky is because it's got a funny
size. It's a little more narrow as a
device and longer than a lot of other
devices. And so the way certain apps
will load into it is just a little
funky. It doesn't, you know, one of the
things that works great with the iPhone
is all apps essentially just work
naturally well uh with some Android
devices. I found this with the Pixel as
well. It wasn't always a perfect fit
with [music] the screen size, especially
a screen size that is not as normal.
It's longer than the average device. So
that's throws it off a little bit. Not a
big deal, but it is quirky with some of
the apps. [music] The other thing is
I'll miss the ease of FaceTime. A lot of
my family is on FaceTime. [music] We're
trying to get everyone to move to
WhatsApp as a platform to be able to
communicate and basically move from text
messaging to WhatsApp for everyone. And
you can do video calls easily in
WhatsApp, similar to what you can do in
FaceTime. I will try Google Meet. Now, I
use it for business for meetings a lot
on a desktop, but I haven't used it a
ton on a device like this. I'm curious
how that will work with others,
especially those that aren't on Android
devices. And so I'm hopeful uh that
there will be a natural, you know, video
conferencing platform that will work
phone to phone really easily when you
want to just jump on like a what in the
past has been let's just jump on a
FaceTime real quick, especially with
[music] family. So I I want to work on
that. So here's the question though. Now
that I am just 3 days in, do I regret
making this leap from the iPhone 14 to
Samsung Flip 5? And at this point,
absolutely not. This device just gets
cooler the more I play with it. I am
curious to see even over time what
happens and I've gotten to see 6 months
in with my daughters where some of the
the stripping along the edge because
you're folding it is stripping off now
it hasn't damaged the device yet but I
am curious will this screen last as long
as an iPhone uh typically does are there
some other quirks about it but so far it
has [music] been it gets cooler and
cooler for me the device itself more
functional than I anticipated the
[music] transition has been a bit easier
than I anticipated I've got some trips
coming up so trips are a good test of
like Okay, you're really dependent on
the mobile device when you're out and
about and on the road. [music] So, that
will be a good tell sign when I come
back with my one month update. But 3
days in, I'm [music] thrilled with the
jump. And so, it's yeah, we'll we'll
see. I'll I'll keep you posted. Love to
answer any questions you might have. So,
you want to drop those in the comments.
Love to answer the questions. But, as of
today, I'm an Android guy. I have broken
my Apple addiction. Okay. Before I wrap
up this video about uh my transition to
Android are a couple of the other areas
that I broke my Apple addiction. First,
the first is the AirPods. I loved the
AirPods, especially the AirPods Pro, and
the way they fit into the ears better
than the regular AirPods, and the way
they blocked out background [music]
noise when you're on phone calls. But
these JBL Vibe Beam headphones are about
50 bucks on Amazon. They they jump.
Sometimes they'll go down to like $30,
$40 on Prime Day. and bought several
pairs of these, but they are so good on
the-go everyday headphones. This these
are my AirPod uh replacements and the
fraction of the cost and I would say
just as good in my opinion. So, JBL Vibe
Beams. The other is the Apple Watch. I
see this as like a second monitor.
Definitely not essential into my Apple
ecosystem, but it works good and it
hasn't broken. I've had this one for a
couple of years. Probably my third Apple
Watch. I like having it, but the thing I
don't like about it is it the battery
doesn't last as long. Well, I have moved
to the Fitbit. This was like $50, the
Christmas special, I suppose, that I
just bought for myself. And it's been
great. The battery lasts about 5 days on
one charge. And yeah, it's it's smaller.
I don't need the big screen. I like some
quick alerts. I like the health aspects
of the Fitbit. And so, yeah, I'm easing
my way from the whole Apple ecosystem
for addiction. Now, if it is the best
device, I'm going to keep it, but I
don't want to be dependent on these
Apple devices. So, I am happy to be
breaking my Apple Watch addiction, my
AirPod addiction, now my iPhone
addiction. So, the only one left is my I
still have a Mac laptop and I use the
Mac Mini here in my office. But yeah,
other than that, I am breaking my Apple
addiction. I'll keep you posted. I hope
this video helps you if you're
considering Jump, [music] but 3 days in,
I'm a happy Android guy. We'll talk to
you again on the next video.
Heat. Heat.
[music]