Hey guys, Neil Smith here and today we
are testing the Cammonic microphones
compared to the Fifine microphones and
we're going to let you decide which ones
are better and I got Shelby here with me
today to help. Shelby, thanks for being
with me.
&gt;&gt; No problem.
&gt;&gt; So, I introduced the video. I introduced
my daughter Shelby and we are both
holding these little microphones that
you could just clip on to your shirts if
you want to, like a lavalier microphone.
And the back plugs right into the
computer and then it comes with this
little case. So Shelby, what do you
think about the ceremonics?
&gt;&gt; Looks pretty nice. So this is about $120
if you buy it on Amazon or when I bought
this and I've had this for about a year
and it's a pretty good little microphone
set. Comes with this charging case.
Everything you just put them right in
here and they charge and plugs into a
USBC. Great setup and it plugs right
into the back of my iPhone or I can
switch it out for a USBC case. Now,
Fifine sent me this new microphone set
that's almost identical to the
Ceremonic. Oh, I almost just broke it
already. But you open it up, you can see
it all in here. So, I'm going to take it
out and connect it to Shelby's phone
here in a minute, and we'll be able to
test. Now, this video, to be clear, is
about the microphones, but we're also
recording the ceremonics on my iPhone
14. We're going to record the Fifines on
my daughter's Samsung Flip. So, you kind
of get to check the video as well, but
let's focus on the audio. So, yeah, let
us know how does the cammonic sound and
then we're going to switch to the Fifine
here in a minute. So, Shelby, just test
the microphone a little bit. Go test
&gt;&gt; test.
&gt;&gt; Okay, so you hear mine and these are
great for interviews. You can use it.
You can also put it has like a filter
you can put on the top of the
microphone. So, let me show you up
close. That is what the microphone looks
like. I don't like to have the filter on
there. I think it works pretty good
without the filter. But if you're in a
really noisy place, you're outside and
there's wind, you can put the wind
filter on there. And I like to just hold
it rather than clip it to my shirt. But
depends on what you're doing. Maybe you
can just clip it to your shirt. But
works great connecting to your phone if
you want to get some good audio. So
yeah, that's the Cammonic. I think
that's everything to do with that. Let's
jump into the Fifine now. All right,
welcome back. We are now on the Samsung
Flip phone and now we're also using the
Fifine microphone. So Shelby, what do
you think of the Fifon microphones?
&gt;&gt; Looks pretty good.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, similar. You pointed out something
that was pretty cool just a second ago.
What's on the back?
&gt;&gt; Uh, it has a little face on it.
&gt;&gt; A little smiley face. So maybe a little
happier now. It does feel it is smaller
than the other one, right?
&gt;&gt; So maybe it feels a little cheaper. And
I think when you get into the the little
adapter that connects to the phone, it
doesn't have like a full like screen
like the Cammonic has. And so let me
actually show you the Cammonic. Got to
even cut a little bit out here. and turn
this on.
&gt;&gt; Okay. When you get on the ceremonic, you
can actually see here it's got like a
full screen. This just has some like
lights to show that the microphones are
turned on. You can see on each of our
microphones, you can see they're turned
on with a little blue light on there.
And then on the connector, the adapter,
it has a like a couple of like lights
that will show that it's connected and
working to the microphone. So, yeah,
works good. I think the question is is
the audio just as good? And so, I think
that's what is up to you to tell. So,
you know, as you're watching the video,
we're recording right now, so we're not
able to tell the audio is as good, but
Shelby, if you were to pick between the
two, what would you pick just based on
what you see and feel of the two?
&gt;&gt; Um, I would pick this one because it's
like slightly smaller and also easier to
carry around.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So, let's let's actually show the
the microphones next to each other. You
want to show You want to grab one, too?
So you can actually see it is maybe the
Fine is maybe a little bit thicker, but
it's it's a little bit smaller as the
microphone, but the case is for sure
smaller. So let me show these two cases
side by side and like see a little
thinner. Yeah, look at how thin that
much thinner that is. So yeah, so
significant probably half the size in
the case itself. The microphones are
similar, the little connectors, the
adapters are are similar, but the case
itself is smaller. So yeah, I'm with
you, Shelby. You know, the audio is just
as good. I I'm going to go with the
smaller case for sure. So, you tell us
which is better and we'll come back. I'm
going to go back to the iPhone and back
to the Ceremonic and then we'll give our
final thoughts as we come back. All
right. The last test that Shelby and I
wanted to do. We're back on the iPhone
now uh so you can compare the video. But
we want to test what does it sound like
without a microphone at all? Just using
the iPhone microphone. Shelby, you want
to say something to test it?
&gt;&gt; Testing. Testing. That's the perfect
thing. Shelby was also letting me know
that I don't She doesn't think I even
need a microphone cuz I talk so loud and
that's I'm on Zoom calls all day and
that's like in my neighbors in my office
say like, "You're pretty loud in there."
So, yeah, I'm a loud talker. Sorry about
that.
&gt;&gt; That's okay.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, Shel Shel's a 13-year-old. She's
got to put up with old dad, but that's
how it goes. So, all right. This is
without a microphone. And now we'll come
back and share our thoughts right after
this. All right, we're back and this is
the last section of this video. We did
the Cammonic on my iPhone. We did the
Fifine on your Samsung Flip. We did the
iPhone with no microphones. And now
we're back to the Ceremonic on the
iPhone. Shelby, we've watched the
videos, listened to them. We now we're
using the speakers on our phones, so
maybe not the best audio, but we we did
get an understanding of what was better.
What was your take between the different
microphone options?
&gt;&gt; Um, I did like
this one better. I don't know.
&gt;&gt; The ceremonic.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Ceremonic.
&gt;&gt; So, even though it's bigger, uh, you
like the sound better.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. What would be your second
favorite?
&gt;&gt; The only other option,
&gt;&gt; the fifine. Yeah. And we thought too
without a microphone, it sounds a little
tiny, right? Or you said like sounds
AIish
&gt;&gt; and echoey.
&gt;&gt; And echoey. Yeah. So, definitely a
microphone helps. And so, the reality is
and and one of the other things and why
we had to switch to Shelby's phone is
the other problem I had with the Fifine
is only had a USB C connector. And so
that's why I had to use the Android.
Now, most new iPhones have the USBC. I'm
on an iPhone 14 still. Uh I'll catch up
one of these days, but I uh I had to use
her phone to use the Fifine. So, if you
got an older iPhone, the Fifine's not
going to work for you or you're going to
have to get some kind of adapter. The
Ceremonic just had the direct connector
right into my iPhone, and it has an
adapter to USBC, so it would have worked
on everything. So, yeah, I'm with you,
Shelby. I think the Ceremonic sounds
better. But here's the thing. This is
$50. This is $120 and so if you're on a
budget, this sounds great. So I
definitely still recommend the Fine 500.
I wish I could have told everyone that
they should just get this no matter what
your budget is that it's better. I don't
think it's better. I think the Cammonic
is a better microphone set, but for the
price, the Fifine is still a really good
option and it's better than no
microphone at all. And it's two
microphones, so you can do a great
interview with it or you can just use
one microphone. So, for 50 bucks to have
a high quality microphone or $120 to
have a really high quality system that
you can use even in a loud place, I
think both microphones are good options.
But if I'm comparing the two, I got to
be honest, the Ceremonic is the winner.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; All right, Joe Shelby, thanks for
joining us and thank you guys for
watching. We will catch you on the next
episode.
[Music]
Heat. Heat.