Hey there. If we haven't met yet, I'm
Neil Smith, your social media guide, and
I make videos here on YouTube about
digital marketing, social media, and
today I'm talking about my new Meta
Ray-B band glasses. I say new, I've had
them about 6 weeks. I've had some time
to play with them. This is actually my
second pair of Meta Ray-B bands. I
bought the first pair with the first
edition and and they were honestly just
so useless uh that I couldn't justify
keeping them. And so, I had them for
about a week, sent them back. Uh but
with the new ones with Meta AI, I was
curious, are these going to be worth it?
Are these going to be valuable? So,
let's talk about what they do and then
I'll share whether I think they're worth
it, whether I think you should pay
$300ish. I say is because they're never
really just $300 for these glasses and
whether they're worth it for me and
whether they're worth it for you and
whether you should or shouldn't. So,
I'll give you the insights as I have
experienced them and what I'm planning
to do in the
future. So, first of all, let's talk
about what these glasses can do. The
first thing people see is that it has a
camera both here and here on the glasses
and they can take pictures. It has a
little button here at the top. I can
just push that button, take a picture.
Let me look at you and I'm going to take
a picture of myself in my teleprompter
looking at you as you're looking at me.
And so I'll post this picture and you
can see what it looks like. I can also
push that little button twice and now
it's taking a video and you can see uh
took another photo and you can see it
flash there. Uh some I got to hold it
down I think. Now it's taking a video.
You can see it kind of flashes a little
bit while it's taking a video. And so
yeah, it's cool. And then I just push it
again and it stops. Or I can just say,
"Hey, Meta, take a
photo." And it just took a picture. So
yeah, it takes pictures, it takes
videos. The quality is okay. It's not as
good as the phone, but it's better than
the first version. So they're okay. They
also have a little touch bar here on the
side. I can turn the volume down, up. I
can just click on things if if something
happens to play a YouTube video or turn
it off or play an audio book and turn it
off. So, you know, some functionality
that is helpful. I I consider consider
it very similar to the Apple Watch where
it's nice to have, not essential to
have. Uh the other thing that it does is
it has headphones built into it. So, as
I talk to it and a microphone somewhere,
I don't know where the microphone is,
but I make phone calls on it. uh and I
can hear them, they can hear me. And it
honestly does a really good job in phone
calls when I'm in a quiet place. Now,
the reality is it's not really loud
enough uh for me when I'm live in New
York City, so when I'm walking down the
street, I can't really do a phone call
there, but in my office, I'll take phone
calls on them. Works as good as
headphones. I like not having to have
AirPods uh in my ear all the time. I
like having being able to have the
glasses and and I find, you know, that
it works pretty good as headphones uh
essentially to to listen to. But yeah,
that that's pretty much all the
functionalities. You got the camera. So,
I keep getting messages and it's driving
me nuts. It's uh you know, a little
distracting. And for that reason, I
often turn it off uh because of all the
distractions. Now, you can control the
notifications and things like that. So,
there's some good and bad with it, but I
I will say that that at the end of the
day, the value uh of that and the
notifications uh is honestly more
annoying than it is helpful. And so, I
don't love that functionality. But I
think if I were going to really dig into
it and control it a little bit better,
that would get better. But it it at the
end of the day, it works as headphones.
It works as a camera and it has meta AI
built into it. And so basically chat GBT
with voice where I can have
conversations with it, ask it things.
And and my two cents on meta AI is it's
just not as good. I think about I'm
pretty used to using chat GBT and
Claude. I'm actually using Grock more
and more way better LLMs from an AI
standpoint. So, it's cool functionality,
but it's basically like Alexa. And I
feel like the functionality of Alexa,
it's just not as good as what we've
become used to with Chat GPT. So, yeah,
let me talk about the good and the bad
with that and whether I think it's worth
it. So, that's what all it can do. And
let me let me share kind of some of the
good and the bad. So, I would say the
good is that they're kind of fun.
They're kind of cool. They, you know,
the photos are the videos are okay. It's
right there. So, when in a place where I
don't want to pull out my phone, I can
take a quick photo or a video. So that's
that's good. The audio when I'm in a
quiet place is good at listening and you
know for listening to things without
having to put headphones in. So that's
good. I I would say the look of them I'm
mixed. I'm 50/50 on it. I have a lot of
people that like oh I didn't even
realize those were not. So they look
like normal glasses to people. Some
people that are looking for them notice
that they're Meta Ray bands and kind of
like oh that's kind of fun you have the
meta ray bands. Or some people are like
oh are you taking a photo of me right
now? So I think that's mixed reviews.
There are a little bulkier than regular
glasses, but they're not heavy. They
they fit and feel just like regular
glasses. So, I would say that's good.
But honestly, I wouldn't pick these
thick of frames if I wasn't getting the
meta ray bands. They did, you know, and
I'd got prescription lenses put into
mine. So, at the end of the day, the
total cost was more like
$450. So, probably, you know, an extra
$150 of what I would have paid for a new
pair of glasses already. So, little bit
extra, you know, with glasses. But
because they have my prescription in
them, I do use them all the time. I got
the extra lenses with the whatever the
blue filter for looking at computers
more cuz I'm looking at a computer
screen all day. So, I guess that's good.
Uh, but that you get that if you're
getting regular glasses. People often
ask me, can you see things? Does it pop
things on your lenses? No. Uh, it
doesn't do that like people perceive.
Honestly, I think that would be
annoying. Now that I experience it with
the audio alerts, I definitely don't
think I want alerts like that in front
of my eyes. So, I as I look to the
future, I think that's probably going to
be part of our future. I don't look
forward to that as much. I can look at
my my Apple Watch to see quick
notifications in front of me uh easy
enough. I don't need it to be right in
front of my eyes when I'm in a meeting
or doing something else. So, I'm I'm not
looking uh forward to that functionality
and feature. I I will say with the
audio, my wife always tells me she's
like, "We can all hear what's
happening." So, when I'm on a phone call
and somebody else is in the room, they
can hear. It's not where it's just me
hearing it. And so, they give this
perception that it's like you could
listen to it on the subway and only you
hear it. That's not the case. really is
while it's better for you to hear, uh,
other people can hear noise around you.
So, it's not like headphones in your
ear, it is like almost like a mini
speaker right next to your ear. So, I
would say that's a a you know, I got to
put headphones in still when I get on
the subway and do other things. So,
doesn't replace my headphones in that
way. It's also not as good as headphones
for phone calls. So, that's
understandable, but also not it's not
replacing that device for me. Camera, I
think, is as good as I would expect for
this. So, I'd give that a plus. the
audio when it's taking video is
definitely not very good. And so it's
it's really better for just, you know,
the photo and the video image, not
necessarily for a full video. But I
wouldn't expect that uh with my glasses.
So it's not replacing my camera phone or
my phone camera. It's an additional
camera that's right there on my face all
the time and so easier to use. So at the
end of the day, the question is, is it
worth it? And and I would say, you know,
practically the camera isn't that big of
a value ad to me. I'd maybe give that an
extra 20 bucks of value if I were to,
you know, add the camera. And the the
glasses with the headphones built into
them. I I bought some off of Tik Tok
shop for my daughter and she uses them
for her Zoom calls for her classes and
and different things. And honestly, they
work just as good as these glasses. And
so, basically, she has met Ray-B bands
without having to pay the $300 for Meta
Ray-B bands, just the Bluetooth Ray-B
bands. And so they connect to her
computer and to her phone as Bluetooth
headphones, give that functionality.
They just don't have the camera built
into them and they don't have the meta
integration. But what they do have is
you can actually connect chat GPT audio
to it. So she can still use that voice
AI through her glasses with Bluetooth.
So, at the end of the day, if I were
just buying a pair of glasses, comparing
a $20 Bluetooth glasses off of Tik Tok
shop and some Meta Ray-B bands, I'd
probably just get those and use
Bluetooth to do chat GPT audio and and
use use that native functionality and
just pull out my phone whenever I want
to take a picture. I just don't think
the value is here yet. And and so, while
I'm not going to send these back like I
did that first pair of Meta Ray-B bands,
I'll keep them. I'll keep playing with
them. And I'm curious to see maybe Meta
AI will get a lot better quicker. That
that would be the biggest value ad to me
is if Meta AI became as good as Chat GPT
and I could use it all. But at this
point, a camera Bluetooth headphones uh
built into my glasses. Cool little
device, but not worth $300. That's my
two cents. What do you think? Are you
thinking about buying the Meta Ray-B
bands? Do you already have the Meta
Ray-B bands? Do you agree with me? Do
you disagree with me? I want to know.
That's my take 6 weeks into the Meta
Ray-B bands. I'll keep you posted. I
I'll keep posting updates as I learn, as
I experiment with them more and more. It
is a look, I think, into the future. You
can see where Meta is going with this,
and I can see the progress they've made
in the last couple of years since I
bought that first pair. So, I'm
encouraged by that. They're a fun toy,
but they they're not worth the price. At
least not yet. That's my two cents. Let
me know what you think. I can't wait to
talk to you again on the next video.
Thanks so much for watching.
[Music]