Hey, welcome to Zoom. If you are like
me, I'm on Zoom calls all day, every
day. And so, I wanted to have a better
experience on Zoom. So, I bought what
the internet says is the best camera for
Zoom calls. So, that's the Insta 360
Link 2C webcam. But before we look at
this cam, I want to look at some other
webcams that I've currently used, and
you tell me which is the better webcam
for Zoom calls. Let's get into the
video.
Hey, if we haven't met yet, I'm Neil
Smith, your social media guide. I want
to find out what's the best camera for
Zoom calls. I have bought too many
webcams trying to find the best webcam,
and I keep going to what I'm using right
now, which is the Logitech
920C. I believe it is the go-to Logitech
camera that people have. I've had it for
5 years. It's been a great webcam for
me, but it's 720p. It has its
limitations, but it just works. It works
well. That's what I'm using right now
and it's good enough for Zoom calls, but
I want better. And so, I have bought a
lot of other cameras and I just bought,
you know, I looked up on the internet,
the worldwide web, and asked what is the
best webcam out there right now. And it
told me that after a lot of reviews that
I read, this Insta 360 Link 2C is the
best camera. I've used the Insta 360
camera in the past, and I've seen like
their GoPro like cameras, but didn't
know that they had a webcam. But let's
look at a few other webcams that I have
tried along the way before making this
purchase. So, the the best webcam I
would say that I bought is one called
Luminina. You might have gotten ads for
Luminina. Uh they they made a big push
years back. Is basically the DSLR of
webcams and it's supposed to be a super
high quality webcam. And so, let me show
you what that c webcam looks like. So,
let me switch my camera here in Zoom.
Okay, this is the Lumina uh camera. You
can see the lighting is off. Now they
have two versions. They have the raw and
then they have the pro version. Even
look at my screen. Give me RAW or plus
are the options. Now if I go to plus it
will give me different set of tabs that
I can look at. So let me go to the plus
version of Lumina. So this is the Lumina
RAW version which basically if you don't
use the app or use their software, this
is what it looks like. You can see I'm
very washed out. Uh, it actually seems
like it's zooming behind me and yeah,
just not good enough for what I would
want to use for webcam. So, now let's go
to their plus version, which gives you a
lot of different options with what to
do. It's kind of the software edition
that supposedly makes the camera great.
Okay. So, in the Luminina version, I can
turn this cameraman on and it will just
like focus in on me and if I move, it's
going to track over to me. If I move
over here, it'll track over to me. Kind
of cool. The problem I had with this
feature is that it would always be
moving and it was distracting for my
participants. So, I turned cameraman
off. It also allows me to change my my
face position where it's zoomed in. this
where it goes a little bit out or this
where it, you know, changes a little
bit. So, it gives me some options. I can
also change the framing to zoom in and
out a little bit. And then I can even
slow down or speed up. So, I move it
faster that the cameraman's going to
move faster. And so, yeah, there's some
interesting features there. The other
feature is I can change the blur
strength. So, I can make it more blurry
around me. Now, this is a feature that's
kind of built into zoom as well. I
thought that would be cool like a DSLR
camera, but honestly the blur I feel
like is just kind of cheesy looking. And
then it has edge strength and so I can
change the edge strength a little bit if
you can even tell where that's different
or not different. And it gives some blur
padding and add that or I can do
sharpness on my video or not. So yeah,
it gives you some features but honestly
you can see, you know, and I can adjust
the lighting in my office but I did not
find the Luminina camera to be a better
camera. I'd prefer. You can see how it
just keeps moving in and out and that's
distracting for people on a Zoom call.
And so, yeah, I'd rather go back to the
Logitech. Let me go back to the Logic
and Tech now. Okay, we are back on the
Logitech camera. And comparing the two,
it was pretty easy choice for me. The I
think I paid $200 for the Luminina at
the time. I don't know what it costs
now, but yeah, it's not a camera that I
use at all or even used very long, but I
got it. I will go back to it every now
and then, test it, and then continue to
be frustrated with it. My my personal
opinion is the camera probably is good.
I think their software is what really
needs work. So, if you get the settings
just right, it's fine. But, at the end
of the day, a $200 camera versus a $50
Logitech, I find the $50 Logitech to be
the better camera. And so, it might not
have the 4K or, you know, a higher
resolution as the Luminina. It has a
good enough uh for a Zoom call. The
other question that I get a lot and I
I'll get to the other cameras here in a
minute is how is it that it looks like
you're looking at me? Well, that's
because I use a teleprompter for my Zoom
calls. I had to rig this together about
5 years ago when I pulled this together
and until it breaks, I'm going to keep
it. But what I've recommended to friends
is Elgato has a great uh teleprompter
setup that's kind of all built in for
one where you can just add your webcam
behind it or put a DSLR camera or
something else, a mirrorless camera
behind it that you can use for Zoom
calls. Great option. I also tried a
mirrorless camera. I have a Canon M50,
but I I really found that to be buggy in
different ways or had had to work all
these, you know, workarounds to make it
work and I just felt like the webcam was
a better option than using that and it
was harder to then disconnect when I
wanted to actually use that camera for
things. So, yeah, the Logitech is what
I've stuck to. Let's go to the next
camera that I tried. That's cool. They
gave me some stickers. Oh, and some more
stickers. Insta 360.
Okay, so this is the Insta 360 camera.
Pretty small, not surprising. And it
comes with this little tripod mount. And
it comes with a USBC cord. It also has a
USB adapter. So USBC to USBA adapter if
that's what you need. I don't. I'll be
able to go straight into my computer
with this cord. So let's get this
connected. Oh, this is cool. So you have
the mount and you have the camera. Put
it on here. It's magnetic and it just
sticks right to there. Very smart, Insta
360. I like that. So, you could actually
have it loose if you want to or you can
connect it to there very easily. Well
done. I like that move. Okay, so this is
the Insta 360 video. I do definitely see
where this is better quality. It's more
zoomed out for sure. I can see where the
color is not just like blushed out like
the other webcams. And I can just even
from the teleprompter I can see the
green light behind behind it which is in
the Logitech it shows a blue circle that
gives you an idea of where the camera is
coming from of where to look. So it
makes look like I'm making eye contact
through the teleprompter. So yeah we we
definitely see where this is
improvement. Let's look at their
software and see how that helps for a
better Zoom call experience. Okay, I
have downloaded the software and
actually did a firmware update as well,
which I like uh that it's updating the
camera. Let me show you the software and
what that looks like. Okay, so I am in
the Insta 360 controller. I can do auto
framing. I don't know what that does,
but it do whiteboard. Oh, I see. I can
just do this and it'll be whiteboard.
Voice focus, voice suppression, some
other settings there. Uh, let's
you Okay, so I'm seeing here 720p. I
actually want to go to 4K 38 frames per
second. Uh, yeah. So, let's increase
that. Let's do autoframing. Okay, it
framed me. Can do a screenshot. I could
record actually. Oh, I kind of like
that. I could just record right there in
the in Insta 360
controller effects. Let's try this blur
background.
Okay, that's giving me quite the blur.
So, that's way better than the luminina.
And I don't feel like it's grainy in
that that blur. You can do makeup,
filter, portrait,
daylight. What does portrait
do? That brightens it up. What's
daylight look like? Okay,
interesting. Vintage.
Little dark vintage
two.
Okay, clear. Okay, good. Let's go back
into zoom. I wish I could zoom in on
this. Uh that would be the one thing
that I am not seeing or sure how to do.
Let me see if I can find that
again. Oh, there it is.
And a little bit more. There we go.
How's that? All right. I set that up as
a preset. So, it gave me the option of
Insta 360 virtual camera and then Insta
360 2C. I I don't know what the
difference is between these two cameras.
Okay. So, this is the Insta 360 camera.
This, if you haven't seen it, is the
Logitech uh that I am used to using. I'm
going to just hang that right there. And
at the end of the day, I think I just
found a better webcam. I even think I
just found my go-to webcam. So, yeah,
I'm a big fan of this Insta3 Link 2C. It
was about 100 bucks. If you're
interested, I'll drop a link in
description below if you're interested
from Amazon. I get a very small
commission off of that, but I guess I
need to say uh that I do get a uh some
kind of affiliate commission off of
this. But yeah, I just really wanted to
test a new webcam and thought I'd share
what the experience was like. What do
you think? Is this a better webcam or do
you think that the old Logitech uh is
still the better webcam? Definitely not
the other two that I tried. I'm going to
stick with this for a little bit and
I'll be curious what tomorrow's Zoom
calls, what feedback I get of if people
notice the new webcam and what they
think. So, thanks for watching. If you
have any questions or share the comments
your thoughts or if you think you have a
better webcam that that I should test, I
am definitely not committed in infin
infinitely to the instant Insta 360
webcam. If there's better webcam, I want
to find it. I spend hours and hours a
day on Zoom, Google Meet, a little bit
even on Microsoft Teams. And so, yeah,
I've I've used this webcam a lot. I want
to have the best webcam experience for
the best Zoom call experiences, best
video conferencing experiences. And so,
if you have a better option for me, I
want to know. Let me know. Thanks so
much for watching this video and we'll
talk to you again on the next video.
Thanks for watching.
[Music]