with so many new platforms popping up is
kajabi still the best all-in-one
platform for course creators in 2025 or
has it been dethroned in this video I'll
break down kabi strengths weaknesses new
updates and compare it to other top
platforms so that you can decide if it's
still worth your investment in 2025 and
Beyond hey there if we haven't met yet
I'm Neil Smith your social media guide
and I help leaders of organizations of
all kind of pastors nonprofit leaders
business owners maximize social media
digital marketing to maximize marketing
to accomplish their organizational goals
and today I'm looking at one of my
favorite platforms that I've talked
about for years I was literally a a
grandfathered into the original kajabi
when it was kajabi next and uh the
original kajabi and I've been using this
platform for probably over a decade now
and one of the things I love is that
it's always getting better but the
question is is it still the best and I'm
still using it and a lot of times people
keep using platforms just because
they're comfortable with it so I want to
dig in and explain to you how I'm using
it why I'm using it and if uh I still
believe that it's the best platform for
Content creators and course creators to
utilize to accomplish their goals when
it comes to your online courses and
digital products let's go to the website
take a
look okay so we're here on the kajabi
website and it says it very clear I love
good marketing dreams it build it
monetize it there are so many people
that I talk to that have a dream for an
online course or some kind of digital
product where it's like if I if I could
just get this knowledge to other people
and I believe so much in the power of
knowledge sharing online and you get a
lot of great content for free on social
media and you get a lot of great content
through ebooks and physical books uh but
but I believe one of the best ways to
learn today is through online courses
and one of things I've Loved about
kajabi is it makes it very easy for
course creators to not just dream it but
build it uh without a whole lot of
technical skills and then to take the
knowledge that they have and so if
you're being asked you know uh do you do
consulting or if you're a consultant
you're like I'm out of capacity to help
enough people you probably should have
an online course some kind of online
product where you can help more people
in masses with the knowledge that you
have and so uh I think they summarize
what they do well is dream about this
product you want to create build it out
very easily in their platform and then
monetize it put it out there in the
world for people to use and allow your
knowledge to make money uh people often
say passive income uh I'm not sure that
I totally buy into that or believe that
because there's a lot of work uh that
goes on in marketing uh that platform
but uh at the end of the day kajabi
helps you create a great platform so you
can see some of the other creators
Fitness uh Beauty lifestyle education
design and art uh I have created uh at
this point for clients ients probably 30
or 40 different sites and probably
hundreds of digital products at this
point and the majority are courses and
the majority of those courses in my my
case is education a lot of business
education or even faith-based uh content
and products and offerings with Bible
studies and uh different things that as
we create it we can make it easily
accessible through their platform uh
they've had their crators uh sell over9
billion in digital products uh and so
helping them create uh good income uh
through their knowledge you can see here
kind of the different functions that
they have is they have courses coaching
communities newsletters memberships and
podcasts and I'll just speak to these uh
very clearly from my experience in
utilizing uh the these different
functions because one of the things that
uh people will say uh when they sell
their products is we can do everything
but oftentimes when you do everything
you do nothing really well um and so
this is a sweet spot kajabi next started
a decade back uh and it was basically
just an online course platform very
similar to teachable uh if you're
familiar at all with
teachable but I always loved their user
experience better and it's changed uh
through the years and honestly just
gotten better and better better that
that core learning management system the
course experience where people are
guided through uh the education products
that you create uh I believe it's the
best function I still uh for kajabi and
I still think it's better uh than anyone
out out there the
coaching the coaching is kind of a more
newer functionality now you could always
integrate that into courses and other
things but now you can actually do live
streaming uh through their platform you
can do almost like Zoom calls through
their live Community uh portals you can
you can have a community Hub so the
coaching communities kind of fit
together you can actually use it for
in-person coaching too where people can
schedule inperson calls you can take
notes you can have kind of a client
point portal uh so that coaching
communities fits together uh sometimes
though you want to have a product where
it's not just you in community with your
your coaching participants it's them in
community with each other and so this is
almost like a private Facebook group uh
I would compare this a lot to Mighty
networks um this is one of those things
where I I think actually or circle is
another similar platform uh I believe
the community's functionality uh is
almost as good I think might networks is
probably a little bit better I think
it's better than Circle uh if I'm
comparing the platforms having tested
both a little bit uh but but I think as
an all-in-one it's pretty good and and
close to some you know I think you have
personal preferences but it works very
well the functionality is really good um
and how we've been using it for
communities uh we're very pleased
newsletters this is actually one of the
the functions where it was a little bit
buggy at the beginning when you think
about the email Communications their
email automations were good uh but even
open r were not as good it you know I
would compare this to MailChimp uh as a
primary newsletter platform and at this
point I would say it's just as good um
maybe not better than MailChimp but I I
don't feel the need uh to set up a a
separate email platform when using kabi
I think their newsletter functionality
has come a long way um very
customizable very easy to use very easy
to set up automations and when you can
have everything in one platform uh it is
uh tremendous so I love uh that
newsletter functionality we use this a
ton membership essentially when you sell
a product and it's a recurring
subscription uh you can have that
membership uh this something we've used
quite a bit easy with credit card
transactions with PayPal with other
functionality and that people have kind
of access and when they don't pay or
unsubscribe they just lose access to it
it's all automated great function ey for
memberships podcast I you know I think
they prioritize this because a lot of
their platform people uh were to have
podcast I really don't get it uh I I use
libson uh for all of my podcasts there's
lots of uh great podcast hosting
platforms out there um and the analytics
aren't that good uh in the kajabi
podcast so I don't recommend hosting
your podcast uh but if you want
something really simple it is there it
is a function and a feature that is
there uh but yeah that those are kind of
some of those key uh functions of the
platform um and what it does and so yeah
that's my two cents on those you can see
here uh the one platform all the
features and this is what they've often
sold is everything you you ever needed
in one platform uh and I think that's
pretty true uh you really the website
builder incredible uh this is one of
those things too wasn't great when it
came out minimal flexibility now you
know we switched all of our websites
from Squarespace uh and WordPress all
into kajabi um and it's now our favorite
uh platform for building you can you
know if you have coders that want to
custom code uh kajabi you can buy
templates from their
store um lots of functionality that you
can build basically any website you'd
ever want to build uh straight into kabi
so the front-end website experience
fantastic payments that they introduced
uh I believe it was this last year
kajabi payments they work great uh it
just integrates natively to stripe um
creates a great user experience and that
takes Apple pay Google pay all of those
things it's great one of the new
features that they rolled out this year
was the mobile app uh platform and so
where you could basically turn your
course or Community uh and digital
products make them easily accessible
through mobile app uh we have launched a
couple of these uh really easy to do
really easy to set up not real
customizable but honestly I don't know
that you want the expense of a mobile
app uh can be crazy expensive if you're
trying to get an external mobile app uh
but the the option uh for you to have
your own mobile app that's in the App
Store um is tremendous and so I love uh
that kajabi has made uh that mobile app
functionality available um and so and
then even if you go uh into view all
features let's go into this section
Community functions uh websites emails
Pages you can have the custom landing
pages contacts essentially CRM now this
is not Salesforce uh it doesn't go that
deep uh as a CRM but you can tag people
and you can um you know would say it's
better than go high level uh but it it's
not as good as Salesforce uh but for
what most people need in a contact list
especially for digital product
engagement in sales is great funnels uh
are just naturally built in I would
compare that to clickfunnels uh if
you're used to that platform so really
great uh functionality payments
analytics you know and I I'll show um
some of the platform and how we're using
it in the back end but uh this is one of
the things I love and one of the things
they've really improved this year and
are in the middle of continuing to
improve uh and the data uh I'm able to
get of you know where we need to get
better what's working what's not working
uh that gives us great data and
analytics so very happy with that uh and
so let's keep going through their
website if there's anything else to uh
to highlight no Revenue sharing ever
this is huge you know a lot of these
platforms that make available like
they'll keep 30% like they'll give you
this platform but they want to keep uh
30% um and so when when you look at uh
you know so many different platforms
like that that provide the technology
for free it's not really for free
they're they're you know if you're
successful they're getting a bigger cut
uh I I think we should own our knowledge
owner and and just pay for the SAS
product that we're paying for I like
that model that kajabi has always held
uh great job kajabi and uh yeah that's
fantastic now I'm guessing they get a
percentage of the from back a kickback
from stri or something like that but I I
don't know when I've used kjab payments
versus using stripe directly it seems
like they're actually using that
Collective ho to drive down the prices
for us uh collectively by creating that
integration so I don't know if they're
getting Kickback or not but uh it is
cheaper uh to use kajabi integration
with stripe than just use stripe
directly um designed to scale uh worked
with clients that have hundreds of
thousands of you know buyers in their
online products there so never a problem
with scale they've got some good stores
here 247 support uh I actually pay uh
for you can pay extra for pre prum
support um for everyone I've ever talked
to the regular support is plenty uh but
because we do so much on the platform we
pay for the premium support uh and their
support has been tremendous the years I
go back to a moment where I had a big
launch on a Saturday and we had to
switch stripe accounts last minute and
it didn't automatically process they had
to do it manually in the back end and I
just went on LinkedIn and just contacted
everyone and uh their CEO actually
contacted me and just said hey we we
actually have our technology team
working on this they had tens of
thousands of customers and clients and
they were responsive to me on a Saturday
when I needed them um it was
unbelievable uh the support I've always
gotten um and how they they've helped
along the way so if you want to talk to
a person there's almost always a person
in the chat or you can schedule uh calls
with their support to if you pay extra
for the support so it that aspect of it
is great The Learning Hub they're always
putting out some great training and tips
uh but you can generally get that for
free so yeah that's that's all the
functions uh and the features and yeah I
think it lives up to all of these things
uh let me show you a little bit more of
the platform and then I'll share my
opinions of whether I still believe uh
it's the best in
2025 okay welcome to the dashboard of
one of my kajabi uh sites platforms
products whatever you want to call it uh
that I run this is online women Bible
study we've been running this for years
when you first log in you can see the
dashboard come of all the different
features here on the left to log into
and then it gives you this key last 30
days uh so you can see in last 30 days
we've had 63 people uh opt into to our
email list we've added 32 new contacts
uh we've had
$2,600 in sales and $85 in sales uh and
55 comments on our different products
you can actually click down to it uh and
go directly to those comments if you
wanted to uh then you go to these other
features with kjab experts University
over here on the right uh is the chat
button so if you want to help you can
just chat with somebody right there uh
and start a new conversation get that
help you need but really where you want
to go is over here on the leth hand side
is where all of the different functions
are one of things I love about kajabi is
that it's just really easy to use uh and
so if you've ever used
Squarespace um or something like that
it's a lot of that same functionality
but when you think about all the
different things that it does to have
all of it easy to use uh and navigate
around is really helpful so first thing
is the products so you have different
products and so for us we have a portal
uh product that has our Bible reading
plans our Bible study our community page
and so you can see even how many people
have access to this uh so it's easily
accessible and I can just click into it
or edit it uh right here in the back end
uh you can actually have your podcast
and your newsletters uh in here as well
and just manage your digital products
here on this side the sales uh this is
how you actually set up an offer uh for
your products and so uh you can actually
see all the payments that come through
and uh list your different offers uh
here in the platform and it will give
you a Tracker of of you know when when
transactions are going through and where
you had a spike or dip uh so me go back
in uh then when you go to the website
this is where you get into all of your
site landing pages let me actually even
show you uh how easy it is to edit a
page uh so if I just go into here and I
go to to online ones Bible study and I
just click on it and I should be able to
just edit it right here yep so you can
see here these are all the different
blocks within the website uh or you can
just edit the banner or edit a section
and you just go into it just like
Squarespace and I can just click into it
and then I could just change this text
over here or I can update the background
image and so really easy uh to go in and
uh adjust those landing pages I'm a big
fan of the website side of things and
how easy it is uh to manage uh the the
website side of uh your website that
gives you a great front end uh
experience and you saw there we had
motion video background and you know you
you can do a stagnant image background
you can change your text and font sizes
and all of that is just super easy in uh
the platform and then if I go down
branded app uh you can actually see here
uh we have a a mobile app uh for this
platform and so you can see here app
name and design and so you can see
actually here what that mobile app looks
like where somebody could click around
uh the library and have access to
everything uh there within the Branded
app and we just simply add in some Lo
logos and connect our products and it's
all there within the app uh then if we
go to marketing this gets us into email
automations push notifications uh for
the email app and uh even automation
when somebody unsubscribes or when
somebody does this then it will send
this and so these are all of our
newsletters and just like a mailchip
account they will tell us we were sent
this to 3400 there's 37% open rate 1%
clickthrough rate uh and so you you get
good data on uh your emails that you're
sending uh and then you can set up these
funnels and automations and forms uh so
you man I think about all the different
tools I used to use with form stock and
Squarespace and uh all the different
platforms it's all
uh here in kajabi um and works great and
then my favorite uh is this analytics
section um and so you can get into gross
revenue net revenue purchases reports
you can dig into all kinds of things
refunds over time net revenue
subscription metrics sales tax you know
lots of great reports uh great visuals
you can also change them to net revenue
all time or you can you know uh change
it to the last you know 30 days or 90
days however you want to break up those
reports uh that the reporting
functionality is is really tremendous um
and then they have this Creator Studio
that will help you in creating content
has some AI functionality built into it
and uh yeah so that is the back end of
kajabi and what all it can do so let's
talk about whether it is the best
platform for you okay so if I'm going to
compare uh this platform and so the
question would be is is there a better
platform out there for me and and so the
first one that that's probably out there
of your tring a course is teachable um
and teachable is is a great platform
they're they're basic a learning
management system very similar to kajabi
and I think if you're just going to have
one course you don't need a website or
want in an email and you already have an
email list somewhere else and you just
want one simple platform for one course
teachable might be a better platform for
you but if you're planning on having
multiple courses if you want to have a
place where you can have a website and
you want to set up some automations and
have uh marketing uh behind that course
I think ajabi is a far Superior uh
platform uh to teachable I think then
then the question I get is like on the
marketing side with the web page and the
funnels uh and this is where I talked
about clickfunnels earlier if I were to
compare this to clickfunnels
clickfunnels the thing that always d
drove me nuts about clickfunnels is it
does have great funnels and they do work
they're just not real customizable and
so there there are a lot of brands that
I work with and uh things that I do
where I'm like I just wanted to look a
certain way and I know you know this
this kind of funny looking website says
clickfunnel soften crates will work
better uh but it just dutes our brand a
little bit what kajabi can do all of
that and and so if I were to compare the
two uh I I'm going to choose uh kajabi
all day uh now I think if you want
something easy that's just going to work
uh and you don't you got a very simple
digital product that you're selling like
an ebook or something like that
clickfunnels is probably a good pathway
if you're just trying to get people to
sign up uh for your coaching program
maybe clickfunnels is a good product but
if you want a full digital product both
both the front end of website and the
back end user experience will sign up
they create a username and log in and
they have easy access uh kajabi far
superior uh to clickfunnels in that way
and then I talked about the community
functionality so if you were wanting to
basically have just a private group uh
where people could meet people have used
slack or Facebook groups for free for
this or they've used Mighty networks or
Circle uh for a place to do community uh
and I think it's Apples to Apples I
think this is where it's not Superior or
you know know uh or lesser than uh miny
networks probably has a little bit
better user experience because that's
what they're centrally focused on uh but
but I I don't think it's um that much
better and uh I I think the cost
effectiveness of kajabi is actually
better on that side of things so uh
comparing the two I I think depends a
little bit uh on what you're trying to
build if your whole product is just
Community uh you want to have a private
community that that's where I think um
Mighty networks is probably if I were to
compare comp Mighty networks to Circle
I'd probably pick Mighty networks over
Circle but uh kajabi is still a really
great platform I would actually
recommend a lot of people consider
Discord I think Discord is is can be a
really interesting place to build a a
private Community if you're looking for
something outside of a Facebook group um
to have that Community within uh so at
the end of the day I think probably the
bigger question is is the cost uh how
much does this cost so let's go back to
the website and look at the cost okay we
are on the price pricing page for kajabi
and this is the first time that kajabi
has ever ticked me off a little bit so
uh I'll be up front uh that that I'm
going to the pring PL page expecting to
be able to show you how much uh kajabi
cost you can see their different plans
of they this Kickstarter basic growth
where you can have all the features and
landing pages and and basically it's up
to 7500 emails or how many products you
have uh for these different packages so
you're just starting out you probably
just need this front-end package uh
that's pretty simple and then as you
grow uh you actually can't have a custom
domain that's kind of strange so you
probably want to at least start with the
basic I think you do want a custom
domain I think that's valuable um and
then web hooks 247 support I think is
good and custom branding um interesting
that they don't make that available but
anyways I I think you you're probably
fine uh with this basic package to start
and then when to move to a growth
package um and uh but look I don't like
it when I have to put in an email to get
a quote on the price um I so I can't
tell you exactly what their prices are
today um I can tell you one I when I got
into kajabi um it was about $100 a month
and what I have found you know and as
I've gotten a bunch of clients into it
is it typically starts uh at about $1
$150 a month uh to to utilize uh the
plan and then as you grow and you get to
where you need uh more contacts and the
truth is you're less worried you know
when when you're up here at this 100,000
contacts list you got 100 products uh
you know your your price is probably
going to go up closer to three to $500 a
month uh but you're making a lot more
money than3 to $500 a month so you're
less worried about it at that point so
you grow into it uh but I would plan you
know on and go through the process uh if
you want to you're comparing but if
you're like how much does it cost that
put it on there uh what I have
experienced in the past is it the start
you know starting rate and probably for
this one on the left the kickstar I'm
guessing is going to be somewhere around
$50 or something like that to get you
into it but I do think based on these
features that I'm seeing here they
probably going to want to start with the
basic probably going to be close to $100
and then probably going to be around 2
250 for the growth plan and then
probably closer to 5 600 for the pro uh
plan uh and so as I have been using this
uh for a long time I I think those
prices are incredibly reasonable when
you think about all the software I I
have replaced from Squarespace to
mailchip to um man I you know I think
about Zoom uh you know for coaching
calls or um just so many different F
website hosting GoDaddy uh is what I use
for website hosting I guess Squarespace
Squarespace uh does the hosting for you
but there are so many features it just
automatically you know instead of having
a bunch of things it's it's now one um
and a bunch of SAS products I got to
manage and keep up with and usernames
and passwords uh but then it's also just
as good if not better than then uh those
platforms uh and it's so much easier and
it just works better so whatever the
price is today uh I can tell you uh for
the most part uh kajabi users are never
complaining about the price when it
comes to the service they get and the
quality of the product uh kajabi uh as I
think about recommendations uh for your
platform I'd put your pricing uh back on
the site uh it might turn off people but
I also think that it uh you're probably
going to turn off more people uh than um
you're going to get leads uh that are
good leads on the other side because I
think your pricing is more than fair um
and I think the reason people typically
High pricing is to prevent sticker shock
uh and get you on a call and get your
lead so uh at the end of the day uh
don't let this hidden pricing structure
scare you uh I would still progress and
reach out to kajabi uh and I think it is
worth it I got a few other thoughts that
I want to add before I close up this
video if you are interested in checking
out kajabi I do have a link it's an
affiliate link uh below I I refer a lot
of people to kajabi uh and uh have you
know lots of friends whove thanked me uh
for making that connection uh so if you
want to click that uh and then go visit
kajabi uh there's you know there's a
link down there sometimes uh that
affiliate link has a access to a
discounted sign up or or one month free
uh and how you connect with that link to
whatever the best deal is uh at the time
that they offer to those those of us who
are are part of their affiliate program
so if you would help me out uh as I'm
sharing this with you by just clicking
that link um and visiting the kajabi
website if you're considering giving it
a tri Runner or checking it out uh would
appreciate that and other thing I want
to just say say if you want help uh
building out your kajabi platform our
team at Amplified social media would
love to help you uh I've got a link to
that you just got to amplify social.
media uh reach out to the team and they
would love to help you uh set up build
out automate all of your kajabi stuff
for you so all you got to do is create
so plug and play uh so you can use the
great tools uh we build it we give you
the keys you own it you run it it's
yours uh so if you want help uh with
your kajabi setup you can reach out to
our team and amplify as well so let's
talk to the kajabi team though for a
minute kajabi team first I just want to
say thank you uh thank you for building
an incredible platform thank you for all
of the patience and support uh you've
given to me uh as a kajabi platform
owner thank you for letting me giving me
such a great deal uh as you've God
godfathered me into my original offer uh
where I know you lose money on my
subscription uh but but you have made uh
the software better and better and
better year over year over year uh and
every time you roll out a new feature I
can't wait to jump into it and utilize
it I've love the new uh mobile app uh
functionality you love the new community
uh platform the the the co group
coaching the zoom calls Zoom calls video
conference calls live streaming um great
uh functionality we are utilizing it and
our users uh are really enjoying and our
team is really enjoying it and just it's
more Dynamic the web pages are more
Dynamic the emails it's just all better
thank you uh for your continued
investment in building a great product
and making it even better um two things
two features requests uh I just want to
put out there one is as you've now
launched mobile apps I would love for
you to also launch TV apps uh so YouTube
uh just actually announced that there's
now more engagement on their TV app than
there are is on their mobile app which
is crazy for me to hear there's nothing
about course creators and a lot of the
products we've created they would
actually work really well on a TV and so
I would love it uh if we had Apple TV or
Amazon Fire TV apps uh that we could
also push out uh where our products were
then available on the TV um so that's my
first feature request TV apps is
actually something that the development
team uh talked about early days and then
it kind of came off of the road map and
I get it because I helped start a TV app
company I understand how complicated it
is and expensive it is uh but also
understand how complicated mobile apps
are and you went down that path makes
sense that that was a first priority uh
but now as a second priority I would
love uh TV apps the second thing is SMS
now SMS I also know is very expensive um
and uh you know it's not the same as
email but it is so direct if we can
incorporate SMS uh like we do email and
push notifications into our systems in a
higher tiered or you know price
structure I don't I don't know how you
structure it but uh you guys have always
figured that out I think SMS integrating
into the marketing communication
functionality would be a great addition
as well that's it that those are the
only two things that I can even think of
that would make ajabi better everything
else uh just keep being great thank you
uh for what you're doing and I am a very
happy uh customer and I would actually
update your processing page just my two
cents uh maybe it's working for you I
don't know uh but but I think your
prices are incredible for the value that
you provide so uh I think making it
publicly available would be a good move
but just my opinion so thank you so much
thanks everyone for watching and I can't
wait to talk to you again on the next
video
[Music]
he