in this video I'm going to talk about
the top three tools for your church when
it comes to technology and just digital
engagement that I believe in 2025 are
going to best move your church forward
make sure you're using the right
Technologies and the right
way hey there if we haven't met yet I'm
Neil Smith your social media guide and I
help churches Ministries nonprofit small
businesses maximize social media to
accomplish their goals and this video
I'm very specifically going to talk to
church is and the function of the church
and how you Align Technology to your
mission and objectives but practically I
think if you're nonprofit leader small
business leader you're going to gain
some insights from uh this advice that
applies to any organization but I am
most specifically talking to churches
and Pastors in this video so I just want
to clarify that before I jump in the
number one tool when it comes to our
churches is the website yes the website
it seems simple and we want to talk
about some of the Tik toks and Instagram
and social media and I'm the social
media guy but practically uh it is your
website the the your website needs to be
great and so however good it is right
now uh we need to prioritize it being
better so that when people come to our
website uh that it looks good that it
works well on different devices and that
it gives them clear calls to action uh
so that they can plan a visit to your
church so that they can easily give to
your church they get integrated into the
Ministries uh within your church our
website needs to be good the technology
be needs to be good the design needs to
be good the copy uh messaging in your
website needs to be good uh and so when
it comes to the most important
technology for your church uh if
everything else is bad make sure that
one thing is good because a great
website could take you a long way even
if you get none of the other pieces
right you have to have great website but
I can tell you this if you get all the
other pieces right and don't have a good
website you're probably going to have
problems so prioritize your website make
sure you have good hosting behind it
good Security on it all of those things
prioritize your website make other
videos uh in this year that will talk
about your Church website and how to
make it better uh but that is the number
one technology still in 2025 that you
need to prioritize more than anything
else the second technology platform
digital engagement platform whatever
language you want to give it uh that you
need to prioritize in
2025 is email yes email boring old email
we all have a love hate relationship
with our inbox uh me especially on the
hate side we really like we to move on
past email but the reality is there's no
better way to communicate directly with
our congregation than email uh and so
email is cheap it's easy we can get
MailChimp for free or you know low price
or there's other great tools out there
that help you design great emails uh
help you lay out good emails help you
make sure you have good open rates and
keep your email list clean uh that do
all the things to make email work so the
technology is actually pretty easy when
it comes to email it's how we utilize
email uh that is most important and we
need to think about how do we better
segment emails so we email the right
people the right things rather than
emailing everything to everyone and then
beginning to just ignore our emails and
so we need to have a great website that
helps people get onto our email list
easily and then we need to make sure
we're effectively utilizing email uh to
get the right information to the right
people in a timely and consistent way
and and so if you're not maximizing
email to consistently engage with your
congregation you're missing out on what
I believe to be the second most
important technology in 2025 for your
church now I'll throw a caveat in there
that SMS or text messaging is kind of
the the bonus tool that kind of rides
alongside of email has a very high open
rate big opportunity I think practically
though it is more expensive I think it's
worth it because of the higher open
rates and it's also more limiting and so
there's only so much you can put into
one text message versus an email so it's
not an either or with texting an email
but I do believe email is the have to
texting is the really good to have and
so I put email over text messaging still
in 2025 uh but I think it's more of a
both and not an either or and so when
you think about your priorities website
number one email number two let's talk
about number three when it comes to the
number three technology in
2025 I'm going to say and this is
probably more of an opinion it's YouTube
I think YouTube is the third most
important technology digital platform
for your church in 202 5 because of the
amount of time more and more people are
spending on YouTube YouTube is that
social media platform or digital
platform whatever you want to call it uh
that that is basically
multi-generational uh older people watch
YouTube younger people watch YouTube and
YouTube has so much functionality it's
what the number one app people are
watching on their televisions now and
guess what your church is probably if
they're not if you're not already you
need to be creating content for YouTube
not just your sermons too by the way you
need to create shorts uh for YouTube
shorts you need to be creating Community
post for the social media side of
YouTube you need to be engaging in the
comments in the community that's
happening there on YouTube and I believe
YouTube is going to open up even more
functionality in 2025 that we need to be
ready for and so if you're not
maximizing YouTube I Believe YouTube
which is also owned by you Google and is
a huge search Eng for people to find you
but it's also a place where people are
going to engage and consume uh your
content on consistent basis whether
they're sharing your serving content
consuming your content maybe you add
devotional series on YouTube lots of
opportunities on YouTube and so in 2025
website number one email number two and
then I would say YouTube is number three
what would you agree with or disagree
with what are your opinions uh on the
best and most important Technologies for
churches in 2025 I'd love to know your
opinion thanks so much for watching I'd
love uh to connect with you in the
comments or on my website Neil smith.com
let's connect online uh and send me an
email I I read them most of the time and
reply almost all the time thanks so much
for watching we'll talk to you again on
the next video
[Music]