Is it time for your church to get into
virtual reality? In this video, I'm
going to talk about why you should
consider getting into virtual reality,
when you should get into virtual
reality, and what I believe churches are
going to do in virtual reality. So, get
into the video, let's talk about it, and
share your opinions in the comments
afterwards. I want to know what you
think.
Okay, so a lot of people ask me, is it
time for our church to invest in the
metaverse? Is it time for us to be
thinking about virtual reality? And the
answer is is probably not. There is not
a critical mass of
yet. There's not a good reason to begin
to go all in in virtual reality, but I
do believe, and this is one of the
things I've been wrong about is I first
experimented with virtual reality about
10 years ago, and I thought, oh, this is
going to get here quick, and we're all
going to have VR headsets soon, and it
just didn't happen. They haven't reached
mass adoption yet, and they're primarily
used for gaming at this point, but I do
believe it's still coming. When I look
at the investment that tech companies
are doing with Apple Vision Pro, with
Meta, everything with their with their
headsets, the Quest headsets, and the
different things that they're investing
into with augmented reality and virtual
reality, it is coming. And I think we
don't know exactly when, and it's still
probably 5 or 10 years away from
reaching mass adoption, but I do believe
it's coming, and I do believe it's
something we need to be thinking about
where this might go, and how we can
prepare for a future in virtual reality.
And it doesn't mean that we're doing
away with incarnational, you know,
in-person church. It means that as we've
engaged people on their phones and on
their computers and through their
televisions, that that we're augmenting
what we do at our in-person churches
with virtual reality technology. And
it's a great tool to engage and connect
people in between Sundays, and maybe
just to engage people that you couldn't
otherwise reach. So, here are the top
three ways that I think churches are
going to use virtual reality, and how I
think we can begin thinking about it and
preparing for that in the future. So,
the first way I think churches are going
to use virtual reality in the future is
VR virtual reality worship services, so
streaming in 360 videos. So, it means
you basically put a camera that has
camera has, you know, on all directions.
So, when it records, if you're in a
virtual reality headset, you can look to
the left as if you're in the worship
environment. It can actually do this in
a 3D environment, so it feels for the
person that's watching in a VR headset
like they're there in your worship
environment. And so, I think about
people that are home or sick worshiping
with you. It's one thing to watch it on
a flat screen on their phone or computer
or television screen. Good experience.
What would be a better experience, I
believe, is if they can put on a headset
and feel like they're there. And so, I
think that's going to create the optimal
viewing experience for our content that
that immerses people in it, rather than
having them passively watch it on a
computer screen with all kinds of
distractions around them. So, virtual
reality worship experiences is what I
believe will probably be the primary
use, just like we've started live
streaming our services, and the pandemic
expedited a lot of people being able to
do that. You can already use a 360
camera. You can already stream that on
YouTube and and on Facebook. And so, the
technology is already there,
but there's not enough users yet with
the headsets that make it worth the
investment from a production standpoint.
So, I don't highly recommend doing it,
but you might begin testing a little bit
and maybe preparing if you're already
streaming your services, renting a 360
camera and testing it, and being
prepared for when that day comes that
you might want to begin getting into
360, depending on your timing of whether
you want to be an early adopter or kind
of right when it begins to hit mass
adoption. The second thing that I think
see churches doing and ministries doing
when it comes to virtual reality is
quiet time experiences or devotional
experiences. One of the problems with
devotionals on our phone is that we're
going to get text messages in the middle
of reading them. We're going to have
other distractions where if we put in a
headset, we can actually then go into
maybe a walk through the Holy Land, or
we could be walking down a stream, or be
immersed with kind of this 360 sound and
audio. And so, we can actually have a
virtual quiet time, virtual devotional
time where we read the Bible, or we
meditate, or we do different things, but
we do it in this immersive headset
environment that I think is going to be
so much more effective than just
headphones listening to an audio
devotional or a video devotional on a
phone. And so, I think a VR devotional
experience is going to be a powerful use
as people start creating these, and
people can use these. And so, I would
love to see churches start creating
virtual reality devotional experiences
ahead of virtual reality mass adoption,
so that content is there as users begin
to adopt it. Now, the third thing,
probably the weirdest use, but I think
it's going to actually become a more
common use, and that's going to be small
group environments where people use
avatars to interact with each other. And
that's the side of VR that I think
people have a struggle with when it
comes to the metaverse is I don't want
to interact with other cartoon
characters or even function like a
cartoon character. But when you get into
these environments, they become a little
bit more normal, and these environments
are actually making it look more like
you, and other people look like them.
And so, when you compare one of those
environments versus a Zoom call, it's a
much more interactive. You can see more
of their body language. You can see more
of their facial expressions, rather than
just what they put on the screen in
their little box on Zoom. You can
actually look around the room as if
you're in the same room. And and you
might be saying, I wish we were in the
same room. Well, the reality is is
because geography or travel or putting
kids down at late at night, it's not as
good as being in the same room, but it's
the closest thing to it. And I think
it's going to be better than Zoom calls
for people that do early adopt with that
technology, and as as it becomes more
common, and people become more used to
it. We weren't always used to Zoom calls
prior to the pandemic, and now it's
becoming more common. So, those are the
three functions that I see churches
primarily integrating into what they do
with virtual reality into the future.
And at this point, I think the only
thing that's preventing us from
progressing is adoption of the
technology. So, with if you should get
into this technology really depends on
who you're trying to reach, and how much
they've adopted the technology. Mobile
apps didn't necessarily make sense 15
years ago, but they sure do now. And now
that the adoption is so high with mobile
phones, and so virtual reality
integration will make more and more
sense the more people adopt and begin
using that technology. So, that's when I
think you should consider it, and I I
think it's a matter of when, not if, and
how, not, you know, whether you do it or
not. And so, yeah, I believe virtual
reality is going to be a part of our
future, and I think it's going to
benefit what we do in very positive ways
we're intentional about innovating
around this technology, but we can also
waste our time and go too soon. We can
also miss an opportunity and go too
late. So, pay attention to the
technology, be thinking about how this
technology can be integrated into your
ministry purposes and functionalities.
Thanks so much for watching. I can't
wait to talk to you again on the next
video.