are you looking to run a campaign on
meta ads for your ministry or for your
nonprofit I'm going to share
transparently pull the curtain behind
what we're doing at online Women's Bible
study with our meta ads campaigns and
see if that helps you in understanding
exactly how we're running our campaigns
and if you might be able to learn from
some of what we're doing that might be
effective or ineffective uh to in
comparable to what you're doing I hope
this
helps hey there if we haven't met yet
I'm Neil Smith your social media guide
and I help organization leaders
nonprofit leaders church leaders
Ministry leaders maximize social media
to accomplish their goals and amplify
their message and so today I'm going to
just pull a curtain on a project that
I've been working on with my sister for
several years called online Women's
Bible study we actually launched it with
online women's retreat during the
pandemic and then that led to thousands
of women attending this online women's
retreat and they asked for can we do
Bible study too so we launched online
womenbible study.com you can go check it
out if you're interested we have a free
7-Day trial by the way uh but I want to
just share kind of what we've learned
along the way we have found meta ads to
be our most effective place to engage
New women in this Bible study that we've
created and if you want to look at how
it works you know got as I said we have
a free 7-Day trial so you can actually
sign up and then unsign up and you can
see the whole thing there but I think
this could be helpful so whether you
have a membership program or not or
whether you just have a free sign up
meta ads can be such a powerful tool and
we have just kind of found this formula
to begin to work really effectively to
help us and one of the things we want to
do is just engage more and more women in
Bible study and transparently this is a
business that we started but at the core
it's a Ministry objective that we have
is to get more women uh engaged in the
Bible study into a $15 a month
membership program to help women study
the Bible so that's what we're doing and
this is how we're doing it so the first
thing we had to figure out when it came
to setting up our advertising campaign
is figure out how much we're going to
spend on us and one of the things that
we did is we actually hired a coach to
many membership sites and shout out to
Jamal Miller who was a tremendous coach
and helping us especially as we were
getting started and his recommendation
was is spend 40% of your revenue on ads
every month to reach more people and so
one of the just stats that people often
talk about in business is what's your
customer acquisition cost what's your
lifetime value of a customer what's your
cost of good sold so this is our
customer acquisition cost is this is how
how much it cost us to get new customers
and we to decide how much money to spend
on ads well for us that's 40% of Revenue
every month and so you know that's
whatever it is every month and so the
more we grow the more money we're able
to spend on ads which means the more
women we're able to engage into our
Bible stud so it's motivation to help us
grow and engage more women so that's how
we determine our budget for online
women's Bible study ads every month we
look at what was our revenue and we just
automatically designate 40% to go to ads
and so we don't determine it based on
what the conversion rate is every month
we really try to optimize the conversion
rate every month based on the budget
that we set aside each month from the
past month's Revenue so that's how we
came to our budget every organization
needs to understand figure out what is
your budget going to be for advertising
it might be 10% might be 20% but this is
important even for nonprofits is when
we're looking at donor engagement we're
looking to engage new people in our
nonprofit We need to spend money to
reach people and tell people about our
story and and how to engage people and
so we've got to reinvest in marketing
and I've learned this in business and
talking to so many other people is we
can't just assume that our product is
going to sell itself we need to invest
money to tell people about our products
so and invite them into engaging with
our product or service so that's how we
budget our ads and how we determine our
customer acquisition cost in case you're
curious right now what we're seeing is
it cost us about $2 $9 per new
subscriber $29 actually per free trial
into a subscriber and we have an 80%
conversion right from 7-Day free trial
to paying subscribers so that's what
we're seeing when it comes to our met
metrics around our budget and our
customer acquisition cost okay so we
determined our budget and now we had to
determine our audience who are we going
to Target with our meta ads now one of
the advantages we had is because we had
launched first with online women's
retreat we now had a built an audience
and and then we were able to promote on
the one B to them so we were able to
take that audience and connect meta ads
to our website and give it the database
of the users that we already had engaged
and create a lookalike audience and so
we tested different 2% 3% 1% lookalike
audiences to our current members for
targeting purposes and so we target
women in America and Canada in a few
different countries but mostly North
America have a lookalike 1% lookalike to
our current members and that's what we
found to be our sweet spot so as we
tested different audiences we refined to
a 1% lookalike audience of our current
members and I think as you run ads one
of the most powerful opportunities I
believe with meta ads is there lookalike
opportunities if you have data that you
can give it to create those campaigns
and so that's what we have found to be
extremely successful for on the women's
B study so yeah that's that's what we
found so we have our budget we have our
Target now let's talk about the creative
so what we did when we started out is we
created five different variations of ads
five different copy changed ads and five
different visual ads and we mix and
matched between those five versions of
different copy and different Visual
creatives and combine those to create
our campaign and then what we do is
every month we take the top three best
performing ad creative combinations of
the three best copy and three best
visuals and then we'll refine and take
out the two lowest performing copy
options and two lowest performing visual
options and add two more to that
combination and see which ones work best
and kind of refine off of the ones that
are performing best and so we just kind
of have that rotation of every month we
refresh our creative and because we're
targeting run the same basically
initiative every month we're not having
to change it to a campaign it's ever
green in nature but we're always looking
at how can we take what what we see
working best and just tweak it even just
a little bit to see if we can make it
work even better so we're using that
flow of five ads running at the same
time or five different ad copy and
visual distinctives or you know
variations and testing those and then
removing the two lowest performing each
month and just refining based on the
highest performing and so that's our
kind of variety that we're finding to
continue to drive down our customary
acquisition cost to make our ads more
effective every month so the last thing
we're doing and that we found to work
effectively with our ad campaigns is
we're engaging in the comments one of
the things that people miss with meta
ads is they're basically posted as
regular posts and people can comment on
those posts and one of the missed
opportunities is you'll often see people
posting negative comments on your ads or
positive comments or questions about
your product or service right there in
the post itself but you don't see it
because it's not in your page feed and
so you've got to do that through the ad
platform so we're monitoring all of our
ads and we're commenting on all of the
comments that people make and replying
or we're deleting you know very negative
ones that might not be relevant or
helpful to people that are seeing those
ads so modering the comments have been
really helpful and effective in MA
maximizing the effectiveness of these ad
campaigns so those four steps is what we
have found to prioritize our budget
prioritize our creative prioritize our
targeting and then prioritize our
engagement within the ads and that's
what we're continuing to see work and
we're always looking at how can we drive
down our customer position crossed what
you know our lifetime value we found
that average user is about 7 months so
it's about $15 and we we're learning our
numbers and and how at the end of the
day our goal is to get more women to
engage in Bible study and so how can we
do that and make sure we're budging it
enough to be able to promote this to
more women and then also understanding
our cost of good sold is how much does
it cost us to do this and how can we put
more money into the product to make it a
better experience for the women that are
engaging with us so we're measuring
those numbers we're learning those
numbers uh but we're really finding meta
ads to be the most effective way to
engage more women so if you're running
an ad campaign and you want help you can
reach out to our team and amplify social
media we'd love to help and yeah and
transparently give away our secret sauce
just like we did here in this video I
hope this is helpful for you yeah that's
behind the curtain of online women's
Bible study if you are woman or no woman
that is interested in the Bible study
free 7-Day trial love for you to check
it out on the Women's Bible study.com
thanks so much for watching this video
we'll talk to you again on the next
video
[Music]