are you ready to amplify your
organization's social media presence in
this video I'm going to talk about five
tools to help you become more effective
and efficient on social media to amplify
your message and reach more people let's
get into the
video hey if we haven't met yet I'm Neil
Smith your social media guide and I help
leaders and organizations and pastors
and nonprofit leaders maximize social
media to accomplish their goals and I
want to help you uh and I want to share
some tools that we use uh at our
marketing agency amplify social media
and uh and I hope these can help you and
practically if you want it done for you
hire us amplify social. media you can
skip this video and just go uh reach out
to our team and we can help run your
social media but I want to basically
give away our secret sauce today and
tell you here are some of the tools that
we use uh that are a lot of them are AI
driven or just softwar driven to be more
efficient and effective on social media
so I'm going to give away some Secret
Sauce today I hope it's helpful to you
uh but if you need help feel freee to
reach out to our team let's get into
these tools the First Tool uh that we
use that's really our go-to Tool uh when
it comes to social media scheduling and
comment moderation basically our social
media management software that is
metrical metrical now we've used a lot
of different Tools in this area we've
used aore pulse we used Sprout social uh
we've used social report but metrial has
become our go-to for two reasons one it
works works really well bottom line and
two it's more cost effective now we love
Sprout Sprout social Sprout social is
probably our favorite at the platforms
but the reality is is we got more
clients we were managing more accounts
it became not very costeffective for us
to use and we needed something that
worked as well that wasn't so expensive
and Metric cool we found it work just as
well uh but be a fraction of the cost
and so uh if you are considering what
social media management tool to use and
cost
is a barrier metrial I believe is a
platform that gives you all the
functionality and then some that you
probably need at a fraction of the cost
of something like Sprout social now I
would say metrol is far and above
everything else we've used uh outside of
of sprout social so the only thing that
I would even compare it to is Sprout
social so first tool that I'd recommend
is met cool the second tool that I'd
recommend is Riverside and so whether
you're creating standal Lo videos or
you're creating podcast content I have
found Riverside to be just a great tool
to capture video and audio content
really professionally really easily and
then be able to Output it and distribute
and even edit it right there within
Riverside and a really efficient way to
not lose quality of your content done in
a cloudbased setting and so Riverside is
the best video and audio capture tool
I've ever used uh so I strongly
recommend and Riverside the third Tool
uh that we have really uh begun to use
more and more is a platform called mvo
and I have another video where I compare
mvo to Opus Clips so if you ever used
Opus Clips uh you know what that does
but you can basically take your YouTube
long form video content or your podcast
content and it will create clips for you
for reals and for YouTube shorts and for
Tik toks uh it's now a very popular
opportunity for you to then clip up your
content for vert short form vertical
videos uh so mvo has become our go-to
and nvo actually goes beyond just the
clips they're spending into a lot of
other features and functions as well so
I have learned to appreciate mvo over
Opus Clips that's my two cents so a lot
of people the fourth tool that we're
experimenting with more and more but
using here and there is a platform
called my Mary now my Marky is like a
full AI uh done for you social media
content I would say this is more of like
a filler content I would make it your
primary content but it creates content
just pulling stuff off of your website
and other things that it finds online
and creates content that you can just
pick and choose from the content it
creates to then post right on your
social media platform so it's pretty
amazing for what it does and for the
cost uh that it is and so if you're not
looking for really customized content
but you do just basically plug in your
brand and it will uh basically pull a
lot of that off of your website it's
pretty impressive pretty cool uh and
it's a very lowcost solution for the
output that it provides and the fifth
Tool uh that that continues to be our
go-to and so many people's go-to is is
canva and now a lot of our team still
likes to use Photoshop and some of the
premium tools but canva when it comes to
creating social media Graphics when it
comes to creating PowerPoint slides when
it comes to creating uh YouTube
thumbnails canva does such a great job
in their new AI features make it even
better and so we love uh canva and so
those five tools uh will help you
tremendously they're very cost effective
and so we're I'm I'm fairly cheap when
it comes to what I'm using and so always
like to test the best but then compare
uh the the more cost effective solutions
to the premium products and so those are
my five top recommendations of the most
efficient and effective tools that we
use in our digital marketing agency to
support our clients and the work that
they're doing I'd love to know if you
have any other tools or things you'd
recommend drop those in the comments I'd
love to learn about those things I'm
going to leave an affiliate link to
several of the links or just a regular
link uh for those that I maybe don't
have an affiliate link to but I want to
be transparent some of those are
affiliate links uh and so yeah if if
those are helpful to you I'd love to
know which ones you're using which ones
you're not using or answer any questions
you might have about these tools but
that's a little secret sauce behind the
curtain of how we do what we doing some
of the tools that we're doing to help
support our clients and amplify their
message so hope this video helps if you
have any questions drop in the comments
I'll be there to answer them thanks so
much for watching and we'll talk to you
again on the next video oh
[Music]