your church using AI we're hearing about
AI all the time in so many different
places and spaces uh and I think there's
a big question is should we use Ai and
if we should how should we use AI I'm
going to answer that in this video and
I'm going to give you four tools that I
think your church should consider using
immediately and potentially into the
Future these are the four tools that I
believe are probably the most
immediately effective tools for your
church
today hey there if we haven't met yet
I'm Neil Smith your social media guide
and I want to talk to churches today and
how church leaders can begin to
integrate AI in should do I think
churches should begin using AI yes do I
think churches should be concerned about
AI yes do I think church should be
learning about AI yes I I think at the
end of the day AI is going to just like
any other Technology Innovation in
history is going to add value to what we
do as church leaders and it's going to
create unique new challenges and the
best way I think that we're going to be
prepared for those challenges is to be
using it ourselves and be understanding
it uh and navigate those challenges as
we come but ignoring it is not going to
be the solution so I believe AI can
actually help your church pretty
effectively today and better prepare you
for the future that's coming tomorrow so
the first tool that I think every Church
leader should be integrating into their
workflows this one's free I think it's
actually worth paying the $15 a month or
whatever it cost for the premium account
and that is chat GPT chat GPT is the
most popular most widely adopted AI tool
and chat GPT can just help us with so
many different things uh and so if
you're not yet using chat GPT I highly
recommend just download I actually have
the desktop app on my computer always
open uh and just begin using it and ask
it questions and ask it to help you uh
with different things ask it to help
brainstorm there's lots of things I got
a whole video just about how to use Chad
GPT you can go learn that I have another
video about how to create your own GPT
Chad gbt is a great tool that can be
used in lots of ways and and I think you
won't really know how to use it and if
you want to figure out how to use it
just ask chat gbt how can I better use
this for my church and it will give you
some tips uh and things to learn so Chad
gbt is the first tool that I think every
church needs to be integrating today the
second AI tool is one that I've been
getting to know better and better over
the last six months or so and that is a
platform called sermon shots sermon
shots is kind of best known for their
Clips uh that it's pulling
out of your YouTube videos you can put
in your YouTube video and it will create
clips for Instagram reals and Tik Tok
and YouTube shorts and it does a great
job with that but they've also expanded
into other features and functions
including things like creating social
media graphics and creating YouTube
thumbnails I love seeing uh their
platform continue to innovate and get
better uh and it's just a really good
tool for churches that does works really
fast really easily uh and I think just
about anybody can use it so surmon shots
great AI tool that's also getting better
all the time that's one of the things
I'm always looking for in software tools
is is it improving or is it stagnant and
as I see constant Improvement uh that's
a good sign for this is going to keep up
with these changing Technologies
especially the changing landscape of
social media the third tool is similar
to sermon shots and they have some
similar overlapping functionalities and
that's Pulpit AI uh and and so one of
the things I would actually recommend in
using both of these platforms is they'll
have similar functionalities and what it
will actually do even with the clips uh
that that popit AI might pull out of
your sermon as well is you can test the
different ones see which ones perform
best but popet AI will do more when it
comes to even creating like some sermon
uh conversation starters for small
groups or sermon summaries and uh
different outlines and so popit AI has a
lot of additional functions that helps
take your sermon content and get the
most out of it uh and so as I had
another video called uh the podcast
squeeze I would often call this the
sermon squeeze of get the most out of
your sermon Pulpit AI we actually use AI
to get the most out of your sermon so as
your pastor is putting so much energy
and effort into creating that sermon
content Pulpit AI will help you get the
most out of it so I think combining both
sermon shots and Pulpit AI will take
your sermon content and squeeze uh the
most out of it for social media and your
other Platforms in a very effective way
now the fourth tool is not a tool that a
lot of people consider AI but they've
had a lot of AI functionality and that's
canva uh and so canva has this you know
magic feature as they call it uh but
where it will really you can almost
treat it like a graphic designer and
tell it what to do and what to create
and so you don't actually even have to
design as much it will use AI uh to
create a lot of graphics for you to
create YouTube thumbnails for you to
create social media graphics for you and
so using the AI functionality of canva
is a great way to take your canva usage
and to another level and to make your
visual graphics for your church look
better and better and one of the things
that I love that these AI tools are are
making available is you know I think a
lot of times smaller churches don't feel
like they can afford a graphic designer
and afford all of these you know tools
that larger churches have had or or
these support systems that other
churches have had well the end of the
day AI is replacing a lot of that and so
you don't need that because you have
canva ai and for $10 a month or whatever
it costs uh for a small monthly fee you
basically have a graphic designer to
help you look great on social media look
great uh on your website Graphics or
your sermon uh slides and so use canva
AI to just enhance your visuals in a
really uh impressive way um pretty
quickly and rapidly and the more you use
it the better you'll get and the smarter
and better it will learn your brand and
and how it will best represent you so
those are the four tools I'd recommend
if there are other tools uh that you'd
recommend drop them in the comments I
want to test new platforms we can learn
from each other uh and let's find the
best AI tools to serve uh churches and
help us do ministry more efficiently
more effectively uh and be able to focus
more on Ministry rather than a lot of
these other you know detail process
things uh that that we need to do uh to
to do ministry so those are the tools
that I would recommend for you to
integrate today uh drop in the comments
if you have any other AI tools that you
would recommend for churches to look at
or consider that you're using Claude is
another popular one that I know a lot of
pastors are using uh so chat gbt versus
Claude which one maybe do you prefer
let's have a conversation in the
comments let me know what you think uh
I'd love to hear uh your thoughts and
what other tools might be out there that
that I don't yet know about or that
others uh are using and let's grow and
learn together as we integrate AI into
our systems into our workflows and we'll
deal with some of the problems in the
future I'll make videos about those
things as they pop up but I hope this
helps and look forward to engaging with
you in the comments and we'll talk to
you again on the next
[Music]
video e