Parents, this video is for you. Do you
have kids that are using technology,
feeling overwhelmed, confused, not sure
what to do, how to monitor their
engagement online? This video is for
you. I'm going to share three tools that
are going to help you better engage with
your kids as they begin to use these
devices
and give you a lot of peace of mind when
it comes to technology integration with
your kids.
Hey there, if we haven't met yet, I'm
Neil Smith, your social media guide. And
today, I'm going to talk to parents. I
want to talk to parents about three
tools that we have found as to how to
better engage your kids and how to
better basically give them access to
technology and for you to feel
comfortable with that. One of the things
I hear from parents all the time is it's
just so overwhelming of like kids have
access to all these things that we
didn't have. It was so much easier back
in the day. And the truth is as a
parent, it actually freaks me out to
think about what my parents had to go
through not being able to to communicate
with me excessively through a phone when
I started driving or when I was roaming
around the neighborhood, they couldn't
just get a hold of me and track where I
was.
I believe it actually makes it easier to
parent through technology today than it
did back in my day when I was growing up
for my parents. And so, I think it's
actually a great opportunity. There are
some other unique challenges that come
with it. I'll be clear about that, but I
think there's just incredible
opportunities to be engaged with your
kids with their activity online. So,
let's get into the apps that I'd
recommend using. The first app is, you
know, a go-to for anybody when it comes
to just tracking where your kids are,
and that is Life360.
Life360 is what we use in our family and
we can actually track where our kids go,
where they went. We can actually track
if they're in a car where somebody's
speeding or if they're in their car and
they're speeding. Now, our kids live in
New York City, they're not driving. But,
if the case, you can actually track it.
My wife will actually give me a hard
time if I'm traveling and she can see
that I'm in a car that's going too fast,
it will send her an alert. And so, it's
just a great way. Some other people use
Apple Find My Phone and other things,
but Life360 works on both iPhones and
Android devices. And it's just a great
tool to track where your kids are all
the time. And so, for my kids, they they
got phones when they're probably about 9
years old and we've been able to track
anytime they go anywhere they leave our
house, they have their device with them
all the time and we're able to track
where they are. And we can kind of know
where they are at any time. And so, it
gave us a lot of trust with knowing
where they are at any given time to be
able to track that and keep up with them
easily. And they know where we are and
they're able to track when I'm on my way
home
or when I'm traveling.
And so, Life360 is just a great way to
just stay connected with where each
other are in in the world through our
devices. So, Life360 is a good just
tracking platform from a location
standpoint. The second app that I
recommend is a platform called Bark.
Now, I tested a lot of different things.
Disney had a great tool called Circle. I
don't know if that's still a thing, but
Bark has become the go-to for a lot of
people when it comes to just internet
tracking. It works great on computers,
it works great on smartphones, it works
great on Android and iPhones. I actually
find it to work better on Android than
iPhones because of some of the privacy
stuff on iPhones.
But but at the end of the day, Bark is
what I've found to be the go-to in just
tracking what my kids are doing on the
internet. And it will track their text
messages, it will track their social
media engagement, it will track a lot of
different things going on online. And
you can actually control the levels of
tracking and accessibility that you're
giving their kids on your kids on their
different devices. And so, Bark is
really the go-to in really monitoring
their internet engagement. It will flag
certain things and give us alerts. And
one of the things I've actually enjoyed
is my kids will, prior to even knowing
that we get alerts, they'll have
something pop up on their computer and
they're just like, "Hey, I want to let
you know in case this pops up on my Bark
that I didn't mean to do this and this
happened." Bark is such a great just
tracking platform as to what they're
doing on the internet. And it will flag
certain words and and phrases or videos
that that might pop up. And so, it has
great filters on it and I have found it
to be the best just engagement online
engagement tracking tool with my kids.
Now, one of the things I'm trying to
figure out is I've got a
12-year-old and a 15-year-old. When do I
begin to pull off of some of these
things to give them more freedoms? But
at this point, I'm all in. I'm tracking
everything they do online. And that
gives me great peace of mind as to
what's going on without having to look
over their shoulder all the time and
have everything
publicly accessible because I can access
everything they're doing on their
devices pretty much all the time thanks
to Bark. Now, the third tool I love,
especially as my kids get older, is
banking and online banking. And people
have asked me too like, "What do you do
with like PayPal and you know, things
like that?" And so, we have used a found
an app called Greenlight. And Greenlight
is basically a way to give your kids
their first bank account
and and begin to get used to tracking
their money. And and so, where we do
allowance in our house can earn money or
they our kids babysit, they use
Greenlight and they basically have a
bank account. It started as they get a
debit card and
we're able to even track their chores
within Greenlight and then get send them
a money from our account to their
account. But then, Greenlight has gotten
better and better the more we use it.
And so, they can actually have a savings
account. They have like a checking
account or they call it a spending
account in Greenlight and they can have
a savings account that has small
interest, but then it also has an
investing account where they can
actually choose stocks that they want to
invest in. It's like Robinhood on their
app. And so, my youngest daughter is
actually invested in the S&amp;P 500 and
she's seen her money begin to increase.
We've been able to talk about
compounding interest and learning how to
make let your money make money. And and
so, it's been a great platform to teach
our kids about money
and especially as the world has gotten
more digital. So, when I was growing up,
it wasn't until I was about 18 years old
that I got my first debit card and a
checkbook and I had to track everything
in my checkbook. Well, now they're able
to do this online and they're able to
use their phone and it actually connects
to Apple Pay. So, they can actually
spend through their debit card off of
their phone or use their physical debit
card. And one of the things we also like
about Greenlight is that with their
debit cards, they can actually design
their own debit card. And so, they were
able to kind of create a custom design
for their debit card. So, Greenlight has
made money engagement and tracking very
fun. It also allows us as parents to
track everything they're spending money
on. When I was a kid and I had just
cash, my parents had no idea what I was
spending my money on. They couldn't help
guide me along the way of excess
spending and
saving my money. They they didn't know.
It was all kind of in my pocket or
wasted on something silly. And
with our kids, we're able to monitor how
they're spending money and help guide
them along the way and teach them about
budgeting and saving and all of those
things that help our kids become more
independent and mature and grow in
financially. And so, those three apps as
a parent have really given me a lot more
trust and just freedom in allowing my
kids to be digitally native and grow in
these digital tools while also feeling
safe in these places where their banking
is done in a safe way that's made for
kids and not just giving them direct
access to a full checking and bank
account that's going to be overwhelming
and confusing. It eases them into these
tools. And as they get, you know, a bank
account at Chase or Wells Fargo or
somewhere else, it will be more natural
for them moving from Greenlight to that
banking system. And as they get more
freedom and I move off of Bark, then
they they'll have that freedom. But for
now, we're able to use these apps to
help them integrate into their digital
lives and engage with them in safe and
trusted ways. And so, I hope these apps
help you. If you have any other app
ideas, drop them in the comments. I'd
love to hear. I love testing out new
apps, but I believe that in this day of
digital world and
with kids, we actually have a lot of
opportunities as parents to really help
them, monitor them, and and help guide
them through these platforms. And
they're not overwhelming for us and
they're not overwhelming for them.
They're they're actually quite effective
and they're very cost-effective as well.
So, hope these helped. Would love to
know your thoughts. Thanks so much for
watching and we'll talk to you again on
the next video.