are you podcasting yet if not it is a
huge opportunity not just for the sake
of the podcast the podcast content but
all the content you can get out of the
podcast it can be great content for your
website it can be great content for your
email newsletter it can be great content
for social media get the most out of
your podcast so if you're not yet
podcasting we're going to talk about how
to podcast in this episode and we're
going to talk about how you squeeze the
most out of your podcast to get
engagement across all of your digital
platforms so let's dig into this video
and I want to give you some howtos of
squeezing your podcast to get the most
out of it across all
platforms hey there if we haven't met
yet I'm Neil Smith your social media
guide today we're talking about
podcasting and I love podcasting and
whether you have a podcast yet or not
you can have a monologue podcast or a
conversational dialogue podcast it
doesn't matter there are opportunities
for you to squeeze that podcast and get
the most not just out of the fulllength
podcast but out of the clips out of the
newsletter opportunities out of the
website engagement opportunities for SEO
we'll dig into it all so the first thing
you got to think about is how are you
going to capture your podcast and maybe
it's speaking directly to a camera and a
microphone but but the tool that I
highly recommend when it comes to
capturing your podcast and this is what
I do for both monologue podcast and for
conversation interview style podcast and
that's Riverside uh I'm I'm going to
leave a link to all the software
recommendations in the description below
so you can go check that out but yeah
Riverside is one of the best tools out
there because the way it captures high
quality video and high quality audio and
then it has lots of other features to
help you transcribe that podcast to
export that podcast and so if you're
looking for a great way to capture your
podcast and you're not yet using
Riverside I highly recommend it it's a
low cost solution that gives you a high
quality product on the other side so
step one you got to you got to cap your
podcast but you're not squeezing it yet
so we'll get to those steps uh and how
you squeeze it but capture it well and
Riverside is a great way to do that so
the first way that you squeeze the
podcast is in your distribution of that
fulllength podcast and if if you're not
doing video yet I I cannot encourage you
enough to do video because the number
one place that people are consuming
podcast today is YouTube now Alpha
podcast has historically been the go-to
place or podcast and then we saw Spotify
and so many other platforms pop up and
prioritize podcasting especially from an
audio standpoint but I would encourage
you both capture it in video and audio
so that you can get the most out of
YouTube YouTube is the second largest
search engine in the world it's where so
many people are consuming especially
long form content like a podcast so you
want to distribute on YouTube as a
platform if at all possible and so get
set up on a on a podcast hosting
platform with your audio we recommend
Lipson Li IBS YN it's a great solution
that we've been using for years it was
actually existed before even Apple
podcast existed and so it's a great
steady host but there's lots of good
other hosting solutions that are like $5
to $10 a month it's a lowcost need and
then you can create that RSS feed that
can go to the different audio podcast
networks and then you need to set up
your YouTube channel where you can then
distribute your videos in YouTube
packaging is one of the most important
things of you got to create your title
in your description but the thing that's
going to affect how many people watch it
more than anything else is your
thumbnail and so having a a a catchy an
eye-catching thumbnail that's going to
get people when YouTube recommends your
video to hit play is going to be based
on how appealing that thumbnail is to
get them to click and so the tool that I
would recommend to create a high quality
thumbnail for your distribution of your
podcast is canva now canva is is a
popular tool that so many people know
already but one of the things canva has
now created is canva AI which is an
upgrade from a a basic canva account but
it can really help you create those
really compelling high quality
thumbnails now the other opportunity you
have and I i' recommend testing as well
if you don't feel like you're good
enough on canva to create your
thumbnails is just go to fiverr.com and
pay somebody $5 $10 to create thumbnails
for you for your YouTube videos and that
that investment of whether it's your
time with a software like canva or it's
paying somebody five or $1 to create
high quality creative attention grabbing
thumbnails for your videos it's worth
that investment to get more views on
your podcast content so distribute your
content to all the audio networks and
put it on YouTube so the first part of
the squeeze is making sure your
distribution is not just to Apple
podcast but it's also to Spotify it's
also to Stitcher it's also to all those
audio podcast platforms audible is now a
popular place for people to consume
podcast but YouTube with your video side
of the podcast is also a big opportunity
the second place that you want to make
sure you're Distributing and squeezing
the most out of your podcast is your
website you want to post a basically a
place where people can consume both the
video embedding your YouTube video into
your website the audio embedding your
Lipson embed audio player or whatever
podcast platform you you have there and
then have show notes and and have a
transcription of your podcast there on
your website
and what this does is this is actually
all of those words that are then on your
website are searchable by Google and
it's a way to get more traffic to your
website and so by squeezing the most out
of your podcast is Distributing it to
all the podcast platforms but it's also
Distributing it to Google for Google to
then index everything that's on that
podcast and for it to be a new traffic
driver to your website so squeeze your
podcast by Distributing it effectively
and integrating it into your website
typically that's done in basically the
blog format on your website with each
new episode being a blog post that then
is searchable and can engage people
right there on your website a tool that
I highly recommend when it comes to your
website optimization is listener. FM and
I've got a link in the description below
that's an affiliate link so if you want
to support this channel if you want to
click that link it'll just help us in a
little way but listener. FM will
basically take your audio file and then
create your blog post for your website
from your podcast content it will create
the description that you need and
basically kind of all of those output
needs that you have in distributing that
podcast to get that SEO juice so as we
talk about squeezing that podcast Google
search is a big way for people to find
you on the internet and every word you
say in your podcast is now searchable
when you squeeze the most out of that
podcast and have it on your website and
searchable through Google searches and
so part of squeezing it is Distributing
it to YouTube Distributing it your
podcast to all the audio platforms then
also distribute on your website and this
is a great way to get people to your
website to then find other things on
your website as well as well as engaging
with the podcast itself the third part
of the podcast squeeze is your email
newsletter so often I think we feel like
I'm trying to build my email list but
what do I send them I don't want to just
send them a bunch of sales emails well a
great thing to send them is your podcast
it's a great excuse to email your list
on on a regular basis and ideally you're
releasing a new podcast about once a
week that's a great rhythm of sending
people updates of your email newsletter
I actually can go to nil smith.com and
get on my email newsletter and this
video is being sent to my entire email
list and so I release a new video about
once a week and I send them a link to
this video and and so with your podcast
and I have another podcast called social
media church we do the same thing every
week we release a new episode and we
email our newsletter and so we're barely
ever we're sending sales newsletters
we're almost always sending new content
new value to our email list and so your
podcast is a great way to engage that
list and sharing with them another great
free resource that's available to them
is a good value add to your email
newsletter and so using listener. FM
will help you write that email
newsletter but just go ahead and include
that in your email rhythms as a high
value to that list and getting more
traffic to the podcast which then is
going to shoot it up the charts the more
views gets on YouTube YouTube is going
to say this is valuable we're going to
show it to more people the more listens
it gets on Apple podcast Apple podcast
is going to say this more valuable we're
going to recommend it to more people so
as you begin and continue that podcast
squeeze you want to make sure you're
Distributing it well make sure your SEO
is done well on your website and then
you want to make sure that you're taking
the people that already trust you and
have signed up for your email list and
you're letting them know about about
this new content that you've now made
available so part of the squeeze is your
email newsletter now the final part of
the podcast squeeze is probably the most
popular part and maybe even why you
started a podcast to begin with is it's
a great way to create content for social
media people are always like what do I
post on social media well post clips of
your podcast and so out of every podcast
episode it's likely you can get three
four maybe five clips that you can
easily post on TI to and Facebook and
Instagram and Linkedin and all the
different platforms and so whether it's
a video clip whether it's a quote that
you pull out of that podcast squeeze the
most out of it so that you're getting
content for your social media channels
that isn't just sales pushing different
things it's value ad and so maybe in
that 30 second clip something catches
their attention to where they go and
then listen to the whole episode The
Tool I'd recommend using when it comes
to Ai and getting them the squeeze out
of your podcast is mvo m i NV and I got
to link again in the description below
but mvo is a great platform that you can
just put your YouTube video right into
the adino platform and then it will just
automatically generate recommend about
10 different clips for social media
right out of your podcast itself so you
don't have to go through the effort of
finding it it'll then recommend it and
then you can pick and choose and then
edit make kind of micro edits right
there on the podcast clip itself and
then you can use thatc podcast clip to
then link to and promote the full
podcast episode and so that's the
podcast squeeze that's how we want to
take content that we create one time and
then squeeze the most out of it both on
our distribution of our podcast content
on our website for SEO to our email
newsletter and for social media and so
with one piece of content you're able to
get now dozens of pieces of content for
our multiple digital platforms so that's
the podcast squeeze I would love to know
are there other things we can do to
squeeze the most out of podcast also if
you have a podcast go Ahad and Link that
in the comments I'd love to check out
your podcast if this helps at all and if
you want help with your podcast squeeze
it's what we do at amplify social media
we help people that are creating content
get the most out of that content
optimizing it for distribution
amplifying their voice to reach more
people and so if you want help with
these things we'd love to help reach out
to us at amplify social. media thanks so
much for watching we'll talk to you
again on the next episode
[Music]