are you interested in building a
coaching business online but not sure
where to begin in this video I'm going
to look at an interview that my friend
Sean Kel did Donald Miller where he
looks at how you can build a coaching
business online and I'm gonna apply that
to kajabi the software platform that I
love our business in manyways has been
built around so I'm going to look at how
you can take the principles that Don
Miller shares and then the practical
application with kajabi and how you can
combine those two things and build your
business online easily efficiently and
scalably so let's jump into this
[Applause]
video are you interested in building a
coaching business online but not sure
where to begin in this video I'm going
to look at an interview that my friend
Sean kenell did Donald Miller where he
looks at how you can build a coaching
business online and I'm going to apply
that to kajabi the software platform
that I love our business in many ways
has been built around so I'm going to
look at how you could take the
principles the Don Miller shares and
then the practical application with
kajabi and how you can combine those two
things and build your business online
easily efficiently and scalably so let's
jump into this video so in this video it
is an interview I'm going to react a bit
and share insights as to what I've
learned about kajabi building uh various
online coaching businesses for myself
and for many of my clients at amplify
social media uh and then I want to share
practically how you can build your own
business using the software of kajabi
and the principles that Donald Miller
shares he's written lots of books if you
ever read story brand uh this is
actually his most recent book uh coach
Builder uh where he gets very practical
and he's one of my favorite authors
because he is so practical uh and you
can apply uh very very naturally the
things that he teaches to your business
and the problem that you are solving and
so let's get into this video interview
and then I'll jump back in and share my
thoughts along the way and look at how
kajabi can be used to do exactly what
Don Miller is talking about $100,000
plus per year and really eight practical
steps for that my guest today is Donald
Miller author of Coach Builder and other
Classics like building a story brand and
I'm super fired up for this conversation
with Donald how's it going wonderful
yeah thankful to be here um so I just
finished your new book coach Builder and
the big idea here is that when it comes
to starting a YouTube channel a lot of
times people think about ad revenue and
things like that and often times a
full-time career off of Just YouTube ads
might not only be a long ways out it
probably might be never for a lot of
people because you just that you're
getting pennies for your views but so
many people listen to this that are
Educators that are maybe have experience
they don't realize they have that they
could in turn turn into coaching or
something like that so can you give us
the big idea you really help business
coaches in this book but you expand it
out to like what it could be like you
have some experience what's the big idea
and the opportunity when it comes to
coaching the idea is knowledge is worth
something because knowledge helps people
make money save money experience less
frustration you know just recently I I
went through a little Health transition
trying to figure some things out nothing
critical at all but I realized well I'd
love to pay somebody 800 bucks a month
to help me understand you know this MRI
and this and all that kind of stuff we
need a coner medicine coach but they
don't exist and I thought well there you
go we have all these nurses who are
underpaid who could actually be
Moonlighting as coner coaches for five
or six clients and probably double their
salary uh had an experience with my home
you know married with a baby and
realized okay I need a front gate I need
a security system all that kind of stuff
I wish there was a a police officer or
former military who could come to my
house and take me through a checklist on
everything I needed to do to what do I
do with my weapons and you know how do I
keep them safe from the kids and all
those sorts of things so now you have
underpaid police officers and former
military underutilized with their
knowledge professionalizing their wisdom
and productizing it in such a way that
it's helpful to the world that's what
coach Builder is about you know we we
talk a lot about business coaching
because people understand business
coaches but there are so many people who
have wisdom and a lot of them they they
go to YouTube and they start sharing
that wisdom without realizing you can do
this for advertising Revenue that's
really terrific but you can also
actually create a menu of products and
sell them for two three five 10 $15,000
a pop and actually make a lot of money
and now you're YouTube presence is
promoting something that is really good
for the world that's so powerful and I'm
curious how big is the opportunity from
the angle of I think it's a new idea
that people would actually pay for
knowledge right to some like how much
can I charge how much they they may hear
numbers oh that wouldn't work for me but
what's actually what's actually
happening out there it's it's it's not a
new idea in the sense that you know
consulting firms like Accenture and KP
and been making billions and billions
and billions of dollars the New
Evolution is that the average person is
now able to do that just like YouTube I
mean you know it was media was something
when I grew up it was five channels you
actually physically clicked the dial to
get some other frequency uh and now it's
just democratized and so I think wisdom
is also being democratized and I'm and
I'm telling everybody listening get in
on it because people are now very very
much used to it uh you know my wife uh
works with a woman named Nicole Burke
with an organization called gardenary
that she started her vision is to make
gardening ordinary and Nicole came over
helped us with our kitchen Garden helped
us know what the spring planting would
be spend a day with us she makes a
million dollars a year giving gardening
advice she has no degree in gardening
she just discovered it when she started
her own garden she realized she's got an
incredible Green Thumb she had so much
lettuce she had to pass around in the
community and that's a great fruit free
advertising so these ladies said how are
you growing this lettuce teach me and
she's making a million dollars a year
with that knowledge now I so let's just
stop it right there and he is talking
about all these different ways that
knowledge people have and how you can
monetize the knowledge and at the end of
the day it's it's how can you solve
people's problems with what you know and
and this is where I'm you know becoming
more and more pessimistic on College and
things like that of people often ask me
how do I know so much about social media
well I've taken a lot of courses uh that
people are selling online uh Sean canell
who is conducting this interview is a
friend of mine and I've paid uh for a
number of his courses he teaches people
how to use YouTube and so a lot of
people know him because he has millions
of YouTube subscribers and he makes some
money from the ad advertising dollars
that they talk about here but he makes
more money uh from the coaching programs
that he runs uh online and and so he
uses tools and I I believe he and I know
he at one time used kajabi I don't know
if he still is uh but used a platform
like kajabi uh to do that so let's just
take a look at kabi's website together
okay so when you go to kabi's website
it's very clear of go from Creator to
business from digital products to
marketing tools get everything you need
to build a profitable business all in
one place and this is one of the things
I love I I remember years back you know
probably a decade ago I was doing quite
a bit of Consulting around social media
and I thought is there a way to do this
in bulk and I think there's a lot of
people that couldn't afford my
Consulting fees but maybe I could put
this in in a course I could put this in
another platform and the technology was
so complicated uh and that's when I
actually found kajabi and that was early
days of uh kajabi and uh and it became a
place that I could put a website I could
I could create a store where people
could check out and pay online I could
create a a course where I could simply
upload videos and then have those
sessions and uh the platform has grown
and developed and and now a lot of the
platforms I have you they actually have
mobile apps that you can have that
nobody knows it's kajabi behind the
scenes but you have that uh tool uh
behind it and it will do all the
emailing and all the the the tools that
you need so you don't have to buy you
know a MailChimp subscription and a
WordPress website hosting and uh you
know H have all of these different
pieces you have it all in kajabi and so
it takes your knowledge and helps you
package it through your website through
your learning management system and and
through your email Communications all in
this one platform and so just as Donald
Miller is talking about how can you take
your knowledge and monetize it as a
business uh this is where you need a
tool uh to do this and so yeah this is
where I I have found kajabi to be the
best tool I will just you know say this
up front I have an affiliate uh
relationship with kajabi meaning if you
click the link in my description below
uh that takes you to kajabi uh I get a
you know very small percentage of
whatever it is you pay uh for kajabi and
so uh I I'm just a big fan and so I I
have referred a ton of people uh to
kajabi uh because I love it and I think
it's a great tool and uh so many people
have also found it valuable so I want to
be transparent that if you do sign up
after watching this video uh through my
affiliate link it will help uh me in
that way so it's a way I can of help run
my business is by talking about other
software uh like this Beyond just the ad
Revenue I might get from uh this video
being on YouTube and so yeah so going
from Creator to business okay so let's
jump back into the video and do Miller
is going to talk a little bit about why
people need to pay for your business and
how you can begin to productize the
services the knowledge that the
information you have into a coaching
business so let's jump in let's get into
these steps and so Step One is create a
menu of products and services to sell
your clients break this down a little
bit Yeah so if you're if you've got a
job and you want to start coaching and
you're dreaming about that let's start
don't leave your job yet what I want you
to do is actually create a menu of
products of the thing that you can sell
you know for instance let's say you're a
marketing executive somewhere or uh you
know something like that you could
actually sell a one-day marketing
strategy session for $7,500 where you're
going to go into a business and you're
going to help you're going to look at
their ex current marketing strategy and
you're going to improve that you you
want to have that be a deliverable
product I like creating a keynote deck
and a workbook so you're clicking
through the keynote and they're filling
out the workbook as you go along that
would be a product that you could sell
for 7 500 bucks a lot of coaches well
honestly that's cheap 15 $20,000 we sell
them for $20,000 M let me just pause
there because I think probably a lot of
people are listening to this like why
would somebody pay me5
$20,000 for what I know and the answer
might be they won't uh you know Donald
Miller has some things that helps
businesses go from like millions of
dollars to billions of dollars and uh in
certain context obviously you can charge
that much I think Sean's course is like
$100 a month and so there are ranges as
to what you can sell and for how much
you can sell it and a lot of that is
dependent on the value uh that that it's
going to bring uh to the consumer so
don't obsess over the price initially uh
in this step of the process uh focus on
the value uh that you can deliver and
what somebody would pay you whether
that's $5 or whether that's $5,000 uh
focus on what it is that you know and
you can deliver to somebody and add
value to them so just wanted to flag
that for those that might uh be checking
out a little bit or you know a little
cautious of like this is not realistic
for me uh I believe this is realistic
for almost anybody uh in in your various
levels uh and unique expertise is that
you you hold so let's let's jump back
in so you know and also if you create
the keynote deck in the workbook I can
charge $20,000 for somebody else coming
in we have three or four facilitators
who go do that so you know it's just
really smart to create those Frameworks
um but the menu of products what it does
is it gives you confidence that you have
something that you can sell if you are
selling just coaching if you say I'm
quitting my job and I'm going become a
coach would you like to be a client I
can coach you that's like walking into a
restaurant and saying what what are you
known for what are your specials and
they say protein protein is we're really
known for our protein we make really
great protein yeah that is a true
statement but it's unhelpful in terms of
helping me give you money yes if you say
listen I am biased we have the best
cheeseburger in the city of Nashville it
is the best guess what I'm
ordering in the form of a cheeseburger
because I know what that is that I think
is the number one mistake people make
when they get into coaching is they just
sell their coaching and I think that's
fine you can end up selling your
coaching but let's start with a
six-month Mastermind in which we
overhaul your leadership let's start
with a 12-month Elite Mastermind
demographic are only people who make
more than $10 million let's start you
know so you want to actually come up
with something specific that has a start
date an end date a deliverable and a
price and when you have three of those
and you really dial them in and you know
how you're going to deliver them you are
ready to start a coaching business I
still don't recommend leaving your day
job yet because there's another step
step two but you okay I going pause this
again okay so he's talking about you
know basically how to package what to
package uh and where to deliver the
value and I think you know I want to
summarize what he's saying to you
selling outcomes and and so you you want
to give it a what are the deliverables
where what are you going to get uh and a
lot of people will say well you're going
to get 27 videos and you're going to get
three worksheets and you know four
templates or whatever it might be uh but
really what people are buying are the
outcomes what are what are those 27
videos going to lead to is it going to
lead to more sales in your business is
it going to lead to uh a new understand
you're going to become a better Gardener
uh at the end of this and and if you're
a better Gardener it's still vague and
so you will be a better spring Gardener
in you know Northeast uh America or I
you know I don't I don't know what it
might specifically be but get very
specific of who you're helping and what
outcomes uh you're going to help them
get if they take your course if they go
through your coaching program um and and
so think through what outcomes have you
helped other people get in other aspects
of the work you've done the knowledge
that you have uh and I think that's how
you begin to think through productizing
your business would you recommend when
you seven of these four of these 12 of
these also that maybe you have low
medium and high in terms of your menu
too yeah it's always great to have sort
of an entry-level product in fact one of
the steps in the book is to have a
ladder of products and that the the
whole bottom of the ladder is actually
free and I realized I said don't charge
nothing but nothing is actually free
some of them are in exchange for your
email address you're going to get this
PDF and then I'm going to send you these
free n SE email just automated they
don't cost me any time and then I'm
probably going to invite you to a
webinar well by this time I've given you
enough value and there's time plus
contact where we've created a bond a
little bit even if we've never met It's
All Digital uh and now you're willing to
buy my $275 product at which point is
still digital I've not put any skin in
the game but by the time that you and I
are in a room together we're probably at
about five grand yeah and that's really
where my time starts to come into play
I'm giving you Time bottom price is five
grand yeah there's some automated
digital products in there there's some
automated digital lead generators those
sorts of things but you know starting
from zero all the way up to $50,000
would be that ladder of products I think
that's a good Clarity Point okay so he's
now beginning to talk about the ladder
of products and and this is where I
think kajabi uh really comes in and so
as you think about your products some of
those as he mentions are free uh as ways
to get people on your email list not
everyone who gets on your email list
buys everything uh that you sell some
people are going to only go this far uh
in engagement with you as as you kind of
begin to build out that ladder and I
think this is where it's important as
you think about products of what what's
kind of the the minimum uh product that
you can create that can help people and
then what's the maximum if they do all
of this uh H how can this help and I
think about maybe even like a uh a
fitness trainer you know I think
practically play a fitness trainer the
best you you know sell is getting you
know and working out with somebody 3
days a week or five days a week and
you're handson with that individual
helping customize their workouts but the
minimum might be here's a kind of a a
workout sheet and worksheet that you can
use on your own that most people uh can
use and here's a freebie uh and then you
upsell into the you know regular
coaching ongoing uh training that's
one-on-one that's the highest value
that's going to get people the best
outcomes now the worksheet might get
them good outcomes starting out but the
Hands-On coaching you know and uh
training is going to get them the best
outcomes and so as you think about that
value ladder think about what it is that
you can offer people uh that gives them
that those best outcomes and productize
the the tiers of that and and then you
could begin to uh price out what that
looks like let me actually even just
show you in in my website what this
looks like uh as I do a version of this
um within my own website so this is my
website uh that I built on kajabi and
you can see all the stuff here uh but
you can see here the first thing uh that
I do is your social media guide download
the top 10 mistakes leaders make on
social media and somebody clicks this
they give me their name and their email
uh and they can get uh information about
uh you know the top 10 mistakes people
make on social media that will help them
utilize social media but what I know is
that what will help them even more is if
they sign up for Consulting with with me
and then I'll be able to help them and
then what I know actually what will help
them even more is if they hire my social
media marketing agency to do uh the
social media for them uh and so there
are tears as to how uh we can help
people uh and so it starts with kind of
this lower now this is just one PDF
download uh but I do know that this will
help but but the Consulting will help
even more and the Hands-On support will
help the most and so there are tears to
how uh we can support people and this is
all built in Gabi so this email capture
will come in and it will go right into
my system and then I'll have a sequence
of emails the first email will send them
uh access to the PDF uh and then the
next email we'll send them more
information and then ongoing they'll get
other you know have a Weekly Newsletter
that comes out and uh they'll get that
and and they'll find out about the
products and services that I provide and
so uh this is how that lad is built in
kajabi and all of this is uh built in
Gabi the website the email capture and
uh all of the courses uh involved with
it as well
okay let's jump back into the video
point2 because if you say we're going to
put really high valueable free content
on YouTube yes and content that can get
people results in advance start
implementing wow that was helpful in in
one sense this idea of a lead magnet for
email some people call them freebies
premiums YouTube is a step in front of
that or or in a way a similar step it's
and let me give you an example uh I
wrote a book called Hero on a mission
and it's basically the description or
the the step-by-step instructions for a
morning ritual that clears a busy mind
and helps you stay on track and kind of
plan your life we created some software
around that hero on a mission software
where you can go in and and spend 15
minutes on a daily ritual uh you know
you fill out some questions what am I
grateful for you look at your calendar
of events my primary tasks those sorts
of things and we put the book out you
know it gets us 15 people a day signing
up for the software we did a YouTube
video and it gets us a hundred people a
day signing up for the software so
that's more powerful than a book and the
book was a bestseller you know so yes
YouTube is a great strategy to lead
people to your lead generator which
captures their email address and so
forth and so and then let's go ahead and
monetize that the software is free
nobody has to pay for it but we would
actually email you and say would you
like to spend 275 bucks and watch the on
demand course well first we're going to
say you want to buy the book you like 20
bucks then the on demand course versus
$275 would you like to hire a coach to
spend a year taking you through this
system well that Coach pay me $10,000 to
be certified to be that coach so you can
see how the monetization of the YouTube
video can work in ways that are just
beyond advertising and it requires you
scaling up a little bit of a coaching
business step two generate and manage a
list of potential clients yes who are
you going to sell your products to and a
lot of people start with clients and I
would say start with products s because
until you know what products you're
going to sell you don't know who you're
going to sell them to so basically what
you want to do is you want to take a
list of the problems that your products
solve and then make another list of the
potential people who you know who could
actually use the solution to that
problem and then write an email and send
it to them and sell them that that's
before you even get into a CRM then once
I get into a CRM I want a lead generator
that's providing emails to that CRM and
automating the division of those three
products and the three things that I'm
going to sell people but most coaches
for instance a guy I know named Chad who
actually helps run my company the reason
Chad is with my company is he sent an
email he left uh another not competitor
a friend of mine who does something
similar left their business sent out one
email to a small list of contacts that
he had that said uh here's what I did
for Mike and here's what I can do in the
marketplace I'm going to be doing some
Consulting and hire me if you want want
teach you kind of what we did over here
I hired him immediately paid him a lot
of money enjoyed the relationship so
much that I bought him out of his own
consulting firm and he gets an enormous
amount of money being on my leadership
team now from one email but but let me
tell you what he did in that email he
described the problems that he solved at
his previous company and said if you
have those problems I can help you solve
them that's the and by the way in the
book there's formulas for writing emails
and we have now put inside of a a a
server artif icial intelligence inform
formed by story brand that will help you
write that sales letter so you know
there's just so many ways to to do it uh
but you need a menu of products and then
you need a list of people that you can
sell those products to and ultimately if
you really want to grow a coaching firm
you need a CRM managing leads selling
those products so pausing uh here
quickly on the video uh as we talk about
a CRM is something that people don't
know it's Us customer relationship
manager and this is essentially what you
need of when you have leads for your
business and for your coaching business
and just like I I'm capturing those
email addresses those are leads email
gives me a direct way to communicate
with people now I'm I'm a social media
guy uh you know so if you watch any
other my other videos I'm always talking
about social media social media is an
opport opportunity to drive you know
brand awareness and uh connection uh but
at the end of the day I'm always looking
to drive people from my social media to
my website to get on my email list uh
that's part of the engagement pathway uh
that I'm taking people to so we need uh
this CRM uh typically you know starting
out it might just be your Gmail account
uh you know your basic email account uh
but but as you grow and expand you're
going to need a CRM and this is one of
the things I love about kajabi so let me
show you in kajabi as I capture those
email addresses where they go and what I
do with them so we're in the back end of
my kajabi account with my website you
can and please ignore the negative2
$2,997 in sales you look like is he
really a good coach uh I was running a
program uh I had somebody that had to
drop out from a past program uh and I
reimbursed them here so got nothing live
happening right now but you can see here
in the last 30 days eight people have
signed up for uh you know Google or
social media has driven them my website
and they've gotten on my email list and
and this is everything this is the back
end of kajabi so you have your products
as he's talking about and in here you
can have a whole list of products and uh
in mine I have this church YouTube Lab I
have social media for parents uh
LinkedIn influencer academy uh so I've
got a few different just courses or
programs uh that that I run uh within
kabi and these are all of your products
uh that you would create um and then you
have you know getting into the people
you would Market to you have contexts
and and this is your CRM um and so we're
gonna have to if any names pop up block
out any names I'm GNA actually reverse
before it gets into that uh but but all
of that lives here in that context and
so uh what what essentially happens is
it builds a CRM for you and it it will
let you know who uh the people are that
are in your CRM uh and uh and and then
you can basically get their contact
information communicate with them um and
where you then communicate with them is
through this marketing channel so you
have these email campaigns these funnels
these uh where you can sit up when
somebody signs up for that PDF from my
homepage I'm able to send them a
sequence of emails or if I'm running you
know a program um or a new course that
I'm launching I'm going to set up a
sequence or if if I'm just sending out
my weekly email I go into email
campaigns and you can see here uh this
is from my most recent uh email that I
sent out and so I just create just like
I would in like MailChimp or Constant
Contact uh and I can email everyone
that's here on my list to join that
program so this is exactly what Donald
Miller's talking about of you start with
the products and then you move to the
people uh that that are going to buy
your products and and this is how kajabi
can manage all of this for you and in
many ways once you get it set up uh you
can kind of forget about it it's
functions Automation and you can really
focus on how do you drive more people to
get into that funnel uh of Engagement so
let's jump back into the video uh how uh
this continues to progress uh in this
structure okay let's jump back into the
video and continue on with this process
so we've got uh you develop products and
then people and now let's see what's
next a pull and saying well I'm not
swimming let because you're not in the
pool yes you will swim really fast
especially if you're in the deep end so
I encourage you to jump in and start
coaching but also to tell people that I
now coach people through X and you're
gonna have to kind of memorize a line
because it's not going to feel true even
though it is true you are actually
coaching somebody so I wouldn't be too
self-deprecating about I think that's
going to cost you in your career but you
want to jump in and and begin to your
action will follow I mean your your
identity will follow action we've got to
get in there and start coaching call
ourselves a coach put together a
coaching website begin promoting
yourself in 12 months you're not going
to have that problem anymore so strong
and step three is create a compelling
website that attracts your ideal clients
and in this chapter you do touch on your
sales pitch or your elevator pitch which
you kind of just mentioned like maybe
that's a I solve x problem or what is
that yeah well let's go through we can
go through all the parts of a website
but I just want to give you the part
that needs to be at the top yeah and the
part that needs to be at the top is uh
identify the problem that you solve as a
coach and position your Co coaching
product as the resolution of that
problem you know for instance you would
say uh a lot of people dream of being a
really good uh cook um I leverage my 10
years of experience in uh you know fine
dining kitchens to teach you how to cook
six amazing dishes of your choice I'm in
I mean I literally I just made that up
and I'm like where is that person I will
pay the money now now now imagine that's
$2,500 and you get six different
interactions where and you know you're
going to videotape that interaction and
put it on YouTube well I just videotaped
me with a client who's paying me 2500
bucks with their POS permission putting
it on YouTube you know how many clients
are going to be wanting the same
experience yeah I literally just started
a a a business chefs don't make any
money you know my friend Annie little
ran Josephine here in Nashville and they
you know sadly the neighborhood that he
was in became very very popular and they
tripled his rent he had to shut down his
restaurant jez and he's getting older
and he doesn't want to work in a kitchen
anymore it's a it's a it's a young man's
game it's a young woman's game I
literally just Andy if you're watching
this is you could do this and you could
do it you could work four months out of
the year and make three times what you
made as a chef leveraging your
experience I will but what's the key the
key isn't I will teach you how to cook a
lot of people will teach you how to cook
I will teach you to make six meals that
blow people's minds so you always have a
go-to and we'll do it in six sessions
and you know what when we're done we're
going to eat it yeah that's the best
part by the way Andy I'll show up for
that and work the camera as long I I
just want to highlight this real Qui
that is so good like do you hear that
value proposition of this is very
specifically the outcome uh that you're
going to get uh if you hire me as your
coach and so as you're continuing to
process what is it that I'm telling how
do I uniquely position myself uh that
specific example around cooking and
you're going to at the end of this
coaching have six unbelievable meals
that you could prepare when people come
over uh that that's a very tangible
practical real outcome that people can
get if they hire you uh and so think
about those things and how you
communicate uh your things then we're
we're going to dig into the website side
of things here more and uh it it'll make
more sense as long as I get a bite man I
love that that's amazing okay so you uh
you want to create a website and we'll
keep it moving and of course you break
down all the step-by-step of the that
top is the problem you solve and the
products that you sell to solve it
problem you solve and okay so let's get
into the website uh more more
specifically and how you do that in
kajabi uh and so let me go back to my
website uh and so you can see here my
website and on the website I I I put
your social media guide and and so what
I'm trying to communicate now I'm
actually even as I'm hearing that I'm
like I could probably better position uh
myself of your the problem that I solve
uh but and because the problem I solve
is I help leaders understand and utilize
social media to accomplish their goals
uh and and my business is called amplify
social media and we help amplify
people's voices through uh social media
um that's the problem we solve where a
lot of people are I just don't know how
to do this social I know I need to do
social media I just don't know how I
don't know where where to invest my
resources and then I go on to here's a
link to my book so first thing is you
know get on the get the free pdf then
it's buy my $10 book on Amazon uh now
I'm getting into practically what I do
Consulting speaking execution uh even as
I think about those tiers of uh what I
provide and then here's the podcast that
I'm on here's what some other people are
saying uh some clients uh that I've
worked with and and another opportunity
to get on my email list and then I have
other Pages here so all of this built on
kajabi so let me show you how I do that
in kajabi uh so back into kajabi as you
have these different features uh one of
those is website and So within the
website you can go in and uh design your
website and I'll show you very tangibly
how this works so I'm going to go to my
landing pages here um which are the
various pages on my site and if I just
go to let me just go to my homepage uh
and if I go here and then I click on
customize uh what you'll see is uh I I'm
now in my website and I can easily
update uh my website now it is not going
to work right now while we're doing this
let's
see hopefully it'll work
now hey there it is okay so let's start
that over okay so now I'm in my website
in kajabi backend and so I can update
all aspects of my website and so you
could see the various layouts and
navigation and um you know aspects here
and and because my website is custom
coded uh it's it's a little bit more
complex than a lot of other sites on
kajabi but I could just easily go in
here and just hit edit uh and then I go
over here to the right hand side I can
edit uh the copy on the web page or what
it links to and uh all all the
information in there um within that post
or area or I can go into this this one
and I can just update uh this this space
uh if I want to um and it will just edit
it over there uh I don't really want
that to happen so I'm going to go back
um and so yeah it's it's very simple to
just simply build out uh and it has all
of these different boxes you can just
add content you can add custom code you
can add a blog or you can add audio
podcast or call to action button um and
so it's very similar like a Squarespace
if you use Squarespace or Wix um and it
has kind of this layout and feature and
it will automatically adapt to uh the
platform you're on so your website can
be easily built uh in kajabi using all
of the tools that they have uh and this
platform and so it is this allinone uh
online Builder uh for your business uh
and so it's one of the things that I
love is that I you know previously had
all of these other moving parts and now
everything uh for me is right here
within kajabi so let's keep going uh
with the video all in products you sell
to Sol make sure your website says that
and so then step four Once you have that
set up WR Auto at sales emails that land
clients while you sleep and eventually
that can be your CRM is what's sending
those automated emails and as a reminder
we uh have a couple email-based um tips
on email marketing on the think media
podcast and we'll link other show notes
and resources as well as coach Builder I
hope by now you can see it's an
essential book to grab I just finished
it absolutely love we actually have
emails in that book that you can cut and
paste and then I've written 52 two
emails that any coach can use to
convince people that you're a coach also
use that's so Priceless in more than you
know $2 or whatever the book is on
Amazon so um but what are the biggest
mistakes people make when writing emails
and following up well the biggest
mistake is they don't do it yeah so that
that's the that's by far that's 95% of
it yeah I remember when I was a young
publisher I I accidentally Forest gumed
my way into the president of a
publishing company in my 20s and I would
this is pre it wasn't pre- email but
people didn't do email marketing we were
actually sending snail mail and the
company became the fastest growing
publishing company in our sector and the
boss the the sort of absentee owner came
in and just said how how are you doing
this what are you doing and I said well
I'm taking the 20% of our clients who
are giving us 80% of our revenue and I'm
just writing them a letter every every
week and it's you know going to their
desk and he said Don the last letter you
wrote was literally was about you going
camping it had nothing to do with
publishing I said oh I know that's
because nobody's reading them all
they're doing is they're seeing our logo
and they're putting it in the trash can
and he said how in the world is that
grow in the company he said because
they're not forgetting us you've got to
send something out week after week after
week with your name or your your logo
the name of your company the name of
your brand I get text messages once a
day from Hanks belts Hanks belts by the
way I'm not sponsored by Hank belts
although send me a free I'm doing you
some promo here uh you know I I bought a
belt for my father-in-law for Christmas
and great belts and they started texting
me all the time yeah well I don't need a
belt you buy one Bel I've got five belts
and then I realized you know what I
actually don't have a black dress belt
and so I bought a black dress belt and
then I realized well I could actually
get this other guy belt this is kind of
a cool belt I got another belt as a gift
then they're having a 40% off sale on
belts I don't need that that' be a great
email 40% off on a belt you don't need
will sell by the way that's free yeah uh
and I ended up looking around I'm like I
don't need this spell but I really 40%
off only me 100 bucks 60 bucks you know
they got another I know $400 or $500 out
of me because they reminded me they
exist and the reality is people will
forget that you don't exist they will
forget that you exist if you don't
remind them and so that's the importance
of getting those emails out the actual
email copy is not as important as you
think uh it's the hey I exist hey I
exist hey I exist people don't buy from
you when you email them they buy from
you when they have the problem that your
email offers a solution to and the
reality is for 6 months out of the year
they don't have that problem and one
week after 6 months they do and if you
don't send them an email in that window
you're not going to sell anything so
it's a percentage game and you want to
be in touch with people all the time so
strong
and one of the experiences I've had with
another kajabi uh site that that we help
to manage uh and and this is you know
one of the things I think Donal Miller
speaks to here is done is better than
perfect which is an old Facebook uh
slogan that that's commonly used uh that
that sometimes we we want to refine and
perfect this whole email engagement
series and conversion series and uh all
of these and and the best email is one
that is actually sent and a lot of
people are building an email list but
they're not actually emailing those
people on their email list uh and so
your emails are not going to be perfect
and I think the key is to continue to
make them better and so one of the the
clients uh that that we have that we run
uh through kajabi is they do a 7-Day
trial uh for new members to their
Community uh and in that 7-Day free
trial uh they basically have a an email
sequence of five emails that they send
in those seven days uh with the idea of
really demonstrating and showing them
all the value they can get when they
engage as a monthly subscriber and
recently they updated
those five emails and and spent about
two hours refining that email copy and
they've seen their conversion rates go
from about 60% uh that stay on to about
75% um just by getting a little bit
better now at the end of the day if they
hadn't done them at all it wouldn't have
been 60% it probably would have been
more like 30 or 40% um of people that
would stay on and so the the 60% was
good but the 75% is better uh and and
the reality is we'll probably go back
next quarter and refine them again and
hopefully will go from 75% to 80% now I
don't think we'll ever be at 100% um but
but even what we're at every point of
our funnel uh I think one of the things
that you want to look at in your
coaching business and as you use kajabi
uh is how do you use these automations
so that you're not having to manually
email people every time uh but you
utilize the automations in a platform
like kajabi uh so that that you can
really do the coaching business and
marketing of your coaching business at
scale uh and and I think it's one of the
great things that technology provides us
today one of the things that I love
about kajabi so let's let's keep going
and we're getting closer to the end here
I I hope you're finding a lot of value
uh in this um as I gain so much Valu as
I watched this video and wanted to share
with you and talk about how uh kajabi
applies so directly to uh this this for
format that that is working for so many
leaders out there and so many coaches
and uh I think about all the text
messages that I get reef
sandals you don't unsubscribe I don't
unsubscribe and I'm paying attention and
then when the sale hits that always gets
my attention I'll look over and I get
sandals I don't need or your flip-flop
falls apart and now you need it and they
text you right then it's Fourth of July
is coming out that's the artificial
intelligence we need when the flip-flop
falls apart email Sean yes um so step
five is create a marketing funnel and a
product ladder we talked about that a
little earlier yeah so just to find at a
high level before step six what is
though a marketing funnel if you were
kitchen table talk talking to a family
member like what a marketing funnel
relationships work in three phases all
relationships romantic relationships
friendships relationships with Brands
relationships with politicians they all
work in three phases curiosity
Enlightenment commitment and they go in
that order and you can't get the order
wrong curiosity is when there's
something about you as a thought leader
as a person as an individual that I
sense could help me
survive so Sean knows a lot about
YouTube I really want to crack this nut
there you go I'm now interested in Shawn
Sean you're a great guy you're an
amazing person they're not interested in
you they interested in the wisdom that
you have that can help them survive and
so that's one of the reasons we want to
lead with that now that I think Sean
might have something that can help me
survive on YouTube I'm not going to buy
anything from him what I'm actually
going to do is see if he's trustworthy
see if my susp is true so I'm going to
watch some YouTube videos I might
download a lead generator I might and
when I download a lead generator by the
way I'm getting emails maybe every week
from you that is continuing to enlighten
me about how you could help me survive
what it looks like what it cost I'm
doing the I'm in the due diligence phase
without even knowing it uh and then you
enter into the commitment window and the
commitment window is when the problem
that Sean solves overlaps with him
asking asking me to buy something to
solve it and so we have always got to be
doing three things peing people's
curiosity enlightening them and asking
for the money we always have to be doing
those three things because we just don't
know where our customers are and we're
doing some Mass advertising well in
order to do that you create a marketing
funnel you create lead generators that
capture the email something about your
lead generator pequ my curiosity so I
downloaded it you began to enlighten me
and at the bottom of the Enlightenment
you said PS by the way we're running a
30% sale on this and we'd love to have
you so you're always I say you're always
saying will you go out with me and will
you marry me at the same time how I got
married I I kept I just kept asking my
wife to marry me finally she goes okay
you're sad case we I gota I gotta give
you this so you know there's a you're
dating in order to get to know somebody
and you're you're asking for you know
their hand in marriage it's it's it's
all relational everything's relational I
say that as an analogy because um my
wife sat me down after we've been dating
for about 3 or 4 months and I was listen
I'm ready to get married you're the I
wanted to marry you two years before we
ever started dating you know this is I'm
done and she said Don you know what
you're a quality time guy I thought she
was being nice she was actually
correcting me I said what do you mean
she said well you you just know what you
want very quickly it doesn't take you
very long you always make fast decisions
she said I want you to understand I'm a
quantity time girl meaning it's going to
take you a minute later years later I
thought that was just a funny anecdote
in our marriage but later I was looking
at data from my business and I realized
that 85% of our orders were coming a
year after somebody gave me their email
address and I realized oh these are
quantity time buyers 85% of buyers are
quantity time meaning if you're not
emailing me every week for a year you're
going to lose the order wow that's a
profound Insight this is a master class
and I'm uh really appreciating you
breaking this down and before to just
want to you know reemphasize how
important this is and that building a
coaching business isn't going to happen
overnight I think a lot of people think
and I love Donald Miller said early on
in the interview don't quit your job yet
um you got to build a lot of these
things uh and then you got to capture
those email addresses and drive traffic
to your website and then you got to
email them month you know weekly or
monthly and consistently and build that
trust before uh they're going to sign up
for your coaching program and you've got
to have a lot of people in that funnel
uh going through that funnel and and so
this this is not a process that happens
overnight uh this is a business that you
build over time uh but and and one of
the things that's been fun for me is
watching Sean uh Sean's been a friend uh
for many years before he even started
this business and back when he was a
pastor and I remember uh when he was
starting out and he was you know really
getting his YouTube channel uh was
starting to pick up traction but his
business was still kind of you know the
amount of money he was putting into it
was about equal to what he was making
and and it was just you know just trying
to get it off the ground um and then but
then it was like oh because he had been
building this though so intentionally
then it began to really build momentum
and now he's really built an incredible
business at scale that I'm assuming is
doing seven eight figures um because of
what he has built because of these
systems and processes that Donald Miller
is talking about uh I've seen Shawn
apply directly in Donald Miller too with
you know his his story brand and and all
that he's built there and so it it
really this this proves true but it's
also something that isn't you know
you're not going to get a viral video
and all of a sudden have a massive
coaching business there is a a process
and a and a and a building uh process
and a trust building uh that's needed
and so uh you got to do some of this
hard work but it is worth it uh as you
build it and build it for the long
haul go to step six you also say build a
product ladder and we touched on that
the product ladder might be a way to
engage free lower ticket yeah half of
your half of the things you create are
actually free but they're they're also
not demanding your time yeah so it and
and when I say free they're giving you
their email address which I put the
economic value of an email address at
about $35 in other words the
psychological money that I'm giving you
when I give you my email address is
$35 I will part with my email address
about as willingly as I'll part with $35
so let's not think that this isn't a
sacrifice on the part of our customer
yeah yeah absolutely and then it can go
up and if they're getting your time that
could be higher ticket which brings us
to step six set realistic business goals
and accomplish them what types of goals
should we set and how do we know if
they're realistic yeah I give you
several categories of goals to set for
your coaching business in the book but
let me give you two that are really
important the first is the most
important and that is lag measure or
lead measure goals lead measure goals
are how many people downloaded my free
PDF F how many people watched my YouTube
videos or better how many YouTube videos
did I create quality YouTube videos did
I create if I want to build a coaching
business I'm just going to let the money
take care of itself what I'm actually
going to measure are the the number of
lunches that I have with potential
clients um the number of email
Acquisitions that I get the number of
emails that I've written to put into my
CRM those are the goals that I'm going
to establish in order to get my business
started the money will take care of it
self if you do things that lead to
orders you'll get orders later don't
worry about the orders it's just it's
kind of like everything else in life if
you want to lose weight don't set a goal
to lose weight set a goal to get up
every morning and go for and get 10,000
steps right and and also set a go to eat
less than 2200 calories if you just do
that the weight will take care of itself
uh I think it was Brian Walsh who wrote
a book after winning so many super bowls
with the San Francisco 49ers the score
takes care of itself never think about
the score think about the process it
takes to win then set goals within that
process and you're going to be just fine
Step seven build okay so I want to pause
there and and as you're getting started
uh I I think it kind of kind of goes
back to the beginning of productize and
and think about those products but then
begin working on especially that that
first free product that first thing that
you're going to create to get people on
your email list and so the first thing
you need to look at is what are you
going to create uh that that's a value
ad uh that that somebody can download
and you know Donna Miller saying for him
it's $35 of value to get them on your
email list so don't jump right to the
sale jump right to getting people on
your email list and then begin emailing
them weekly those are your lead uh
targets to focus on and then the lag
targets is once you got a th000 people
once you have 10,000 people on that
email list uh then you can really really
begin to focus on the conver versions
and more of that automations and those
sequences and so don't get ahead of
yourself and don't be overwhelmed by the
whole funnel uh at the beginning focus
on building that email list driving
traffic to your website uh and getting
people onto the email list and then
nurturing them by adding value through
every email that you send build or join
a community to help you grow yourself
and your business yeah there are eight
steps to build a coaching business being
in a community of other coaches is a
greater predictor of success than
whether or not you have a CRM a website
a menu of products a product ladder all
of that is secondary to being in a
community of other coaches but here's
why because if you're in a community of
other coaches you're going to build a
CRM of products all of that's going to
happen uh but it's going to happen
because we tend to behave like the tribe
that we are hanging out with it is the
number one predictor of success so if
you can find and all you need to do is
find other people in your area who are
coaching and buy them breakfast once a
month
you know I remember you know Brendan
brashard yeah Brendan used to live in
Portland Oregon and Brendan had a um a
condo that he didn't live in it was a
condo that he furnished that he used
maybe once a week he would he would get
a group of guys together for breakfast
in the morning he would pay for
breakfast then we would go up into his
condo and he would just say what' you
learn this week and he created a master
rind it was all free we were all
learning an incredible amount but it was
actually Genius of him to create a
community of content creators was 25
years ago you know how he's I mean I
don't know he's got got to be worth tens
or hundreds of millions of dollars and
he was he put together a community um I
was amazed in re I I want to pause again
there and Brendan bashard is is somebody
that if you're not familiar with him uh
he's actually one of the top kajabi
sellers uh out there on the platform and
so you know one of the things that I
have found uh for myself and for other
content or or course creators or
coaching uh community Builders uh is
people that are successful that selling
courses buy courses they experience
courses and they're learning from those
courses and so go and find courses that
you can buy and learn from and how they
sold to you uh how they added value to
you and why you trusted them and some of
those are going to be good some of those
are not going to be so good uh I would
say Brena brashard is actually probably
a great person to go and check out his
course see what he's selling uh do the
same thing with Donald Miller you know
if you're interested in getting more on
YouTube uh go look at what think media
is doing with Sean canel and uh and I
think you'll find uh by taking other
people's courses you'll gain a lot of
value from those courses or gain a lot
of value from being a part of those
other communities I'm a part of a
mastermind group that's been so valuable
to me as they speak into my business but
they also share from what they're
learning and their businesses and the
insights I gain from that uh so get
connected to other people that are
looking to do the same thing as you and
maybe uh somebody that's maybe already
done uh something that you want to do uh
get to know them and you know I think
I've spent probably close to a quarter
million dollars now in coaching uh and
courses that have helped me build uh my
business and helped me build other
people's businesses through what I learn
uh from those coaching communities and
from those courses so uh make sure
you're being a learner and not just
watching free videos on YouTube uh
because often the best even
accountability uh is when you put skin
in the game uh and buy that course and
consume that content and and apply it to
your business in researching that
chapter that it always struck me as odd
because I've been a big fan of
psychology that so many you know fathers
and mothers of modern psychology came
out of Vienna in the 20s through the 50s
so they were all in Vienna 20s to 50s
and like an idiot I thought oh well that
must be there must been something in the
water those were the smartest
psychologist that's not true there were
smart psychologists in in Australia
there were smart psychologists in the
United States of course smart
psychologist in South Africa what what
made Austria different was two things
the university system and the coffee
shops they were meeting with each other
and they were threatened by each other
they competed with each other they
learned from each other they disagree
with each other right Alfred Adler is
gonna disagree with Sigman Freud uh I I
I don't think I'm mistaken say my
favorite psychologist Victor Frankle
spent a day with Sigman Freud uh and you
know Sigman Freud launches this thing
and Adler completely disagrees and
Franco says it's not pleasure it's
meaning and you know and all of a sudden
there's a midrash taking place that
launches the the fathers of modern
psychology think about this uh in tennis
I'm a big tennis fan Rafael Nadal Roger
feder and Novak jokovic are the top
three winningest tennis players in on
the male Circuit of all time they
actually accomplished but by the way
like Pete SAS has won like nine grand
slams then it's 20 for Federer I believe
21 or something like that for I'm going
to butcher this for Nadal and then Novak
I believe is right now at 23 or 24 and I
hope he gets one more because then he
passes Margaret Court as the greatest
tennis player of all time Undisputed and
I like Novak um they all did it at the
same time I think now think about that
the scarcity of the actual Grand Slams
available while they're doing it at the
same time so Pete won it with no
competition the greatest players of all
time the three of them are playing at
the in the exact same season competing
at the exact same tournaments wow but I
think you removed two of those and the
number one players probably got 10
because it was the competition that
forced those three guys say winning is
scarce right now a grand slam Victory is
scarce because those two powerhouses are
trying to take it from me and they all
upped their game if you want to be a
seven fig business coach get in a room
every week with somebody else who's
competing with you and you're going to
do just fine you're going to feel you're
going to lose sleep over that and
hopefully it's a those guys all love
each other massive respect and I feel
the same way about Michael Hyatt and
Dave Ramsey and Patrick lyion and yeah
John Gordon and Henry Cloud I have
dinner with these guys I'd love to have
dinner with Patrick I haven't met
Patrick yet yeah but we sit and we we
talk about what we're doing and what
we're sharing and what we're writing and
all that kind of stuff and I leave
dinner with Henry Cloud first of all I
think Henry cloud is a savant I will
never be as intelligent as Henry cloud
but I leave so inspired in wanting to do
more and wanting to write better so it's
the community I think is the greatest
predictor of success it's such a strong
point and as we land the plane and I
have one of my favorite chapters
actually came after the eight steps but
step eight is then navigate the nuances
of the client coach relationship and you
say master the soft skills of client
coaching break this town listen the
Frameworks that we teach the CRM that
you use the lead generators
that those are very helpful to you to
build a coaching business and some of
those are helpful to get your client
results their life will be changed by a
human being and I think this is the part
that in the book that the coaches
probably need the least because they're
actually good at it it's why they're in
it they want to change lives I want to
be the guide that helps the hero win I'm
I'm leveraging that transition in my
life to do that uh but I wanted to put
it in the book to be able to say don't
leave your heart behind uh at the end of
the day your economic objectives are not
going to be fulfilling even if you hit
them uh you're not going to you know on
your dying breath you're not going to
say if only I would have charged
more what you are going to say is if
only I would have been a better listener
if only I would have been more
compassionate toward the people that I
work with if only I would have
empathized more if only gosh if I would
have said such and such they might not
have made that critical mistake and I
should have called them and so I didn't
I wanted to end the book on that note
okay so that those are the eight steps
that Donald Miller lays out uh to build
a successful coaching business and I
cannot agree more and I think one of
things that really stands out here in
these eight steps is basically seven of
them are around marketing uh your course
so often we get so focused on the
product or the service that we deliver
and and we end up having no one uh to
coach and so we've got to really focus
in on how we Market our course but we
cannot do that at the expense of not
delivering high value uh and so at the
end of the day what I have found uh time
and time again with the coaches that I
work with and the businesses that that
we helped support is that the more they
coach the better they get uh the clearer
their Frameworks get the the better the
results are for their clients and you
wouldn't likely get into this if you
didn't already care if you didn't
already even see some success uh in what
you've done uh and and have that
confidence and what you're going to
deliver but don't work so hard on the
marketing and and not at the end of the
day deliver uh the end results that your
customers are looking for because at the
end of the day the best marketing you're
going to do is from those those core
people that have gone through your
Consulting and they're going to tell
other people about what you do where
they learned it uh and how they can get
the same coaching from you and so you've
got to deliver and good coaching often
comes from good list listening uh and
and I I don't want to get into in this
video how uh you you do all of the
coaching I think you probably understand
that better than I could tell you uh but
but but that's you know practically on
the technology side that's the easy part
and you know uh so kajabi makes it
really easy they have a lot of different
platforms and functions I really like
their Community uh feature and function
which almost functions like a Facebook
group with zoom integrated into it uh I
think it's a great platform for uh
coaching
uh to happen in a community setup or you
can just simply use zoom use kajabi for
all of your marketing and then use zoom
or Google meet for all of your calls uh
there there are lots of ways to deliver
uh the coaching um and support on that
end uh or just a a course with
pre-recorded videos uh and so there's
lots of ways to deliver the value uh but
practically I think we've got to really
refine our marketing we've got to really
refine our audience uh and how we're
going to build trust and convert them to
being a customer of our coaching
business and so it's it's a really
exciting day uh where we can take our
knowledge and share that with others or
we can go and gain knowledge from almost
anybody on anything uh and and coaching
uh building a coaching business is such
a great way to do this so I've Loved uh
this book from Don Miller I've Loved uh
just watching other coaches and learning
and what I want to wrap up this video
with is if you are thinking about
getting into coaching I don't have a
course for that I think these guys
probably have uh better better coaching
and I I'll leave links uh in the bio to
or in the description to their websites
and into uh Donald Miller's book uh but
but really what what I want to offer to
you is if you are ready to launch a a
coaching business and you have uh kind
of these products but you're like I'm so
overwhelmed by the technology that's
where uh we can help uh so my team at
amplify social media and we'll have a
link uh Down Below in the description uh
is is here and ready to help you we can
help you run your social media we can
help you set up your uh kajabi website
we can help you set up your kajabi
course products so that you can focus on
both the content you create in that
product ladder uh and the community that
you build uh to serve and support
through your coaching business uh and it
can all be done for you and so that's
what we do as a business to help you so
if that's something you're interested in
reach out to our team schedule a call uh
and we'd love to talk through your
business and how we can help you accompl
your goals thanks so much for watching
and I look forward to connecting further
on other videos uh and if you are
interested in kajabi and you want to do
it yourself uh I hope you'll click the
link uh Below in the description uh and
sign up for kajabi and get to know it
test it out uh I think you'll be overly
impressed I think it's the best thing on
the market TurnKey easy to use uh great
platform and scalable and people are
building businesses they're making you
know a couple hundred bucks a month and
people are building businesses they're
making a couple million a month on the
platform and so I I think it's a great
Tool uh for wherever your business might
be uh to grow and to scale and to build
onto for the future thanks so much for
watching we'll talk to you again on the
next video
[Music]
he