have you ever felt like just a
traditional email sent to somebody is
just too impersonal too cold and what
you really want to communicate and the
excitement that you have about the
message that you're communicating and a
video or voice message might be better
but you're sending this via email well
this is a platform that might be perfect
for you that I've been using for over a
year now and I'm a big fan of how it
works and I'm going to show you this
platform and how it might step up your
LinkedIn cold Outreach strategy or just
your regular emails that you're sending
to people making it very easy to send
video emails to your friends your
contacts or anyone that you want to
reach out to
online hey if we haven't met yet I'm
Neil Smith your social media guide and
today we're talking about email so we're
stepping a little bit outside of social
media but this is actually a tool that's
used quite a bit for LinkedIn or other
platforms so you can use it outside but
it's primarily used for email and a lot
of people use it for cold Outreach but
there's a lot of different uses I'm
using it regularly for just emails that
I'm sending where I wanted to be a more
personalized email and honestly I find
it to be a lot faster just like voice
memos have become a big part of how we
text message and communicate via SMS
this is a great way to communicate in
that personalized way in an even more
personal way with video in addition to
audio through email so let's take a look
at
sspark okay before I jump into the back
end of the platform I just want to show
you how they talk about their software
and what it does and how it works so s
spark here is a cord once personalized
with AI and so just like every other
software platform today theyve got to
incorporate AI into their platform and
this is boost your Outreach schedule
more meetings and increase uh Revenue
with the number one video platform uh
and essentially what this is if you've
ever used a platform like Loom it's a
way that you can create basically a
screen capture video you can show a
slide deck in the background or you can
literally just make it a video that's
what I primarily do is I just make it a
regular full video and then it sends in
an email and what it essentially does is
it creates a gif I call it a gif you
might call it a gif but it sends a gif
to whoever is viewing it and then they
can just click play on that email and
then watch the video right there and so
you can see here they talk about you
know 50,000 companies are using this get
your own personalized video number one
video sellling platform so video video
video that's what this platform is all
about you can import even a list of CSV
files where you can just input a bunch
of emails and send it out through their
platform you can personalize those
emails and you can use it in a lot of
different ways but what they're really
saying is basically more people pay
attention because it's different than
the typical emails that you're getting
and so yeah that's basically what it is
is it's a pretty simple platform and you
you'll see that in the back end as I
show that to you and then if we get into
pricing there's a lot of different
options here so a lot of companies will
buy a plan for their whole company to
use it especially if you have a sales
team it's a great tool to use but I
think this is good for I I can see it
for fundraisers if you're running in a
nonprofit and you want to send a
personalized message to a donor great
platform to do this but most people are
probably just going to use the solo plan
so whether you're a small business owner
or you know just running your own system
here you might want to start with this
solo plan and see how it works or you
can move to a team plan or scale plan
there's lots of different options here
depending on the size team that you have
and uh they have kind of here these
monthly and annual price points and so
you're going to start at about 50 bucks
a month and if it does what it says it's
going to do it's going to create a lot
better open rates a lot better
responsiveness and so if you're finding
that you're setting up a lot of messages
that people aren't paying as much
attention to this is going to be a great
platform for you so let's get into the
platform and how it works so I'm gonna
go ahead and sign in so this has my
account set up here and and and now I'm
in my dashboard and so you can see here
video library so these are videos that
I've already created I can send out uh
these are templates uh that they have
and you can create a template where you
can create a header and this is
basically the landing page of what that
looks like and how you want to message
this and if you want to have a call to
action button and all of those things so
kind of similar to like a mail jimp
template and then Dynamic videos you can
actually create you know different kind
of AI functionalities within the dynamic
videos or make them interactive for
somebody to then click within the video
and the team overview is everyone else
that has that account access so let's go
to the video library and really this is
the bread and butter of how it works I
do want to add too that they have a
great Chrome extension is that something
that I use quite a bit where you can
just easily uh just do it and let me
actually see if I have it set up in my
Google yeah so if I'm here in my Gmail
and I can just click this record spend
send spark video right here within my
Gmail and it will open up where I can
record a video just right here and yeah
and I just have to hit record and then
it records but if you don't want to use
the Chrome extension I'm going to come
back here to the library and you can
just record right here within the
platform so I'm going to just hit start
recording and it looks a lot like what
it does right there in the email and you
can just hit start recording and it'll
give you the countdown 3 2 1 and now I
am recording a video here that I can
send as a message and so now you can see
that video is there and I can click for
sound and watch that I can give it a
name and so I'm going to just call it
sample s
spark and I can just copy that link and
now it's ready to do so I'm going to
take that linked GIF here and then if I
go into my
email and just send myself a sample
video or test just call it test and if I
just put uh let me just do here's my
test s spark
video and I'm going to just then paste
that jef and you can see it's right
there for people to watch and just like
that I can just hit send and that send
spark is sent and it will it it will let
me know in the library if anybody's
watched it and so you can see here right
now it'll show zero on that video but
then if I go into my email this is what
that email looks like so somebody gets
this they're going to most naturally
click this video and then you could see
here this is what opens up and they can
just hit play uh and watch the video and
so naturally I could lay out this
template in any way that I can and put
buttons on there call the action buttons
so look at the end of the day send spark
is super simple to use great features uh
and why I like it is literally just how
easy it is for me to send a video email
that I find to be much more personal
than a reg their email and the
responsiveness I get from people like oh
wow it was you I loved getting the video
and so I think the downside to it is
similar to voice memos you got to be in
a place that you can listen to it but at
the end of the day people typically even
go back to to look at it and look for it
and I find them to be have a much higher
open rate responsive rate and they just
kind of have a wow factor and so it's
really not that complicated I love the
GIF format where it looks like the video
is playing already you can tell that
it's a video and I love that I can
personalize those templates that that
people view them on and so yeah all the
features and functions are just really
easy to use I I always say that if I
can't use the software within an hour
functionally it's too complicated and
this is a platform that within about 5
minutes I was able to use it and create
video emails that I was able to send to
people and I've been using it now for
about a year and and playing with it so
I reached out to S spark asked them if I
could become an affiliate uh for their
program because I've been telling people
about it over the last year and I just
wanted to make a video and let other
more people know about this cool
platform and so yeah it it's get gets
two thumbs up from me there's nothing
about it that I you know I'm like ah I
wish did this it you know honestly does
everything uh and then some that that I
needed to do and yeah I find it to be a
really great platform to help my emails
stand out and it's something that I am
planning to use more and more within
LinkedIn as well and on other platforms
but for now it's primarily an email tool
for me and uh it works great for that
and so if you're looking uh to send more
personal emails to people this is a
great easy way uh to do this to just hit
record and hit send and honestly I find
it to be even easier than writing an
email and so yeah great tool two thumbs
up go get it I've got an affiliate link
down below would love for you to use
that affiliate link if you're going to
test it out and let me know what you
think or do you have another preferred
platform that does similar
functionalities to this that that you'd
love to share or if there's features
within send Spark that I didn't
highlight that you have have found to be
extra beneficial I'd love to know about
those as well and what uses you have
found for this platform because I I want
to lean into it I want to use it more
and more as I Look to just better
communicate uh with my clients with my
potential clients with uh the people
that interacting with and working with
and so yeah that's s spark thanks for
watching we'll talk to you again on the
next video
[Music]
n