in this video I'm going to show you how
to convert any content that's audio in a
video or just audio in and of itself
into any
language hey there if we haven't met yet
I'm Neil Smith your social media guide
and I am so excited to show you this new
software platform 11 Labs now it's not
that new but it's been progressing a lot
and become more and more popular and one
of the things people are seeing and
they're hearing is I'm seeing these
videos of somebody speaking a different
language but it looks and sounds like
they're saying it but I know they don't
speak that language and it's using this
kind of technology and 11 Labs has been
on the Forefront of this audio
translation technology now it can do a
lot of other things other than translate
but I think the most most popular use is
being able to take your podcast or being
able to take your YouTube video
and just instantly plug it into this
platform and then let it output uh the
content in the different languages for
you this is mindblowing uh and so I
can't wait to show to you so let's first
start by jumping onto their website all
right so here we are on the 11 Labs home
page and I just want to walk through
kind of how they communicate who they
are and what they do so 11 laps uh
basically creates the most realistic
speech with our AI audio platform
pioneering research and text to speech
AI voice generator and more and so it's
an audio platform uh that's using AI uh
and and one of the things this actually
does is a lot of people are UNC putting
their face camera or even their voice uh
but you can literally even type anything
and it will then generate it in a voice
and I think we've heard and seen videos
that sound very robotic but this
technology is progressing quickly and so
it's not all super robotic it's actually
uh can be very realistic and then they
get down here and you can actually see
how this works they let you just test
the platform form uh right here and
these are kind of the core functions of
their software so the first is text to
speech so I could say it type
anything and now I can just push play
and I can actually choose any of these
people so let's have Bill say
it create a test audio segment for me so
there's Bill saying this or I could
choose Charlotte uh saying whatever I
wanted her to say create a test audio
segment for me okay so that's text of
speech so I could literally type
anything and one of the things that
people can use to create this you can
actually build a whole podcast on this
where you could have chat GPT write a
script for you and then have one of
their AI voices uh speak it for you now
I can go speech to speech as well so let
me try starting a how this
works we test uh did you hear that I
think someone is following us this is a
test by the way
okay false alarm it was just a
squirrel so now we could have Alice bill
or George because let's go with
George let's give him a minute to
[Music]
process we test uh did you hear that I
think so someone is following us this is
a test by the
way okay false alarm it was just a
squirrel okay so it is using the what I
spoke and then Auto translating it or
Auto not translating it but Auto uh
converting it to somebody else's voice
and so it doesn't sound like me but it's
using my inflections uh that that I'm
using and translating it let me have
Alice speak it uh in her voice the same
thing that I said and so it is
converting my voice to her voice
communicating the same thing in this
audio
segment well test uh did you hear that I
think someone is following us this is a
test by the
way okay false alarm it was just a squir
and so as you hear that it doesn't sound
very robotic does it uh but that is an
AI generated voice uh so impressive so
text to speech speech to speech not
dubbing uh this is where I believe most
people are using it uh what I am most
excited about so uh here's a sample of a
podcast I'm going to just hit play and
you can hear him communicating in both
English uh and then in I believe that's
Italian I've interviewed some of the
best seers in the world and I'm
fascinated by leadership b or
style today okay so just like that it
was able to just switch between uh
English and uh it I'm going to say
Italian uh I apologize if I'm looking
and seeing the flag wrong but it is yeah
so that is how it just dubs uh that your
voice and it actually have multiple
voices but it sounds just like the
person that was speaking but then in
their voice in their tone in their
inflection it's being translated and
even when you watch that video it looks
like he's speaking that language so it
aligns it so well uh it's pretty
incredible now this is a cool feature
this text to special effects and so I'm
going to ask it to um it a
um paper
clip falling off a desk
onto a tile
floor so let's see what it generates
here for us so you can literally create
create any sound effect that you wanted
to create and it will then generate
those sound effects for
you okay let's check out the sound
effects generation number
one let's do that again number
two okay just a little quiet drop
there okay that sounded like a few
paperclips falling
there you go and I would go with number
four but it would give you actually
options of which you know as you had
that that sound effect in mind which
which one did you have that sounding
like uh but it can actually generate any
kind of sound effect that you come up
with uh and then this is voice cloning
and so let's let's take a look at a few
of these different uh voice
clones all right so get this I'm at this
new Cafe downtown trying to act all
sophisticated with an espresso all right
so get this I'm at this new Cafe
downtown trying to act all sophisticated
with an espresso you know and I'm
sitting there scrolling through my
phone Sherlock Holmes's quick eye took
in my occupation and he shook his head
with a Sherlock Holmes's quick eye took
with a SM so what this is doing is it's
essentially taking and learning
somebody's voice and then being able to
convert that into uh you know where you
could just text to speech uh in in
anything else that you wanted to say
once it learns your voice and has that
cloned file available so yeah so those
are kind of the core features of the app
and how they work and then uh you you
can see some of their other messaging of
voice voices fit for all of your ideas
uh and you can essentially create your
cloned voice to then use uh for anything
making any content universally accept
accept accessible uh not not acceptable
uh but accessible uh and this is a just
one of the most powerful things about AI
is that we can now take our message and
globally allow anybody anywhere to to
watch it and this is thing Mr Beast uh
has has been well known for is
translating and using voice actors in
his case his content uh into multiple
languages and then getting lots of
Engagement Beyond uh the us through uh
that that translation and so this is I
believe doing this even more effectively
because I think when people can actually
hear uh the person speaking and their
inflection and their voice it will be a
much more natural experience rather than
uh voice actors you know uh you know
speaking on behalf and or translating
the content and then complete voice AI
tool set so you have so many different
uh functions uh there and then this is
one of the things I really like about 11
Labs is you can tell and they're
communicating this on their homepage
that safety is important to to them uh
and and I think one of the dangers of AI
is that uh people will be able to
essentially rip off our voices and make
things sound like us when it wasn't
actually us saying them and so they they
have built into their platform safety
features and they are prioritizing this
in their development and uh I I am
grateful to see this uh because I do
think this is an important uh aspect of
AI development and then they they share
some case studies here so let's jump
into uh the platform itself and the
software uh and what I want to
uh and when you first get here it goes
right to the text to speech or speech to
speech uh that you want to create uh and
then you go here to the right hand uh
side and you can see the different
options of what do you want to create
voices sound effects uh Speech uh or
getting in here to workflows uh and
dubbing studio is the main feature that
I I wanted to highlight I do want to
also just highlight this other Tool uh
real quickly voice isolator um and just
a cool cool thing where you can upload
any of your files that you create if you
recorded a podcast so this isn't about
translation but it just cleans up uh the
audio for you uh with eliminating
background noise and I just did some
testing of this previously and it just
it did an incredible job and so there's
some you know Dobby has uh of something
similar to this and there's some other
tools out there but cool to see that
they've Incorporated that into their
platform uh but let's let's jump into
the dubbing studio and so this is where
you can translate social media content
YouTube videos marketing assets
educational videos uh whatever content
you have you can then uh convert it so
I'm going to take uh one of the video
that I created um and so I'm going to
title this
Nils um uh what is it called just put
called Mr Beast video translated and so
I did a video recently where I uh and
let's translate this to Spanish uh um
and I I made a video of Mr Beast um and
about his new software platform and so
then I can go here and I can literally
just upload the file or I can just go to
YouTube so I'm going to pull this from
YouTube um and it checks that it's
creating a dubbing Studio project and
add Watermark to reduce character usage
by 33% okay while that you can actually
uncheck that or you can number of
speakers autod detect that uh I'm going
to just put what there actually I think
there's some clips of Mr Beast on there
video resolution highest uh extra time
of
dubbing uh time range for dubbing we'll
just let it be all there and yeah so
let's go to create so just like that it
took my YouTube video that was in
English and now it's creating a Spanish
version of that and so uh yeah so that
is processing and we'll give that a a
minute to process and then we'll come
back and show you the out outcome okay
so it just finished dubbing the video
and you can see here status dubbed and I
can just go here to view it uh and so
it's going to pull up here but while I
do that uh I thought I'd just go ahead
and show you the original video so let
me share this tab in said so this is the
video so watch the first little bit then
I'll show you how it
translated for a platform called view
stats and I subscrib to it you don't
have to maybe you want to in this video
I'm going to dive into every aspect of
the software and whether I think it's a
good investment for you you're you so
let's go back now and see what the 11
Labs translated video looks and sounds
like
[Applause]
software okay so you can see there that
it pretty well translated and used my
voice uh to translate it just with a
YouTube link and that's how easy this is
and if you have a podcast or you have
YouTube videos that you want translated
uh and it's giving you the full video
and I can just download it and I'll
upload it to YouTube or download it
and pull the audio out and upload that
to the various podcast platforms and
it's done for me and yeah this is really
good and and from the the reviews I've
gotten from translators that have looked
at it is the the stat that I heard now
please don't quote me on this uh as as
factual but the stat I've heard is that
human translators are about 92% accurate
and AI translation is about 97% accurate
so a lot of people have said how can I
trust the translation well the reality
is how can you trust a human translator
too you know they they're going to make
mistakes and what's kind of being being
proven out is they generally make more
mistakes than an AI translation you know
tool does and and so and and from what
I've heard from people that watch you
know these videos that are translated uh
that that they and that understand both
languages that they can track it and it
just feels uh very natural and the
translation uh H has been very accurate
for
what uh those that are using this kind
of software and more specifically 11
Labs um the accuracy is really strong
and so this is the beginning of this
technology I don't know how it gets much
better than this it's hard for me to
imagine probably faster uh but but man
this is really good um and one of things
I'm even curious about is if you could
see even the graphics that have overlays
of could you get that translated within
the video too where it will just
autodetect where there's going to be you
know text overlays and then Auto uh that
those text overlays and things like that
into uh the the you know different
language we'll see uh where this goes
but this as where the product is today
and how it can be used incredible so if
you know you're a church and you want to
translate your sermons to other
languages if you're an educator and you
want to translate your education content
if you're a podcaster and you want to
translate that content what a great Tool
uh to do this and it's you know there's
a free uh trial uh that will only I
think you know translate about two or
three minutes within the free trial of
content um and so I you know my plan I
pay $11 a month for uh and it gives me
you know more than I need at this point
uh and then they have prices that go up
if you're translating you know hundreds
of hours of content every month and
that's what you want translated you have
a huge Library you want translated you
know you can pay more uh but the cost
Effectiveness as compared to a voice
actor and all of that you know
historically you know I've worked with
voice actors in the past it's about 20
to $30 a minute of for translated
content from a voice actor and so yeah
this is way more cost effective that and
I would challenge that this is way
better than that too uh so not only is
it more costeffective uh and and more
efficient uh it's also more effective uh
in the output that people are going to
consume and the experience they're going
to have with your video content so I'm a
big fan of this technology I'm going to
be using it uh for clients uh here in
the very near future I'm going be using
it uh for my own content uh in the near
future and I'd encourage you to test it
out I have I do have an affiliate link
for this product so some products that I
talk about I don't some I do um 11 Labs
was generous enough to share an
affiliate uh offer with me uh to share
with you and so you can uh use that link
below and go check out 11 Labs do the
free trial test out kind of the features
there on the homepage and see if this is
a tool uh that that you can begin to
integrate into your workflows now so if
you want to get your content into other
languages uh I've found this to be the
best tool uh so far to get this done so
go give it a try let me know what you
think uh if you have other options out
there things you've tried or
experimented with or that you use 11
labs for I'd love to know drop that in
the comments I'll be engaged there and
look forward to following uh along in
the conversation and following this
technology Innovation and to see where
it goes thanks so much for watching
we'll talk to you again on the next
[Music]
video 2