in this video I'm going to react to Gary
vaynerchuk's recent interview where he
talks about what he sees as the future
of AI and social media influencers and
he digs into a lot of aspects about Ai
and it's going to change everything and
I think people aren't seeing the big
picture when it comes to Ai and Gary ve
has stayed on the front edge of
technology and media and social media
and we're going to dig into his thoughts
and my opinions when it comes to what
this world of social media is going to
look like as we prepare for the future
and Gary says it in this video that
we're not looking at the big picture
here and he's not talking necessarily
even just about the future but the
present uh and so this is moving quickly
and we're going to dig into it in this
video hey there if we haven't met yet
I'm Neil Smith your social media guide
and one of the people I've looked to as
a guide through the years is Gary
vanderchuck at his book crush it 15
years ago when I read it was
transformative uh for my career of
really how big this social media thing
is going to get and one of the things he
digs into in this video is how big AI is
going to get and I think it's a really
unique perspective and so let's dig into
this video uh let's see what Gary has to
say about Ai and social media and how we
need to approach it looking into the
future and being prepared for the future
you know I think one of the things that
many of the people at vorx
in my organization though and many of
the clients that I've interacted with in
the room is there's this obsession with
everyone thinking that these things are
coming tomorrow like more stuff more
stuff sold today because of social media
organic and
advertising than any other media drove
sales today so you know I think
obviously I understand you're setting it
up but I took the opportunity to like
really pound this home to everyone you
know the day trading attention means
that I believe marketing has shifted to
something that is minute by minute
second by second not let's sit around a
boardroom for 3 months and come up with
an idea that will come out in 9 months
that world is super over you
know I know there's a new Seinfeld movie
on Netflix that has Don Draper coming
back but he's super dead and and I think
this the industry um is really
struggling with Fortune 500 the the all
the companies listed on NASDAQ are
really struggling with marketing in my
opinion and I think they have bad
reporting I think that they um are
confused and I believe that until the
world realizes that organic social media
right now is the single most important
thing to understand in marketing and
then you build from there I just want to
pause this real quick quick and I mean
he just says it right there that we
don't understand how significant the
opportunity of organic social media is
in the marketing world in the marketing
space and so many people H have really
taken this side over the last even 5 to
10 years that social media is this
pay-to-play game and that's just not
true there are plenty of people that are
having plenty of Success Through organic
social media and we can see businesses
built on the back of that when we look
at Mr Beast and what he's done with
febles or we look at Logan Paul and what
he's done with Prime and those are
businesses that they own but beyond that
we when we look at different brands and
what they have built on the back of
organic social media and so while paying
to play is an aspect of how I think we
need to lean into and understand social
media organic social media is the
biggest opportunity and play right now
and you know into the future I think
Gary says it so well so I love that
perspective in that that call out to
what he sees and what I agree with as
the biggest opportunity in marketing
today not just digital marketing and
marketing today and into the future so
let's let's jump back in until that
happens we will see what we've been
seeing which is on the flip side for
every American Airlines or
BMW there are real significant
businesses being built every day purely
on social
and for I'm not talking about the long
tale
of thousands of companies doing $5
million a year selling a health and
wellness product or t-shirts or you know
something on the side I'm talking about
the poppies the Prime energy drinks the
Mr Beast beables you're going to start
seeing multi-billion dollar Revenue
companies that are built purely from
social and uh and that should make sense
to everyone
because a stunning percentage of the
most famous people in the world right
now came from and live within social
they're not actors and actresses on in
film and television and so you know I I
think I'm excited that I put out this
book now um because I went very nerdy
with it I went into very heavy detail of
like okay that's what I have to say it's
not especially if you pay attention to
anything I've said it's nothing I
haven't been saying for a decade what
I'm proud about with this book is I'm
showing people how to like really think
about it this is much more a classroom
textbook than blue yeah it's a it's a
real blueprint I
mean you know I think I wrote it for my
employees to be honest I'm trying to get
2,000 employees I I I want to just shout
out this book I have not read it yet I I
bought it you know immediately when came
out is one of the things I've just done
through the years is anytime Gary ve
releases a new book I I buy it and I
consume it and so I haven't read it yet
the fact that he's saying this is a
blueprint it it really does remind me of
that crush it days and so I I need to
jump into it but I you know I just want
to just shout out the book daying
attention because I do believe this is
going to be kind of the textbook for
marketing over the next five years as I
study so much of what Gary Vee teaches
and preaches when it comes to social
media marketing digital marketing just
Marketing in general and so I I think
this opportunity and what he sees is
when you can capture attention on the
back of attention is successful business
and and I think historically that's been
done through buying TV and radio ads and
Super Bowl commercials and and things
like that but but I think at the end of
the day we can actually have attention
uh without paying for it but we pay for
it through our Sweat Equity of you know
content marketing through organic social
media and these algorithms actually have
the power to uh allow us to build
businesses on on the back of it and so
it's such an important part of where
where marketing is going in Gary C set
so clearly and he's giving the blueprint
for how to do it in both his book and
and really in all of the content that he
puts out 2,000 employees to do this
properly I'm like you know what I'll
just write a book and make them read it
on on boarding that might that
everything else hasn't worked maybe this
will work sounds like maybe you
also wrote it for the Fortune 500
companies and what it sounds like you're
saying is that um what kept
companies competitive for the last let's
say 10 15 20 years is not what's going
to keep them competitive for the next 2
5 10 15 20 in in a real way yeah and
they really need to catch up so with
that though what do you think is the
opportunity here um to actually do it
because there's especially when you're
talking about Fortune you know 100 200
companies there's a lot of you know old
school systems there's a lot of you know
two-year point about we don't need to
sit for three months and have build a
strategy and then you know launch it in
9 months how do you how do you how do
you think about mindset change and how
do you think about real change within
organization to adopt this kind of
thinking I think real life it's going to
come down to
pain you know the real answer to your
question and I'd like to keep it real is
I don't believe they'll do it until they
feel the pain that they're starting to
feel I believe that we have had more
significant conversations you know I
look at kayin and Avery who are my
partners in in a lot of these convos and
many others in this room we've had more
real I mean this week last week more
real conversations where it's not just
hey we need social media and like we'd
like to work with you like it's part of
our mix or we need it as a compliment
you know to put it in food terms for
everyone here that's not deep in this
Vortex on a good day social media has
been in a moose Boos it hasn't even been
an appetizer or a dessert and it's
definitely not the main meal
what we're saying is it's the surf and
the turf it is the mainest meal there is
I would say we've had more conversations
in the last month two months this
year about okay like we're ready to take
this serious and it is only because
they're feeling pain they can smell it
they've got emerging Brands taking
market share or a or a churchery
competitor that out of desperation has
gone into this and they can feel it and
so what I love about this is I think
Merit is about to Prevail I think the to
answer question I think it's going to be
pain and I think the reason they're
going to come to it is Merit like you
know for me when all of you get to read
the book hopefully you will I don't I am
only talking about social
media because that's the biggest
opportunity of underpriced scaled
awareness right now as a matter of fact
it's the in this Nano second just
thought what I'm about to say this could
this book could actually become like a
dummy series for me the subtitle is very
important this book the book is called
day trading attention I've done that my
whole life if I wrote this book in 2000
I'd be talking to you about websites
email right and and and search engines
right and so when I look at this it's
called day trading attenion but then the
subtitles how to actually build brand
and sales in the new social media world
in the new social media world I can
replace that every 5 years I can
literally write this book in 12 years in
the new VR world because you know for
example social is incredibly vulnerable
to VR because the second this doesn't
become the primary device of our
society all of a sudden social media
becomes dramatically less valuable that
is what has happened to television
commercials the television that we all
grew up with is a churchery device now
you do not go to a television and turn
it on and click channels but between
Network and cable that is gone at even
you know
even Boomers I love when people think
this is all for kids anybody here who is
70 or has 70y old parents know that half
the content that their parents are
consuming is YouTube and at bare minimum
they're turning on a smart TV and they
know how to go to streaming services
there's not a 95-year-old that doesn't
consume a Netflix or a Hulu or a YouTube
it's over and and we are hold like
unfortunately companies are holding on
because of politics and corporate bull
crap it's I I want to jump in here at
the end of the day and I think you know
the so so much of the data speaks for
itself of you know as the last data I
saw the average American is spending
about two and a half hours a day on
social media and the mobile device and
engagement on mobile with social is is
consuming us and and consuming attention
in such a significant way and and one of
the fascinating things even from a
business example is Logan Paul's you
know Prime brand in the hydration space
just surpassed Power Aid which is a
known entity and their chasing Gatorade
that these have this kind of established
brand presence and all of a sudden a
social media influencer that has
attention is able to explode in this
space a disrupt or or you know Mr Beast
with febles is exploding and chasing
Hershey's you know it's been around
forever that you don't think these Major
Brands can be disrupted but with
attention they can and this is where you
even see Elon Musk with Tesla because he
has attention they don't need to spend
money on marketing they could put more
into their product and disrupt the whole
Auto industry and so he has mastered the
art of attention and can essentially
scale whatever Brands he's aligned to
professionally or in his business
because of that attention and so it is
such a big play I you know I think even
highlighting Logan Paul specifically is
he's also pivoted you know so as social
media has changed he kind of had this
kind of silly teenager you know shock
videos Vlog that he has now pivoted to a
podcast with his brand yet he's also
huge on Tik Tok and using clips and
things from his podcast from his WWE you
know wrestling matches and and different
things to build his brand and I think
where we continue to go is we it's not
just like okay now we need to go all in
on social media but it's pivoting along
the way as social media changes and I
think it will require additional pivot
as VR emerges and as as different
mediums emerge and and so just like we
saw Tik Tok and vertical video explode
in the past few years we don't know
necessarily what that next big emergence
is I think we can see VR is coming but
but that's not it's not switch up flips
overnight just like we didn't switch
from desktop devices to mobile phones
overnight from an engagement perspective
but we could see it happening but the
question was is who jumped on that
bandwagon fast enough and and could see
what's coming and so we've got to be
paying attention to to the trends that
are developing and pivot along the way
as we both gain and keep
attention
yeah everybody's stock price downstairs
should be more valuable if they stopped
releasing
money and they waste more money on bad
marketing than anything else they
do so you've been at the Forefront as
you're talking about social media and 10
years from now you know right now we're
talking about AI we can't really go
anywhere without talking about AI
especially as it has to do with brand
creative you know it taking over new
ways to create content we're talking
about the fact that you know we're going
to be interacting with AI Bots what is
you know 5 to 10 years if we were
looking back since you've always been on
the Forefront what do you think we will
say about AI at this point you know it's
funny I've been at the Forefront
predominantly based on my little rant
for the last seven minutes my Forefront
is I talk about today and the world is
all about yesterday so you know
historically even like all the images
and quotes that have been running here
today they were set at the time it's not
like I said you know Tik Tok is going to
crush before it started crushing I only
talk about what's actually happening so
this question's always been challenging
for me because I really don't predict I
just I just pontificate in the truth of
the moment that being said of course
like any other human in here I have
thoughts I try to debate it I have
pattern recognition couple things
first you know the AI conversation is
really interesting cuz it's almost like
it feels to me like electricity it's
going to be so Omni it AI is not like an
app it's like the oxygen like you know I
was in a meeting today around AI legal
Maneuvers that we want to make as an
organization and I was like man none of
this is like we're we're talking about
it and already it's become so default
it's like what is AI right and what I
mean by that is Automation and and then
profound automation how it thinks for
you but I see us in the meeting today
talking about
automation as AI not just and so like
it's so big and so I guess in 5 or 10
years I think we'll stop talking about
it the way we're talking about it now
the way that nobody here talks about the
internet you know for everybody who
who's over 42 and here raise your hands
so everybody that just raised their
hands we used to talk about something
called the internet like we would talk
about it a lot we're like the inter the
internet's gonna and the internet and
this internet you know and like and we
don't do that now it's oxygen and that's
what's going to happen with AI in 10
years we're not going to be talking
about AI it just is I would to speak to
AI you know I think in general because
one of the things and I love how he said
it's not an app and I think what he's
saying here is chat GPT is not AI Chad
GPT is one tool that is you know an AI
powered tool that we're seeing disrupt
and it's the most popular and it's it's
bringing it to the mainstream AI to the
mainstream but AI has been here for a
season and it's integrating faster and
faster than it has today and I think the
internet is a great comparison because
when the internet was birthed we saw it
as the worldwide web we saw it as the
information super highway but then it
was also the Google search but Google
was an app built on the internet and
then social media emerged and we saw it
kind of Web 2.0 and the internet is
constantly emerging it's evolving it's
improving we couldn't have even thought
about YouTube streaming it was all just
text based articles when the internet
emerged and then even some images and
things like that but we we didn't even
thought about the speed of bandwidth at
which we could stream videos in in the
future or high definition videos or even
knew what High defition videos were a
and so the internet has emerged and
evolved and become much more than the
information Super Highway and and I
think AI is going to do the same thing
it's not just going to be chat gbt it's
going to be kind of integrated into
everything in a very significant way and
used in in a lot of different ways and
so the disruption of AI will be similar
likely to the disruption of the internet
and that will be something that will
come over years and probably Decades of
of development and emergence just like
the internet has and continues to as the
internet develops and emerges and
becomes faster and more integrated even
when the internet was birthed we we
heard of things like ethernet you know
and what what is that what's the
difference between ethernet and internet
or what is an intranet versus the
internet and so there there was a lot of
confusion in early days and now it's
just we don't even talk like it's just
there it's a part of our lives and
everything we do and I think about all
the things I do on my phone of banking
and mapping and you know social media
and calendaring and emailing it's all
inter at into the internet and it's just
there it's just a part of our lives that
we can't even fathom functioning without
it so AI is becoming that but but it is
more than an app uh and I think that's
such an important statement that he
makes here as we even begin to
comprehend how significant AI is going
to be in the future especially the
future of marketing and so it's that big
and I think every single human and every
single organization will be massively
affected by it it's actually one of my
greatest concerns
as a human being right this nanc it's
almost like you know I think the thing
that has worked for me and what I admire
in others is when they can think about
seven things not one thing so many
people struggle because they look at
things they can only look at one thing
at a time and all the all the
opportunity sits when you're able to
take seven to 50 different data points
and make a strong observation critical
thinking by the way something AI may be
able to take away as an advantage you
know what I what I think is really
interesting
is I'm incredibly concerned that we live
in a day and age where the human is more
thoughtful than ever about work life
balance mental and physical health and
it's actually beautiful there's so much
good about that you know obviously I'm a
very well documented I love the grind
and but that's only cuz I'm passionate
about my what I do for a living like
when I don't when I'm not passionate
about it I don't want to do anything
there's a reason I was a poor student
there's a reason that I don't do things
around the house like if I don't if I
don't like
it you know but I but I think this is
really an interesting Insight like if I
don't like it I don't want to do it I
have no passion for it I'm giving it
zero effort so obviously I'm very well
documented in believing in hard work and
going hard and all this because I love
it I'm thrilled when people want to find
their balance I feel like I have my
balance balance is individual but here's
a very very like important conversation
that's about to hit its head at a time
where people are like not interested in
going to the office are looking for more
time than
ever we're going to have a problem that
problem is humans are going to be
replaced by Ai and companies are going
to do it just like we did with tractors
on farms Farms used to employ everyone
almost everybody on Earth only a couple
hundred years ago worked on it and was
employed by a farm and then tractors
came along and you didn't need as many
people this beautiful city do you know
how many people used to be employed here
120 years ago to clean up cow poop a lot
but then the car came along and we
didn't need to ride horses anymore thus
rendering our not needing people to go
around this city and clean up horse
poop there's not a creative person on
Earth that is a Mason an architect and a
Mason are two different things if you
sit in this room or you're watching this
video or you're listening to this and
you're the idea person good news AI is
about to become your partner in thinking
but if you are not the idea person if
you're the person that opens up adobe
and you make
it it's game
over and a lot of people do that for a
living and when I say that I don't I'm
not happy about that I'm not actually
not happy not sad not pro not con it
just
is my question is every single Adobe
designer or video editor knows that to
be true so no M you what I just said was
not some sort of like that's impossible
we actually know it to be true there's
unlimited videos that are viral on the
internet right now that were made in one
second that are profound they used to
cost thousands and tens of thousands of
dollars and take 20 people my question
is if you do that for a living and you
know what I just said is true what are
you doing about it yeah I I I want to
speak to this and and this is one of the
things that I have communicated a lot of
people have talked to me about fear of
AI and what are my concerns about AI as
I study this you know so in in such
depth and you know I think there's just
going to be the end of the world our
robot's going to turn on us is you know
what what's going to happen here my
biggest year of AI is it is not even the
the loss of jobs I think it's the loss
of purpose that's going to be tied to
those jobs and I think I think just like
new tech like farming technology and you
know tractors and and things like that
they created efficiencies that helped us
be able to you know have more access to
food and resources and AI is going to do
the same thing it's going to you know a
lot of our tasks are going to be done by
robots and you know AI Bots that is
going to make our lives easier but it's
also going to take a lot of the jobs
that people are used to it I don't think
while he's saying like what are you
going to do there's a lot of people that
are like well hopefully somebody will
help me solve this and and I think what
he's saying is no nobody's going to
solve this you know your lost job for
you it's going to create a significant
societal problem of people not just
losing income I think our cost of living
will decrease alongside the efficiencies
created you know in at least in a lot of
places and but it's to cost purpose that
I think people find in their jobs but I
think just hoping that it's not going to
take your job if you're a designer if
you're a copywriter if you're you that
that's unrealistic and and so it is this
is going to be a complicated societal
issue that we all need to be thinking
about not just in our work but the work
of our employees and and the people
around us is how can we help set each
other up for this future but this
Future's happening fast and I and I
think we need to be thoughtful about
this and and it's the most significant
concern I have about Ai and and the
effects of AI from a negative
perspective and so I'm worried that we
have this conversion two things
happening at the same time at worst an
enormous amount of entitlement by human
beings in First World
countries and at best people being
thoughtful about what they want in life
and what balance they want but all of it
there's one there's technology is the
best but it also has one thing that is
very very challenging it doesn't care
about our
feelings and so this is going to be and
it is going to reshape our society and I
I went through this F minute rant to beg
someone who hears it who is in the
business of what AI is about to
commoditize to challenge themselves to
put themselves out of business before AI
does it and what I mean by that if you
don't understand is adjust I think about
it my agency gets paid lots and lots of
money to make
creative so I think about this every day
and I think all of us
should that and and it goes pretty far
one of the things I don't think I
touched on no I don't think maybe I
touched on a book all blurs together but
virtual
influencers like everyone who's an
influencer right now who's really
winning is loving life that turned out
to be a great great job
right I mean there's real pressure
coming it's called virtual influencers
and not real people correct influencers
that's right and the brands have all
sorts of feelings towards influencers
they pay a lot of money then they don't
post it the way they want or do the
thing they want or do another brand deal
with their competitor the the day after
the six Monon
exclusive so you know what they're going
to do about it they're going to create
their own
influencers why not it's not only why
not they
should this is the thing that I found
incredibly interesting about everything
in life and definitely in marketing and
business people act as if they're owed
something are you owed nothing this
is business this is Merit this is you
know every influencer that got paid $1
today took that out of an actual
celebrity 15 years ago that's where that
money went so we're not crying for them
and the people that own the AI
influencers are not going to cry for the
influencers I think that industry is
going to get massively affected in the
next 10 years okay so we'll just stop
the video there because it really speaks
to that virtual influencer aspect of
what you know is is starting to become
one of the popular features of AI and
what's happening and and just to
describe it a little bit is I can
literally create an avatar like a person
that looks like a real person I can make
them look you know like anything I want
to look you know to look like and I can
have them use whatever accent I want
them to have and I can get them to say
whatever I want them to say and so
essentially where I'm making a video
where I am a human you know somebody
could create video like this with
somebody that has hair and has the
ability to to grow hair and you know and
and says things without saying as much
as I do and really you know be better
than I am on camera or even as better
than Gary V is on camera and we've had
this emergence of the Creator economy
and we we've had the development and you
know the number one job that kids want
to be when they grow up as a YouTuber
and I do think we'll still have
YouTubers and people on camera and and
and things that humans are doing but
we'll also have virtual influencers
we'll also have you know I I saw Ashton
Kutcher recently said with what he's
been experimenting with with open AI
Sora video creation platforms he thinks
he will produce a full feature film
using AI that will look like the actors
and actresses are all you know real
people but they won't be they'll be
virtual actors and virtual influencers
and and the script will actually be
written by AI for them and the scenes
will all be generated by ai ai is going
to change everything and and it's
mind-blowing to think about this but I I
think even as I think about that is you
know one of the things that I'm the
actions I'm taking is I'm beginning to
work on creating virtual influencers
that that can help both my you know
companies that I work with or my clients
that I work with and how they might be
able to be used you know to accomplish
the marketing efforts that we have and
this is just one of the uses of AI and
and so I don't think this is necessarily
good or bad but it's also an example
another example of how AI is going to
replace everyone and everything and so
he talks about your you're a graphic
designer your job will be replaced by AI
because the AI will be a better graphic
designer and definitely a more efficient
graphic designer than you are it's going
to replace video editors it's going to
replace copywriters and it's even going
to replace actors and actresses and so
much of even the recent you know protest
by the the film you know creators and
the writers is they don't want AI to be
part of those things well it's going to
happen whether we like it or not in
different ways and there will be things
that will delay it and slow it but but
there and there will be music created by
AI that will probably be better than the
music created recorded produced by
humans and so you know I think there's
some things that are hard to predict
where where this is going but AI is
going to become more and more a part of
our lives and I I think the question is
one the best way of how we can even
approach this is learning about it
understanding it and and then also even
speaking to where is this healthy where
is this unhealthy where do I need to
lean in where I need where do I need to
to pull back but AI used at its best is
an assistant to help us accomplish the
things that we're doing and so I think
that's how we can begin to learn how can
we begin to integrate this not with the
goal of replacing humans although that
will happen task will be replaced but
what I see that happening for me is that
AI is going to allow me to do the things
that only I can do and so AI is going to
help me manage my email more effectively
AI is can to help me manage my calendar
more effectively AI is can to help me
edit these videos more effectively a is
going to help me script these videos
more effectively and it's going to make
me more effective at the things that I
want to do and it's going to help allow
me to not have to do a lot of the things
I don't like doing I don't want to do
but I've often had to even Outsource to
humans that I'm now going to just
Outsource to AI That's going to probably
do a better job not have human error
integrated and it's going to be a lot
more cost effective and so naturally I'm
going to lean into that but the effect
of that is lost jobs which is why I
believe that that is going to be one of
the the biggest challenges we Face
society when it comes to AI so it is an
interesting day things are moving
quickly and I believe that AI is in the
days of early days of the inter we're
dialup internet days right now and it's
pretty amazing you know just like the
worldwide web it was pretty amazing when
we when we first got on but we could
have never dreamed of where that this is
going and and we've seen plenty of
downfalls to the internet we've seen you
know increase in in you know pornography
addiction we've seen increase in you
know suicide rates due to social media
you know unhealth or we've seen you know
just all all kinds of negative things
come out of the internet but we also
have seen all kinds of positive things
come out of the internet where it's used
well and used effectively and so I think
we've got to be thoughtful in how we
approach AI but I think if we lean into
just concern and fear and rejection of
this technology we're we're going to get
left by behind and so I think now is the
time to lean in and understand and you
know if you're I'm in my 40s and so we
talked about if you're 42 or older
you'll understand this so I I naturally
have a a place of like this is just
weird you know virtual influencers
that's that's weird but it's coming I'm
going to lean in and understand it and
and I think you know at the end of the
day look to have integrity with how I
use some of these tools but I'm going to
do it with the deepest level of
understanding uh that I could have so I
hope this video was encouraging to you
an understanding where some of this is
going and how you can lean in and so my
my big takeaways is you know Gary ve who
who continues to to be you know so
thoughtful in his projections for where
Technologies is going is one organic
social media is the biggest marketing
opportunity today and into the future
and AI is is just at the beginning and
it is going to affect everything into
the future and I think those are big
takeway is big picture ideas but if
you're not leaning into organic social
media and you're not prioritizing
understanding and learning when it comes
to AI you're missing out on significant
opportunities for your business your
organization your church ministry
whatever it is that you do we need to be
paying attention to these things and and
I believe can have an exciting future on
the other side of this as well it's not
all bad as much as it might be perceived
that way there there are really exciting
opportunities on the back of this as
well so thank you for watching if you
haven't yet subscribe to the channel
ring the bell do all the things go
follow me I'm I'm on all the Instagram
LinkedIn you know X all the social media
platforms love to connect with you there
my DMs are always open if you have any
questions I can help in any way don't
hesitate to reach out and I will see you
in the comments drop a comment share
your thoughts and I'll be engaging there
in the comments I look forward to
connecting with you there thanks for
watching we'll talk to you again on the
next video
[Music]
oh