does your church need a mobile app
that's a question I get a lot and I'm
going to talk about in this video why
not why maybe and what I hope is the
future of church
[Applause]
apps hey there if we haven't met yet I'm
Neil Smith your social media guide and I
help church leaders Ministry leaders
Business Leaders nonprofit leaders
leaders of all kinds maximize social
media digital Ministry digital content
technology to accomplish their goals and
this video I want to talk specifically
to church leaders and also Ministry
leaders outside of the church do you
need a mobile app and this is a question
that I get a lot and I've been an app
guy I you know maybe 15 years ago when I
first got my first iPhone I built a
church mobile app in a weekend uh just
because I was curious and I saw the
opportunity potential it got me in the
newspaper which actually got me my job
at Community Bible Church in many ways
and got a lot of the attention for that
uh but the truth is that church app was
kind of use less if I'm honest uh but it
taught me about mobile apps mobile apps
are a brilliant part of our lives and
helped us in a lot of ways but does your
church actually need a mobile app so let
me start by talking about why you don't
need a mobile app okay the first reason
that I think churches should think about
saying no to mobile apps is the cost now
mobile apps have become much more cost
effective I remember uh early days of
mobile apps when I was helping build
maybe my second Church mobile app it was
pretty expensive it was probably around
$20,000 and $500 a month which still is
actually pretty cheap uh when it comes
to mobile Development I've helped a lot
of businesses do mobile apps and
spending six and seven figures to build
apps and they can be that valuable but
they have to align to our mission and
the cost now while I think the costs
have come down it's still a significant
expense that I believe the value is not
necessarily worth the cost so I think
the cost is actually the first reason
you should consider not getting a mobile
app the second reason I think you should
think about saying no is it's one more
thing to update I think about most
smaller churches that you have one or
two staff people and you got to update
the website you got to update the
bulletin you got to update your signs
you got to update you know signs around
your church you've got to update social
media uh it's having an app is another
thing to manage and another thing to
update and what often happens is then
you forget to update it and it's out of
dat and then it's even more useless for
you and so uh unless you have both the
money and the time to keep it updated
and make it valuable I think it's maybe
a no the third reason to say no is
confusion for your church members and I
think your members have a question of
like do I go to the website do I go to
the app like where do I go for
information about the church and so when
you have one place and you're always
saying go to the website uh that's clear
but when you're like go to the website
or the app that the or creates question
and and so we want to avoid confusion
and so we're going end up spending more
money more time and additional confusion
in communicating with our church members
and so for that reason it might also be
a no and the fourth reason uh that that
I would consider saying no is the
current functionality just isn't that
valuable the primary use for most
churches with their app is three parts
it's basically sermon engagement it's
giving and it's push notifications well
the reality is is people can watch your
sermons on your website or they can
watch it on YouTube or they can listen
to it in their podcast apps that you can
communicate more directly through text
message than push notifications uh and
you can basically do everything on your
website that you could probably do in
that app and the giving s is actually
probably pushing to your website anyway
uh and so the value proposition of the
current functionality of most Church
apps uh I believe make both the cost and
the time investment probably not worth
the value that you would pay in both
your time and your money to get the
functionality that they currently do all
that said I am not anti- mobile apps I
love mobile apps I love working I work
with several companies that their
primary platform is their mobile app and
mobile app development and I believe
that smartphones are probably the most
important technology of our lifetime and
the accessibility and the opportunity
that we have and we look at the Bible
you version at that's changed the way we
read the Bible uh and so mobile apps can
be an Incredible Gift uh to the church
and I can believe can be an incredible
resource to churches uh and have been
for a lot of churches and and I believe
can be uh the question is whether
they're the right for you right now so
let me talk about why mobile apps today
can be a good thing for your church the
first reason is is differentiating
communication for your visitors and your
members when you think about somebody
that hasn't yet come to your church
where are they going to go first they're
going to go to your website well if your
website just has a bunch of information
overload for your members that visitor
isn't going to get the key essential
information that they're looking for so
when you have a mobile app that can be
that primary place of communication and
engagement for your members it creates
differentiation for your visitors and so
maybe when it comes to announcements in
your church you continue to say go to
the mobile app go to the mobile app to
get engagement it's not go to the
website or the mobile app it's contining
to Comm communicate to your congregation
this path to your potential visitors
this path and you can create
differentiation between the two
platforms so that is a high value when
used differentiated rather than
basically having the same thing
duplicated on both places and then the
second opportunity is the native
functionality and one of the things that
I am seeing more naturally integrated
more and more into Apps and I'm seeing
this most specifically with my churches
we use Planning Center and how their MO
Church Center app which is not the
native custom mobile app for our church
but it's shared among other churches but
how you can register for events how you
can give easily within the platform
they're using Create native
functionality uh that we're used to
using in other apps and it's built right
into that app and it's really built for
members visitors are not going to go to
the church Center app and find our
church and get information it is a place
for our members to engage and sign up
for things and register for things and
pay for things and donate and and so it
is a great platform functionality wise
that is native to the app that you can't
really do easily in mobile web and so
that differentiation is high value now
the user interface isn't great it's it's
still Limited in a lot of ways there's a
lot of opportunity for that to de velop
but that wasn't the casee 10 years ago
uh and it is way more than just a media
player and so I am happy to see where a
lot of these platforms are progressing
from an integration standpoint now let's
talk about where I hope mobile apps go
into the future and I do see some
platforms already heading in this
direction and the first is more native
integration especially with our database
system so that our app can actually be a
customized platform for each of us
individually to both find content uh
that that we can engage with from our
church uh to to find events and
activities for us to engage in to maybe
even connect and communicate with each
other among the church and with the
staff uh and so I believe that basically
this hub for our members for Content uh
for events for activities for giving it
can all live and basically be our own
kind of database uh integration platform
or social network even for our church uh
right there within the app and so I do
believe this differentiation of of a
website that's primarily focused on
first-time visitors with other
functionality built into that as well it
doesn't have to exclusively be be that
uh and then this app that is really
built as a hub for our members uh is
where I think in in integrating more and
more the native functionality of a phone
like we're using the Uber app or like
we're using Google Maps or like we use
uh you know our Airlines apps and how
how we use these apps and so the native
functionality really helps us uh
integrate it and make it very useful for
us and then the second thing that I
really hope to see more and more of from
churches is discipleship content more of
like a learning management system built
into an app where people can go through
a Bible study that's created just for
their church right there in the app or
or they can go through trainings if
they're if they're going to start
volunteering in a Ministry or uh and and
really begin to become more interactive
in how we're more effectively discipling
our congregation now discipleship
happens in community and it can it
happens best face to face but it can be
augmented with digital resources that
can be natively integrated into our
mobile apps and so I'm really excited
about where these Technologies can go
into the future and where I believe I'm
seeing hints of development moving into
the future but it's still not there yet
at least not from what I've seen if you
have a mobile app that you love or
functionality that that you've really
found to be valuable I'm curious do you
find your mobile app to be well worth
the investment in time and money or are
you moving in the other direction of you
know what maybe it's time to bail on the
mobile app it's just not that useful for
our church I'd love to know what you
think but those are my two sents of my
opinions for what it's worth I love
mobile apps I hope they're a big part of
our future in the church but for the
last 10 years I've watched them become
probably too expensive uh and
ineffective for the cost and the time
investment and so I hope that changes
into the future that's my two cents tell
me what you think I'd love to know drop
your thoughts in the comments thanks so
much for watching we'll talk to you
again on the next
[Music]
video 2 1