in this video we're going to talk about
the three most important pages on your
Church website and how to optimize these
three platforms to get the best results
for your Church
website hey there if we haven't met yet
I'm Neil Smith your social media guide
and I help church leaders Ministry
leaders nonprofit leaders maximize
social media to accomplish their
organizational goals and in this video
we're going to talk about church
websites and the three most important
pages that I found to be both from a TRC
standpoint and from a priorities of the
church standpoint and how to optimize
those three pages to get the results
you're looking for for your church so
let's dig into those pages the first
page not surprisingly is the homepage of
your website and this page is important
for a lot of reasons one it's what
Google is looking for as to how people
are going to find your website and so
you've got to make sure you have things
like your church name the city of your
church and things that people would
search and probably your pastor 's name
on there as well and then come to your
Church's website and so when somebody is
searching for your church and I'm in New
York City New York City Church is your
church going to pull up at the top of
those search results well the reality is
if your website isn't easily found by
Google it might as well not exist on the
Internet it's how we find everything the
number one way people often get to our
websites is by even searching our domain
name in Google people just Google search
everything and so don't assume that
everyone's going to know your url to get
to your website you've got to prioritize
your site for Google so making sure it's
optimized or search is key especially
with the homepage of your website the
other is that it's clean I think if
somebody comes into a cluttered lobby at
your church it's going to immediately
turn them off well if somebody comes
into a cluttered website it's going to
immediately turn them off and so have
welcoming faces on the homepage of your
website visuals and make sure it's clean
and easy to navigate make sure your
church name is easily seen make sure
your messaging is welcoming and not just
a bunch of news and announcements for
your church members then you want to
make sure the layout is really laid out
for a firsttime visitor more than a
member now a member is going to find the
information they're looking for on other
pages and navigation through the website
but make sure that homepage is really
laid out well for the visitor and so
that visitor is going to know what time
of your services at where is your church
location what are your service times how
should I dress what should I expect what
your music style some of that basic
information now it might just even be
service times and then you can find out
more information or plan your visit but
make sure you're thinking about that
visitor first and the other thing to
include on that homepage is watch the
latest message because this is a way for
people just like they're checking out a
restaurant on Yelp to see the menu this
is their way to checking out of like do
I resonate with the teaching style or to
the format and even give me an idea of
what should I wear because this is what
the pastor's wearing in that video and
so it gives people idea an opportunity
to engage with your church before they
come so watch the latest message and
plan your visitor kind of those key
calls to action on the homepage of your
website and then just make sure it's
clean and informative beyond that but
don't over complicate it don't over
clutter and prioritize the first-time
visitor on your homepage the second most
important page is I found it and just
from website traffic is about the pastor
or your church leadership page it would
surprise you how many people who are
going to your website are also then
secondarily going to this page on the
website more than small groups more than
Ministries more than anything else
people are checking out the pastor and
so that could be the Pastoral team but
primarily the senior pastor and so on
that page you'd likely want to have a
great photo or maybe a family photo or
maybe multiple photos but give a good
bio and description of the pastor so
that people can understand basically who
leads this church and maybe what is the
the leadership structure of this church
and and I think too what they're looking
for is maybe when I go to Church who
should I connect with and so if you're a
multi-site church you would want to make
sure you have your your campus Pastor
visible and people could find them and
see maybe who that leader is that I
should maybe look to expect to see when
I go to church on Sunday and so make
sure you're thoughtful about that about
the pastor page and so the there will
often be about the church so maybe gives
church history and theology Mission
people check that out but but they're
really primarily focused on the pastor
and so a pastor often like to be like
it's not about me the truth is it's not
about you but you are often a way for
people to feel a person personal
connection with the church before they
attend and so this having this page is
not making it about you it's really
making it about them and what they're
curious about before they connect to get
them integrated into the community and
life of your church and then the third
page that people don't often like to
talk about is the giving page and so
it's like oh we don't want to make it
all about giving we don't have a
flashing red button for giving
definitely don't have a flashing red
button for giving but you do want to
make giving easy for your congregation
giving is a spiritual experience and
giving is an important part of how we do
church and so we want to make sure that
our giving page is integrated naturally
into our website experience so when a
first-time visitor comes they're not
like oh they're just pushing giving
everywhere but when they come and that
you know look people do give here or
when a member is looking to give that
they don't have to look really hard to
give and so we want have a giving
exp is both easy to use I see a lot of
giving Pages where you get to click like
five times to give a gift and you to
sign in and do all this stuff we should
make it really easy to give but we
should also remember giving is a
spiritual experience and so as part of
that giving page maybe we have a video
that that talks about giving maybe we
have resources related to giving that
giving page or scripture passages
related to giving and we don't use that
to pressure people into giving we use
that as just part of the spiritual
experience of giving and you think about
giving in the church they past the
plates we often have offertory music
playing and offertory prayers and things
that we do that really help to enhance
that that spiritual experience of giving
of our resources to God through the
church and so we want to do the same
thing and not just make it transactional
but make that a giving experience
spiritual and meaningful and so there's
ways to do that with our messaging
around that giving experience and so
don't just have hly put a link to a
giving you know form on that giving page
but really be thoughtful in the giving
experience you're creating on the
website so those are the three from my
perspective most important pages on your
Church website I hope that helps if you
have any questions about giving drop
those in the comments or reach out to me
personally I also by the way have a
Church website company that we have have
closed to new signups but if you want to
get on the wait list for that or even
get a free SEO audit for your church you
can go to church press. that's church
press. I'll have a link in the
description below but we' love for you
to check that out and as we reopen up
new signups to build out your church
website we'd love to support you in that
way so go check that out thanks so much
for watching we'll talk to you again on
the next video
[Music]