do you want to get more views on your
YouTube channel of course you do in this
video I'm going to share four tips that
you can apply today to begin to get more
videos on your YouTube channel
[Applause]
today hey there if we haven't met yet
I'm Neil Smith your social media guide
and I help organizations and leaders and
Ministry leaders and church leaders and
nonprofit leaders and small business
owners utilize social media digital
technology any kind of technology to
better accomplish their goals and in
this video we're going to talk about
YouTube uh the platform that you're
likely watching this video on right now
and so here are four tips to help you
maximize your YouTube content to reach
more people the first one is so simple
and straightforward but I've heard this
from Mr Beast over and over again who is
the fastest growing YouTuber in the
history of YouTube and he's like look
it's pretty simple create great content
and and and that's it you know at the
end of the day getting more views on bad
content isn't really a good thing and
YouTube's not going to continue to show
your videos to more people that people
are engaging well with it so the best
way to get more views is to create
better content and and and I think we've
got a question if we're not getting very
many views is it something wrong with
how we're promoting our videos or is it
something wrong with our videos
themselves and so I think we have to
first ask ourselves are we creating
great content and with whatever content
we're creating how can we make it better
so whether maybe it's in the content
itself maybe it's in the production
quality uh may maybe it's in the length
you know there there are different ways
to improve the quality of your content
but you've got to start with are you
creating great content and the better
your content gets the more likely you're
going to get more views the second thing
that we need to think about when it
comes to getting more views is having
titles that are searchable YouTube is
the second largest search engine in the
world and when we often will create our
video titles that we'll say like part
two of this that that kind of describes
something that isn't really that
relative to our video that people aren't
searching and then these are going to
show up we've got to Think answers to
search results that when they search
this our keyword is going to come up
first or in their search term you know
this is right aligned to their search
term so we want to answer people's
questions that they're searching on
YouTube and so we really need to make
sure that our titles are optimized and I
would add description second to that but
our titles are so important in YouTube
search engine algorithm showing our
videos which is the first way that
people are likely going to find our
videos which is then going to be driven
and get more engagement which is going
to drive the recommendation algorithm
which is prioritized based on our
content itself we need to make sure that
our titles are really optimized for
search the third thing and and what many
people would often say is the most
important is your thumbnail your
thumbnail is the basically trigger that
people will decide whether I watch this
or not so once YouTube recommend your
video whether that's through search
results or after they watched another
video uh it's based on that thumbnail of
whether they push play or not so that
thumbnail needs to be visual in a way
that's going to capture people's
attention give them an idea of what's
going to be in the video and create
curiosity so that they'll hit that play
button and watch your video so don't
skimp on the thumbnail definitely don't
use the auto thumbnail generator that
YouTube creates for you I wish YouTube
would create better autogenerated
thumbnails uh and I believe they
probably will in the future because it
is so important uh but at this point I
think whether we use Fiverr or use canva
uh do what you got to do to create great
thumbnails because the better those
thumbnails get uh the better your video
is going to get new views and so keep
improving your thumbnail game uh and
that's going to lead to more views on
your YouTube channel and the last thing
I want to note and the fourth Point uh
to get more views on your channel uh is
kind of going outside of the normal
videos on YouTube and that's moving to
the different format of shorts uh what
YouTube has prioritized is I think
they're trying to bring the Tik Tok
audience into YouTube is shorts so when
you open your mobile app the first thing
that pulls up are shorts uh and and your
shorts are likely going to get way more
virality as a way to engage in new users
than your traditional long form you know
horizontal videos and so we've got to be
creating and distributing shorts if we
want to reach more audience and drive
more views and so it isn't just the same
game we've always played with
traditional horizontal videos we've now
got to either clip our videos into
shorts uh to then drive new videos or
just create videos just made for shorts
uh and and make them in that format
because that's how YouTube is bringing
new people into our channels today and
so we've got to be creating shorts
because that's where YouTube's algorithm
has shifted uh in 2024 and I think we've
got to adapt with that adjustment and
lean into that opportunity I hope that
helped give you some direction to help
you optimize some of your YouTube
workflows I Believe YouTube is the most
important social media platform uh in 20
the 202 uh so I believe in the last four
years and what I believe over the next 5
to six years YouTube is going to be the
most important platform for us to
continue to build and engage an audience
and so I'm glad you're prioritizing it
by watching this video I hope it helps I
would love for you to drop a link to
your channel in the comments I'd love to
check out your channel if there's ever
anything I can do to you you can reach
out to me go to my website nil smith.com
uh and I've got a contact page on there
feel free to send me a message or go to
any of my other socials at Smith send me
a DM I'd love to connect with you uh and
learn more about your YouTube channel or
your organizational goals or help you
however I can thanks so much for
watching we'll talk to you again on the
next video
[Music]
oh