today I thought it was time welcome to
my office I wanted to give you a tour of
my New York City office to show you how
I set it up and uh what I do and where I
am about 9 10 hours a day let's take a
[Music]
look hey there if we haven't met yet I'm
Neil Smith your social media guide and I
help leaders of all kinds Ministry
leaders Business Leaders nonprofit
leaders maximize social media accomplish
their goals and this is where I do that
uh about 10 hours a day you know
multiple days a week when I'm not
traveling and so this is my little eight
foot by eight foot box in New York City
uh where it all happens and so you've
likely seen this background if we've
done Zoom calls or as you've seen some
of my YouTube videos uh this is my
office and so I want to show you not
just this back what's behind me but I'm
going to show you all directions and
basically the setup I use to do all the
work that I do so let's take a look
let's take a look at the desk I've got
this sit stand desk and so I have these
controls down here where I go up and
down and yes I know my cord management
is out of control and that's probably
going to create some stress I also have
down here my over the- ear headphones uh
that I use for podcasting and then this
is hanging on this mic stand is my
Samsung q9u podcast mic that I use and
so I've got it on this boom stand and so
that's what I use for podcasting and
when I do product reviews uh and this is
my screen setup a lot of people ask me
about the first thing I want to point
out is this is my teleprompter I use
this for all my video conference calls
uh and podcasts so that I can basically
make eye contact with people so it's
just a basic teleprompter I'll leave
links to it uh from in Amazon and what I
use uh so I've got three monitor set up
so this is basically set up as my left
monitor this is my Center Monitor and
this is my right monitor this looks
maybe like two monitors but it's just
one uh I like the vertical monitor setup
because he such I can have two things uh
on there two kind of almost like double
monitor stacked is what it what it feels
like I used to use two vertical monitors
over here uh but because I do so many
slide presentations and meetings they
get messed up uh when I am using the
vertical monitor so I have a horizontal
monitor that I primarily use for text
messaging and uh my messaging apps and
of course for chat GPT is always set up
there in that extra window uh and then
for slide presentations when I need to
share those in Zoom calls uh that is the
setup for that I also want to point out
here on my desk is my sister's new book
but God can you go get a copy uh love
you sis bu God can go get that copy and
then I've got my water and and my coffee
mck uh and so yep the essentials for the
desk let's keep going around this way
this is my door uh so I'm in a
co-working space with a bunch of other
offices and so if I keep turning this
way you can see I actually have a uh
frame photo of one of my uh humble
Hedgehog vriends nfts and then I also
have just sound foam and you'll see even
behind my desk I have uh this sound foam
uh then I have a a Center light here
that I use uh for lighting and then
you'll see up here in the corners I have
these two LED lights see if I can go
look up there you can see uh that that's
the lighting that I use for my video
conferencing calls so let's keep
scanning over this way coming around uh
I've got just basic drawers uh with all
my stuff my camera gear my pins pencils
all that kind of stuff I don't really
use pencils but pin and random stuff uh
and then let's get to some of my
favorite cool
[Music]
stuff we'll come over here and then you
will see here on the floor now I got a
small office so it's hard to even create
some space but these are my Astros
chairs these are from the Astrodome in
Houston and these have followed me
around in all of my office spaces and
several of our apartments and so Katie
is happy not to have these in our
apartment uh this is where my daughters
when they come and hang out in my office
where they sit uh and then I've got some
other Astros merch there behind uh and
then I have this lamp that my wife got
me uh and I use this essentially as a
little uh just background light uh for
my zoom calls and for videos and crit
kind of a cool effect and uh I've got
you know my office has Glass Walls here
you can see that uh and then it has this
exposed brick which I love uh and then I
have you know just my basic bookshelves
you can see up here at the top my wife
set that up I've got some be friends
merch and then some of the books that I
wrote uh and then some of my favorite
things here on this shelf I want to
point out just a couple things this is
my Oculus go this was my first kind of
legit uh VR headset this is the iPhone
uh first version iPhone look how small
that thing is if if you could see that
this is a 4 gigabyte iPhone and so I
just kind of keep this for Keepsake in
history and then this is the first ever
Amazon Echo device and so it's a little
beat up uh it doesn't work anymore but
uh it's history so this is kind of my
history shelf uh this is my
grandfather's um just a memory this is a
moving company that he ran and uh he in
many ways has been kind of my business
hero uh and just a hero a lot of ways so
I love having that me memory uh there
from him and here's a Bible uh that dlan
company gave me uh and then moving over
a little bit uh this is a uh YouTube
plaque from one of my clients uh they
actually hit the gold with a million
subscribers and so uh they let me have
the 100K subscribers PLA and uh LinkedIn
gave me this coffee mug when I was in
their offices and then I I like
celebrating this this is the the best
husband award I don't know you can see
this but uh this was given to me uh by
my wife's dance team while back uh and
so when I was there supporting her and
her work there uh and this is this is an
Astros championship ring so I got more
Astros merch here um and then if we
continue to head around you can see here
those rebok and that little gorilla
these are more vends merch uh that came
as a part of uh just being a vs holder
and ex always excited to celebrate uh vs
and what's happening there so let's keep
going
around uh and so here is my fridge so if
you're curious what's in my fridge let's
open it up and see what's in the fridge
well just one thing I only have one
thing just a big bottle of water so
every day I fill this thing up and I
drink the whole thing and then I fill it
up before I leave and that's what's in
the fridge uh I also keep a TV up here I
rarely use it uh I primarily use uh that
TV uh as a way to test TV apps uh as I
helped start a TV app company
if you're interested in that uh and that
is basically my whole office all right
so this is the whole office and that's
the tour hope you enjoyed thanks for
hanging out in my office and if you have
any questions about any of the things
any of the attack or any of the setup in
my office uh yeah just ask me in the
comments I'd love
to let's see so that's my office uh if
you have any questions about uh the
office space the setup the TCH that I
use I'd love to share in the comments
and would love to tour of your office if
you got a link to that uh thanks so much
for just hanging out in my office for
the day this is my 8 by8 box that I
spend the most time in so thanks for
hanging out we'll talk to you again on
the next video
[Music]
a