in this video we're going to talk about
Sam Altman and his recent interview on
the all-in podcast Sam Altman and open
AI have exploded over the last two years
they went from him being fired to him
coming back and this interview is one of
his first interviews back and I believe
it's extremely important in the digital
landscape in the technology landscape
and in the social media landscape we're
going to talk about it all we're going
to dig into the entire interview and
talk about why these conversation and
what he saying and how that's important
to leaders as we look to the Future and
how we begin to integrate AI more into
our businesses into our organizations
moving forward so let's dig into this
interview
together hey there if we haven't met yet
I'm Neil Smith your social media guide
and I help leaders maximize social media
and new technology and a lot of the
focus over the last year has been on AI
and I've looked at a lot of different
software tools that are coming out and
available and there is no more important
company I believe to follow and to
Monitor and Technology specifically to
pay attention to then chat GPT in this
world they are the leaders in this space
and Google's doing some interesting
stuff I think Amazon's got some stuff on
the horizon meta has prioritized AI into
the future but AI has continued to lead
the way and Sam Altman as the leader of
open AI I believe is one of the most
important voices and leaders and
innovators in this space and so I
believe this is a really insightful
conversation I listened to it this
weekend I thought you know what there's
some just nuggets out of this that I
want to dig into and talk about here on
this YouTube channel so let's jump right
into this podcast and I'll pause it in
between and share my thoughts and what I
believe we can take away from what he
shares because there's a lot of things
he doesn't say and he can't say but I
think there's some things that we need
to listen closely to and begin to
understand where this Tech techologies
going and how we can be prepared for
what's coming and how we can begin to
integrate these Technologies effectively
and efficiently into our
organizations experimental fund that Sam
and I were part of a Scouts is sequoia's
highest multiple returning fund couple
of low digigit Millions turned into over
200 million I'm told and then he did
yeah that's what I was told by ruoff
yeah and he did a stint at Y combinator
where he was president from 2014 to 2019
in 2016 he co-founded open AI with the
goal of ensuring that artificial general
intelligence benefits all of humanity in
2019 he left YC to join open aai
full-time as CEO things got really
interesting on November 30th of 2022
that's the day openi launched chat GPT
in January 2023 Microsoft invested 10
billion in November 2023 over a crazy 5
days span Sam was fired from open thei
everybody was going to go work at
Microsoft a bunch of hard emojis went
viral on x/ Twitter and people started
speculating that the team had reached
artificial general intelligence the
world was going to end and suddenly a
couple days later he was back to being
the CEO of open AI in February Sam was
reportedly looking to raise $7 trillion
for an AI chip project this after was
reported that Sam was looking to raise a
billion for masu yoshian to create an
iPhone killer with Johnny I the
co-creator of the iPhone all of this
while cheat GPT has become better and
better and a household name it's having
a massive impact on how we work and how
work is getting done and it's reportedly
the fastest product to hit 100 million
users in history in just two months and
check out opening eyes insane Revenue
ramp up they reportedly hit two billion
in ARR last year welcome okay so let's
just stop right there and you know the
few key things to to notice here and
that they mentioned one I I just got to
say I love the Allin podcast there are a
few podcasts I listen to pretty much
every episode of and this is one of
those podcasts and so they're really on
the Forefront of new technology and
investing and business and and culture
and politics and some really interesting
things so I want to highly recommend the
Allin podcast as a great listen every
week and and to the leaders that are on
in a lot of the interviews that they do
but he talks about how when you know
open AI is one the fastest growing
technology from an adoption standpoint
in the history of technology and and
those of us who have kind of lived
through the internet social media and
the explosion of Tik Tok and some of
these platforms that have grown
tremendously fast this is faster than
anything else we've ever experienced in
history from an adoption standpoint and
then he goes on to talk about when Sam
Alman left everyone is going to go to
Microsoft and I I think this is an
important note that in many ways while
open AI isn't owned by Microsoft it is
Microsoft is very involved both as an
investor in open Ai and an integrator
into open Ai and so I would in some ways
almost consider open AI as a part of
Microsoft and so where we look at Gemini
being you know Google's AI system that
is fully integrated into Google and you
know we look at you know llama and you
know Facebook or meta AI being their big
investment Microsoft is investing
through openai and integrating uh very
closely with open Ai and so I think that
connection
is important as we look to the future of
this technology and who is involved in
what and where we're going to be aligned
and and then the other thing is is that
basically people perceive chat GPD to be
this free tool that's available online
and app their free version is incredible
but they're also making a lot of money
now practically as I understand they're
Lo still losing money their spend is
higher than their revenue and so they
still have a burn right and things
they've got to figure out from a revenue
model standpoint but they figured out
how to make money and and just to grow
that fast in annual revenue is just
unbelievable and so yeah it's pretty
impressive what Sam Alman has done
through open Ai and how fast they're
growing so let's get back to the
interview to the Allin podcast Sam thank
you thank you guys saak you want to Le
us off here okay sure I mean I I think
the whole industry is waiting with
baited breath for the release of
pt5 I guess it's been reported that it's
launching some time this summer but
that's a pretty big window can you
narrow that down I guess where where are
you in the release of GPT 5 uh we we
take our time on releases of major new
models and I don't think we uh I think
it will be great uh when we do it and I
think we'll be thoughtful about how we
do it uh like we may release it in a
different way than we've released
previous models um also I don't even
know if we'll call it G pt5 um what I
what I just going to pause it there real
quickly when they did this interview
they had not yet released chat GPT 40
which is not 4.04 and then the you know
o the the the letter O and you know you
might have seen some of the releases
that have come out where it's almost
more like an Alexa for chat GPT but it
can do a lot more things for you and
it's free and accessible to everyone and
and so it's one of things that chat GPT
just keeps getting better and it's able
to use things like your camera and it's
able to use more video integration and
it's more Voice driven and so for
instead of being text input text output
it's now voice input video output or
Graphics output or you know it's more
conversational in nature more natural
conversation not just text
conversational so he's not talking about
that here because it hadn't yet been
released in this interview and so just
timing I think was tough there of you
know you can see him kind of avoiding
that but he is speaking to you know
we're we're we're constantly looking to
innovate we're trying to be thoughtful
with our releases and and moving quickly
but making sure everything is well baked
before we release it to the public I
will say is you know a lot of people
have noticed how much better gbd4 has
gotten um since we've released it and
particularly over the last few months I
think I think that's like a better hint
of what the world looks like where it's
not the like 1 2 3 4 5 six seven but you
you just you use an AI system and the
whole system just gets better and better
fairly continuously uh and I I just want
to add in here as a chat gp4 user I you
know as I think about all my different
subscriptions that I use professionally
the 20 bucks a month I spend spend on I
think it's what I spend on GPT 4 is it's
probably the last one I would cancel I
mean maybe my my Google Suite with Gmail
and Google Drive is maybe the very last
one and then gp4 being the next one it
is such a valuable tool for the work I'm
doing and it is it since I you know
subscribed maybe four months ago to you
know how I'm using it today I've seen it
improved and so I you know I'm I'm
seeing that as well as not just even
with the iterative improvements just the
ongoing you know improvements that that
that I'm seeing on a regular basis of
using gp4 and so yeah I I second that
we've seen improvements along the way um
I think that's like both a better
technological Direction I think that's
like easier for society to adapt to um
but but I assume that's where we'll head
does that mean that there's not going to
be long training cycles and it's
continuously retraining or training
submodels Sam and maybe you could just
speak to us about what might change
architecturally going forward with
respect to large
models well I mean one one one thing
that you could imagine is this just that
you keep training right a model uh that
that would seem like a reasonable thing
to
me do you think you talked about
releasing it differently this time are
you thinking maybe releasing it to the
paid users first or you know a slower
roll out to get the red teams tight
since now they's so much at stake you
have so many customers actually paying
and you've got everybody watching
everything you do you know is it is it
more now yeah still only available to
the paid users but one of the things
that we really want to do is figure out
how to make more advanced technology
available to free users too I think
that's a super important part of our
mission uh and and this idea that we
build AI tools and make them super
widely
available free or you know not that
expensive whatever it is so that people
can use them to go kind of invent the
future rather than the magic AGI in the
sky inventing the future and showing it
down upon us uh that seems like a much
better path it seems like a more
inspiring path I also think it's where
things are actually heading so it makes
me sad that we have not figure out how
to make gp4 level technology available
to free users it's something we really
want to do it's just very expensive I
take it's very expensive yeah and I I
just want to add to this of it's very
expensive and sometimes people don't
understand that the cost of technology
and it's not just the developers to
develop the software in a technology
like this it is all of the and you'll
hear Sam talk about it later and and
you'll hear it if you listen to other
interviews is it's the compute needed is
the processing needed to have all of
this data to input in you know your your
you know request your message it's not
just like a Google Search and an
algorithm it is having to basically
aggregate all of that knowledge and then
output so rapidly it takes a lot of
computing power and so if you think
early days of the internet part of the
challenge was we people wouldn't want
too much traffic because that would cost
them a lot more in their servers and and
so even you know platforms like Facebook
wouldn't have video natively into their
platform because that that processing
power was too expensive for the revenue
they were generating so they had to some
way slow down Innovation because of
computing power and that's where you are
they
is a lot of it is the expense of the
computing power not just the development
cost but the actual server systems that
power this kind of technology and so
making it available for free is just
cost prohibitive even the $20 a month
I'm I'm confident they're losing money
on those subscriptions they just get
more you know Insight you know from
those users and it helps offset some of
those costs while they innovate and
prepare for the future but it's not you
know Amazon lost money for a long long
time
but they kept building that ecosystem
they kept building the processes where
they were able to in time make money on
fractions of pennies and so they had a
long-term plan and I think chat GPT or
open AI being the parent company has a
great structure and idea I you also want
to note people have often commented on
you know Sam Alman 15 years old he looks
so young and I don't know how old he is
but but he's not this isn't his first
rodeo the guy the guy has had tremendous
business success in the past and and I
think he he really from my perspective
and what I've you know paid attention to
in his background and what he's doing is
you know he's he's a really good leader
thoughtful leader and and I think you'll
pick that up in this interview so I'm
I'm just impressed with how he has led
open Ai and his perspective and how
they're building their business for the
long term not just for the immediate
Revenue
opportunities chamach your thoughts I
think maybe the the two big vectors Sam
that people always talk about is that
underlying cost and sort of the latency
that's kind of rate limited a killer app
and
then I think the second is sort of the
long-term ability for people to build in
an open source World versus a closed
Source world and I think the crazy thing
about this space is that the open source
Community is rabid so one example that I
think is incredible is you know we had
these guys do a pretty crazy demo for
Devon remember like even like five or
six weeks ago that looked incredible and
then some kid just published it under an
open MIT license like open Devon and
it's incredibly good and almost as good
as that other thing that was closed
toour us so maybe we can just start with
that which is tell me about the business
decision to keep these models close
source and where do you see things going
in the next couple years so on the first
part of your question um speed and cost
those are hugely important to us and I
don't want to like give a timeline on
when we can bring them down a lot
because research is hard but I am
confident we'll be able to um we want to
like cut the latency super dramatically
we want to cut the cost really really
dramatically um and I believe that will
happen we're still so early in the
development of the science and
understanding how this works plus we
have all the engineering Tailwinds so
I let me just pause it I don't know like
when we just pausing this real quick I I
think that what we just heard right
there is really important we are still
so early to this science to this
Innovation and and I think this is
important to remember this is dialup
internet days of the worldwide web and
and the internet that we know today the
internet wasn't always on a phone in our
pocket with highspeed data access it was
you know many of us remember when we had
to plug in a computer with AOL and and
and it would take us you know five
minutes to download just one image
that's where we are in this technology
this is the worst it's ever going to be
man we are still early and they're
moving really fast we get to
intelligence too cheap to meter and so
fast that it feels instantaneous to us
and everything else but I do believe we
can get there for you know a pretty high
level of intelligence and um I it's
important to us it's clearly important
to users and it'll unlock a lot of stuff
on the sort of Open Source closed Source
thing I think there's great roles for
both I think um you know we've open
sourced some stuff we'll open source
more stuff in the future but really like
our mission is to build towards AGI and
to figure out how to broadly distribute
its benefits we have a strategy for that
seems to be resonating with a lot of
people it obviously isn't for everyone
and there's like a big ecosystem and
there will also be open source model and
people who built that way um one area
that I'm particularly interested
personally in open source for is I want
an open source model that is as good as
it can be that runs on my phone and that
I think is going to you know the world
doesn't quite have the technology for
for a good version of that yet but that
seems like a really important thing to
go do at some point will you do will you
do that will you release I don't know if
we will or someone will but someone what
about llama 3 llama 3 running on a phone
well I guess maybe there's a 7
billion version yeah yeah uh I don't
know if that's if that will fit on a
phone or not but that should be fitable
on a phone but I don't I I'm not I'm not
sure if that one is like I haven't
played with it I don't know if it's like
good enough to kind of do the thing I'm
thinking about so let's talk quickly
about open source versus closed source
and there's lots of debates about this
in you know just the development world
and open source I think has been made
Popular by WordPress being an
open-source you know website it you know
content management system that people
could then build these plugins and they
could you know use it and then resell
these themes and different things of It
kind of built a base of technology that
could people could build on top of and
then sell things around it and meta has
really communicated their objective in
their AI development has been to build
an open source a you know AI structure
for developers to to work with and what
that does is that speeds up innovation
so that other developers that aren't you
know based on the core you know
technology system can the open AI or
whoever is building it can focus on the
core system while other developers kind
of work on kind of the side aspects of
how people can use that system and so
there are benefits and and you know good
and bad things of Open Source verus
closed source and I think what he's
saying here is there's there's going to
be opportunities in this space not just
for open AI but it was really started
with the idea of being open source and
this is where he and Elon had a lot of
following out falling out is that it's
now moved to being more of a private
company and closed Source model here so
when when llama 3 got released I think
the big takeaway for a lot of people was
oh wow they've like caught up to GPT 4 I
don't think it's equal in all Dimensions
but it's like pretty pretty closed or
pretty in the ballpark I guess the
question is you know you guys released
four a while ago you're working on five
or you know more upgrades to four I mean
I think to jamas point about Devon how
do you stay ahead of Open Source I mean
it's just that's like a very hard thing
to do in general right I mean how do you
think about
that what we're trying to do is not
make the sort of
smartest set of Weights that we can but
we're trying to make is like this useful
intelligence layer for people to use and
a model is part of that I think we will
stay pretty far ahead of I hope say
pretty far ahead of the rest of the
world on that um but there's a lot of
other work around the whole system
that's not just that you know the the
model Waits and we'll have to build up
enduring value the old fashion way like
any other business does we'll have to
figure out a great product and reasons
to stick with it and uh you know deliver
it at a great price when you founded the
organization you the stated goal or part
of what you discussed was hey this is
too important for any one company to own
it so def needs to be open then there
was the switch hey it's too dangerous
for anybody to be able to see it and we
need to lock this down because you you
had some fear about that I think is that
accurate because the cynical side is
like well this is a capitalistic move
and then the I
think you know I'm I'm curious what the
decision was here in terms of going from
open we the world needs to see this it's
really important to close only we can
see it well how did you come to that
that conclusion what would the part of
the reason that we released chat GPT was
we want the world to see this and we've
been trying to tell people that AI is
really important and if you go back to
like uh October of 2022 not that many
people thought AI was going to be that
important or that it was really
happening um and a huge part of what we
we try to do is put the technology in
the hands of people uh now again there's
different ways to do that and I think
there really is an important role to
just say like here's the weights have at
it but the fact that we have so many
people using a free version of chat GPT
that we don't you know we don't run ads
on we don't try to like make money on we
just put out there because we want
people to have these tools um I think
it's done a lot to provide a lot of
value and you know teach people how to
fish but also to get the world um really
thoughtful about what's happening here
now we still don't have all the answers
and uh we're fumbling our way through
this like everybody else and I assume
we'll change strategy many more times as
we learn new things
I I just want to pause real quick and
and and he's saying here that we just
want to generously give away GPT 3.5 or
this free version to people and and
while I think there is pro a general
desire to do that and and make it more
accessible I think the reality is while
doing that they're able to get
tremendous insights on how people are
using it and the system becomes smarter
the more people use it and and he said
earlier
to we're focused on intelligence and I
think people often forget about this
with artificial intelligence that this
isn't just you know I think when we
think about the worldwide web it was an
aggregate of data and information where
intelligence goes a step further where
it takes that aggregate of intell of
knowledge and information that used an
algorithm to then help help you find
that knowledge and integration to
intelligence takes your knowledge and
and you make decisions based on your
knowledge to effectively respond to
situations and people and to take
actions and and so that's what this is
doing is it's taking knowledge and it's
aligning a you know layer of
Intelligence on top of that to get
smarter when somebody requests this this
is how I go and find them and help them
you know solve this problem and make
this decision and do this task on their
behalf and so this is where intelligence
becomes this just mindblowing you know
Innovation and what happens for all of
us as people intelligent beings is the
more decisions we make the more things
we learn the more experiences we have
the smarter we get the more intelligent
we become and that's what they are
building this system to do is to
basically take not just our brains to
store knowledge but our decision making
our intelligence processing that we de
develop as humans over time and build
these systems to be intelligent similar
to how humans are you know when we
started open AI we had really no idea
about how things were going to go um
that we'd make a language model we'd
ever make a product we started off just
I remember very clearly that first day
we were like well now we're all here
that was you know it's difficult to get
this set up but what happens now maybe
we should write some papers maybe we
should stand around a whiteboard and
we've just been trying to like put one
foot front of the other and figure out
what's next and what's next and what's
and I think we'll keep doing that can I
just replay something and just make sure
I heard it right I think what you were
saying on the open source close Source
thing is if I heard it right all these
models independent of the business
decision you make are going to become
asymptotically accurate towards some
amount of accuracy like not all but like
let's just say there's four or five that
are well capitalized enough you guys
meta Google Microsoft whomever right so
let's just say four or five maybe one
startup and on the open web and then
quickly the accuracy or the value of
these models will probably shift to
these proprietary sources of training
data that you could get that others
can't or others can get that you can't
is that how you see this thing evolving
where the open web gets everybody to a
certain threshold and then it's just an
arms race for data beyond that doesn't
so I definitely don't think it'll be an
arms race for data because when the
models get smart enough at some point it
shouldn't be about more data at least
not for training it may matter data to
make it useful um look the the one thing
that I have learned most throughout all
this is that uh it's hard to make
confident statements a couple of years
in the future about where this is all
going to go and so don't want to try now
I I will say that I I expect lots of
very capable models in the world and you
know like
it feels to me like we just like
stumbled on a new fact of nature or
science or whatever you want to call it
which is like we can create you can like
I mean I don't believe this literally
but it's like a spiritual point you know
intelligence is just this emergent
property of matter and that's like a
that's like a rule of physics or
something um so people are going to
figure that out but there will be all
these different ways to design the
systems people will make different
choices figure out new ideas and I'm
sure like you
know like any other industry I would
expect there to be multiple approaches
and different people like different ones
you know some people like iPhones some
people like an Android phone I think
there'll be some effect like that I want
to go back to he he's continuing to
repeat the word intelligence and that
this is not about more data and and I
think we can see and I think it's often
being compared to like Google and search
engines and I think we've seen Yahoo and
Bing and other search engines and Google
won the race for search engines and it
became better by aggregating as much
data and the algorithms it built
connected to this data what this is is
being built is is is basically like we
have access to all of the the data in
the world the worldwide web has given us
that now it's
basically how intelligence how
intelligent can these models become will
these models become more intelligent by
training them and that's done by through
development but it's also done by users
using it and giving it feedback and just
like we as humans we get better through
every experience that we have and the
more experiences we have the more
intelligent we become but our minds
sometimes deteriorate or you know have
have certain weaknesses but these
Technologies don't you know have that
same human you know limitation they have
higher capacity in so many ways and so
it's of like if you're going to choose
between gemini or llama or chat GPT
you're going to choose the most
intelligent one the one that really is
the smartest and it's like hiring your
next executive leader which one is the
smartest that's going to help you make
the best decisions or is not going to
help you but maybe just make themselves
the best decisions that's the AI model
that you want to use and so that's
that's really what they're they're
developing intelligence which is it's
just it's a whole new mindset shift that
we've got to make as we approach this
Technology Innovation let's go back to
that first section of just the the cost
and the
speed all of you guys are sort of a
little bit rate limited on literally
nvidia's throughput right and I think
that you and most everybody else have
sort of effectively announced how much
capacity you can get just because it's
as much as they can spin out what needs
to happen at the substrate so that you
can actually compute cheaper
compute faster get access to more energy
how are you helping to frame out the
industry solving those problems well
we'll we'll make huge algorithmic gains
for sure and I don't want to Discount
that you know I very interested in chips
and energy but if we can make our if we
can make a same quality model twice as
efficient that's like we had twice as
much compute right and I think there's a
gigantic amount of work to be done there
uh and I hope we start really seeing
those results um other than that the
whole supply chain is like very
complicated you know there's there's
logic Fab capacity there's how much hbm
the world can make there's how quickly
you can like get permits and pour the
concrete make the data centers and then
have people in there wiring them all up
there's fin the energy which is a huge
bottleneck but
uh I think when there's this much value
to people uh the world will do its thing
we'll try to help it happen faster um
and there's probably like I don't know
how to give it a number but there's like
some percentage chance where there is as
you were saying like a huge substrate
breakthrough and we have like a
massively more efficient way to do
Computing but I don't I don't like Bank
on that or spend too much time thinking
about it what about the device side and
sort of you mentioned sort of the models
that can fit on a phone so obviously
whether that's an llm or some slm or
something I'm sure you're thinking about
that but then does the device itself
change I mean is it does it meet to be
as expensive as an iPhone
uh I'm super interested in this uh I I
love like great new form factors of
computing and it feels like with every
major technological Advance a new thing
becomes
possible
uh phones are unbelievably good so I
think the threshold is like very high
here like what like I think think like I
personally think an iPhone is like the
greatest piece of technology enity has
ever made it's really a wonderful
product what comes after it like I don't
know I mean I was going to that was what
I was saying it's so good that to get
Beyond it I think the bar is like quite
High well you you've been working with
Johnny IV on on something right I I I
want to just pause here real quickly is
they're talking about you know basically
Hardware now and one you know the
hardware needed with servers and things
like that that that I mentioned earlier
but now they're talking about basically
the iPhone being such a great product
and people are often like what's the
next thing is it VR is it AR is it you
know mixed reality is it like Google
Glasses things like that and he's like I
don't know you know so this is a guy
that lives in this world and he knows
what's limiting his essentially software
to be accessible to everyone and him
saying the iPhone is the greatest
invention ever made or basically
Hardware device ever created and I think
that's pretty significant to understand
and I think how important that mobile
technology is going to continue to be
into the future and so he he he really
is kind of like look this is the the
basically the primary Hardware platform
that we believe we need to be
integrating with for this technology to
get the best adoption in use and so I I
think this just speaks to our mobile
world is going to probably stay mobile
for you know a a distant future and so
as disruptive as the phone was there's
not going to be anytime soon likely
another phone that that is going to be
so significant to disruption from a
hardware perspective been discussing
ideas but uh I don't like if I knew is
it that that it has to be more
complicated or actually just much much
cheaper and simpler well every almost
everyone's willing to pay for a phone
anyway so if you could like make a way
cheaper device I think the barrier to
carry a second thing or use a second
thing is pretty high so I don't think C
given that we're all willing to pay for
phones or most of us are I don't think
cheaper is the
answer different is the answer then
would there be like a specialized chip
that would run on the phone that was
really good at powering a you know a
phone size AI model probably but the
phone manufacturers are going to do that
for sure that doesn't that doesn't
necessitate a new device I think you'd
have to like find some really different
interaction Paradigm that the technology
enables uh and if I knew what was I
would be excited to be working on it
right now but oh you have you have voice
working right now in the app in fact I
set my action button on my phone to go
directly to chat gpt's voice app and I
use it with my kids and they love it
talking to it it's got latency issues
but it's really we'll we'll get that
we'll get that better and I think voice
is a hint to whatever the next thing is
like if you can get voice interaction to
be really good it
feels I think that feels like a
different way to use a computer oh okay
this this was a big and I think he's
really teasing chat GPT for in in this
statement as voice is a hint and and I
think we have seen this development
through the years with Alexa and as
Alexa has integrated into our homes more
and into you know our mobile devices and
and become a very valuable tool to use
our voice to get information off of the
internet but now voice is expanding to
another level to actually be intelligent
and so we are now having or can have a
conversation with an a form of
intelligence and not just a you know a
voice triggered action item driven by an
algorithm and so this is I think a big
significant development of where this is
going is we've seen it as a chat box on
a screen to now a conversation that we
can have in our headphones or with our
our home speakers and things like that
so I think this is a pretty pretty
significant kind of leak that he's
hinting at here or or kind of teasing
out here but again with that by the way
like why why is it not responsive and
you know it's it feels like a CB you
know like over over it's really annoying
to use you know uh in that way but it's
also brilliant when it gives you the
right answer we are working on that uh
it's it's so clunky right now it's slow
it's like kind of doesn't feel very
smooth or authentic or organic like
we'll get all that to be much better
what about computer vision I mean they
have classes or maybe you could wear a
pendant I mean you take the combination
of visual or video data combine it with
voice and now ai knows everything that's
happening around you super powerful to
be able to like the multimodality of
saying like hey chbt what am I looking
at or like what kind of plant is this I
can't quite tell
um that's obvious that that's like a
that's another I think think like hint
but whether people want to wear glasses
or like hold up something when they want
that like I I there's a bunch of just
like like the the sort of like societal
interpersonal issues here are all very
complicated about wearing a computer on
your face um we we saw that with Google
Glass people got punched in the face in
the mission started a lot of I forgot
about that forgot about that so so I I
think it's
like what are the apps that could be
unlocked if AI was of ubiquitous on
people's
phones do you have a sense of that or
what would you want to see built
uh I I think what I want is just this
always on like super low
friction thing where I
can either by voice or by text or
ideally like some other it just kind of
knows what do I want have this like
constant thing helping me throughout my
day that's got like as much context on
as possible it's like the world's
greatest assistant um and it's just this
like thing working to make me better and
better uh there's there there's like a
and when you hear people like talk about
the AI future they imag they imagine
there's sort of
two different approaches and they don't
sound that different but I think they're
like very different for how we'll design
the system in practice there's the I
want an extension of myself um I want
like a ghost or an alter ego or this
thing that really like is me is acting
on my behalf is um responding to emails
not even telling me about it is is is
sort of like it it becomes more me and
is me and then there's this other thing
which is like I want a great senior
employee it may get to know me very well
I may delegate it you know you can like
have access to my email and I'll tell
you the constraints but but I think of
it is this like separate entity and I
personally like the entity approach
better the thing is not you but it's
it's like a always available always
great super capable assistant EXA okay
now I think we're getting into where AI
is replacing jobs and and I think he's
saying basically it can be that
assistant that is taking notes in your
meeting we're seeing AI apps like that
and or can be that assistant that you
don't like you're like hey what is that
that I'm looking at and it can tell you
what that is or you know even look when
you look at the the refrigerator that
your milk is getting low so I'm going to
just automatically order that for you or
and it's just always there to help you
throughout your day whether that's work
related personal related calendar
related email related it's assisting you
in those kind of just tasks that we just
have to get done but then he's also
saying it can also be like a senior
level you know executive too that can
help you make better just decisions and
analyze and see things on the horizon
and and I think this is a unique
challenge with Humanity we have seen new
technologies you know through the years
and in agriculture and other things that
have replaced human labor jobs but I
think this is replacing a lot of both
you know hourly employee type of work
and you know salary executive type of
work and decision making that might
require fewer Executives in an
organization because AI now has a seat
at the table to help you make uh better
decisions you might not need that
consultant or you might not need those
other senior level Executives because AI
is using its intelligence to help you so
it's just pretty big conversation of
what's to come and you can see where and
that's really beneficial from an
efficiency standpoint but and that gets
really complicated from a societal
standpoint an agent in a way like it'ss
out there working on your behalf and
understands what you want and
anticipates what you want is what I'm
reading into what you're saying I think
there'd be agent like Behavior but
there's like a difference
between a senior employee and an agent
yeah and like I want it you know I think
of like my I think like a like one of
the things that I like about a senior
employee is
they'll they'll push back on me they
will sometimes not do something I ask or
they sometimes will say like I can do
that thing if you want but if I do it
here's what I think would happen and
then this and then that and are you
really
sure I definitely want that kind of vibe
which not not just like this thing that
I asking at blend does it can reason
yeah yeah and push back it can reason it
has like the kind of relationship with
me that I would expect out of a really
competent person that I worked with
which is different from like a siop Fant
yeah I I think this is an important note
here of we are going to have a form of
relationship with AI or with you know AI
systems that is complicated and and I
think we're seeing even the societal
impact of that already where people are
in many ways having like a romantic
relationship with these AI Bots and it's
kind of sick and twisted in a lot of
ways but it becomes you know it's
interesting because you know my kids
might tell you that Alexa is a part of
our household but it's not like we have
an actual relationship but this AI that
we're really talking about here is going
to learn us it's going to understand
it's going to understand how we need to
be communicated with and how we like to
be communicated with and it will adapt
to us and we will have you know a
relationship it's different than human
relationship but I think sometimes it's
going to be complicated of do we end up
liking AI better than we like other
people people you know like this AI is
going to do whatever we ask it to do but
it's also saying it's going to push back
on you too maybe if you want it to and
so this is this is a really interesting
dynamic as we start thinking about
intelligence and and the interactions
that we're going to have with this
technology in the future and so yeah
it's it's very heady when you start
going down those paths in your mind and
obviously they're they're putting a lot
of thought and and and insights into how
they're developing it around those
things in that world where if you have
this like Jarvis like thing that can
reason what do you think it does to
products that you use today where the
interface is very valuable so for
example if you look at an instacart or
if you look at an Uber or if you look at
a door Dash these are not services that
are meant to be pipes that are just
providing a set of apis to a Smart Set
of agents that ubiquitously work on
behalf of 8 billion
people what do you think has to change
in how we think about how apps need to
work of how this entire infrastructure
of experiences need to work in a world
where you're agentically interfacing to
the world I'm actually very interested
in designing a world that is equally
usable by humans and by AIS so I
I I I like the interpretability of that
I like the smoothness of the handoffs I
like the ability that we can provide
feedback or whatever so you know door
Dash could just expose some
API to my future AI assistant and they
could go put the order in whatever or I
could say like I could be holding my
phone and I could say okay AI assistant
like you put in this order on door Dash
please and I could like watch the app
open and see the thing clicking around
and I could say hey no not this or like
um there there's something about
designing a world that is
usable equally well by humans and AIS
that I think is a interesting concept
I'm like excited about humanoid robots
than sort of robots of like very other
shapes the world is very much designed
for humans I think we should absolutely
keep it that way and a shared interface
is nice so you see voice chat that
modality kind of gets rid of apps you
just ask it for sushi it knows Sushi you
likeed before it knows what you don't
like and does its best shot at doing it
I it's hard for me to imagine that we
just go to a world totally where you say
like hey Chachi BT order me sushi and
it's say okay do you want it from this
restaurant what kind what time whatever
I think user I think visual user
interfaces are super good for a lot of
things um and it's hard of me to imagine
like a world
where you'd
never look at a screen and just use
voice mode only but I I can imagine that
for a lot of things yeah I mean Apple
tried with Siri like you supposedly you
can order an Uber automatically with
Siri I don't think anybody's ever done
it because
why would you take the risk of not well
the quality to your point the quality is
not good but when the quality is good
enough you're you'll actually prefer it
just because it's just lighter weight
you don't have to take your phone out
you don't have to search for your app
and press it and oh it automatically
logged you out oh hold on log back in oh
TFA it's a whole pain in the ass you
know it's like setting a timer with Siri
I do every time because it works really
well and it's great I need more
information but ordering an Uber like I
want to see the prices for few different
options I want to see how far away it is
I want to see like maybe even where they
are on the map because I might walk
somewhere I get a lot more information
by I think in less time by looking at
that order the Uber screen than I would
if I had to do that all through the
audio Channel I like your idea of
watching it happen that's kind of cool I
think there will just be like yeah
different there are different interfaces
we use for different tasks and I think
that'll keep going of all the developers
that are building apps and experiences
on open AI are there a few that stand
out for you where you're like okay this
is directionally going in a super
interesting area even if it's like a toy
app but are there things that you guys
point to and say this is really
important um I met with a new company
this morning or I'm barely even a
company it's like two people that are
going to work on a summer project trying
to actually finally make the AI tutor
like and I've always been interested in
this space a lot of people have done
great stuff on our platform but if if
someone can deliver like the way that
you actually
like they used a phrase I love which is
this is going to be like a monory level
reinvention for how people how people
learn things yeah um but if you can like
find this new way to like let people
explore and learn in new ways on their
own I'm personally super excited about
that I I just want to add to this even
as a parent and and a learner that that
this is a really powerful opportunity is
the Educational Opportunity where you
could say chat gbt teach me how to play
the violin and then it is like our coach
along the way and it's learning like no
CH change that or do this and it's a
personalized tutor that knows where we
are can respond to that and and I think
about how we've done that to date a lot
of times we'll just either buy a course
online or we'll you know go to YouTube
and like teach me how to do this or you
know somebody's training and now chat
GPT can actually be a teacher that is
creating a
personalized teaching experience for you
now I'm really intrigued of what does
this look like in you know the the
actual education space for kids growing
up but I think even as adults anything
we want to learn how to do allowing you
know AI systems to be educational for us
as humans is is a really fascinating use
of this technology I love that that he's
focused on that um a lot of the coding
related stuff you mentioned Devon
earlier I think that's like a super cool
vision of the future the thing that I am
Health Healthcare I I believe should be
pretty transformed by this but the thing
I'm personally most EXC yeah I just want
to pause there so he said coding and
Healthcare I'm very intrigued by both of
these I've worked kind of in both of
these spaces coding you know one of the
things they they've often said is you
know as these things come along we're
going to just teach people how to code I
think coding is actually going to become
more of the least useful you know things
to to know in the future because AI will
code better than humans code that would
be one of the first tasks I think that
AI or is already one of the first tasks
that that is being replaced by Ai and so
why coding infrastructure software
engineering is is still going to be
critically important what direction we
take it but the actual writing of code
can be done so well by Ai and then the
healthcare side of if you think about
just even some of the scans the way AI
could re scans could read our blood you
know and we run things through computers
already but it's going to go to another
level of just learning and understanding
health and wellness and basically being
able to better give us insights of each
of us individually what our bodies are
needing and where deficiencies are and
we've seen this even with like the Apple
watch and some of the features that are
available through new technologies but
AI is going to be a big part of that and
it's very exciting and I'm I'm really
intrigued to see even with cancer
research where a plays into that so huge
opportunities there excited about is the
sort of doing faster and better
scientific discovery gp4 clearly not
there in a big way although maybe it
accelerates things a little bit by
making scientists more
productive but Alpha 43 yeah that's like
but Sam that will be a Triumph those are
not like these these models are trained
and built differently than the language
models I mean to some obviously there's
a lot that's similar but there's a lot
um there's kind of a groundup
architecture to a lot of these models
that are being applied to these specific
problem sets these specific applications
like chemistry interaction modeling for
example does you you'll need some of
that for sure but the the thing that I
think we're missing across the board
from many of these things we've been
talking about is models that can do
reasoning and once you have reasoning
you can connect it to chemistry
simulators or I guess yeah that's the
important question I I wanted to kind of
talk about today was this idea
of networks of models people talk a lot
about agents as if there's kind of this
linear set of call functions that happen
but one of the things that
arises in biology is networks of systems
that have cross interactions that the
aggregation of the system the
aggregation of the network produces an
output rather than one thing calling
another that thing calling another do we
see like an emergence in this
architecture of either specialized
models or network models that work
together to address bigger problem sets
use reasoning there's computational
models that do things like chemistry or
arithmetic and there's other models that
do rather than one model to rule them
all that's purely
generalized I don't know
um I don't know how much reasoning
is going to turn out to be a super
generalizable thing I suspect it will
but that's more just like an intuition
and a hope and it would be nice if it
worked out that way I I don't know if
that's
like but let's walk through the the
protein modeling
example there's a bunch of training data
images of proteins and then sequence
data and they build a model predictive
model and they have a set of processes
and steps for doing that do Envision
that there's this artificial general
intelligence or this great reasoning
model that then figures out how to build
that sub model that figures out how to
solve that problem by acquiring the
necessary data and then resolving
there's so many ways where that could go
like maybe it is it trains a literal
model for it or maybe it just like knows
the one big model what it can like go
pick what other training data it needs
and ask a question and then update on
that um I guess the real question is are
all these startups going to die because
so many startups are I I just want to
jump in here as we think about where
this technology is going you can hear
you know the these wheels spinning among
the these different leaders and and I
think this is like early days of the
internet is who like one we didn't even
know about a phone that was going to
come or we we couldn't have predicted
highspeed internet and that you know our
televisions would now be all connected
to the internet and all the TV we'd
watch would be on the internet and we'd
have a mobile device that we use for our
camera camera and we watch you know
videos on and we use to Uber a car or
deliver food or pay our bills and
deposit checks and all the things that
our phones do today with the internet
and so it's kind of this innovation of
hardware and software that has made our
lives better in a lot of ways and more
accessible and simultaneously I think we
we can agree that there's been aspects
of the addictiveness of social media and
just screen use that has been
problematic too to society and so we're
we're in this day of like we can see
what's developing and and beginning to
connect dots of now we can do this or
now we can unlock this and now and so it
it simultaneously there's some
complexities we have to be thinking
about but there's also just all of these
potential new opportunities and I think
this is where there's such a unique
opportunity for leaders is when when you
you have to understand what this is and
and functionally how it works but then
when you can begin to connect those dots
to your mission and what you're doing
and and I think the other side of it is
we also have to part of our reaction can
be well this is going to cost people
like what what are they going to do
anymore what are they going to do or you
know and and and the reality is is every
entity even pre- internet you know
there's things that ways that we
communicate we sent out Direct Mail we
did manual phone calls and then we used
email and then we you know moved to text
messaging and and so we we have
different ways that we do things and we
are going to adapt adapting to this
Innovation is going to be such a an
important issue for us as Leaders to
adapt within our organizations but I
think we need to not just think about
how we're going to react to to some of
the the adjustments that are going to be
need to made but how are we going to
need to lean into the opportunities that
are now going to be created I think
that's where we we can really get into
some exciting potential with this and so
yeah I I think I I hope your wheels are
spinning like theirs are around some
just ideas of when you really think
about this innovation of Intelligence
being created and how that can be
utilized within our organizations
working in map modality which is go get
special data and then train a new model
on that special data from the ground up
and then it only does that one sort of
thing and it works really well at that
one thing and it works better than
anything else at that one thing you know
there there's like a version of this I
think you can
like already see when you were when you
were talking about like biology and
these complicated networks of systems
the reason I was sming I I got super
sick recently and I'm mostly better now
but it was just like body like got beat
up like one system at a time F like you
can really tell like okay it's this
cascading thing and uh and that reminded
me of you like talking about the like
biology is just these like you have no
idea how much these systems interact
with each other until things start going
wrong and that was sort of like
interesting to see but I was using
um I was like using chat GPT uh to try
to like figure out like what was
happening whatever and and would say
well I'm you know unsure of this one
thing and then I just like posted a
paper on it without even reading the
paper um like in the context and it says
oh that was the thing I was unsure of
like I think this instead so there's
like a that was like a small version of
what you're talking about where you can
like can say this I don't I don't know
this thing you can put more information
you don't retrain the model you're just
adding it to the context here and now
you're getting them so these models that
are predicting protein structure like
let's say right this is the whole basis
and now now other molecules and Alpha
3 can they can yeah I mean is it
basically a world where the best
generalized model goes in and gets that
training data and then figures out on
its own and maybe you could maybe you
could use an example for us can you tell
us about Sora your video model that
generates amazing moving images moving
video and and what's different about the
architecture there whatever you're
willing to share on how how that is
different yeah so my on the general
thing first
my you clearly will need special
ized simulators connectors pieces of
data whatever but my
intuition and again I don't have this
like backed up with science my intuition
would be if we can figure out the core
of generalized reasoning connecting that
to new problem domains in the same way
that humans are generalized
reasoners would I think be be doable
it's like a fast unlock faster unlock
than I think I I think so um
but yeah you Sora like does not start
with a language model um it's that
that's a model that is like customized
to do video uh and and so like we're
clearly not at that world yet right so
you guys so just as an example for you
guys to build a good video model you
built it from scratch using I'm assuming
some different architecture and
different data but in the future The
General generalized reasoning system the
AGI whatever system thetically could
render that by figuring out how to do it
yeah I mean one example of this is like
okay you know as far as I know all the
best text models in the world are still
Auto regressive models and the best
image and video models are diffusion
models and that's like sort of strange
in some sense yeah yeah so there's s
want to speak to this real quick and
what he's kind of saying is when you get
to AGI you know artificial general
intelligence is the word that's used
here a lot this is what scares a lot of
people is basically this is when it
becomes smarter than humans and when
when you get there essentially if the
you know the the intelligence doesn't
yet know how to do something it
basically goes and says then I'm going
to tell myself to go and learn how to do
that and so you almost teach it how to
learn and then when it learns how to
learn that it learn you know and it and
so this is how it just keeps learning is
it in many ways it learns how to learn
and and just mindblowing how this will
work and and honestly just how smart
these intelligence
models can and will become and and I
think this is where you know for many
people it gets scary to think about but
yeah pretty pretty heavy you know he
stuff to think about the big debate
about uh training data you guys have
been I think the most thoughtful of any
company you've got licensing deals now
ft Etc and uh we got I guess be gentle
here because you're involved in a New
York Times lawsuit you weren't able to
settle I guess an arrangement with them
for training data how do you think about
fairness in fair
use we've had big debates here on the
Pod obviously your actions are you know
speak volumes that you're trying to be
fair by doing licensing deals so what
what's your personal position on the
rights of artists who create beautiful
music lyrics books and you taking that
and then making a derivative product out
of it and and then monetizing it and and
what's fair here and how do we get to a
world where you know artists can make
content in the world and then decide
what they want other people to do with
it yeah and and I'm just TR to your
personal belief because I know you to be
a thoughtful person on this and I know a
lot of other people in our industry are
not very thoughtful about how they think
about content
creators so I think it's very different
for different kinds of I mean look on
unfair use I think we have a a very
reasonable position under the current
law but I think AI is so different that
for things like art we'll need to think
about them in different ways but I would
say if you go read a bunch of math on
the internet and learn how to do math
that
I think seems unobjectionable to most
people and then there's like you know
another set of people who might have a
different opinion well what if you
like actually let me not get into that
just in interest of not making this
answer too long so I think there's like
one category people are like okay
there's like generalized human knowledge
you can kind of like go if you learn
that like that's that that's like open
domain or something if you kind of go
learn about the Pythagorean theorem um
that one end of the spectrum and then I
think the other extreme end of the
spectrum is um is Art and maybe even
like more than more specifically I would
say it's like
doing it's a system generating art in
the style or the likeness of another
artist um would be kind of the furthest
end of
that and then there's many many cases on
the Spectrum in between
uh I think the conversation has been
historically caught up on training data
but it will increasingly become more
about what happens at inference time as
training data
becomes less valuable and the what the
system does accessing you know
information in in context in real time
or uh you know taking like like
something like that what happens at
inference time will become more debated
and and how the what the new econom IC
model is there so if you say like
uh song in this in the style of Taylor
Swift even if the model were never
trained on any Taylor Swift songs at all
you can still have a problem which is it
may have read about Taylor Swift it may
know about her themes Taylor Swift means
something and then and then the question
is like should that model even if it
were never trained on any Taylor Swift
song whatsoever be allowed to do that
and if so um how should Taylor get paid
right so I think this this is so
interesting and and a big debate and I
don't live in in this world so much but
but I think about as you think about
this being intelligence that that there
is this complexity of you know
practically any artist that is creating
something has been inspired by other
artists to develop their art and
essentially what these intelligence
models that are already creating art
they can create graphics or if you ask
chat G to write you a poem about red
roses it will write you a poem about red
roses and and it's pretty good and then
that was created based on just
inspiration from other poems that
historically been created and the
intelligence these systems have gained
from things like that and so it really
is complicated as we think about what
the future of Art and even films will be
you could have it in the future just say
hey create a cartoon about this and this
you know you know and these AI systems
will be able to generate this art for
you and and I think this is going to be
a big question into the future of I
think some of the questions are what
what should and what from a consumption
standpoint do we want to consume things
that were created by AI or do we really
want to guard you know art in in certain
ways or different mediums so yeah it's
really really fascinating uh to to begin
to think about there's an opt-in opt out
in that case first of all and there's an
economic model um staying on the music
example there is something interesting
to look at from the historical
perspective here which is uh sampling
and how the economics around that work
this is not quite the same thing but
it's like an interesting place to start
looking Sam let me just challenge that
what's the difference in the example
you're giving of the model learning
about things like song structure Tempo
Melody Harmony relationships all the
discovering all the underlying structure
that makes music successful and then
building new music using training data
and what a human does that listens to
lots of music learns about and and their
brain is processing and building all
those same sort of predictive models or
those same sort of uh discoveries or
understandings what's the difference
here and why why are you making the case
that perhaps artists should be uniquely
paid this is not a sampling situation
you're not the AI is not outputting and
it's not storing in the model the actual
ual original song learning structure
right I wasn't trying to make that that
point because I agree like in the same
way that humans are inspired by other
humans I was saying if you if you say
generate me a song in the style of
Taylor Swift I see right okay where the
prompt leverages some artist I I think
personally that's a different case would
you be comfortable asking or would you
be comfortable letting the model train
itself well a music model being trained
on the whole Corpus of music that humans
have created without royalties being
paid to the artists that um that music
is being fed in and then you're not
allowed to ask you know artists specific
prompts you could just say hey pay me
play me a a really cool pop song that's
fairly modern about heartbreak you know
with a female voice you know we we have
currently made the decision not to do
music and partly because exactly these
questions of where you draw the lines
and you know like
even I was meeting with several
musicians I really admire recently just
trying to like talk about some of these
edge cases but even the world in
which if
we went and let's say we paid 10,000
musicians to create a bunch of music
just to make a great training set where
the music model could learn everything
about strong song structure um
and what makes a good catchy beat and
everything else um and only trained on
that let's say we could still make a
great music model which may maybe we
could um you know I was kind of like
posing that as a thought experiment to
musicians and they're like well I can't
object to that on any principal basis at
that point um and yet there's still
something I don't like about it now
that's not a reason not to do it um
necessarily but it
is did you see that ad that Apple put
out maybe it was yesterday or something
of like squishing all of human
creativity down into one really thin
iPad what was your take on
it uh people got really emotional about
it yeah yeah stronger reaction than you
would think there's something
about I'm obviously hugely positive on
AI but there is something that I think
is beautiful about human creativity and
human artistic expression and you know
for an AI that just does better science
like great bring that on but an AI that
is going to do this like deeply
beautiful human creative expression I
think we should like figure out it's
going to happen it's going to be a tool
I I I just I love you know and and you
can hear his wrestle this is one of the
things I love is it's not like you know
what we just need to get over ourselves
and you know like AI is going to just
you know like we need to embrace all the
great things it does and he's he's
really sharing this very real wrestle
with humanity and how Humanity will be
affected by this technology and how
important this aspect of humanity is
that you know maybe there's not maybe
this really does diminish our our
Humanity if we prioritize this aspect of
innovation with AI and so I I I love
that he's at least articulating this
tension because it's kind of say it's
going to happen whether we like it or
not but there's also like something
maybe we should be intentional to guard
this aspect of humanity that will lead
us to Greater creative Heights but I
think we should figure out how to do it
in a way that like preserves the spirit
of what we all care about here and I I
think your actions speak loudly we were
trying to do Star Wars characters in
Dolly and if you asked for Darth Vader
it says hey we can't do that so you've I
guess red teamed or whatever you call it
internally you're yeah you're not
allowing people to use other people's IP
so you've taken that decision now if you
asked it to make a Jedi Bulldog or a
Sith Lord Bulldog which I did it made my
bulldogs at Sith bulldogs so there's an
interesting question Spectrum right yeah
you know we put out this thing yesterday
called the spec um where we're trying to
say here are here's here's how our model
is supposed to
behave and it's very hard it's a long
document it's very hard to like specify
exactly in each case where the limits
should be and I view this as like a
discussion that's going to need a lot
more input um but but these sorts of
questions
about okay maybe it shouldn't generate
Darth Vader but the idea of a Sith Lord
or a Sith style thing or Jedi at this
point is like part of of the culture
like like these are these are all hard
decisions yeah and and I think you're
right the music industry is going to
consider this opportunity to make tellor
swi songs their opportuni it's part of
the four-part fair use test is you know
these who gets to capitalize on new
Innovations for existing art and and
Disney has an argument that hey you know
if if you're going to make Sora versions
of a aoka or whatever Obi-Wan Kenobi
that's Disney's opportunity and that's a
great part parnership for
you you know to pursue so we're I think
this section I would label as AI in the
law so let me ask maybe a higher level
question what does it mean when people
say regulate AI totally Sam what does it
what does that even mean and comment on
California's new proposed regulations as
well if you if you're up for it uh I'm
concerned I mean there's so many
proposed regulations but most of the
ones I've seen on the California state
things I'm concerned about I also have a
general fear of the states all doing
this them themselves um when people say
regulate AI I don't think they mean one
thing I think there's like some people
are like be on the whole thing some
people like don't allow it to be open
source required to be open source um the
thing that I am personally most
interested in is I think there will
come look I may be wrong about this I
will acknowledge that this is a
forward-looking statement and those are
always dangerous to make but I think
there will come a time in the not super
distant future like you know we're not
talking like decades and decades from
now where AI the frontier AI systems are
capable of causing
signant Global harm and for those kinds
of systems and the same way we have like
Global oversight of nuclear weapons or
synthetic bio or things that can really
like have a very negative impact Way
Beyond the realm of one country uh I
would like to see some sort of
international agency that is looking at
the most powerful systems and ensuring
like reasonable safety testing you know
these things are not going to escape in
recursively self-improve or
whatever I I I just want to speak to
even the way he talked about art and the
way he's talking about this is that that
he's and and and in other things he's
been proactive in just saying this space
needs regulation we need you know some
boundaries to work within and I think we
have seen this with big Tech that in
many ways they've gone they've moved
faster than government regulation can
keep up with and and I think this is
another you know situation here where
the government doesn't know what it is
even to make regulation around it and so
I I don't know you know the answer here
I you know I think what gives
me peace in this is everything I hear
and see and experience with Sam Alman
and some of these other leaders is I
think their intentions are good and how
do we prevent this from being used
you know in in negative ways and in
dangerous ways because there will be
opportunities to do that and I think if
we can get ahead of what those ways
might be and how to regulate it we can
actually create you know greater safety
boundaries for these companies and for
these innovators and you know even for
the government and how the government
uses Ai and so I I think this is a
really important conversation and I
think it's not a real easy conversation
but I think his concerns are valid is
some of the regulations people are
talking about are all over the place and
I think they come in many ways from from
a lot of ignorance too that that's going
to limit innovation in some ways create
even more reactive behavior when when we
get behind as you know with with this
technology so it's a it's an interesting
topic that doesn't have a good solution
but it anything that has been proposed
to date definitely does not seem like
the optimal Solution that's for sure the
criticism of this is that you're you
have the resources to Cozy up to Lobby
to be involved and you've been very
involved with politicians and then
startups which you're also passionate
about and invest in um are not going to
have the ability to Resource uh and deal
with this and that this regulatory
capture as per our friend you know Bill
Gurley did a great talk last year about
it so maybe you could address that
headon do do you if the line were we're
only going to look look at models that
are trained on computers that cost more
than 10 billion or more than 100 billion
or whatever dollars I'd be fine with
that there'd be some line that'd be fine
and uh I don't think that puts any
regulatory burden on startups so if you
have like the the nuclear raw material
to make a nuclear bomb like there's a
small Subs set of people who have that
therefore you use the analogy of like a
a nuclear inspector kind of situation
yeah I think that that's interesting sax
you have a question tras go ahead you
had to follow
can I say one more thing about that of
course I'd be super nervous about
regulatory overreach here I think we can
get this wrong by doing way too much I
or even a little too much I think we can
get this round by doing not enough
but but I do think part of and
I and now I mean you know we have seen
regulatory overstepping or capture just
get super bad in other areas um and you
know like also maybe nothing will happen
but but I think it is part of our duty
and our mission to like talk about what
we believe is likely to happen and what
it takes to get that right the challenge
Sam is that we have statute that is
meant to protect people protect Society
at large what we're creating however a
statute that gives the government rights
to go in and audit code to audit
business um Trade Secrets uh we've never
seen that to this degree before
basically the California legislation
that's proposed and some of the federal
legislation that's been proposed
basically requires the fed the
government to audit a model to audit
software to audit and review the
parameters and the weightings of the
model and then you need their check mark
in order to deploy it for commercial or
public use and for me it just feels like
we're trying to re in the the the the
government agencies for fear and and
because folks have a hard time
understanding this and are scared about
the implications of it they want to
control it and because they want and the
only way to control it is to say give me
a right to audit before you can release
it clueless they're cluess I mean the
way that the the stuff is written you
read it you're like G to pull your hair
out because as you know better than
anyone in 12 months none of this stuff's
going to make sense anyway totally right
look the reason I have pushed for an
agency based approach for for kind of
like the big picture stuff and not a
like write it in laws I don't in 12
months it will all be written wrong and
I don't think even if these people were
like True World experts I don't think
they could get it right looking at 12 or
24 months um and I don't these policies
which is like we're going to look at you
know we're going to audit all of your
source code and like look at all of your
weights one by one like yeah I think
there's a lot of crazy proposals out
there um by the way especially if the
models are always being retrained all
the time if they become more dynamic
again this is why I think it's yeah but
but like when before an airplane gets
certified there's like a set of safety
tests we put the airplane through it um
and totally it's different than reading
all of your code that's reviewing the
output of the model not reviewing the
insights of the model and and so what I
was going to say is I that is the kind
of thing that I think as safety testing
makes sense how are we going to get that
to happen Sam and I'm not just speaking
for open a I speak for the industry for
for Humanity because I am concerned that
we draw ourselves into almost like a
dark ages type of era by restricting the
growth of these incredible technologies
that can prosper human that that
Humanity can prosper from so
significantly how do we change the the
sentiment and get that to happen because
this is all moving so quickly at the
government levels and folks seem to be
getting it wrong and I'm I'm person
concern just to Sam the architectural
decision for example that llama took is
pretty interesting in that it's like
we're going to let llama grow and be as
unfettered as possible and we have this
other kind of thing that we call Lama
guard that's meant to be these
protective guard rails is that how you
see the problem being solved correctly
or do you see at the current at the
current strength of models definitely
some things are going to go wrong and I
don't want to like make light of those
or not take those seriously but I'm not
like I don't have any like catastrophic
risk worries with a gp4 level model um
and I think there's many safe ways to
choose to deploy this
[Music]
uh may maybe we'd find more common
ground if we said that uh and I like you
know the specific example of models that
are capable that are technically capable
not even if they're not going to be used
this way of recursive
self-improvement um or
of you know
autonomously designing and deploying a
bioweapon or something like that or new
model that was the recursive
self-improvement Point um you know we
should have safety testing on the
outputs at an international level for
models that you know have a reasonable
chance of of posing a threat there uh I
don't think like GPT 4 of course does
not pose any sort of well I want to say
any sort cuz you don't yeah I don't
think the gp4 poses a material threat on
those kinds of things I I just want to
add real quick on this point is that I
think this is really smart is let's
create some Universal just safety
testing procedures before any model is
released to the public now this
obviously we've got to have efficiency
in those processes so they don't just
get stalled but just like before you
release you know medicine or any other
things before they release the public
they got to go through testing and and I
think that that this is a thoughtful way
to make sure that there's room for
constant Innovation but there's also you
know effective safety testing and you
know maybe you know stamps of approval
that that get put on on certain models
that that become before they become more
publicly available and I think there's
many safe ways to releas a model like
this um but you know when like
significant loss of human life
is a serious possibility like airplanes
or any number of other examples where I
think we're happy to have some sort of
testing framework like I don't think
about an airplane when I get on it I
just assume it's going to be safe right
right there's a lot of hand ringing
right now Sam about
jobs and you had a lot of I think you
did like some sort of a test when you
were at YC about Ubi and you've been our
results in that come out very soon just
it was a 5-year study that wrapped up um
or started 5
ago well there was like a beta study
first and there was like a long one that
ran but can you explain yeah why you
start why you start it maybe just
explain Ubi and why you started it um so
we started thinking about this in 2016
uh kind of about the same time started
taking AI really seriously and the
theory was that the magnitude of the
change that may
come to society
and jobs in the economy and sort of in
some deeper sense than that like what
the social contract looks like
um meant that we should have many
studies to study many ideas about new
new ways to
arrange that um I also think that you
know I'm not like a super fan of how the
government has handled most policies
designed to help poor people and I kind
of believe that if you could just give
people money they would make good
decisions the market would do its thing
and you know I'm very much in favor of
lifting up the floor and reducing
eliminating poverty um but I'm
interested in better ways to do that
than what we have tried for the existing
social safety net and and kind of the
way things have been handled and I think
giving people money is not going to go
solve all problems it's certainly not
going to make people happy but it
might it might solve some problems and
it might give people a better Horizon
with which to help themselves and I'm
interested in that I I think
that now that we see some of the ways so
2016 was very long time ago uh you know
now that we see some of the ways that AI
is developing I wonder if there's better
things to do than the
traditional um conceptualization of Ubi
uh like I
wonder I wonder if the future looks
something like more like Universal basic
compute than Universal basic income and
everybody get gets like a slice of GPT
7's compute and they can use it they can
resell it they can donate it to somebody
to use for cancer research but but what
you get is not dollars but this like
productiv slice yeah you own like part
of the productivity right I would like
to shift to the gossip so I I think this
is one of the most interesting aspects
of this conversation where he's getting
into Universe basic income and the
societal effects of and and he talked
about something that is that before they
even started developing a chat GPT they
started thinking about what could be the
societal effects of this technology and
maybe we need to do some research around
Universal basic income or he proposes
their Universal basic compute that seem
Ubi is already hard you know I think to
to comprehend just giving away money and
how that will affect things but
Universal comp complicates that even
more but but really interesting that
that you could tell even from the
beginning of open AI they've been
thinking about how big this is and how
significant this will affect the future
and I love that they approached it from
that standpoint instead of just
developing something been like oh no now
what do we do and I think that's kind of
what happened with Facebook is it just
got so big and they're like we're going
to connect the world but no now that you
know this is affecting people and it's
addictive and you know now now I don't
know what to do now and obviously
there's been some you know progress made
and priorities you know adjusted but so
often Innovation happens and then we
react to the The Fallout of it and
they're thinking ahead of that even from
the beginning of building out the
technology so I just want to wrap up
this video and this conversation and I I
ended you can go listen to the rest of
the conversation that kind of get into
the drama of what happened at Microsoft
and with open Ai and him getting fired
and and and you know I think that's an
interesting story but but I think at the
end of the day I I think what we can
hear here he here but but we what we can
pay attention to is that this is very
significant open AI has been very
thoughtful in what they're building and
that this is just the beginning and so
I'm I'm really I think the more I listen
to Sam Alman the more I'm impressed with
him as a leader the more my mind begins
to think about what's coming and
practically what I'm seeing is Chad gbt
is incredibly efficient and effective
for me today but what it's going to be a
year from now is going to be way better
than what it is today honestly what it
is since this interview came out and
with you know GPT 40 uh it has gotten
even better and so I'm really excited
about where it's going I'm really
excited about the opportunities I I want
to continue to also lean into the
societal effects and and be a part of
those Solutions as well and so for
leaders I think we have an opportunity
here to continue to learn continue to
lean in and pay attention to what open
AI is doing and and what meta is doing
what Google is doing and this Technology
Innovation is going to imp impact our
world I believe just as significantly as
the internet has and as our mobile
devices have and maybe even more so and
so this this is coming this isn't kind
of a a quick Trend this isn't basically
like a new website this is a new this is
intelligence that is being built into
technology and it's powerful and it's
exciting and it's scary and it's
overwhelming and and I think we've got
to just lean in in this moment and learn
and prepare and adapt and adjust and so
I'm excited I would love to know what do
you think about drop it in the comments
I'd love to hear from you and hear your
thoughts on this conversation thanks so
much for listening and watching and I
look forward to connecting with you and
growing with you together as we lean
into social media Technology Innovation
all the things and become better leaders
as we lean in to these Technologies
thanks so much for watching and we'll
talk to you again on the next video
[Music]
oh