Mr Beast just launched his new software
platform called view stats and I
subscribe to it so you don't have to
maybe you want to in this video I'm GNA
dive into every aspect of the software
and whether I think it's a good
investment for you if you're a YouTuber
and you want to grow your
channel hey there if we haven't met yet
I'm Neil Smith your social media guide I
make videos about software technology
and social media to help you grow your
organization using social media and
digital technology and so we're going to
dig into Mr BEAST's new software
platform he just released I saw him
tweet about it if we call it tweets uh
still on X and I was like I got to check
out you know Mr Beast is the gold
standard in social media he has led the
Way's fastest growing YouTuber in the
history of YouTube Built multiple
businesses now on the back of his social
media influence and he's a genius if
you've ever watched any of his content
where he talks about how he's built his
YouTube channel and so I pay attention
to everything he does and when he
released the software I was like I've
got to find out everything that this
does why he built it how he built it and
at the end of the day is this useful for
me and is this useful for others so
let's dig into the platform first thing
I notice when I get to the website is
it's basically call to action is search
any YouTube channel and so I'll do what
it says I'll search any YouTube channel
I'll actually search for
myself there I am here's my channel and
it's going to give me all these stats
about my YouTube channel uh and so you
can see I can find out about myself
youat subs and it's actually tracking
bringing in all of this data and this
looks a lot like YouTube analytics in in
the back end uh and so he's pulling this
out now I could do this though with any
channel so I can see this of my own
channel but then I could also go to Gary
ve and I can look at his channel and I
can see what's his estimated Revenue
what's his estimated growth what's
spiking and if it spiked on this day
what did he do that his channel did so
well on this day what videos was it
shorts was it long form uh and then you
can get into things like looking at his
videos or even projections of where's
his channel what's the growth Trend
that's expected based on his existing
growth trend on his channel uh you can
look at similar channels so what other
channels are similar to his channel and
if if I'm paying attention to him as a
model for how to better utilize social
media then uh this is going to be a good
tool to effectively dig in and learn
about others uh that have similar
channels to his I can go to the about
section and see basically all of this
data uh that that really is you know
available there through YouTube and it's
bringing it all into one platform and so
it's a great research tool and it's it's
a free platform uh one of the other
things that I I just want to note note
uh with this platform as I go let me go
back to the homepage here is it's just
clean and simple of searching a YouTube
channel and then they also have this
light mode and dark mode and I just love
sites uh that make that available uh I
am one of those people that likes dark
mode uh and so love that he integrated
that but it's very simple and clean uh
but then what jumps out to me is view
stats Pro get more views with the best
tools for YouTube and so this is the
software product so he gives you a free
tool right here to get data and insights
and basically learn about other channels
and research and I think one of the
things that so many people think in in
any kind of business is you know what I
I want to be me uh but but I think how
we become ourselves is so often learning
from others that come before us and so
researching other YouTubers and finding
out what worked for them saves us a ton
of time it's silly to think that we
shouldn't look at history uh to learn
from history and YouTube's history is
short uh but I think there is a lot of
history and this is basically a history
platform of based on the history of
YouTube this is what has worked for
those that are succeeding on YouTube if
you want to succeed on YouTube you
should look and learn from others not
just try to figure it out for yourself
and hope hope you identify it uh you
know save yourself a lot of time and
learn from others and so I wanted to
look at you know what's what is the
upgrade to Pro uh what what is you know
if this is the free platform uh what
what does Pro get you and so the value
proposition is very simple create videos
that get more views that's the value
proposition so if you're a Creator on
YouTube do you want to reach more people
with your videos do you want more people
to see them that's what this is designed
to help you do now I think what I
immediately think is is this vid IQ you
know is this comparable to vid IQ uh and
we'll get into that comparison later um
so there have been other tools or to
buddy is is another similar tool out
there uh but this is coming from the
perspective and mind of Mr Beast and I
watch this video I'll let you go and
watch this video on his site uh but but
essentially he goes in to say this is
not something I am promoting for another
business this is my platform that I
built for me and now I'm making it
available to you and one of the things
that I have l about listening to Mr
Beast and his process of building his
YouTube channel is how hungry he
constantly is to learn and improve and
optimize uh his channel and listen and
learn from others to see what's working
for them uh so that his videos can reach
a bigger and broader audience and so he
says here get to know Pro built for
creators organize and brainstorm your
next upload make better decisions with
better data supercharge your YouTube
channel sync with powerful Chrome
extension you know if you're fam with
vid IQ they got a great Chrome extension
uh and then it starts with five game
changing tools one of the things he says
in the video is it's starting with five
tools uh they've got several others that
they're working on and will release soon
uh and I love hearing that that this
isn't a finished product this is the
basically Alpha version of this product
and what's available so you can track
track long and short outlier videos in
every category we'll get into what uh
what that looks looks like uh then you
can get notified for video alerts search
thumbnails and URLs explore AB test uh
create your video and thumbnail
prototypes and collections uh and then
supercharger growth with YouTube with
view stats Pro uh and that's what you
get with it so I went in they've got
some FAQ so I went in and signed up so
let's just jump right into the actual
platform itself so once you subscribe uh
this is the back end so you kind of
start uh with this home uh page and then
you can add this
a Chrome extension uh to your browser
and then you've got these five features
alerts outliers thumbnail search AB test
and collection so let's go through each
of these features one by one uh and talk
about what they do uh and how they can
help so alerts is a way for you to go in
and and create certain things that that
you're looking for so I I make videos
about social media and technology and so
I went in and and created uh alerts
around videos like that so you can say
you know I want to create alerts for new
technology videos that are coming out uh
I want them to have a minimum of 100,000
views uh only long form uh not shorts uh
I want them to be in English uh they're
advanced settings where you can add more
things in there uh they could be have
technology related I'll just do create
and now it will be monitoring videos
around technology that match that
criteria and when new videos come out
and they hit that threshold uh I'm going
to be alerted and then what I can do
when I get a video that is trending
around that topic I can go look at it
and I can learn from it of oh that's an
interesting thumbnail that they chose
that's an interesting title uh that they
chose this is how it performed and and
maybe it's a timing thing um with that
video and and I can get as much insights
as basically YouTube is going to share
about this video and it will help me as
I'm creating videos around the same
Niche uh it's going to give me ideas uh
of what's working for others uh so that
I can create uh similar videos and and
be paying attention to the trends and
what's what's picking up uh with the
video so then getting into outliers
outliers was an interesting and a
feature that I you know is definitely
not in any other platform that I'm aware
of and so you can also similarly I I'll
put in uh things like uh technology or I
could search social media here uh and it
will look for
videos that perform well on other
channels and you know it significantly
better than their other videos in a
certain Niche and and I think this gives
us a unique opportunity of this was not
necessarily you know this stood out
across their other videos so what is it
about these videos that basically went
viral compared to their other videos uh
and it it this gives us another learning
and so so much of this platform I I
think we look for software to with AI to
do it for us this platform is not that
this platform is really an education
ational platform uh as I've gotten to
know it to help us better understand
YouTube better understand what's working
why it's working how it's working and
getting insights uh and and I think it
it's the value proposition is for those
people that are just deeply curious
about how YouTube's algorithm works and
how we can get more views by better
understanding the platform and what
what's working for others so that
outliers uh I think can really help us
within our niche to begin to look at
maybe it was something to do with their
thumbnail or their title uh or things
that that made that video pop out in
comparison to their other videos then
going into thumbnail search uh one of
the cool things you can do here is
actually plug in your thumbnail uh and
and post a you know a video about that
or I could just type in a uh a search
here for social media trends and it will
pull out the top thumbnails for videos
related to social media media trends and
I can look at what what is it about
these thumbnails that worked that I can
learn from for my YouTube channel uh if
I'm posting a video about that or maybe
I'm going to make a video about Twitter
uh or let's just say Instagram uh and so
I'll I'll search Instagram here and uh
these are the videos that pop the most
uh when it came to Instagram and so
finding what's uh what's working uh with
thumbnails and basically not directly
copying it but you you know integrate uh
those features those layouts those
things that worked on those other videos
they're likely going to also be
effective for you uh then you can go
into AB test one of the things that's
fascinating is YouTube is now making it
available for people to run AB tests uh
with their thumbnails and and upload
multiple thumbnails and then it decides
after a couple of weeks which thumbnail
performed best and that's what gets
locked in and so you can just go in and
look at basically all of the recent test
and see you know uh was it this one on
the r or this one on the left uh with
lender borrow uh well it was the one
Bolder test text that worked better what
you that gives you a learning of let me
use Bolder text uh with my thumbnails if
I'm if I'm considering you know even
though I might prefer the way this looks
this is performing better or this ice
cream video they use some of these
screenshots or the thumbnail with a
little you know uh text box in there uh
with the ice cream and a face on there
well yeah it's not surprising that that
worked but that was a test that was run
and uh and that worked or this coinbase
uh video was it the coinbase logo or the
phone screen that performed better the
phone screen perform better and so it
it's giving you insights and and I can
do this you know similar where I can go
by video I can go by channel uh and look
at other other people's test and and to
see what works uh with their thumbnails
and what YouTube's algorithm is
essentially telling them and so when we
run test instead of you know guessing
with three you know optimiz optim cized
thumbnails uh we can actually look at
all of these make our best guest with
our three best thumbnails and instead of
blindly creating different thumbnails
and doing our own AB test so it doesn't
mean we stop doing ab test I think we
learn from other people's AB test to
make our AB test that much more
effective and the collections is a way
to basically bring in and so I just uh
pulled in a video so if I were to even
go into outliers again U and then say I
wanted to save this one I can just do
save to collection and I'll choose
social media trends and I'll add it to
that
collection and so when I go down here I
can look at these different videos and
so if I go into it it will give me deep
insights on that specific video and what
uh you know how it performed and where
it took off and so that the analytics
that are available uh with that video
and so it's helpful uh for us to just be
continue to just learn and study uh
especially people that are in a similar
Niche and space as us that that that
have gone before us and have tested a
lot of different things and likely just
because we know who they are and we have
seen several of their viral videos
there's probably you know that's we're
only seeing probably 1% of their videos
uh because they had tested into the
success that they found rarely do people
just automatically with their first
video go viral and then every video
after that is also you know massively
engaging Mr Beast took 5 years before he
even had like a thousand subscribers as
I understand
and so it takes time to grow and learn
but we don't have to wait 5 years we can
learn from Mr Beast years of learning uh
and he's making this platform available
to do that so that's view stats Pro
that's everything uh that's available
right now with the software so let me
share my thoughts so as I look at this
platform from Mr Beast I I think kind of
my initial thought is it's $50 a month
is how how much it costs for this on a
monthly basis or if you do annual it's I
think $40 a month uh unless you're
pretty serious YouTuber that's a pretty
significant expense for a hobby YouTube
channel uh and I think as an agency
owner is very valuable to me as I
managed you know 20 probably plus
YouTube channels uh within our agency
and so it is a high value to us or if
you are serious YouTuber tremendous
value or if you plan on getting more
serious about YouTube look $50 a month
for the education that a platform like
this is going to bring you I think
that's a high value if I'm compare
comparing this to like vid IQ
uh as a somewhat similar platform vid IQ
has a lot more features a lot more
functionality uh it's been around a lot
longer uh I'm going to keep using both
platforms and I am really excited to see
where this goes what I what I have
learned about Mr Beast is is that he
doesn't just halfway put things out
there and then he does he doesn't just
stop innovating around it and YouTube is
his greatest passion so as I think about
what he's done uh with febles and his
other businesses or even his own YouTube
Chann channel uh he's obsessed with
getting better and and so this platform
in its base state is pretty cool and for
$50 a month I I think it's it's a really
great Tool uh and so I'm going to keep
using it I'm going to say stay
subscribed I can't wait to see what his
new features are uh and so I think it's
up to you whether you you are ready to
invest in YouTube and I think $50 a
month is an investment in yourself and
your own education even if you just did
it for a month and just obsessed and
studied over what you could learn
through this platform in a month I think
it's a high value and so I I think it's
super cool even the free platform of
just looking at other channels I think
that's cool alone and so I I love that
Mr Beast put out something that everyone
can use but if you're serious about
YouTube 50 bucks a month uh I think is a
good investment uh into where you want
to go uh and and look I'm serious about
YouTube uh I I it is where the majority
of my attention is right now for myself
and for my clients and so yeah this is a
great investment for me uh and so I have
no affiliate link for this it's brand
new uh it's you know we'll see where it
goes I'll I'll make an update video
probably soon but it just came out this
week I just subscribed I had had to get
in early and see what it was all about
and you know looks pretty cool so far uh
so check it out let me know drop your
thoughts in the comments if you have any
questions about it how it works or uh
what what it can do I'd love to help
answer your your questions or hear what
you think uh do you think this is a good
uh direction that Mr Beast has taken
with this software platform are you
using it anything that features uh that
you're using that you're getting the
most value out of I'd love to hear from
you and have a conversation with you
about view stats YouTube uh all the
things and if you want help uh with your
social media efforts love for you to
reach out to us uh and our team and
amplify social media you go to amplify
social. media check out our website uh
we've got a contact uh form on there
we'd love to hear from you and help you
in any way we can we manage TurnKey
social media services for leaders so if
you want help taking your social media
to where it is to where you desire for
it to go we'd love to help you get there
uh so just reach out to us and our team
we'd love to connect with you there
thanks so much for watching and we'll
talk to you again on the next video
[Music]
n