this is how to make content that
converts $2 on Instagram reals this is
the same strategy that I used to go from
0 to $68,000 in Mr in one month it's the
same strategy that I use in all of my
Instagram reels to go from 50,000
followers at the beginning of this year
to now 181,000 followers on Instagram
this video is for business owners and
you are currently posting on Instagram
but not getting sales this video is
going to be high level so it's going to
centered completely around how to
convert through your Instagram real
there's other steps to the funnel
there's going to be a many chat there's
going to be a landing page in vssl but
specifically there's three things you
need to do in your content in order to
actually get people to want to buy from
you later down in the funnel and these
three things are you don't want to sell
directly in your content you want social
proof and you want natural tonality so
the first thing with sending a free
guide that sells is you don't want to
sell directly in your content you don't
want to say click the link and buy and
then send them directly to a sales page
or even a book call Page and the reason
why is because in your content these
people are strange
when you post a video onto Instagram
reals when you post a video onto Tik Tok
these people have never seen your face
before and they have no reason to
actually want to trust you enough to buy
from you in fact if they see that you're
actually here to sell somebody something
they will not even want to watch you and
your watch time will Skyrocket down to
the point where your video will not get
pushed out if viewers can even have an
inkling that you're here to sell that's
the precipice of this entire content
strategy is being that kind of like
nonchalant dude on Instagram reals who
doesn't seem like they have something to
sell you because what viewers hate most
especially on these social media
platforms that are super top of funnel
like Instagram Tik Tok and even YouTube
shorts is that they don't want to feel
their sales resistance go up because
they feel like somebody he's here simply
to sell them so the first thing is send
them to a free guide AKA just say in
your video comment blah blah blah and
I'll send you a free guide and this free
guide can be in the form of a PDF I've
done a Google doc PDF that's converted
before or it could be in the form of a
long form video like this but either way
send them to a free guide especially one
that's longer that you can convey more
more information more of your expertise
so then people can trust you more
instead of simply trying to sell
directly through your video and be like
go click the link and buy or go book a
call or go apply in my Linkin bio
because people need more of a reason to
trust you first second way to get people
to trust you in your content enough to
buy from you is social proof and you
want to specifically put the social
proof in the first 10 seconds or another
metric I like to use is simply in the
first to second sentence of your video
now what is social proof for those of
you who aren't acquainted like internet
marketing social proof is simply proof
that you know what you're talking about
through either numbers or stories and I
use that in almost all of my content
especially a Content that is educational
that is providing straight value which
is the highest converting form of
content on social media it's just
teaching the viewer something related to
whatever your info product or coaching
or Consulting business is and providing
that kind of numerical proof of results
like I scale the business from0 to
$68,000 in Mr in one month I've gone
from 50 to 180k on instagam this year
these kind of numbers are what really
get people to instantly trust you and
you can go on this long spiel about why
people should trust you because you're
this like cool guy you're just like
super ethical super trustable guy or you
could just simply drop a number and
people can't refute numbers because it's
so quick yet so point it too and it's so
specific if your number is bigger than
their number they're going they're going
to want to listen to you because it's
just inherent in our human DNA to
compare and it's probably going to piss
your viewers off a little bit when you
just throw out numbers but trust me
every single big business owner is
killing it with their content is
dropping social proof whether it's like
I make a million dollars a month or I've
scaled a company to like I think was it
like 100 million for Alex rosi people
use this kind of social proof and they
use it super early on to capture your
attention and make sure you don't fall
off out of distrust so use it in the
first 10 seconds drop whatever number or
story that is most compelling to your
info product in that first 10 seconds
now the last thing that you need to do
in your content and if you don't have
this one it's absolutely going to kill
your retention and it's also going to
kill your ability to convert to any
sales is your tonality if you have this
like really wacky tonality where it's
super forced where you feel super
constricted like you're trying to play
this characterist it's it's not your
real voice it's some like content voice
where it's like this is the best
automation that you need to use people
want to buy from like actual human
beings they're not here on Tik Tok
Instagram reals especially to watch
anybody who's like here to sell them
directly it sounds like an ad it sounds
like they're about to get CTA in like
the first two seconds and people hate it
viewers hate it actually will be a
massive detriment if your tonality
sounds really forced so I highly
recommend somebody talk in a normal
talking voice as if you're talking to a
friend I always say imagine a friend on
the other side of the camera I know it's
really difficult talking to a camera
with like natural tonality but it takes
practice and just try and get your body
in a more relaxed State of Mind simply
because if your body's in a more relaxed
state of mind then your videos and your
tonality is going to come off a lot more
naturally sit back relax take a deep
breath before you film your
videos and then start spitting sausage
your videos use that social proof in the
first 10 seconds and then when you do
your CTA call it to action where you
want people to actually start converting
to that next step in your funnel which
is your many chat then simply say
comment blah blah blah and I'll send you
a free thingy bob now I just covered
very raw basics of how to get your
content to sell I haven't covered how to
get your content to get way more reach I
haven't covered like the actual Min chat
automations how to set those up the
landing page vsl Etc I have all of that
in my content Academy I also have like
full videos script templates so I have
guides on exactly what buttons to press
while you're editing your videos what to
film where to film how to film things
like that I also have like a popping
community on Discord of like super high
level creators entrepreneurs people who
are starting out as well and lastly we
have group coaching calls twice a week
where we review your content if you want
any of that simply just join the content
Academy Down Below in the link in this
description and thank you guys for
watching