in the last two semesters of college I
have hit 10K a month not just once but
seven times and here are the three
things that I had to give up that I wish
somebody told me sooner and the first
thing you have to give up is this need
to socialize and I know you're probably
thinking dude that's the freaking point
of college that's why I'm here is to
socialize and I guess also like get a
degree I guess okay that was me freshman
year before I made any k a month every
single night after a long day of classes
I even hit the gym right I know big
whoop it was so difficult I had to so Iz
I had to get my injection of social
dopamine because I could not function
without it every time I saw in the group
chat yo come over to room 301 we're like
we're going to play poker we're going to
drink tonight I had to go okay there was
this like massive massive itch of fomo
and even if there wasn't any plans going
on I was the one to tell people yo let's
hang out yo let's get dinner let's get
food and it doesn't sound bad because
it's healthy to socialize at least
that's what people tell you but you have
to understand and the reason why this is
linked to hitting 10K a month or AKA
just hitting your goals and getting
actual difficult goals is that hanging
out with friends is a metaphor for
simply relying on vices to stay happy
and safe this could be your afternoon
video games for all you care okay for me
it was hanging out but you have to
understand that if you are constantly
relying on this Vice for your highest
source of dopamine you're not going to
have the motivation to actually go out
and do the hard thing it's not fun
compared to going out and drinking at
least temporarily but as long as this
temporary instant gratification is your
highest source of joy in your life
you're not going to want to actually
pour your love and your attention your
serious effort into your outside
Endeavors because you're not going to be
able to compartmentalize and your hour
of socializing every day is a lot more
insu than it seems which it brings me to
point number two which is that you have
to stop caring about having Aura on
campus and this sounds really silly but
the reason why socializing especially
for that 60 minutes a day especially if
you're this massive social butterfly
who's liked on campus who has a ton of
friends I wasn't necessarily like that
but I valued my friendships and I valued
how people thought of me and saw me the
reason why this will get in the way of
you hitting 10K a month with whatever
side hustle side hustle or online
business that you want to actually
pursue is because it's going to make you
look weird inherently with any side
hustle that you actually put your full
effort and love into you're going to
have to tell your friends yo my bad I
can't hang out I can't all today because
I need to work on my Drop Shipping Store
or I need to work on my Tik Tok shop
videos and they're going to be like what
the [ __ ] does that even mean it's lame
and you're going to have to repeatedly
go through that cycle of turning down
hangouts or turning down longer Hangouts
because you have to work on your own
thing and that's what it takes this was
a serious issue for me in the last
semester of college between January and
may I Grew From 50,000 to 150,000
followers over 100,000 followers
increased and during that time I had to
post once every single day and I didn't
have the time to like meticulously
re-shoot every video video 10 times
every single day make sure the message
is just just perfect enough so it
doesn't step on any toes you just have
to keep showing up and eating [ __ ] and
eating dirt and posting a video that
you're not proud of that's going to
embarrass you because you're putting a a
bit too much of yourself out there
putting being a little bit too chalant
on camera because that's what actually
gets attention on social media or you're
going to be making Tik Tok Shop videos
and one of them actually goes viral and
then your friend's going to start
sending it into group chats and saying
this dude make a freaking ad for ash
Honda pills what the [ __ ] is he doing
meanwhile the kids who are actually
doing that every single day for 30 days
straight are the ones who are making 10
15K a month from Tik Tock shop in order
to achieve anything extraordinary which
is realistically hitting 10K a month in
college it's really uncommon you have to
be a little bit too chalant and too
effortful at what side hustle project
that you're working on and you have to
get over this obsession with making sure
everybody likes you your friends are
going to subconsciously judge you
because you are doing different things
and especially when you integrate my
third point which is probably the
craziest one which is that you have to
give up your academic prowess and this
one is probably the most insane one okay
and this doesn't apply to everybody me
personally I was a business major I was
a marketing major at Boston College
finishing my marketing degree and
getting a marketing position at some
random company making like 50 60k a year
I did not want that for myself and so I
literally just stopped giving a [ __ ]
about any business classes I was taking
at school I was focusing a lot lot more
on the self-education that I was getting
reading freaking books outside like
Atomic habits subtle art of not giving a
[ __ ] millionaire fast lane and I don't
want to be the guy to say give it up
right away okay let the academic growth
falter when it needs to not when you're
at 0k a month you haven't made your
first dollar online you're like I don't
want to do school okay that's not how it
works you should at least build a safety
met 1 to 2K a month where then you have
proof of concept to actually scale and
that's when you'll actually start
meeting people online as well who make
similar amounts of money when you join
online communities you'll find that once
you actually reach that level of growth
in your online business Journey but once
that possibility and that opportunity
stares you in the face you have to
understand that trying to hold on to
both dreams of being a super safe easy
route 50 60k a year marketing job by
getting like you know a 3.5 GPA in
business school versus going all in and
not just trying to hit 10K a month but
20 30k a month as well which I have hit
last month I did 25k in August and I'm
not just talking about time but I'm
talking about the ment emotional side of
knowing that you have this backup plan
where H you know what it's okay if I
don't get my product up and running in
the next week because I have my backup
plan oh it's okay if my videos all flop
in the next 30 days because I'll just
resort to my plan B of being you know
marketing position it's fine you know
I'll go back to doing decently well in
classes you are turning off the
subconscious part of your brain that
will look for Solutions in your sleep
that will look for Solutions when you're
on random Walker School at your workout
sessions where your brain will still be
turned on if you have a problem to solve
but if the problem is not that dire
right it's going from 1 to 10K a month
if the problem is not that dire where
you're not depending your actual future
on it your brain's not going to actually
turn those gears when it needs to on
these extra hours running a business
scaling an online income even if it's a
side hustle like affiliate marketing or
actually building a personal brand
succeeding with content creation these
are things that don't have concrete
answers okay you're not going to pour in
one hour a day easily knowing exactly
what the content is going to look like
and you're going to blow up after 30
days it's not how the game works because
online business is competitive you're
competing when you launch a product into
the space at least a little bit with the
other products or services or agencies
on the market if you're creating content
you are slightly competing for the same
viewership space on the for you page
explore page as other creators are and
your competition is putting in many
hours a day into strategizing they're
spending so much time with their brain
just constantly turning about new
content ideas about new additions they
can add to their Community or their
business okay that's me I actually
dropped out of college right and that's
who you're competing against kids who
are literally thinking about their
online business their content 24/7 how
can you realistically compete with them
when your brain is only turned on
towards those Endeavors for 2 hours a
day and even in those 2 hours you're
like eh I'm chilling it's not that deep
of course your brain is not going to
work as hard to find those tiny
important Creative Solutions that are
going to give you the 1% Edge every
single day pause I said edge that's
going to stack to 37 times better in a
year intelligently when the time is
right let go of your safety net and
understand that it's going to be a
[ __ ] terrifying process but when you
do that that's when you're really going
to accelerate your growth that's when I
took a gap year and that's after that
Gap year is when I first hit my first
10K month now letting go of all three of
these things is really difficult which
is why I made this video because I know
that you're probably leaning towards
this this new opportunity where maybe
you're already making like a little bit
online right 500 bucks a month or
something and you're staring at this
opportunity where you suddenly see these
guys on social media and you know it's
possible what they're doing for your own
life as well and I want to give you the
comfort and Solace that it works out but
it's not going to be a pretty Journey
it's not going to be a comfortable
Journey especially during college
because of all these external pieces of
friction that you're going to get from
being on a college campus from going to
college classes from being surrounded by
other college kids who all think in a
specific mode of career paths and they
all have a pretty similar view on Career
paths and money so you're going to be
fighting against that social friction
you're going to be fighting against that
internal friction that you feel where
your identity is going to feel kind of
ripped apart a little bit where you
don't know yourself anymore and that's
part of the process and that's okay
right it's just part of the things you
have to give up for something that you
want even more and I love my life now
doing your own thing and building your
own future with the true creative depth
that you can have when you fully control
it is beautiful that being said good
luck on your journey it's going to be a
long process and I just gave you very
vague fundamentals but comment down
below if you want to see more of this
kind of yapping style of content all
right I'll see you guys peace