if you clicked on this video I know
you've been watching self-improvement
gurus on YouTube for months now it's
addicting like some of these titles and
thumbnails are insane what the [ __ ] but
you love getting your daily dose of some
chat or Cadette whipping their
metaphorical pee PE in your face telling
you these seven SS to become unstoppably
confident I quit consuming any of the
self-improvement content 14 months ago
and it's funny because now thinking back
a year later I actually achieved my
dream life goal one ever since high
school I literally dreamed of visiting
New York City and U was my dream School
5 days ago I actually just moved into a
new York City highrise goal number two I
taped down on my wall 2 years ago
$10,000 a month I haven't hit less than
10K a month in the past 8 months this
month in September we actually hit
$40,000 in our business full number
three I hated my body 2 years ago I felt
so ugly and unattractive virgin never
kissed a girl boom transformational
visual yes I'm not a virgin anymore see
here's the one thing that actually
changes when you stop watching this
self-improvement motivational BS videos
and it's so simple but chasing your
dreams requires you knowing what your
dreams are you're probably so used to
people telling you no fap this semen
retention this dopamine detox is the key
here are the seven study hacks to
absolutely lock and become how are you
going to watch seven different videos on
locking in if you don't even know why
you want to lock in and I'm talking like
deep deep down in your personal Mas loan
hierarchy of needs what do you actually
want deep down what are you working
towards and if you're watching this
video you're probably Young right I'm 20
so I get the feeling of wanting to just
say I don't know what I want I'm young
okay I'm just going to figure it out
after I've started working or I left
College okay I'll figure it out later
but the reason why it's a problem is
because you are subconsciously getting
oiled up to be someone else's perfect
person like you might be thinking oh I'm
not getting oiled up to be an employee
in the 9-to-5 rat race because I'm
working to build my smma and hit 10K a
month and Achieve Financial Freedom when
in reality you are just one of millions
that this YouTuber is oiling up to
become his perfect customer for is smma
course I'm not here to say oh all
self-improvement YouTubers are nefarious
all they're trying to do is sell you a
course I sell programs online too that's
how I make my money these programs do
actually help people I've helped
countless people in my program hit
10,000 followers on Instagram and start
monetizing so don't miss the point I'm
not trying to make you hate on these
other YouTubers but quitting
self-improvement and quitting the
self-improvement content means quitting
the pursuit of goals because of someone
else it means letting go of the absolute
Chokehold that other people have on you
and I know it's probably hard if you
grew up with strict parents I get it my
parents are Korean I took like seven APS
in high school I got a 1540 on my SAT
but you have to realize that watching
these videos where they're emotionally
heart tearing fighting over who can have
the most emotionally striking title and
thumbnail combo to make you relive your
childhood pain of your parents yelling
at you telling you exactly what you need
to do that's not getting you closer to
your actual dream life I haven't been on
this side of YouTube in a while in the
past year I spent a lot of my time just
reading books if I watch YouTube videos
that were like business YouTube videos I
just spend time with friends in my free
time we like play Smash and smoke
sometimes and smoke weed sometimes not
saying that's good but I know how much
it hurts to be in this lost State
chasing the next productivity hack
that's going to change your life making
you run around like a carrot on a stick
I was there for 2 years straight so if
you actually want to change your life
achieve that happiness Financial Freedom
Freedom that you actually want you have
to detail your dream life in every
specific detail because it actually
works it makes your motivation 10 times
stronger so let's talk about it here
what's the practice that I actually use
to build out that vision for my dream
life where now I can wake up every day
confidently saying that I actually love
the life that I live I simply asked
myself what is my perfect day hour by
hour another way of putting this is if
you had one more day left to live and at
the end of the day I'm talking 12:00
a.m. you have died that is your last
time to experience life on this Earth
what is that day look like and be as
crazy as possible cuz you're probably
going to feel so insane when you write
down this answer or say it out loud pull
out a piece of paper and please just do
this practice with me I promise it's
going to help CU you're going to sound
insane you're going to say I want to
wake up next to a waterfall and then I
want to get lunch with my friends next I
want to create content and share some
beautiful art to the world and then I
want to go skydiving and then I want to
eat a $200 steak dinner watching the
sunset that was my ideal and it's insane
but it's crucial because getting into
this childlike state where anything
anything is possible is how you truly
accept deep down your true self it's how
you accept the true childish desires
that you have deep down that lights us
all up with true joy that becomes our
North Star for how we want to design our
life and okay maybe you won't get that
$200 steak dinner next month but you
enjoy eating dinner out with your
friends okay how much money does that
actually take to achieve that $30 every
night getting dinner with your friends
900 bucks a month you could do that you
want to have money to travel and have
beautiful experiences but me know I'm in
college I can't drop everything and just
travel and Chase my dreams I'm not
saying you need to drop everything and
just chase this right now tomorrow take
principles of that Northstar and apply
it to your life if you like adventuring
what principles do you like about that
trip to Bali hm well I guess I like the
idea of new experiences and nature I
like the feeling of Freedom that I get
to have when I'm with my friends perfect
today create that time to spend with
your friends and actually be free
together try new restaurants on a Friday
night and actually do your [ __ ] work
beforehand so you don't feel guilty and
you can actually experience that freedom
that you know you want because that's in
your North Star of your dream life and
it'll take like 5 to 10 minutes to
really identify this just be as crazy as
you want but suddenly it'll give you a
reason to actually lock in you have
something to work for but it's different
this time because you chose it it wasn't
your mom it wasn't your dad it wasn't
wasn't some gigachad YouTuber that's
telling you you need 10K a month you
need dopamine detox you'll actually
achieve these dreams and you'll work so
much harder to achieve them you won't
get into this cycle of binge watching
the content when you feel so unmotivated
and burnt out because it's actually you
you know it's such deep truth that this
is what you want you're not hedging your
future against testing somebody else's
thesis on happiness you're testing your
own thesis on happiness you're
hypothesizing your own happiness formula
and you're testing it yourself and
you're not afraid to explore the answers
that are actually truly you because it's
[ __ ] hard to tell yourself I want
this and tell the world I want this I
actually want to travel I don't want
this job Mom I want to create content
and it's [ __ ] cringe okay but I want
to be able to impact people I want to be
able to spread a message isn't that
[ __ ] weird yes and it's hard to admit
that to yourself because that stares the
true honest future that you want in the
face you'll wake up and you'll see that
that you truly want that it's going to
be hard to accept but I'll leave you off
with this because there is quite
literally no no other alternative if you
are motivated by shame that is the
lowest frequency of emotion that we can
experience as human beings when we're at
a low vibrational frequency we're not
going to be able to settle into an
actual Flow State when we work when we
do our homework when we create you're
literally going to work at half of your
capacity but if you're operating at the
highest possible vibrational frequency
which you might think is love but
there's actually a vibrational frequency
that's higher than that and it's
authenticity if you are simply living
out of the frequency of emotion that is
authenticity where you can genuinely
look at yourself in the mirror and say I
want this and I'm doing it for myself
that's when you can actually start
building your dream life and that's when
self-improvement habits and all the
discipline tactics actually make sense
when you are doing it for you I go to
the gym every morning I got up at 7:00
a.m. I work on my online business and I
work really [ __ ] hard at it cuz I
told myself that I chose it deep down
you're going to know what your dream
life is and you know exactly what you
want the real shame is that most people
are too afraid to actually admit that
tosel and start working towards it all
right peace