did you ever grow up telling yourself
you want to be a YouTuber well I did too
and then I realized how much easier it
is to do it on Instagram and just become
an Instagram content creator and in the
past 9 months I have grown 160,000
followers on Instagram I'm not here to
give you some BS advice on clout I'm
going to give you the literal clout
equation that I used to grow 160,000
followers in 9 months and the first
thing I did was post 200 reels in the
last 9 months you got that right 200 100
times that is posting 200 times editing
200 times and filming 200 times so once
you get that done we can figure out our
first C in our Cloud equation CX C
equals cloud and the first C is
consistency and it sounds corny but that
is what it takes in order to grow
160,000 followers now if you have
posting anxiety and you're so worried
about making your first five or 10
videos perfect well rest assured that
it's going to take you 200 to get to
whatever clout number you want so don't
even think about your first 10 okay okay
so we got our first C and now we're
going to spend a majority of our time in
this video focusing on our second C
which is consistent Improvement or
constant Improvement now if you couldn't
already tell I'm a big fan of acronym so
the way we achieve constant Improvement
is with the three V's viewer visuals and
value so let's start with the viewer
what does that mean right obviously you
have a viewer and you want to Stack up
more views but what I mean by a viewer
is that you need one specific viewer now
the Instagram algorithm the way you
stack up more viewers VI you go from 100
views to 1,000 views to 100,000 to a
million views on a video is by making
sure your video gets a high average
watch time get comments and shares and
the way you do that is by hacking the
viewer psychology and making sure you
give the viewer exactly what they want
and to understand what people want you
need to focus on one specific person
because the riches are in the niches if
you're a fitness creator for example and
you say come with me to do an arm
workout why would they listen to you why
would anybody listen to you they've
never even met you before why would you
expect somebody on explore page would
randomly watch you out of all the other
Fitness creators and this applies to
every single other Niche right cooking
business videography you need to know
what your viewer wants use the wording
and say exactly what your viewer wants
to hear and that's all achieved by
understanding exactly who your viewer is
and I'm talking name one specific person
that makes it so much easier to actually
communicate in flow and communicate with
authenticity once you know exactly who
that one person is literally list out
who they watch online so then you can
use them as inspiration creators what
their problems are what their deepest
desires are in life and that's exactly
the messaging that you want to use so
instead of saying come with me to an
arms workout say these are the three
bicep exercises I used to grow my arms
by 2 cm in 2 months if you know exactly
who your viewer is you know that they
respond to the words 2 cm you know that
they respond to the words arm and that
is the power of understanding your
viewer because you stop shooting videos
in the dark and your ideas don't become
this scrambled game of what should I
post today let me you just copy who else
like somebody else well maybe you should
focus on your viewer instead and give
them exactly what they want and need in
their life so then you can actually
start building a following of people who
know like and trust you but that being
said once you actually understand the
wording and the communication that your
viewer responds to you still to
understand the visual side because if
your videos look like poop you don't
have good lighting and your videos look
kind of like this it's a little bit flat
with the lighting maybe you're not
relying on these cool visuals like a
little fancy whiteboard and if you take
out these fancy captions at the bottom
well there's less for the viewer to
actually kind of chew on visually while
they're watching your video and the more
pleasant of a viewing experience it is
the more of the Dead Space you cut the
more of the breathing time that you cut
out from your video the better your
video is simply going to look visually
put nice captions that change two to
three words at a time use trending music
so you can hijack familiarity bias so
people can actually start being
subconsciously suede to watch and like
you and keep your visuals clean and easy
to understand don't clutter your visuals
with 10 different pieces of pictures all
over the screen and 10 different lines
of text no keep it really simple one
line of text at a time one visual on the
screen at the time because the main
focus of your video should be the value
you provide to your viewer and nothing
else you might think having the flashy
visuals the cool animations maybe you
need a cliff jumping or a skydiving clip
at the beginning of your video to make
it visually captivating and no that's
not the point because think about it
from the viewer's perspective why would
a viewer watch your video it is very
simple it's because there's some sort of
value that you're providing them and
this might sound nihilistic like oh I
want my viewer to care about me I want
to build an audience that's what clout
means right wrong the art of succeeding
on social media is understanding that
nobody really cares about you especially
if they've never seen you on their page
before all they care about is the value
that you're going to provide them for
example if they want to grow 2 cm on
their biceps stop yapping about
something hey guys welcome to the
channel welcome to the page follow for
more nobody asked for that cut exactly
straight to the point cut out any
sentence that does does not contribute
to delivering the main value of your
video talk about each bicep exercise why
it matters and why they should apply it
to and then go on to the next one if
you're talking about how you grew your
business from $1,000 to $10,000 a month
and you want to get 100,000 views on
that kind of video I'm sorry but you got
to stop spending time trying to Showcase
your personality and joking on the
camera if you detract completely from
your main point which is simply how you
wear your business from $1,000 to
$110,000 a month and this applies to
every single type of content you are
simply going to bore the crap out of
your viewers if you were not focused on
simply delivering that kind of value I
could talk about what kind of shirts I
like I could talk about this like chain
on my neck and I can talk about all the
little things that I did earlier today
but that's not the reason why you're
watching this video right now it's
because you want this formula and you
want this 3vs and the instant I detract
from that and start dancing and prancing
around you're already losing your
retention in fact in my YouTube graph I
know I probably saw a dip in like 1%
when I talked about that because it's
not contributing to the main point of
this video video and ultimately if you
came on this video thinking clout is
some magic Little Pill you can swall
some Magic Buttons you can press on your
phone make clout and followers appear
I'm sorry it's actually hard work you
have to make good videos and that's a
art and that's a science that takes time
to practice think about I spent 2 to 3
hours on my most viral Instagram reel so
when I said 200 reels posted this year
realistically that meant 600 hours of
work maybe even more not to mention the
fact that I've already been posting
content since 2020 on Tik Tok and
Instagram so I I know I've been very
harsh and I know there's a lot to apply
from this video but it's a hard and long
process so if you want my full guides on
how to make these quality videos I'm
talking stepbystep walkthroughs look the
first link in the description and I will
walk you through exactly how to hit your
first 10,000 followers and start
monetizing through Instagram and Tik Tok
thank you guys for watching see you guys
in the next one peace