this month I made more than an
investment banker a lawyer and a
marketer I'm fine this is what entered
my bank account this month I also turned
21 today hence this cat so I'm pretty
young and the only way I was able to do
this is by building my personal brand on
Instagram to overcharge th000 followers
and my Tik Tok fallowing to over 1.3
million followers so today I want to
give you the best guide walking you
through the three levels of personal
branding 1 0 10K followers 2 10K to
100,000 followers and 3 100 th000 to a
million followers and what you should be
doing at each stage to progress to the
next level impact more lives and of
course wake more money that your knobby
corporate classmates first let's start
off with getting your first 10,000
followers or your first 10,000 true fans
which is the hardest at it's for 95% of
people fall short because even for the
most dedicated creators that I coach it
still takes anywhere between 60 to 90
days to hit that first 10,000 follower
Mark and I literally mean 90 plus videos
grinded through consistently on TI talk
and Instagram and within these first 60
to 90 days I laid out a three-step
process the three C's first C is copy
other creators in your Niche the second
C is consistently post and the third C
is constantly improving till the first C
copy other creators in your Niche is
probably something you're already a
little bit familiar with you're still
figuring out what you want to actually
post but you first need to start up with
a niche that you want to talk about
online and once you selected that Niche
for example say it's Fitness literally
just search up on Tik Tok search engine
to two to three keywords related to this
Niche so for example if it's Fitness you
can search up workouts meal plans meal
prep and save three styles of videos
that you find online and if you're
confused about how to actually make
these videos just film them on either
Tik Tok or your iPhone camera and then
edit them on either Tik Tok native
editing app or cap cut it is that simple
that is all that I edit and film on and
it's all I use to grow my 200,000
followers on Instagram and over 1.3
million on Tik Tok and the next part of
that consistently posting is just doing
this for 90 days straight you're
probably going to see results between
the 60 to 90day range or between 90 and
120 days so you really have to think of
those first 30 days as a discipline
challenge to Simply stay consistent can
you show up to those first 30 days
without quitting most people want those
quick tips that'll make you goow up
within the next week but that's
realistically not how B creater works
because like any other skill let's take
math or writing you need to refine your
basic skills like algebra or grammar
before you can go on to the more complex
things now luckily it doesn't take years
of spooling to refine these skills of
editing and filming and writing these
are the three main skills that you need
to master in order to get actually good
at making content this is only done
through consistently putting yourself
through the mud take this as a necessary
step in your personal growth to becoming
a Creator and stepping to that identity
and through this process of consistently
posting then you will see what it leans
to really con still will improve where
then you can refine those skills of
editing filming and writing I cover a
lot of those table mini skills like
editing and filming and writing in my
2-hour mini course just click the the
first link in the description to find
that but I really want to hammer home
that these first 90 days and first 90
posts to get your first 10,000 followers
has nothing to do with your inherent
natural skill set or natural gifts
towards being a Creator it's purely
about grit and it is purely about simply
being able to post every single day and
still put in your maximum effort into
those videos without being demotivated
by the algorithm and if you're going to
focus on anything within this
Improvement cycle simply focus on the
first 5 Seconds of your video how does
it look and what are you actually saying
in those first 5 seconds if you took
those first 5 Seconds of your video out
of context could these still be
watchable and could it spur enough
curiosity for you yourself as your own
viewer to want to watch your own video
because if you can't even watch your own
video for the first 5 Seconds why would
anybody else want to watch your own
video now once you have nailed down 90
days of consistency and 90 days of
constantly improving focusing on those
first 5 Seconds making sure your
captions look clean making sure your
lighting looks good making sure you're
actually making a coherent point in your
video after 90 days you should be there
at around 10,000 followers if not you'll
probably hit it within the next 30 days
if you're just consistently plugging at
it but once you're at 10,000 followers
here's where it gets really interesting
because in order to hit 100,000
followers the main thing is simply
taking it seriously you already have the
Baseline consistency you already have
the Baseline skill set which is clear
and evident in the fact that you have
10,000 people watching your videos and
make the conscious choice to follow you
in order to see your videos again at
this point you have perfect concept that
you are able to make good videos now
it's about taking it seriously and Tak
it dra Next Level now this next stage
will take you anywhere between 6 months
to a year to get to 100,000 followers
from 10,000 followers and I think here
is where it really gets serious about
the Deep value that you want to provide
to your followers at this 10,000
follower Mark you go through the
transition of just simply creating
videos for fun and being a hobbyist
Creator to being a creator that actually
knows exactly what value viewers are
consistently coming back to their page
to watch in this process of consistently
posting a similar topic of value that's
what you're going to build a personal
brand around this is what you're
essentially going to be known for now
part of this is still consistently
keeping up those three C's constantly
posting you can't slip the ball and stop
posting once you've hit 10,000 follow
because you think your audience will
simply care about you that is not true
and you're going to realize that once
you've actually got to that point of
10,000 followers that you can still have
a video completely flop the next day if
your first 5 seconds is still boring the
algorithm is still not going to push out
your video to your followers or to new
viewers so you still have to pump out
quality videos time and time again
doubling down or what works and making
the same style of video over and over
and over again this is what it means to
have a consistent video format that
you're constantly doing in your videos
you should have enough data where you
have videos that have gotten to 10,000
or 100,000 or a million even views I
simply take the data of what topic were
you actually talking about how did you
start the video what literal first
sentence Did you say what was the
lighting like what setting were you in
and what do the captions look like
visually on the screen you simply take
all of that and you just do it over and
over and over again the same exact way
so this is where also monetization comes
into play learning how to actually
monetize on your following is going to
be key towards your longevity because if
you are are not able to sustain yourself
off of your following it's simply going
to be impossible to keep going unless
you simply enjoy making videos purely
for fun and you do not care about the
money but for most of us noal folk you
want to actually be able to start making
money from our followers how do we do
this there's two methods I recommend one
is doing brand deals and posting videos
for other brands or the other one is
making your own product and selling it
making your own product is how I've been
able to scale past $10,000 a month this
month I hit $443,000 but if you want
quicker short-term cash flow I have
recommend going for Bros because if you
have 10,000 followers you can probably
charge anywhere between $200 to $500 for
simply one post on your page on Tik Tok
or Instagram and it's easy cash flow if
you just simply do this like twice a
month that's easily $1,000 a month if
you're at like 50,000 followers I would
recommend you can start charging
anywhere between 500 to 750 per post and
then if you're at 100,000 followers you
can start charging about $11,000 for
each post so if you want to actually
land rad wheals the way I did it is
simply putting my business email in my
Tik Tok and Instagram bi literally just
putting out the second or third line
that's going to help Brands simply reach
out to you so they know that they can
actually work with you but if you want
to actually monetize by building your
own business and Taping that
monetization stream along the CH you
have to monetize on a specific skill set
and this is where having a beast of
expertise really comes in if you've been
making content on a form of value that
is simply entertainment as opposed to
educational or inspirational it's going
to be really hard for people to want to
buy from you because at the end of the
day if you want to sell anything on your
social media be it your own physical
product like a t-shirt or a Dred product
that youve created or maybe it's a
digital Cottage like your coaching
services or an online course with
Community the way you're actually going
to make people want to buy from you is
by making sure they trust you and the
easiest way you're going actually
influence people's buying decisions is
by influencing their life decisions if
you're helping influence people to get
into the gym that is a really easy way
to sell your own coaching services for
Fitness or your Fitness product if
you're doing tech product reviews or
makeup product reviews that's going to
be a really easy way to monetize by
inclining people's buying decision
because they already trust you in what
kind of products you're already
reviewing but if you're simply making
entertainment or comedy videos that's
probably going to be the hardest way to
monetize and that's a small thing I
think I should have realized in my 10 to
100K follower range when I was grown to
900,000 followers eventually on a comedy
cage I to completely scrap that account
and if you're in between this phase of
10K to 100K followers you should start
to have a plan for how you're going to
monetize your following because if you
don't have a vision for what people are
consistently going to buy from you that
it's going to be really hard even at
scale even at like 100,000 million
followers to keep making money
consistently and making say $10,000 a
month but say you simply make an
entertainment content that's okay simply
start to think about is there a skill
set that people want to learn from you
is there information that you hold that
people would want to learn from you does
that is the easiest way to turn your
content into some sort of information
product so if you're at this point start
to think about how you can start
monetizing by using your information and
using your influence to start
influencing buying decisions maybe if
you're a comedy channel or your clipping
Channel start introducing product and it
can simply be for free and for companies
that you like and that's okay but still
doing that process allows you to
literally insert monetizable moments
once you have your content format that
actually works and gets views that grows
your following and you have the concept
where about that can insert monetization
into your page it's simply repeating
that process over and over for 180 to
360 days to hit 100,000 followers but
once you are able to grit through those
10,000 followers then grit through
finding your format that gets you views
consistently doing it not getting thick
of making that format and introducing a
monetizable Avenue into your page that's
when you can really start thinking about
the bigger picture future for your brand
100K to a million followers and I think
at this point it's less about finding
the Tactical side and more simply about
systemizing your content it's going to
be less about this game of chasing that
next number and simply not getting tired
of it and just consistently finding ways
to entertain yourself through this
process of consistently coasting and
staying creatively fresh cuz what you're
avoiding here is simply falling off you
want to consistently be at the top of
your game is if you hit 100,000
followers that means you've probably had
one or two good months where your
content just hit you've had viral videos
hitting like 100,000 a million views but
how do you take that to the next level
and keep growing this is where you
really want to start looking at hiring
an editor and start reinvesting your
money that you can be making from your
monetization from your business and
start pouring it back into your content
so you can start making more of it and
making it more easily you also want to
really nail down between this 100,000
followers to a million follower range
what the main purpose of your content is
and this is some process that I'm really
going through right now in growing my
Instagram page from 200,000 to a million
followers because we just hit 200,000
followers like last month and now it's a
process of what is it that I really want
to get out of my page going forward
because I want to transition into
YouTube so I'm realizing now there's two
main foces that I personally have one
building my business and two focusing on
making a higher quality more impactful
things on the internet because one that
squees more buying decisions toward my
business and two I simply enjoy that
process for I see most scalable if I can
produce a one for of long form content
and have my editor with a system Cur two
or three short form videos from that
then I can just simply focus on making
one long form video every single day or
one long form video every single two
days or three days and just focus on
that one process creating pockets of
time in your day is going to be really
key because you're probably still going
to be leading A busy life I'm a business
owner right I dropped out of college but
even in college I had to find systems to
consistently post content I have a
friend for example who goes to college
and he has an entire studio in this
group I think he has over like 5 million
followers combined on like Tik Tok
Instagram and YouTube he has an editor
he strips out his videos and he simply
goes into his studio and films his
videos in his Studio integrating your
existing following into this figure
evasion that you're going to develop as
you start to realize that content
creation and influencing might become a
very very very core part of your future
and part of your career I've been seeing
this development in the past few months
and it's just an internal frus that I've
been to working through thinking a lot
more about what is the future of my
brand that's going to bring my business
to $100,000 a month in fact what I even
want from life because you're going to
be deciding from a lot of different
different options do you want to go down
building a business route do you want to
just go fullon concentrator go Double
Down on YouTube or streaming it's a
process of figuring out what actually
aligns with you the life that you want
to lead I am still going through this
process which is why I'm not speaking
too directly on exactly what that end
path is like there's some end of what
you want to hit once you're going from
that 100,000 follower to a million
follower range but I wanted to just take
this video to give you a kind of a road
map going forward between zero to a
million followers how this can impact
your career decisions this should be
impacted the way you look at content so
if you like this video you're still
watching leave a comment down below
subscribe and I'll see you guys in the
next one peace