when you're first starting out posting
content online should you focus on
quality or quantity I tested this thesis
on January 1st of 2024 this year 60 days
later I grew on Instagram from 50,000
followers to double my followers at
102,000 followers not only that but I
hit a average views of
212,000 views per video however whenever
I talk to any Creator who's under 1,000
followers who hasn't even posted 30
videos they always look at quality
versus quantity like a trade-off as if
you couldn't have both and I don't blame
you for having this conflicted view of
choosing one over the other because
there's so much conflicting advice on
audience growth Mr Beast saying things
like stop sitting there and thinking for
months and months on in and just get to
work and start uploading everything you
want as a Creator comes for making the
best videos possible and the reason why
this advice doesn't work is because it
literally treats your viewers like a
number and a statistic all the time when
you're forgetting the main point that at
the end of the day the viewer is a
person you watching my video right now I
could treat you as if let's think about
which part of the video we're at 30
seconds in right is the retention graph
going to go up or down when I say this
this numerical statistic tactical view
that you are always assuming the lens of
when you're creating your content traps
you into this view of essentially
depersonalizing the person behind the
camera but how does this actually
connect back to posting every single day
and how is posting once every single day
the remedy towards this problem well
it's simple nobody actually cares about
you that much you're there to provide
highly specific value and the way hey
the best medium to actually deliver
value to somebody and genuinely impact
their life the best way you're going to
do that is not by making the most
captivating nail biting first 10 seconds
of the video no you're just going to
focus on the viewer needs their subtle
dose of value whatever value you provide
and they need it every day or else
they're going to not be able to stay in
that zone of whatever happy place you
want to put them in or whatever inspired
state or whatever educated outcome that
you're trying to get them to they're
going to best progress towards that
outcome if you are simply posting every
single day and best of all you're going
to be sharpening your own sword at
getting better at providing this value
every single day and slowly but surely
you're just simply going to provide
better and more value than if you were
to try and optimize every single video
just the mere act of showing up every
day both benefits you and both benefits
the viewer if you are simply trying to
hack against this mysterious algorithm
against a machine in reality the game
that you should have been playing all
along is a people game where you're
connecting with somebody where you're
genuinely just thinking about okay this
person's behind the camera I literally
thought of my friend who started
creating content last semester and he
fell off because he wasn't posting every
single day that is who I'm communicating
to in this video so who are you
communicating to in your videos not oh
I'm trying to communicate between ages
18 and 26 because I want to reach this
big audience of young men the reason why
that's ineffective is because if you
actually know who your viewer is you'd
know that the very specific niche of
value that you would provide would fall
into a very hypers specific category and
when you can Target specific problems
for your specific viewer that's when you
can really Reach people deeply and start
accumulating your actual audience of
people who love you and like you not
people who simply get tricked into
watching your video through some
thumbnail through some hook through some
fancy flashing text I'm not saying don't
put those in those are like sprinkles on
a cupcake but that shouldn't be the base
of your cake at the base of your cake
should be the person that your actual
specific value and the end outcome that
your page exists to get them to what is
that end outcome that they get have that
very specific outcome very specific
person and that'll allow you to just
come up with the content that'll help
your viewer get to that end outcome
because your content should exist
because there's an actual problem out
there that needs to be solved maybe it's
people who are uneducated about Fitness
who still haven't gotten to the gym for
some some godforsaken reason they could
not show their butt into the gym and
it's causing them this Myriad of
problems of health problems of
relationship problem s of lack of
confidence identify what those problems
are and why people still haven't gotten
to the gym and the way you do that is
simply by talking to I don't know your
friend who still hasn't gotten to the
gym yet ask them you know what's
stopping you from going to gym if you
were to start tomorrow what do you think
would be the hardest part and boom you
just lay out a laundry list of topics to
talk about that hasn't really been
talked about on the internet and that's
where you find your audience of people
who actually love you and not trying to
be this in the thumbnail posting every
single day will not solve every one of
your problems but it will help you
actually build the base of the audience
that will eventually stack up to you
being a genuine Creator and not somebody
who had a flash in the pen video that
hit 100K views just for your next 10
videos to Skyrocket and plummet right
back now to 500 600 views per video
that's not what a real audience is a
real audience is a group of people who
have gotten genuine value from you as a
person and as a Creator and as a result
keep looking to you for value and for
guidance or for entertainment or for
inspiration in their life even if it's
just a small daily dose thank you guys
for watching and I'll see you guys
tomorrow peace