I dropped out of college 4 months ago to
go all in on my online business but this
month and the last month before that I
actually missed me and my girlfriend's
anniversary because I was too busy
traveling so I wanted to surprise her by
visiting her this weekend and buying her
a gift she still uses this 2021 old a
Macbook so I wanted to buy her the new
Macbook Air M3 this is what my bank
account looks like right now so that's
where my story starts off one broke
shitty boyfriend with 3 days to save his
business and his relationship
we got 30 minutes until our first call
so I'm going to hit a quick workout this
probably a really bad idea timing L was
doing we just got done with our workout
time to get pumped for these sales calls
in 5 minutes let's
go let's go so the 3-day plan to save my
business was very simple for the last 30
days I've been working on this $3,000
mentorship So the plan was to sell it to
10 people so before before I'll tell you
the price now $3,000 sounds like a lot
but with my Instagram story on day one
we already had seven calls booked and
they say a good product Sals itself so I
was pretty confident that was my first
mistake sounds good I'll uh what like in
an hour I could just like because even
though I didn't have pretty much any
sales experience I was so confident that
we would sell out all 10 spots and at
the beginning it actually was easy uh
where could I best send the link then
the first guy he was a successful agency
owner he bought in just 15 minutes by
11:00 a.m. my team member Justin had
also closed someone so by lunchtime we
were three sales out out of three and we
were buzzing all right it is 11:35 we
just hopped off a call closed it 3K in
the bank in the meantime till our team
member Justin also closed somebody on a
1K payment plan in total so far we are
at
4289 K today see how finish off until at
12:00 p.m. we got humbled the last two
calls that day just did not want to buy
one of them said it was too expensive
the other one straight up didn't have
enough money in their bank account uh so
we just got off the call and he
genuinely did didn't have money
apparently I don't know I should should
I have pushed to ask him how much money
he had left maybe maybe not but yeah he
said he genuinely does not have the
funds and that's the only reason why he
couldn't join the Inner Circle and you
know what he had a really compellent
story but it's okay but still three
sales were a great way to end the day
right except there was one huge problem
throughout the day I expected more
interested people to book calls except
we didn't have any new people book calls
for the rest of the 3 days so that meant
going into day two we literally only had
two calls left and I went to bed with
this anxious sinking feeling in my
stomach I prayed these last two calls
would be as easy as the first two so we
could at least finish this launch with
five out of 10 spots sold but even then
I knew in the back of my mind that I was
probably cooked anyways because I
promised the first three customers this
Vision that we'd have the most epic
group of 10 in the program like I think
you'll enjoy just being part of the
group like there's a lot of it's
specifically creators SL entrepreneurs
so yeah I think that's important to so
if we couldn't fill up all 10 spots the
three people who joined and bought that
day would feel cheated and they would
want a refund which would leave us with
[Music]
$0 oh my gosh and with all this pressure
in mind we entered day two the last two
of our calls were in the morning of day
2 at 9:00 a.m. and 10:30 a.m. all righty
we are going into our second call today
this one I am anticipating pretty good
things because he's an agency owner I
checked out his content he's got pretty
good content so the first call didn't
even show up the second Prospect however
looked good we were on the phone talking
for an entire hour walking through his
entire business plan all of his goals
how this program would benefit him and
his content through all of these goals
but even after over an hour of talking
he just ended the call saying he still
wasn't sure did you close it no and in
sales there's one rule if they don't buy
on the phone they will never buy that
was it in just 1 and 1/2 days
we completely ran out of meetings and
opportunities to sell our new program
and at that point I was terrified
because not only was my entire business
banking on this new launch and my entire
relationship banking on this new launch
but I actually had just moved into a new
apartment in New York City and I had to
pay $2,700 in rent literally in a week's
time so at this point Not only was my
business and my relationship on the line
but so was my rant oh my goodness I am
an idiot but anyways we had only one
option I had to call an emergency
meeting with my team member Justin and
book more calls that was the only way we
would find any way out of this sticky
situation and after 30 minutes of
cooking up a discussion we decided to do
a hail Mar throw and just send out an
email to 450 of our email list members
with the most hilariously simple email
hey first name you're invited to the
Inner Circle book a call right here it
was the most desperate email but we we
just had to book any meetings you don't
understand and we had seven spots to
fill up with Just 2 days left or else
everything in my life would be cooked
but just when I thought this measly
email to 450 people would lead to
nothing in the span of the next 3 hours
we booked 10 more calls at this point we
just needed to close seven spots so with
10 calls booked all we had to do is just
close them hey how yall doing I'm doing
great just got back from workout however
I was starting to get tired at this
point from all the calls I'd been taking
in the last 1 and 1/2 days but despite
that after after three more calls we
closed all three that night each call
was like an hour long I was tired I was
exhausted
$9,000 as you can see September 18th to
now which is September 20th but
realistically it was
$8,100 yesterday and $10,300
today oh I'm so tired a it's going on
call for that long melt but you know
what great end to the day because at the
beginning of the day I thought we were
Clos any deals let's go but at this
point we had closed seven spots so all
we needed to do in that last day was
close three more day three it was the
final home stretch I had told everybody
online the program closed today so if I
didn't sell out that day I wouldn't be
able to sell any more people in the
future days and if we didn't sell all 10
spots I was mortified because what if
people would just refund expecting 10
people together in this cohort in this
program and you have to understand I was
this 20-year-old hopping on calls with
25 26 27 year olds and that day for some
reason I woke up with just this strong
bout of anxiety like things were going
decently at this point we had that Hail
Mary throw of an email it was doing okay
yet for some reason on the inside that
morning I was just mortified but that's
when I remembered a vital sales lesson
that kind of just applies to life
whatever you chase runs away from you
the previous 2 days we were literally
just chasing and chasing these call Ball
s chasing these sa so that last day with
a whopping three spots left to fill in
our program I just told myself that
morning I don't give a flying who
buys anymore and what happened call one
let's go bro close call two it's
3.6 cuz of tax close call three
close we did
it they always ask what I would
do if I didn't win I guess we'll never
know dude 30 K how does it feel
dude actually 27 CU of payment plans how
how does it feel dad you did it true I
almost lost my apartment man I almost
lost all my friends bro like all my
existing as bro but like now we did
it man so after 3 days and just shy of
$30,000 we actually made $27,000 because
few people were on payment plans and
they would pay the rest of the amounts
later what did we learn sometimes life
does not go to plan sometimes you push
through you have to get creative
sometimes you just say it and have
faith in your ability no matter what
online business is about taking risks
sometimes you just simply have to trust
that you can get through it got it now I
just got to hide this
yeah you can open it's like few chocol
so I'm not going to lie this doesn't
feel like a Trader Joe's
H oh wait this is the chocolate and
then are you so
cutie how
you so I know I I missed our fourth
anniversary cuz I was but I want to get
your gift for starting work I know
you've been using the old poopy Book for
a really long
time why are you looking at me but it's
your birthday
weekend
kidding I
just I love you