welcome to a day in the life of a
21-year-old College Dropout in New York
City this is my apartment gym let's get
to working
out now the title and thumbnail are true
I genuinely have not left my house now
that probably sounds disgusting and
gross to most of you extroverts out
there don't worry I agree with you by
the end of this video I promise I will
convince you why staying inside is
genuinely a happier existence than going
out every single day because I used to
do that and I'm so much happier now as a
home
body the reason why staying inside I
believe is better for you is because of
dopamine of course we need to order our
groceries on Amazon let's get
it all right it is
10:41 and the nice thing about living at
home is that can literally stock your
fridge with all the degenerate drinks
that You' ever need we got our roommate
Daniel's daily routine to get that
morning YouTube in yeah so we are
finally cleaning our kitchen after
living here for one whole month
technically 2 weeks because we just
moved here or we weren't even home for
like 2 weeks that's true for like 2
weeks pretty much burning our $2,700 a
month rent by just being out outside
most of the time right make a lot of
money how much money do you make by the
way Meo wait Dam how much money do you
make um I can't say but I was just say I
make more than an investment banker he
makes an hour guys but we're not allow
he's not allowed to reveal this on his
own channel so I'm revealing it on my
don't worry nobody watches my videos no
you're not putting that
up talk to to to it's currently 2:48
p.m. still in our room still outside
have not left our house yet yeah and uh
Daniel's telling me about the bamboo
ceiling for asian-americans have you
heard of their bamboo ceiling what is
that slight change of pl we were about
to just pick up
food we ended up coming to kbbq here at
let's meet so we're eating out today so
$60 KB never hurt
anyone
let's oh man all right we're feeling
hungry right we got to finish this we're
going to get charged I know we going to
eat we going to eat right now your
mouth's looking awfully empty right now
no no I'm hungry thank you oh thank you
let's dig in right all right it is 10:52
p.m. we got back from dinner called our
girlfriend showered changed we're about
to go to
bed about to take my magnesium pills
before I get to bed as well well I
explain to you guys why I actually stay
inside all day in this road to $100,000
a month and it comes down to one simple
concept focus in May of this year I
dropped out of Boston College after
finishing my second year at the time I
was making $10,000 a month with my
business right it was a low ticket
Community what that basically means is
people paid $59 a month to just be part
of our Discord Community where we help
each other improve as content creators
on Instagram and Tik Tok but the problem
is during this summer for the 3 months
of the summer I was just willy-nilly
doing whatever I was outside all the
time time I was trying to work at coffee
shops every single day my gym even was
outside and it's because I lived in
Harlem so our apartment straight up was
only a 3-month lease it was already
furnished so I didn't even have a desk
inside my room so I couldn't even do
work inside my house and these small
little things where I didn't have an at
home setup added so so many points of
friction where am I going to work today
I don't know and what time am I going to
work out today I don't know what time am
I actually going to start work when am I
going to film a video like this right I
can't just sit down and talk like this
at a coffee shop it's too loud other
than that look at this beautiful view
like y all have to see this like dang
and I'm paying $2,700 a month to be in
this apartment and part of it is
obviously because it's like we're lit
like we're live bro this apartment is
sick and we're in the middle of ktown
but another thing too is simply it
forces me to stay at home and just grind
I told you that at the beginning of the
summer I was making $10,000 a month
right actually it was a little bit more
like 12,000 or $133,000 a month right
same thing this past month in September
even though I moved in on September 16th
so I only spent 15 days in this
apartment in those 15 days my income
shot up from what was probably like 18K
a month in August last month we made
$43,000 in our business that level of
growth can only happen if I'm
realistically I have a routine or I'm
waking up at the same time every day I'm
going to the gym at the same time every
day I have blocked out times where I
know I'm going to film a video and I
feel inspired to make a video like I'm
going to be honest this set up is lit
like look at this got freaking Lego
Bowser up there again having this kind
of setup at home inspires me so much to
create and genuinely it is I 100% worth
paying that kind of money because as a
Creator It'll like any point of
inspiration has positive Roi and that
sounds really silly to say but being
able to dial in all of my schedule helps
me scale even further to $100,000 a
month and my goal is to hit $100,000 in
the month of December before the year
ends of 2024 started off this year
literally I think we made $11,000 in
January so dropping out of college
definitely was a big big plus but
another big step was simply moving into
this apartment that just has enough
where I can simply stay inside my room
for most of the day and get all of the
things I need to get done in the day and
it helps so much to have this Dome this
man cave this Temple for my work where I
literally I'll show you guys what it
looks like from another angle I am
absolutely dialed when I pop into this
room in fact my bed is straight up just
this little it doesn't even have a bed
frame I straight up just sleep is not
that fun like look at this bed it is a
twin XL bed it's tiny okay and I'm 510
human being so like it's tiny so
literally in the mornings to I just get
up and I'm like all right what do I do I
have my whiteboard and it tells me
exactly what to do make my bed send a
picture uh keeping myself accountable
for my wake up to my girlfriend take
shower drink water and eat my vitamins
and then after I'll death meditate it
and journal so I can stay PR read write
and film and then it work out but
realistically this probably goes working
out before I do the read writing and
filming I'm still testing on my routine
but the thing is having this constant
variable of just staying inside helps me
flesh out my routine and I've realized
yes it is cool to travel around and be
this internet entrepreneur that can just
travel all the time and do cool stuff
okay and I was kind of living that this
summer I got to travel to Vegas I got to
travel to Europe and then I realized
while I was at Europe like dude I just
want to lock in I just want to lock
myself in a room and and grind and build
something cool why because I have this
Primal urge to Simply sit down and make
things okay and traveling can come later
okay and I'm not saying I'm not going to
travel throughout this year okay I'm
going to visit Boston because my school
friends are still in Boston obviously
right they're in their senior year I'm
going still visit them I'm going to
visit my girlfriend who's also in Boston
I'm probably just going to like travel I
don't know like maybe I'll pop out to
like Cali or Miami or something a couple
times like that'll be lit too right but
you need a home base where you can
literally go and instantly have times of
Focus right environmentally design your
environment so you can just just wake up
and be so dialed in and that's possible
okay maybe I don't I'm not saying it has
to cost $2,700 a month but like spend a
little bit of money Furnishing your room
to creatively inspire you inspire you
with things that kind of push you to
your limit the last point I want to end
off this video with about this apartment
price specifically is that when I signed
the lease for this apartment I genuinely
could not really afford it my expenses
were at6 ,000 a month and my business
was making 18K a month if the apartment
lease is
$2,700 that means that my run rate is
pretty much like I'm pretty much just
living at my meat because I also have to
account for taxes in my business pushing
myself to this financial limit forced me
to make a ton of money you guys probably
have seen in my $30,000 in 3 days for my
high ticket launch for a business I was
on the freaking Road pushing yourself to
the absolute Financial stress and
absolute Financial gutter helps it helps
you with a fire under your butt and the
boats to escape back to your comfortable
old life absolutely burned you have no
choice but to make it work it's not
always always like you know just don't
throw yourself wildly into the fire with
30 days to make it work when it's
completely unrealistic situation but
sometimes you need to kick yourself in
the butt and tell yourself lock in and
I'm going to do anything it takes to
lock in even if it takes a couple more
dollars a couple Grand more dollars I'm
loving life living inside because I also
love what I'm building right now and I
don't like to to use the word work
because that sounds very demeaning
towards what I do I love what I do look
at the YouTube video I filmed today bro
I drew Mr Beast in in this chart like
what the heck that's cool I get to play
with the Legos okay this is a cool life
being a Creator and an entrepreneur
don't let fomo don't let some internet
gurus tell you you need to be outside
all the time in order to be this cool
Sigma m in 2024 like bro if you want to
build cool stuff sometimes you got to
stay inside and that's fine all right
thank than you guys for watching it's
getting super late I'm going send this
over to my editor and I'll see you guys
tomorrow cuz we are on daily uploads
it's every day bro peace