278 days ago we set the school to make
$100,000 a month last month in September
we actually made
$43,000 with our coaching business so
I'm going to post on YouTube every
single day until we hit $100,000 a month
welcome to day three it's 750 a.m. I
woke up like 30 minutes I'm just at the
[Music]
gym you've probably seen these kind of
videos on the Internet imti is lying to
you you shouldn't build an SM 2020 why
you buy can water dud yo we got broie in
the house drinking his little baby
plastic bottle
wow that's what 100K a month tastes like
Jason Le's popularity is like net
positive for Asians in the entertainment
space yeah you've heard of Jason the wi
but have you heard of Le on the only
reason why we haveed is because of Jason
the really trickle down economics bro
trickle down economics doesn't work I
think content creation fulfills two very
entral points of your life one is the
selfish side of you Fame can give you
money but I think also it can give you
purpose a lot of people are becoming
purposeless but like with your content
you're able to make an impact and like
that's what everyone wants to do with
their job like they're like oh [ __ ] I'm
working this corporate job and I can't
do anything with it like I don't even
think my words means anything but if
you're having reach then you're able to
actually make some sort of change or at
least world we would also just negotiate
better deals on your behalf to increase
your earnings we push the needle a
little to see how far we can go what's
your YouTube Studio screen time bro bro
probably like 10 hours a day or
something that's insane oh my oh hell no
see I got 1.5k views uh let's check your
most recent video really quick oh dude
my my my camera is cutting out a battery
oh wait no no but it's chill cuz these
are Community Builder videos wait those
are Community Builder videos that's true
100 200 views 500 views yeah I can
really tell like you're trying to build
community like the Mr be tile like
that's the amount of videos I you still
have 1,000 views like you must have a
crazy Community what song was
[Music]
it the one
that my
[Music]
God back from
dinner it is 11:17 p.m. and I am so
tired and ready for a calm
peaceful
and what the hey you guys want to say hi
wait did you did you start recording
content creators make
content speaking of our fancy water vus
is trying our fancy water thank you wow
the crack is crisp smells like
water tastes like water M that's good
tast really good it tastes fancy m what
do you think wait wait fake your like
give us a thumbnail wow this is the most
I've ever tried in my life I'm going
to okay my editor will take care of that
right it is the end of the day so we are
going to plan out our next day before we
head to bed waking up at 7 a.m. hitting
the gym at 7:30 because I have a bet
with my girlfriend that we have to hit
the gym every single day at
7:30 I guess I'll do another YouTube
video another YouTube video my YouTube V
trh strategy is like so cooked right now
crazy because I run a whole content
creation coaching program Mr Beast jely
what else am I working on tomorrow I'm
waiting on a lot of stuff so I actually
don't really have much to do I guess
I'll just make tomorrow's YouTube video
really good thank you guys for watching