[Music]
it is 2:55 p.m. and we are working on
uploading our second episode of this
series on YouTube and very specifically
we're working on a thumbnail right now
so this might be the thumbnail maybe not
we'll see our previous video Bang dude
we got 2,000 views so far in the first
less than 24 hours which is the best my
vide has ever formed on YouTube it's
been a grind we've been getting straight
500 views 500 views 200 views on our
video so it's nice to finally get a big
break we're grinding the YouTube me and
my editor we're cooking right
now 9 months ago I was just this normal
slightly bum College sophomore was
looking for purpose in his life so I
wrote down in January 1st of this year
this goal to make 100,000
a month and I would post on Instagram
and Tik Tok every single day until I hit
that goal fast forward 5 months and we
were at $20,000 a month which was absurd
to think about thinking that this
challenge was just some random goal and
now it had turned me into an actual
business owner while I was in college I
had also grown over 100,000 followers on
Instagram in that time it's crazy and
being that bum College sophomore who
hated classes and did everything
possible to get out of class this was my
oneway ti ticket to leave college and
have a path that wasn't simply a 9 to5
so after many many rigorous talks with
my Korean parents I dropped out of
Boston College in May of 2024 fast
forward 5 months now October I am moved
into a new York City Apartment I talked
to some of the Boston College friends
that I left recently and I almost felt
like I was a bad friend for leaving them
and at first it was just Pie in the Sky
Go like it's not actually going to
happen guys you know it's just like just
for fun on internet last month in
September we made
$43,000 and I think we're going to hit
$100,000 in December of this year and
whether you find my story either
inspirational or absolutely delusional
and idiotic I don't really care but I've
been feeling really guilty recently
because I feel like I've chosen my own
goals over my friends and the college
experience that I should have had with
them and at times this summer I thought
to myself couldn't I have just finished
College while building this business
just like yeah I would have had to grind
really hard but probably could have done
it right made my parents happy had blast
at school now I'm alone in New York all
my friends are up in Boston and this
morning as I was just journaling reading
a book I realized that I really didn't
have any other choice because I realize
my life is at its absolute Peak not when
I'm having a blast with friends but when
I'm creating something I truly love and
that sounds really corny but because no
matter what I seem to do in college
staying up until 2: a.m. in my friend's
dorm sing and karaoke together going out
on Friday night to like an MIT frat and
getting blackout drunk the fun always
seemed to dry up and it almost always
end the night maybe at like 12:00 a.m.
just sitting and thinking what is the
point of it all feeling really oddly
empty inside after hitting the highest
high getting drunk at a party or
laughing at some stupid jokes until my
abs her with my friends I had always
seemed to feel empty no matter how
excited I felt I felt this matching
emptiness and what I realize is that you
can't push away this empty feeling
forever yeah maybe you can sit with it
for the rest of the weekend but then we
have class on Monday in college we don't
have time to be empty and sad and
philosophical like bro we got class we
got grades to keep up now what does this
have to do with $100,000 a month if
you're a creative type like me making
cool things is in your DNA I don't
remember too much from when I was under
this age of six but I very vividly
remember Christmas morning when I was 5
years old my parents gifted me this Lego
set for the very first time it was a
Lego Star Wars ship I remember so
vividly that feeling of building it for
the first time and being so amazed at
putting together just a little pieces
and ever since then in elementary school
I was obsessed with building Legos I'm
pretty sure I'm going to hit $100,000 a
month in December by the rate of my
personal growth by the rate of my
business growth and suddenly I'm
starting to think why couldn't I have
just done it during college right
hitting $100,000 a month once my
business is fairly systemized I can let
it run kind of on its own so why not why
couldn't I why did I have to drop out
and move to a different city to do this
I realize now the vision for the company
that I'm building the vision for the
brand that I'm building will have a
million dollars a month in Impact I'm
saying that right now and I'm going to
post every single day until we hit that
goal that's a hell of a grind I'm
promising to put myself through where
I'm leaving the fun that I should be
having in college and if I told myself
that a year ago I would have called
myself crazy like why would you put
yourself through that much hell dude
like barely leaving your house locking
yourself in a room to scale a business
just for money like yeah I want to have
a dope lifestyle but I don't like money
that much so why because scaling a
business to 10K a month I can do that
just by making content and making a
decent product scaling to $100,000 a
month I need to learn how to manage
people but with good enough systems I
can still do it and not probably suffer
like to the end of the world but a
million dollars a month I'm pretty sure
I'm going to freaking suffer I'm going
to probably go through sleepless nights
every single day waking up on this same
boring routine I probably will feel so
different by the end of it to the point
where I almost like alienated myself
from the person that I used to be and
there'd probably always be some sort of
the business in the back of my head so
it would be almost impossible to have
the same level of presence that I did
just 6 months ago in college when life
was simpler my goals were simpler and
I'm not saying this to project my
self-pity and be like Oh I'm so sad
because I'm going to be rich I never saw
myself dedicating years to this business
and now I do so why why suffer through
years of turmoil making my life harder
and harder and I can just more pressure
on myself to just do more and more and
more right I've always considered myself
a lazy person I always did whatever
possible to just get by in high school
I'd stay up until 3:00 a.m. just playing
League of Legends every day in high
school okay I was not your typical
grinder and I think it's simply because
making cooler and cooler things is
embedded into my DNA impossibly
inseparably from me if I can stand by
any truth to the absolute core of my
being it's not that I'm a lazy person
it's not that I love fun it's that I
love building cool things and every time
I finish building a Lego set it would
last maybe 3 days before I had to break
it all down and build something even
cooler out of it as we start to believe
in our potential more as human beings
and what we can achieve in this lifetime
the smaller Lego sets don't challenge us
as much maybe the initial Lego set only
took 1 hour to build and it was really
challenging at the beginning but then it
became easy so we now sought a Lego set
that takes us a whole day to build but
even that became easy enough so now we
sought a Lego set that takes years but
not only just years but sleepless nights
and having to change completely as a
person read freaking business books dude
I I hated reading growing up so the
answer to why we need to suffer through
a painful existence when we could just
Coast by having fun is because I don't
want an existence that is void of
extreme pain but also void of extreme
joy and Extreme Adventure I think every
child has at least an inkling of a dream
of changing the world of doing something
way bigger than thems and I think that
kind of Impossible Dream is the only way
we can genuinely get up out of bed every
single morning as if it was Christmas
morning every day and I genuinely feel
like although I don't have these crazy
highs of going out I don't have these
crazy highs of spending genuinely great
time with my friends right now I think
I'm finding that existence where I wake
up so excited to Simply live this simple
life it was this idea that you could
either choose to live with passion and
drive to create things or you can choose
to live with practicality and safety and
being a content creator and entrepreneur
God I hate those terms so much they're
so cringe I can gladly say allows me to
do both both in this lifetime and I
wouldn't choose any other lifetime over
this existence that is why I must leave
College go all in on hitting $100,000 a
month because it is a necessary
prerequisite to all the other beautiful
things I want to build and I really want
to bring you guys along this journey
every single day so hit that subscribe
button down below it is now 8:00 p.m.
and I need to get dinner so I will see
youall tomorrow peace