[Music]
tell me baby do you
want it is 1147 so here is our current
degenerate biohacking stack first we got
non-stimulant pre because I don't like
the caffeine that's in most pre-workouts
it makes my belly feel terrible I fart
like two times per minute and it also
gives me acne I don't know kills my gut
second we got because that's yeah we we
still need to get our
C stop playing with him RI and I'm like
theie I'm a but I still want a party
like I'm ready to B
I'm now the title is true I made $43,000
last month is
September flexing on you and I want to
talk to you guys about how I actually
did it because I didn't do it by just
doing cretive funds and brand deals like
most influencers do I did it by
launching my own business now before you
discount me as this business nerd I
wanted to break down how business is
actually really simple and it's actually
10 times easier if you are already a
content creator or an influencer you
have your own audience the business I
sell is helping people with content
creation it's very simple make better
videos on Instagram and Tik Tok to help
your account grow and I want you to
disregard any preconceived notions about
being a core seller being a core scammer
Guru grifter selling
air so the first step to running an
online business is ironically and sadly
the part that most creators get wrong
which is that they don't make a
compelling offer and they don't actually
structure their information or their
offerings in a way that people actually
want to pay money for it if you're just
putting together a video course that's
convenient for you as the seller but for
the buyer that's not really giving much
you can find all information online on
YouTube how can you make it so they
actually have access to what they really
want so I recommend to any other
creators out there who want to start
your own business simply ask your
followers what they want right post
stories talk to them hop on calls with
them DM them all the time just giving
them free advice but also asking them
questions about what they're really
looking for and eventually just going to
have so much information even if you
have 1,000 10,000 followers you're still
going to get so much information on what
people actually want and that is the
start of actually being a business owner
it's knowing what people want so you can
cram it together in a packaged system
that you simply sell to them and then
continuously making it better while you
do the other two that I'm about to I
think this card right here
[Music]
maybe
wuc
[Music]
ENT that's that's my line I'm I said to
educate Inspire enter I just kidding I'm
really talk it is
3:51 and we are about to film a little
Tik Tok which brings me to my second
point of the day which is how to
actually convert your viewers into
buyers and I'm going to talk a little
bit more tactically here right the nerdy
side of how you actually convert
attention into sales the strap in I
promise I won't make it boring or
confusing but first let me film a little
Tik Tock all right the short from video
is finally fully edited so let's talk
officially about the strategies to
convert your audience of followers or
people watching content into buyers now
this obviously requires people watching
your content watching your Tik toks
reals and helping them grow and there's
two main things I use to convert my
audience and they are and many chat
they're both softw so is where I
host my course it's also where I host my
Discord and it's also where all of my
free resources are and that's where I
sore a lot of the free information that
I give people which eventually makes
them realize oh shoot this me actually
knows what he's talking about in terms
of growing Instagram pages and ter from
growing Tik Tok Pages now let me buy
from him after I've learned with so much
literally 2 hours of free information
that this guy is legit and they also
have access to seeing all the wins that
we have on our Discord server because
the best way to show a product is good
is by just literally making it so
visible that all of these students using
it are actually succeeding and it's all
done through this software called W but
that being said how do I even get these
people to even go to my w we use a
software called many chat and many chat
automatically DMS on Instagram every
sing single person who comments the word
Gat or viewer on one of my Instagram
reals literally just look it triggers
every single hour and it just sends them
this link to my free it's that
simple but getting that many people to
actually get access to this link is
really really helpful when you literally
have somebody dming you on your behalf
with that link so it really simplifies
this process this vague process of
getting these people to my website to
Simply if somebody comments a word on my
Instagram real my Instagram video
they'll go to my website and that makes
the process predictable it makes it down
to just simply numbers 5:16 p.m. deep
work I just want to be part of your
Sy it is
7:44 we are heading out to meet our
friend Luke for dinner Queen and we're
eating tacos I just want to be part of
your
I met Luke on a bus ride back home from
college like
randomly the train cuz I open something
I was like on the bus I was like this
guy looks really familiar CA go
yeah it's 12:58 it is so late and I need
to wake up at 7:00 a.m. so let's finish
up this video how do you actually get
views on Tik Tok and Instagram from
people who actually want to buy your
product and there's three quick tips
that I want to give you the first one is
simply that you need to talk to a your
audience talk to of your audience the
reason why you need to talk to your
audience is even though it's more
convenient for short-term views to not
talk to your audience and just make
voiceless and faceless edits on the
internet you will build so much more
trust with your audience if you are
actually speaking in your videos think
about how much subconscious report is
being built in this video right now
actually don't think about that cuz
that's going to be really weird in meta
the modern consumer in 2024 and every
year forward now wants to buy from an
actual human face that's why every
single Big Brand in the world is looking
to work with influencers people
associate the face with the trust and
that trust is built so much more when
you simply talk to it tip number two has
less to do with the sale part and more
to do with simply reaching a lot of
people getting your first 10,000 100,000
views on Instagram how do you do that
and how do you do that repeatedly so you
can print views every single day the
infinite viral content system as I like
to call it and it all revolves simply
around knowing the problems of your
viewer which is where you are sourcing
the problem that you're solving for your
product as well but by understanding who
your viewer is down to the literal age
you're going to know what pop culture
they're consuming what media they're
consuming what things are top of mind
what problems are exactly top of mind
and the exact wording of those problems
right are we just going to say l losing
10 lb or are we going to say in our
video gaining the improval of your
friends so you can stop getting bullied
all the time for being skinny fat and
the third tip to end off our video is
simply trust in time I know okay hear me
out I am currently in this process of
just starting off and giving my paying
my dues of trust and time with YouTube
right now we've been getting straight
2,000 views on our YouTube videos which
is really demotivating relative to the
40,000 to 200,000 views that we get in
in every video on Instagram but
Instagram and Tik Tok both started off
the same way for me where I had to pay
my dues in having absolute Flop videos
and here's the thing that even big
business owners that I know right
friends that are making way more money
than me get wrong about content
expecting to get a monetary return on
your videos in month one or in the first
6 months okay I want you to just simply
scrap that mentality completely from
your brain and the instant that you can
do that and so we just be present with
the video that you're creating and the
art piece that you're creating and not
all this other BS of trying to track how
you're going to start monetizing on
month number two and start converting
users all the way just from your first
month of content like do you realize how
difficult it is for simple content
creators to blow up their Channel why do
you think it's going to be so easy on
your page if you just crap out a shitty
piece of content every single day okay
it sounds cliche but it's true no
creator that I have seen whether it's a
friend whether it's a student that
hasn't actually tried and genuinely
cared like you can tell they put in the
consistent effort every day to show up
and actually improve upon their videos
every single day and you might think
it's just a mere Tik Tok it's just a
mere Instagram real okay what's the
point I'm not going to put that much
effort into it okay it's not going to be
my livelihood until it is suddenly you
actually can have tons of interested
buyers just from one instagram story you
send out an email to 450 people in your
audience and you sell out $3,000
mentorship and you make
$227,000 in 3 days this kind of audience
loyalty and this kind of audience wi
takes time but it's worth it because it
pays dividends and I don't think my
brand is making me as much money right
now as it will in the next 2 years I'm
projected to make maybe like 250k this
year from our business right in fact
more than $100,000 of that 250k
projected at least will come in the last
3 months of this year how much more do
you think that will be in the next year
and the year after that you have to
understand how big of a picture you have
to think with the content because only
then when you realize that you can
actually have the potential to change
the world and deeply change and impact
lives and of course build genuinely
generational wealth with your content
then you can start to realize that it's
a freaking long-term game and you're
going to stop being greedy you're going
to stop thinking in this tiny instant
gratification lens and you're going to
Simply put the trust and time that is
necessary and with that note I am very
happy to see you guys tomorrow on this
daily YouTube grind peace out y'all