stop playing with him
[Music]
R it is
8:25 a.m. first action item of the day
it's Monday which means we're paying our
employees today we're sending out I
believe
$2,200
$2,200 exiting my bank
account and it's a very exciting thing
cuz I get to send people money I like
the shitty thing about spending money
isn't losing the actual money it's not
getting your money's value for it but I
feel great sending this money because my
employees did a great job it seems as
though in 2024 we can't even go 30
minutes on Tik Tok or YouTube without
seeing one of those scammy gurus trying
to sell us some $999 program on how we
can make $10,000 a month with this new
shiny business model that gives us
passive income for life and we save our
family and escape the rat race I'm not
going to lie I bought into the stream
and now I sell courses online and I'll
be completely vulnerable with you guys
I've had a lot of cognitive distance
where I simply hate this label of being
a COR seller online yet that's how I
make all my money so today to salvage my
moral compass I decided I'm going to go
on a massive mission to destroy these
scammy Creator Le businesses and the way
that I intend on doing that is still by
selling courses but creating University
level educ education if you're new to
this channel I'm documenting every
single day until our business our
education business hits $100,000 a month
and through this process I want to
document how I'm going to do it
ethically and step one which we're doing
today is focusing on how we're actually
going to structure University level
education in a online course but before
we do that it's currently 11:15 and I
need to head to the
game don't tell anyone I do that in my
thumbnails don't tell anyone now the
mission statement with University level
education is simple but the application
is actually really really complex
basically you need to map out an
education system that actually works how
do you do that I found this fancy little
textbook called understanding by design
it lays out the process for building an
education system that gets your students
results which is the goal now for any of
you out there why is that the
goal right when we should just be
marketing and selling our product and F
our results two reasons One Market
sophistication now has reached a point I
believe where essentially grifters will
die in 2025 people have become so wise
to the idea of grifting and scamming
that even if you tried so hard to grift
it's just going to get harder and harder
and harder and harder every single year
when in reality you could spend that
time better allocated and simply I don't
know like working on making a product
that actually gets results and that's
complicated so let's dumb it down in a
really simple terms one you have to
identify what the actual desires result
for your students is and quantify them
that was actually kind of tough for me
right what is the actual result for my
students in becoming better content
creators cuz that is so vague and so
easy to be like I want to make them
happier I want to make them more fit so
I identified one creators become highly
literate in what makes a viral video
understanding attention psychology
cinematography editing and communication
and two creators understand with
transparent outlooks how to lead a
long-term fulfilling career in the
Creator economy this is what I laid out
here but once you you have that desired
outcome so let's say for example
understanding attention psychology when
I listed out attention psychology is a
really core part of my curriculum
attention psychology in terms of just
understanding what actually captures
viewers attentions but I still had to
lay out an even clearer goal for what is
understanding attention psychology so I
wrote out the goal of attention
psychology curriculum is to understand
viewer empathy content Market fit
pattern Interruption perception
management and how different
storytelling and cinematography helps or
hinders audience retention now once you
have that very clear end point the
Second Step that you need to do which
actually shocked me is understand how
you're going to properly assess Student
Success how are you going to measure
whether students are getting closer to
that goal or not getting closer to that
goal it's really hard to quantify
whether somebody is understanding
something to assess the traits in our
creator students of visual storytelling
IQ written analysis IQ and hook IQ I'm
basically just going to make quizzes
that's going to AB test whether the
student thinks script A or script B will
get more views and then it'll actually
show real data and that is my way of
assessing if students really understood
something I'm going to try my best to
make this education curriculum actually
fun and interesting I'm going to try my
best to make this education curriculum
actually fun and interesting cuz I my
attention span is the attention span of
a freaking goldfish so once you're done
with step number two which is
identifying the metrics that actually
determine whether your student is
getting closer to the goal or further
away from your goal finally you can
start planning out the courses and the
videos you're going to film what quizzes
you're going to make and Etc and I
always went backwards I was like okay
I'm just going to make this module on
attention hacking I'm going to make this
module on hooks I'm going to make this
module on this editing trick and it was
just a massive compilation of just
random information in my course so now
this is going to guide how I'm going to
make this entire course a toz taking
somebody from literally zero followers
to 10,000 followers understands exactly
how to get brand opportunities exactly
how to connect with other creators
exactly how to eventually start their
own entrepreneurial ventures in an
ethical way and this is really exciting
because I know for a fact we're going to
freaking cook with this so yeah long
long spiel on how I'm going to set up my
course to not be a freaking scam and be
University level it's going to be a long
process but I want to take you guys
through it my goal with this product is
to genuinely create stable Creator
education I feel like that doesn't
really exist for us content creators out
there we're kind of just shooting in the
dark being like yeah we might succeed we
might become homeless whatever and maybe
as a result hopefully through this
Movement we can revolutionize the actual
e-learning space to raise the bar for
what is actual good Creator education
that's my big big big picture goal being
Giga delusional life the universe
Fortune it favors the people who strike
boldly business rewards the people who
simply stick to it the longest and have
the biggest Vision as a consequence I'm
really banking my thesis on that yes
we're going to hit $100,000 a month but
I want to scale this business to a
million a month in impact and the way
I'm doing that is by actually seeing a
vision where I'm genuinely changing this
entire space of the Creator economy and
as much as I can say that's a simple
stupid silly Vision I feel so purposeful
about this that I'm waking up every day
really excited to do work that I never
thought I would be able to do like
sitting through reading a textbook well
it was actually a textbook summary I'm
not going to lie I didn't read through
an entire textbook today but I think
that's what we search for as human
beings it's not money it's not
short-term materialism but deep down its
purpose and fulfillment that being said
it's 3:30 p.m. right now and I have a
Inner Circle High ticket coaching call
with my 15 students in 30 minutes so I'm
going to hop on
[Music]
it is 940 p.m. we are about to end the
day are you at the office finish off the
day we basically worked the entire day
on redoing our entire curriculum for the
content Academy now the content Academy
is the course business that I've been
running for the past 7 months and today
I basically rewrote the entire course
structure from ground up here's what it
looks like and I'll explain exactly what
this means for any of you guys who are
building your own information businesses
or just curious about this space in
general this is what the Core Curriculum
looks like honestly you could read it
and you could pause and read it if you
want to I don't want to drag this video
on too long because it is 10:12 p.m. and
I need to head to bed bed because I need
to wake up at 7:00 a.m. so we can hit
the gym at 7:30 a.m. so that being said
thank you guys for watching this video I
will see you guys tomorrow peace