when I was 13 my friend introduced me to
League of Legends I hated it at first
this nerdy ass video game that for some
reason was so difficult but I still
vividly remember the pain of being the
worst in my friend group at the game
being stuck in bronze while all my
friends were silver and gold in fact
this hurt my ego so bad that it made it
my life's mission for the next 2 years
of high school to finish a higher rank
than all of them so after giving 2 years
of my high school life to this Mission
sleeping at 3:00 a.m. every single night
alt tapping at Peak reaction time when
my mom would catch me clicking a little
bit too fast for biology homework at
midnight it finally happened December
2019 11:30 p.m. on a school night 30
minutes before the season
ended none of my friends had ever made
it to Plat in League I achieved my
life's
[Music]
Mission I've been chasing that High ever
since I quit hard grinding League of
Legends the day I hit Platinum because
at that point I just had 2 years to pick
up my GPA and sat to make it into a
decent college or else my mom would kill
me so after somehow clutching up a 1540
on my SAT bullshitting my
extracurriculars on my Comon app I made
it into a top 30 School Boston College
but what was supposed to be the most
important achievement of my life that
first year that was promised to be this
magical experience I couldn't help but
feel empty once I entered College I
realized classes and grades didn't feel
scalable enough you were telling me an
all nighter of effort would lead to at
best a test grade which would lead to at
best a GPA number which would literally
mean nothing once I get my first job
offer yo maybe I was coping for being a
[ __ ] academic but when did the
excitement come in isn't this what we
were supposed to grind the next 4 years
of our life so excited for and what
we're supposed to be excited about the
job that we got after all of that
feeling jaded for the rest of the year I
started grinding more on things like the
gym and my own Tik Tok videos by the end
of that year I decided what better way
to disappoint my Korean immigrant
parents than to take a year off from
college entirely a gap year just to
Chase my dreams of building an online
business but with that new Liberation
came a new pressure if I couldn't make
serious money from this I would have
wasted an entire year of my life while
all of my friends were advancing a year
into their resumés and their degrees I
started getting flashbacks every morning
of stories my mom used to tell me when I
was little of the impoverished homeless
lives that college dropouts LED but
after a full year of grinding my Tik Tok
content and my online business
I re-entered college on the back of my
third failed business idea now any
responsible 20-year-old would sober up
after that year of failure except that
online business wasn't for him and focus
back on school see the interesting thing
about the video game of life is that it
doesn't end after your first second or
even third business death you can queue
right back up and go for a fourth duel
and a fifth but you only get stronger
after every duel it's kind of broken but
it's like life has a built-in comeback
mechanic after every death and if you
actually love the game you're playing
you won't ff15 after each death you'll
just keep scaling you give it another 12
months of trying it your all in this
online business thing trying and dying
but playing smarter every time you start
growing a following on Instagram
suddenly you've grown 150,000 followers
in the last year you find the business
that actually matches your play style
and it finally starts to scale $1,000 a
month goes up to $10,000 a month hits
$20,000 a month you've now upgraded your
gear you've moved into the dream
apartment in the city you always dreamed
of you start investing in people
building a team you start to take bigger
swings you launch a new high ticket
product it makes
$27,000 in 3 days September 2024
$45,000 in 1 month and that leads us to
where we are today hi I'm Mino I'm a
21-year-old College Dropout I've been
documenting my life every day for the
past 9 months in the Journey of starting
this business from $0 back when I was
still in college and I'll be posting a
vlog every single day here on YouTube
until we make $100,000 in a month with
this business business welcome to
episode 7 all righty it is 10:30 a.m. so
what are we actually doing today well
this is what our schedule looks like we
hit the gym at 7:30 we film episode 7
which the intro you actually just saw uh
and then we have our Academy call at 400
p.m. this is our low ticket Community
basically where we teach people how to
become content creators that's $69 a
month so we're doing our once weekly
call there at 400 p.m. and at 600 p.m.
my friend Renzo who runs an agency that
does $100,000 a month is leading our
call for our Inner Circle basically
we're teaching all of our students we're
also content creators how to monetize
upon their following and who better to
do it than my friend who makes 100 Grand
a month from his agency also has like
400k followers on Instagram let's do
some deep work on restructuring our
online course for our low ticket
community and creating an actual pretty
much University level curriculum on
short form film making enter deep work
session mode after drinking some
caffeine
let's go it is
3:47 and we are working on a Tik Tok
video right now that we are going to
post if you couldn't tell already that
is the primary grind that I do posting
content online training people on how to
make their content better and doing that
every single day and I love it
storytelling half number two is even
more important but so like if I already
do
[Music]
all right we are back it's
8:26 p.m. and because it's night time
now we're actually going to turn on our
nighttime lights ooh not to be confused
with sexy time lights nighttime lights
are simply red because red is the lowest
on the Kelvin scale and I wanted to
finish off this video about video games
talking about goals cuz I think that's
kind of what this entire process of
gamifying Life comes comes down to but
I've seen a lot of people approach goal
setting completely wrong not in the
sense that you're going to set goals
that you're going to give up on but
chasing goals that have no purpose to
them just for the sake of a number just
for the sake of the dopamin hit of
hitting a number for example chasing a
follower account on your personal brand
or a mere income number uh 10K month for
no reason I think it's crucial to pair
these numerical goals that give
literally the like set end points for
our game right our checkpoints the B
that we have to beat with simply a
recognition of our deeper 10year plan of
why why are we even trying to hit 10K a
month or 100K a month and I used to
think dude they're I'm freaking 21 years
old why am I thinking about when I'm 30
bro like what what's the point as I've
read more books I actually just finished
Dan Mars buyb your time this is the
audio book that I just finished I've
gotten a better understanding of what
life looks like simply for older
entrepreneurs and it's helped me develop
a North star for where I want to be in 5
10 15 20 years which is crazy to say but
I think life is a series of coming up
with this kind of Happiness hypothesis
and then testing it until we find truths
that we can really stand upon with
absoluteness and fulfillment everyone
especially in the online business space
or even in the YouTube space talks about
gamifying life gamify online business by
hitting that next monthly income goal it
doesn't matter if you're scamming people
with your online business bro it's part
of the video game like no it's not you
just made that [ __ ] up so you can cope
with being an [ __ ] and I think that's
the terrifying but also really really
fun part of life we have to kind of
figure out what the rules of the game we
want to play are and we can try out
other people's happiness game hypotheses
but we still have to test out and come
up with our own I used to think this
kind of philosophical mumbo jumbo was
freaking pointless like I'm trying to
make bread here I'm not trying to be
deep but it's helped me prevent this
kind of midlife crisis or mid business
crisis I'm 21 years old when I say
midlife crisis mid- business crisis
where I'm like I don't know if this is
the mission that I want to be on right
now in my business you know I don't know
if I just want to be chasing money
constantly analyzing the rules of the
game I'm setting gives me the motivation
to try just harder and harder to keep
progressing at the game every single day
the design of your game the route that
you're playing the lane that you're on
is designed with the truth that you
resonate with deep down that's when you
can keep scaling Non-Stop and really
play the infinite game I'll see you guys
tomorrow
peace yo this is a freaking Banger bro
this a freaking Banger dude I'm feeling
so good about this video