I'm going to try and do this all in one
take because I have dinner plans with my
girlfriend in 15 minutes there are two
groups of people on the internet the
first group will tell you that passive
income is an absolute lie it's an
absolute scam it does not exist go put
the freaking fries in the back second
group will tell you it is the key to
your Financial Freedom I've spent 2
hours in this past week on my business
and I have made
$4,700 just this week but I want to be
the first to tell you that it's not
actually as easy as a lot of people will
make it seem online everything falls
apart with time in order to make a
business actually passive you actually
need three
things this is awesome
$5,100 that's awesome because to pay for
a ton of stuff this
week so I laid out this framework called
SPC and the first one s stands for
software pretty much any online business
requires the use of software to keep it
alive and to keep it growing this
software called minich chat which I
believe I pay like 60 bucks a month for
will automatically DM these people in
fact I'll show you that's an automatic
DM that my many chat software sent like
5 minutes ago I probably pay about $700
$800 in software cost right now notice
how passive income still requires me to
pay actively recurring income too $65 a
month on many chat the next software I
pay $179 a month for it's convert kit
it's my email software every time
somebody subscribes to my email list
it'll automatically send them the first
day that they subscribe I'll be like
here's some free resources some free
guides that I made about content
creation and it'll help them out right
in fact if you go down below and you
sign up for my free product my email
list will automatically trigger and send
you a few free guides they're good but
they also help to sell but eventually
too emails will get or people won't be
commenting stuff on your Instagram
videos anymore and thus the many chat
won't trigger anymore eventually your
social media page will die down if you
don't post du entropy the vision is
every day every user gets their name
updated on the right
side the vision is to eventually create
L like an entire network of profiles
where people can pitch themselves to
brand and actually get like monetary
opportunties I call content academ
there's a free course and if they post
once every single day I'll get they can
play and we can track they
actually if you do make it to the end
then you can
get you can use software but at a
certain point there's a limit I believe
and you can get really good at software
and that's the whole concept of being a
solo preneurs but I personally think
it's a lot easier if you just simply
learn the second one which is P stands
for people I pay a community manager a
little over $2,000 a month I pay a
Content coach a little bit over $2,000 a
month I also have an editor probably
going to pay up to like $11,000 a month
right now for the YouTube videos for my
Instagram reals Tik Tok if you add up
all the costs that I just gave you I'm
probably paying now with software and
people included about $6 to
$7,000 every single month to keep my
business alive $6 to $7,000 a month like
look like sit with that for a second
that's a lot of money exiting my bank
account that's like terrifying because
if my business dips below that number
I'm just bleeding money so your passive
income machine could also become a
passive drainer of your cash so find
good people make sure you're training
and motivating them well and that's
something I'm still learning okay I
hired people for the first time like at
the beginning of the summer I'm 21 years
old I'm new to this show I just dropped
out of college I I've never even worked
a job before hiring people is really
difficult for me and understanding like
management that I actually have to work
hard in order to at least motivate the
other people in my company to work hard
as well that's new to me leadership is
new to me I'm used to being like
youngest child and I'd always be the
lazy kid who would just be playing
League of Legends be like watching
YouTube videos until like 2: a.m. I was
a terrible kid I was not responsible so
learning leadership was difficult for me
but you have to learn these things too
and you have to keep yourself at a
standard where if you show up and you
just seem pissy on a call talking to one
of your team members okay maybe it's
going to slightly demotivate them if you
miss a payment like that's bad that's
where really comes into play that it's
not necessarily that passive because if
it was really passive You' just have
like a freaking slave working for you
for free that is not how it works and I
think that's like a big misconception
that a lot of people have about passive
income is that if you click the right
buttons on a website you'll eventually
have this passive income machine
especially when you have customers right
because where is money coming from money
isn't printing fromin air people are
paying right just Dro My Mic so that
being said if people are paying you
you're going to need somebody to
communicate back to those people like
nobody likes just buy from machine yes
you can make your experience really nice
with a nice website you going have like
an onboarding sequence with your emails
but that being said people still want to
talk to a real human being so I hire a
coach I hire a community manager and
these people routinely communicate with
the members in my community in this paid
product that yes Nets me $20,000 in
monthly recording revenue and yes I
don't spend that much time actively
filling on it or marketing it right now
but that being said I still had to build
up my software costs my people costs yes
it can become passive but you still had
to pay these dudes at one point and
build up a good product that actually
sells and only then then you can start
Outsourcing this stuff do you think
people are dumb enough to just pay you
for something that you didn't actually
put work into and that's where the third
one comes in which is I want to make I
think you just got to like post you know
like the time when I was like above 90
and you were trying to influence me I
feel like that's a skill I want to work
on influencing people direct cuz I feel
like my career and my is I think it's
extreme patience you're either going to
pay with time or you're going to use
that time to do something and for me
that's content so yes I'm not actually
actively working in the business as much
but I still make content every single
day right in fact I'm getting my video
out for today I'm paying my dues so I
can keep this stream alive where people
are still actively discovering my
business yes I could probably pay for
paid ads eventually but even those will
get old eventually too so I need to
develop this brand and this is like the
probably the hardest hardest part that I
think a lot of people really
underestimate I've been making content
for over 4 years now and people act like
oh you can just start up your p passive
income stream in 3 months and you'll be
making as much as me 10K a month like no
dude I've making content for over 4
years and that's also how I've been able
to structure a digital product because I
know the ins and outs of content
creation and teaching people content
creation by hopping on calls with them
every single week like multiple calls
every single week I've done one toone
coaching with this stuff too so I
learned exactly what people are missing
what people are struggling with what
people actually need if you're lazy like
me I stumbled across this whole idea of
online business because I thought it
would be really easy and passive it
takes work to at least learn too and
you're going to pay Sweat Equity somehow
and you're going to continuously have to
pay whether it's with your time or
eventually with money through software
and through people but even that takes
time to learn so there's always this
payment of time that you have to put in
it usually takes like 90 videos I'm
talking 90 videos posted on Instagram
real and Tik Tok for them to hit 10K
followers that's a long time if you
especially want passive income sometimes
you'll have to do something that you
don't want to do I always liked content
creation but learning how to manage
people was always a huge point of
friction I delayed that decision so long
to actually hire somebody why because I
was scared that like they're depending
on me right if you hire somebody they're
going to depend on you for that next
payment in 2 weeks you have to also sell
them on this vision of where the
company's going after a month so if
you're so used to living this life of
instant gratification right where you
only think in a month's time well good
luck hiring somebody who's going to stay
with you longer than a month because if
you only sell them on a monthlong vision
they're not going to stay longer than a
month or they're not going to actually
do like really good quality work they're
not going to be invested in the mission
that you have so I have like a 5-year
mission for my company you actually have
to lead these people because passive
income is not free and it's not easy and
eventually you'll get used to it I've
gotten used to now these bi-weekly
contractor payments that leave my bank
account every single 2 weeks right it's
like paying rent every 2 weeks except
it's like double my rent it's okay you
get used to it okay I'm not saying it's
a nightmare I actually really enjoy
running my business but don't
underestimate the difficulty that it
takes cuz if you don't even have any one
of these SPC in your business it's going
to be really hard to make it really kind
of passive passive income is not easy
but you can do it understand that it
takes software people and and content
I'll see you guys tomorrow peace