you know what I'm grateful for today
being unemployed we also just got a new
camera gifted to us for our unboxing
today our Sony A7 S3 here's what they
look like voila we are now on state of
mtic however that is not the only reason
why I'm grateful for being an employee
today because today is me and my
girlfriend's anniversary however I am
located in the beautiful city of New
York but she's located in Boston if I
was employed right now at 2:45 a.m. on a
Thursday I would not be able to see her
she's very busy because she has a full
time job so the benefit of being a bum
unemployed is we're going to go
surpriser today it's 1:46 is our first
meal of the
day we're actually 2 hours early but we
haven't really planned out the surprise
because I'm a neglectable bum College
Dropout entrepreneur so I'm really bad
at compartmentalizing I like to think I
have ADHD but I don't want to admit that
to myself this City's beautiful bro why
did I ever drop out I'm just kidding I
freaking hate it here no I'm kidding
Boston's beautiful now instead of
figuring out what my girlfriend's
surprise should be because I have 2
hours to kill before I go into surpriser
after she's done with work she finished
work at 10:00 p.m. damn bro off we're
working from 7:00 a.m. to 10:00 p.m. bro
I'm calling an Uber right now so we're
going to go surprise our friends at
Boston College first before you see our
girlfriend wait I just said our
girlfriend last time my girl girlfriend
actually roast to me for saying our
girlfriend I keep saying our because I'm
so used to saying our like our business
you Road $100,000 on our business guys
our YouTube channel like it's not our
YouTube channel it's freaking my YouTube
channel but it makes you feel included
when I say our you know small little
hack for for Content here we are we're
back on Boston College campus and I
realized I'm actually kind of nervous to
see my friends obviously they started
the semester and I dropped out before
this semester began there's something I
haven't really talked about online but I
think I almost have a fear of
Abandonment like every time I spend time
away from friends I used to be close
with I have this fear that our Dynamic
becomes different like there's a new
distance that comes between us I I think
it's a purely personal problem sometimes
when I even spend time away from like my
girlfriend or my family I feel like in a
way I've betrayed them if I've
prioritized my work and my business my
content above them it feels really
selfish and I don't know why because
it's just you're career right like it's
not like there's nothing wrong with
prioritizing your career you have to
have at our age when you're 21 you're
trying to make something of your life it
feels like I'm doing something wrong by
leaving College I think I overthink a
lot about relationships but I mean we're
here we're right in front of their dorm
so we're going to go surprise them let's
go surprise them we have to wait for
somebody to buzz Us in though cuz we do
not belong here dude I'm freaking
nervous bro I don't know why I don't
want to accidentally be get caught I
hope it's not
[Music]
Noto what are you what the
[ __ ] guy doing
[Music]
here yes yes so Ben are you the cooked
bro
I'm wait you're you're a age devious bro
Ben you're
de you know what we missed last time the
Boba Friday bro we missed Boba Friday
about to go surprise my girlfriend she
doesn't know I'm here I'm nervous is you
the type that likees surprises some
people don't like surprises like that
oh that's a good question I think she
lik surprises I was actually I was I was
nervous I was asking my roommate
yesterday I was like you know she's
going to be home late from work she
might be tired it's like a week day like
is it a good time to cuz it's her
anniversary today like is it a good time
to surprise so you just going to come
and knock on the door yeah so I ordered
her Uber Eats so that's going to be how
she's going to come
down excuse me my
hold my hand turn I literally put me in
my cash
[Music]
[Applause]