at the very beginning of 2024 I tried a
simple experiment what would happen if I
posted every single
[Music]
day and in those first 5 months of 20124
I posted 140 times and I grew 100,000
followers on Instagram and I want to
share with you today these six habits
that I used every single day to Bear
through that consistency so the first
one is the easiest apply which is a
minimum viable video if you've ever
created content you know the feeling of
staying up until 3:00 a.m. because you
thought a video would just take like 1
hour and then it ends up taking 3 4
hours then you wake up the next day and
you're like dude I'm sick of this [ __ ]
the minimum viable video should take you
no longer than 40 minutes to fully crate
I'm talking from planning to filming to
editing now within those 140 videos that
I posted in the first 5 months of 2024
maybe about onethird of them were simply
this minimum viable video that didn't
take that long and some of them even
blew up some of them got over a million
views but I didn't have any expectation
for these videos to be these growth
driving viral videos of my page the
minimum viable video is unscripted and I
simply sit down and think of my main
idea as quickly as possible in fact this
video right now is pretty much a minimum
viable video I sat here for like 30
minutes thinking about this video idea
but once you have the main idea and
structure which in this case is a list
of six things you want to go on to your
second part which is simply putting down
the camera and pressing record until the
the entire video is done you press
record and you don't stop filming even
for short form videos that I posted on
Instagram and Tik Tok I would let the
camera record for 5 to 10 minutes until
the entire Yap was done then I simply
threw it into cap cut I edited
everything on my phone in the cap cut
app and I used this feature called
transcript and what transcript allows
you to do is analyze the entire
transcript take parts that you don't
want and simply highlight them and cut
them out like that boom it would usually
take me 30 minutes to edit these clips
to now down to like 5 minutes throw on
some autoc captions really quickly and
then I just ship it out I wouldn't care
if the video was really good because I
would be proud of the fact that I simply
showed up that day now that brings me to
my second hack of being consistent which
is using software and Hardware to reduce
the friction in your content creation
process and not increasing the friction
so many content creators will want to
use this complex camera Sony fx3 and
then they'll want to edit on their
Premiere Pro and they throw on 10
different like transitions that alone
will make your content creation process
so brutal when it doesn't really even
add that much to the video I filmed
almost all of these 140 videos on my
iPhone and that process would be so easy
to do because I used software only on my
iPhone I use cap cut I would use this
phone case tripod instead of having like
an actual tripod that would just prop up
so I could just prop down my camera
really quickly in the span of 3 seconds
let's move on to hack number three when
you miss a date which will inevitably
happen make sure sure you don't miss 2
days in a row life will get in the way
at one point whether it takes you 30
days to miss a day finally or it takes
you one week or it takes you a year
eventually that will happen and in that
morning that you wake up and you're like
holy [ __ ] I didn't post a video
yesterday I suck don't beat yourself up
as long as I post a video today I have
made up for it that brings me to hack
number four which is writing down your
why on December 31st of 2023 I journaled
my why for why I will be posting every
single day in 2024 I set a precise end
date when I make $100,000 per month I
told myself that's when I'm going to
stop posting every single day Haack
number five I also journaled my three
biggest pain points the three biggest
pieces of friction that will come in the
way of me posting every single day I
wrote them down preemptively there's a
reason why I hadn't been posting
consistently before and it's going to
come up again so I literally wrote down
and number one what will my
acquaintances at College think of my
cringe content number two I'm going to
be tired on on camera there's going to
be many shitty videos where I don't
really come off coherently where I don't
have a clear value ad and number three
I'm going to be uninspiring most days in
fact it's going to be really
embarrassing to show me waking up hung
over or tired and wanting to show that
on camera you can write down these three
big pain points but it's not going to do
anything unless you appraise them as
strengths so under the line that you
wrote down all three of these flaws and
these pain points that you're going to
come across you have to write down how
they are strengths in your content so
for number one what will my
acquaintances at College think of my
cringe content I wrote down let them see
if I truly believe in my truth then let
them see me live it out every single day
that is the only way to truly inspire
people no [ __ ] it's going to be
difficult no [ __ ] people are going to
judge me but if I really believed in my
truth then yeah of course I'd want
people to see if I want to actually
Influence People of course they have to
first judge me and think of me
differently in order for me to actually
make a clear coherent point and persuade
them to think otherwise number two I'm
going to be tired on camera there going
to be shitty videos where I don't
provide much value I wrote down good
it's real it's honest if I truly believe
I'm going to reach my goals of $100,000
a month I don't want to hide the
mundanity of my process I'm going to
regret it in the future if you really
think you're going to make it wouldn't
you wish that your process was honest in
the future cuz I always watched these
YouTubers growing up Iman Gody Hamza
right and it always had blown up after
they made it their come up didn't feel
real they' always talk about it in posts
like dude when I was in 18 I was in the
mud when I was 17 I was grinding like
show that to me I wish I watched that
growing up so that is my strength as
somebody who is on the comeup I want to
show everything in my process that other
YouTubers creators didn't show number
three I'm going to be uninspiring most
days I wish I could have seen their
lowest lows and this helped me realize
that me being uninspiring is actually
value additive because it's honest and
because it shows and comforts people who
are going through similar struggles so
you don't always have to micromanage
your perception online to show Only the
Good sides of you and doing this process
of reassessing all of your friction
points and all the things that you think
are flaws within you and your content as
actual strengths help you realize that
yeah you can be one of the most
powerfully influential authentic
creators out there as long as you
showcase everything creators in 2024
obsess so much over being authentic and
I think it's [ __ ] I think
authenticity comes from when you simply
have a purpose to show it you don't have
to show everything from you [ __ ] and
brushing your teeth every single day and
you also don't have to just whine and
complain on camera and cry every day for
you to be authentic authenticity I think
happens almost by accident when you
simply show so much and you're still
trying to provide value through your
content but you use every single part of
your life as a means of inspiring people
and this leads me to my final point
which is probably the most powerful
which is write down a vision of who you
want to be in 5 years and reread it
every morning I tend to be really really
anxious in the morning so I always
reread my why when I wake up before I
check my notifications or messages or
social media and actually wrote this
down on my Instagram and posted it back
in September of 2023 Mino 2028 which
represents me in 5 years and I wrote it
down and I'll read it here Mino 2028 I'm
25 years old my business is doing
amazing and I love the impact it has it
feels so aligned I wake up to to a
peaceful mind and I see life's Beauty
and everything with a crystal clear
presence and childlike Joy my creations
and words spread it love and inspiration
I explore and build what I want without
fear that it will be a waste of my time
because I have immense Financial
abundance and I have such a strong
understanding of what I want from life I
create and share content that inspires
and moves and Spurs Positive Growth I do
not doubt my capability to do so the
words I speak and the content I share
every day incites love and empowerment
rather than fear or shame I'm honest I
share openly Fearless of judgment or
critique I know deeply that I love
sharing and helping and nothing else
comes first my insecurities or fears
never silence me or stop me from sharing
my body is beautifully sculpted Fitness
is a deeply Inseparable part of my daily
life I'm so grateful for my past self
for building the habits and mindset I
now have after years of relentlessly
sharing creating trying learning
obsessing showing up and not yielding to
my fear or self-doubt my habits are
strong and make my life and mind amazing
there were moments of Doubt throughout
the past 5 years but I persevered now
the doubts and anxieties are so quiet I
haven't stopped to dwell on them in
years I actually pity people who still
live controlled by these strong negative
internal voices I remember what that was
like and I empathize thank you Meo 2023
my life is amazing right now because of
these past 5 years not that your life
isn't amazing though LOL you can read it
right here this was posted on September
1st of 20123 this is even before I
started doing this whole daily posting
Journey but it's so powerful to Simply
remind yourself of where you are headed
in the next 5 years and say it not with
this doubt and not with this
subconscious fear of like I hope I'm
here in 5 years because when you write
down and remind yourself that you are so
certain and that you have so much faith
that these things will happen your brain
just somehow finds a way to find these
Solutions eventually it's October 2024
now and it's been only a year since I
wrote that but I've already achieved so
much of what I wrote down at the time I
didn't even have a business I just wrote
down my business feels aligned you're
training your mind to think and act in
the identity that you want to be in the
future because true change is hard true
change going from this inconsistent bum
watching porn every night playing League
of Legends until 2: a.m. procrastinating
studies never being consistent with any
kind of grind whether it was the gym
whether it was content whether it was
any goal that I set and going from that
to being somebody who posts every single
day and actually achieves his dreams is
hard true change is not this thing that
you just snap your fingers and do I
expected these goals of posting every
single day growing a following an
audience online growing a business to
come easy as if I knew all the answers
already but you won't know the answers
already and going through the actions
every single day helps you realize
everything that you don't know yet in
this process no matter what I've done in
the past no matter who I was in the past
I don't care what matters is what I'm
doing right now every single day and I
will become the type of person who does
show up every single day and it sounds
so dumb and it sounds so silly but it
changed my life and it's the only way
I've been able to become consistent on
this road to 100 $100,000 a month that
being said in the spirit of consistency
on this YouTube game I'll see y'all
tomorrow peace out