all right guys what's up we're in New
York City we linked up with the one and
only Mino we're going to do a day in the
life with him see his business see his
place go do some fun [ __ ] maybe hit the
gym and just talk about life let's get
into
[Music]
it this feels like a boy setup you know
just like all the boys huddled in just
grinding late at night I love this that
is kind of the vibe we were going for
yeah what are you guys doing for for
eating you guys cooking or you just
firing over eats I mean you could you
could see our pantry bro we got dude
dude Pantry y if y'all want some
s we were thinking like yo during the
summer cuz we all room together we were
like yo we're going to cook like we're
going to get a bunch of like that's what
every chicken bro you need to cook once
we had to throw out everything at the
end of the summer cuz we're just eating
out every day and like I I've just
accepted my fate I'm not going to like
cook so what are you actually eating
you're just eating out during the day
yeah like I I mean you guys will see
like the two spots that I eat every
single day yeah what is that it's like
noise caterpillar thing is that for
recording or for sleeping or both for
both because he's recording in there
taking calls in there and we don't have
our Flex wall setup so you guys ready
yeah put us on put us on the recording
welcome to this the kington this is how
I'm going to uh justify expensing my
entire rent wow this is sick everything
is basically for filming and literally
don't even have a bed frame to my
benefit so I don't even want to be in
bed so I just get up yeah so what is
what is that all about you got to point
that out right out of the gate cuz like
obviously we know like you you're
running your own business you're trying
to make money and you're now living in
New York City why do you not have a bed
frame if you're working in your own room
it's like I feel like it's so easy when
you're just you're like working and you
see your bed and it looks so comfortable
like you you see that right if it was
nice it was high it was big I bro hold
up let me just like I got text up
you you just sleep bro you're just na
your day is gone I feel it I feel it and
then you like that's just like a
repeating cycle so that never taking a
nap like it's so much easier to get out
of bed cuz like half my arm is off the
bed when I wake up so I'm just like oh
my God so like everything here is kind
of designed in a sense to create content
how how often are you recording cuz I
swear at one point you were doing every
day some days you're like missing days
now I don't know what's the I'll show
you what I'm doing right now which is
why it's probably been missing if you
look at the date stamps uh like this is
scheduled for in an hour this is
yesterday day before day before that oh
you're grinding every single day now
YouTube yeah big thing is I'm on YouTube
dailies now what changed cuz I know you
were your main platform is Instagram
correct what what made you want to like
put a lot of effort into YouTube all of
a sudden I feel like I'm kind of hitting
a ceiling in terms of more I could do
with the content in terms of Instagram
how much how much how much he's making
per month right now so it's it's been 9
days in October right so not too many
days let's pull up month to date so
far we're at
88.4k our Mr is at 20.3 so that's
basically like all of our paid
memberships for people who are going to
continuously pay every month for a
subscription that's at
20,300 how much have you made total yeah
I can pull that up too it's uh actually
it's it's right here it's 16
110 dude that's insane is it so it
hasn't been a year and you made
$165,000 last month was huge cuz we
finally launched High ticket to 15
people so that was like a 3K for 90 days
thing the main thing what everyone talks
about online is the second you start
selling a course or a program or just
even anything sometimes people call you
a sellout or a guru or a this or a
grifter or that what are your thoughts
on that I think it's a delicate balance
I think one is just being super
transparent like I'll talk about like yo
I sell courses online like d in the left
of a course seller like being super
transparent not trying to hide it cuz
then I I think the audience understands
what a course is what a community is
right but like they just don't want to
feel lied to so like just tell them like
yeah like I'll literally I'll flash my
numbers all the time right so that helps
them be like oh like this guy's not
hiding something and putting on a facade
so everybody else can buy but then he
can like walk away with like some
secretive profit like I'm completely
okay with sharing any of this data like
yo our business is freaking like I made
a video saying yo our business sucks and
it's making me really sad like earlier
this year because our turn was so high
and that like 40% that's like half the
people left I said hi and I built
relationships with these people just to
see them go a month later I was like
damn like I suck and then I was I was
open about that and I think um I see it
as a long-term game right like the
business right now is nowhere near where
it's going to be in a year's time same
with my personal brand so like there's
no point in trying to extract Quick Cash
because the way I want to see this is I
want to build it to like like we're
definitely going to hit 100K a month but
then pass that to like a mill a month
and like that's crazy have like really
comprehensive impact on the space I
essentially want to create stable
Creator education and opportunities so
like essentially kind of like a LinkedIn
sort of thing where creators can go on
there connect with other people connect
with Brands and opportunities just like
like like you said right being a Creator
is really confusing you go in and you're
just like dude what am I even doing I'm
like posting this video like I don't
even know if it was good like why am I
even here right and like how do I even
make money bro like I hear about like
how much do how much money do they even
make right all these weird questions
there's no stability in it and even
though it's difficult I don't think it's
like a gambling thing as most people I
think perceive it as whereas like being
a doctor right lawyer like what are the
actual success rates on that that's low
right people accept that there's
difficulty in there but they still know
it's a stable path so it's like how can
how can we create a thing that
makes the uh becoming a Creator seen as
that stable kind of career path what are
you doing dayto day to try and keep your
mind fresh not get anxious like not get
overwhelmed so this is something I keep
next to me all the time this is this was
honestly what changed my life journaling
not that I started on the 24th but if
you look at my cabinet there I have the
reason why it has six on is because
that's the six Journal that I'm on now W
sick but I started when I was in like
senior year of high school he's talking
about a girl in there that's okay that's
precisely why I started like yo
she that's like precisely what it is cuz
at the time I was like it was I can see
the phases of my development in this
because at the time it wasn't wasn't
focused on impact right it's like hell
no bro you're focused on the next girl
and you're focused on texting girls in
your class I get it bro I get it we're
all the same bro and I was like dude
like I just wanted to improve like my
confidence with girls and I just felt so
like unconfident and like I couldn't
even talk to people so that's kind of
why I picked up the journal because I
like started to like this girl and like
and then like this one day she was just
like oh yeah like like which guy should
I talk to on this I was
like I enjoyed the process of writing
creating like strict guidelines around
that didn't necessarily help me to show
up more it was just a matter of like
enjoying it and keeping it fresh like I
haven't journaled probably in the past
month maybe I've journaled like 5 to 10
days not like too much but like there's
other practices that I'll do maybe I'll
just like meditate for a little bit cool
we're about to go to the gym because no
business is built or stays strong
without you being strong mentally and
physically let's rock today's back day
yeah all right what we RI here
[Music]
want can't even see you're next to
me don't know how you doing
don't how often are you working out you
know like during the week I try to go
once a day like I would say right now
I'm just trying to get into a groove of
working out now that I'm here it's hard
to compartmentalized oh it's gym time
but I'll be like sometimes checking my
like slack or something so I'm honestly
still trying to figure it out but right
now I'm just like trying to show up
every day at least how did you find the
gym like for me when I found the gym it
was because I was actually like super
down bad I wanted to I was going to
college very depressed I I would say
it's actually it's almost the opposite
at this point I feel like I'm I'm trying
to like force myself into the gym these
days cuz like a lot of days I just feel
like ah I want to focus on other stuff
like I want to work on like content or I
want to like work on some other thing in
the business so actually I'm trying to
get myself to go to the gym first thing
in the morning just so I'm like getting
it done with well what about stress
relief does it help you with stress
relief I think slightly but because I I
try to go to the gym earlier on to get
it done with it's more of like a if I
didn't get it done I'll feel stressed
but if I did get it done it'll probably
just have like I think I'll carry the
day on with a little bit higher
endorphins just you're on camera a lot
too like and you say confidence is a big
thing so when you're doing when you're
doing the gym like when you're lifting
is that because like you hope to feel
more confident on camera because you
know you're in shape and you're feeling
better is that the type of confidence
you're speaking about I think it it's
that and also just the fact that I
tackled something hard in the day makes
me feel like oh I can show up now on
camera feeling like I've accomplished
something you know just like a 30-minute
work out when I first started the day I
can now feel like I go on camera I'm
like okay I feel good I feel like I it
it's like a state of mind that I have to
kind of get into a a speaking Flow State
where I feel like the I trust the words
in my mouth in a sense and I trust
what's in my mind and if I can't get
into that state there's like a slight
bit of friction where I'm just like ah
like I don't know like do I sound a
little weird like makes I don't know if
this makes sense I feel like feel like
I'm just like yeah know like some
[ __ ] that I just like gting I've
heard online but going to the gym helps
me ease a little bit of that anxiety I
think something I missed from college is
the bonding aspect that I think I felt
during the gym oddly like it didn't have
to do with college but it's like I would
go to the gym regularly with my college
friends your was yeah and like now
obviously it's
like kind of just going alone so I think
it it did take out a little bit of the
element that I really enjoyed as like
simply as a hobby or as like
a a social activity too at the most part
you've been in New York
for 1 month did you like you lived in
New Jersey though I lived in so I went I
was in Harlem with my roommate this
summer okay and then we moved into for a
one year okay and how do you like living
in the actual City do you feel like you
know your way around everywhere or is
there like you could turn a couple
streets and be like I have no idea where
I am I feel like so this is K toown
right I feel like the benefit of living
in K toown is going out like but because
I don't really do that I can invite
people over to dinner like oh you want
to get dinner come over here instead let
me go to you and I think the one thing
that I like about this area too is just
literally the view from the window is
really nice and because I spend a lot of
time indoors that kind of scenery does I
feel like uplift my mood very often it's
like a daily kind oh I feel inspired if
I dropped you like in the middle of the
city would you know where to go do you
think like I'm a random street without
Google Maps yeah without Google Maps
like what you know I would say cuz you
can just use the eight AB or like 7 out
and then the street sure like I have a
decent mental model of like I know where
I am in the map itself but like in
general it's kind of hard still if if a
friend is like yo what's like a give me
some Banger places to eat I'll be like
yeah I know like two places in t Town
that's like about it listen obviously
you've been in New York for a month so
this is still on you I've been in New
York for a month we could walk around
and like bike around check [ __ ] out walk
around I think that that direction is
better well wait
we could walk around or we could go in a
helicopter are you [ __ ]
serious yeah bro are you down I'm so
sorry are you down oh my god let's go
we're going to we're going sorry we're
going to a 15-minute helicopter tour new
public we're going to the helicopter
Guys Somewhere hopefully they don't kill
me oh [ __ ] did he leave is that is US
yellow or black the black no right here
we have a helicopter
no what the
fuckly holy [ __ ] all right here we go so
we're supposed to get there at 12:30 the
current arrival says 12:42 and we almost
missed our Uber so I'm going to sure we
could still go biking
like thank you for calling K and
[Music]
Y from the King to the ring to the Bell
to the S any last words if you can make
it in New York you can make it
anywhere yeah SK toilet Ohio
[Music]
R honestly since moving into the city
into the city I I think I had like
really high expectations maybe it's
romanticizing it from seeing it across
the the water growing up now it's kind
of loud I'm realizing you know like I
kind of miss nature being so trapped
right in the middle of New York is like
you don't really get many trees yeah
like every single night it's
like like
it's I kind of miss the piece of just
trees like taking a walk in nature like
right outside kind of thing yeah so I
don't think settling down here for for
sure no but like like I might want to
try a different location next year after
my
leense bu
house like I'm
[Music]
in how long ago did you you dropped into
of college right 4 months ago I was in
college and what were you
studying
marketing that's so contradict or it's
actually just so funny that you go in
from marketing traditional marketing in
college to just doing marketing outside
of college for yourself I thought I was
going to go down like you know typical
marketing I thought the whole Social
Media stuff would just be part of my
resume like oh yeah I have an experience
and I got to ask the question cuz I I
personally dropped out of college too
and the hardest part for me wasn't my
trust in myself it was actually my
parents trust in me yeah that's real
that's real dude what what was that like
for you probably about 20 back and forth
between me and my mom like ranging from
pretty much all out like yelling to
eventually like we're tired of yelling
at each other and like arguing about
this because we're not going anywhere
it's she's from a different generation
she doesn't understand this stuff she
hasn't seen like the opportunity that I
saw and like we came to a point where
it's like we recognize we just kind of
have to agree to disagree yeah and I
think I'm very grateful though that like
my my mom didn't force anything on me
she was just like I really think you
should kind of thing did she like
understand or does she think you're like
scamming and you're like got to be doing
something bad it's funny that you
mentioned that because I used to talk
about numbers pretty much I would only
talk about numbers to my mom I wouldn't
talk about like oh I'm enjoying this
like oh I feel like I have these goals
like and I'm really excited for it it
was always like yo like look how much
money I made like oh last month you know
we did this if I make this much money
will you allow me to drop out of college
no how about this much money no well how
about this much money no and my dad
would be like oh that's you know 50k a
month like okay he could drop out but my
mom was like no like no matter how much
you need to finish college and I think I
realized me projecting all these numbers
and like looking it wasn't even about
college I think it was a deep down need
for me to get validation from my parents
to just here like I believe in you even
despite College I believe you'll succeed
I think that was what I was looking for
right and I don't think numbers really
changed that we didn't want to end the
day there we wanted to end the day on
something big so from us at w myself and
everyone involved we have something for
you this is not only going to it's funny
because you brought something about oh
I'm recording now I'm using a camera
da um so I'm going to grab this bag here
for you yo no shut what is this this is
yours this whole thing so open it up
what this whole whole thing yeah we got
you
uh something yo what the this is not
something this is like we got you a
basket of goods just tell you exactly
what it is bro you can put that aside
first off we got SC card second off we
got a lithium iron battery see you need
a battery and an SD card I'm not sure
what you would need that for maybe
something else in here um let me help
you open this up this is a Sony a7s this
is the topof thee line camera you can
get right now no that's
crazy yeah bro this is the best of the
best wait is this a DSLR or mirrorless a
full frame it's a full frame frame yo 87
S3 I saw you grinding on your little uh
Cannon here I was like bro your roommate
actually hooked you up cuz I hit him up
a couple days ago I was like bro we're
coming this film with Meo what do he
what does he need right now like what we
who's his roommate yo what was his name
again like exactly your roommate bro I
hit him up and I was like what's the
thing that's going to help impact his
life right now like what is he grinding
on he's like dude he's doing content
every day on YouTube I was like bet we
got him with this that's [ __ ] nuts
bro holy [ __ ] dude so anyone who watches
Meo [ __ ] be ready for the content game
to be [ __ ] Skyhigh right now