today is day 12 of road to $100,000 a
month here in New York City baby
[Music]
do all right it is
12:45 p.m. and we're about to get
caffeinated this is a green tea energy
drink with 150 Mig of green tea caffeine
we got a call in 15 minutes our 1 to1
with one of our Inner Circle members Joe
he actually started off in the academy
his agency at0 do now I believe he's hit
highs of like 50k a month and it's
really cool because I've been able to
see the growth of his business because
he's been in our community the content
Academy for the past I think 6 months
now oh bro I [ __ ] vacuumed this
yesterday how is there more hair again
Daniel yeah I actually brought my vacuum
from home if you ever want to uh oh you
did
y all right clean up man bro there's
barely anything there why is your vacuum
built like this I literally clicked the
button yo why is it built like that it's
literally says that Jack the red button
bro why is it like is this how you're
supposed to put it back together yeah
clean that [ __ ] up boy yo cuz
I are you a fan of that song well now I
am cuz now it's stuck in my
head I want to eat a lunch my bad I'm
sure right here and now we're here in
Boston what of my unemployed
gangsters I roast my YouTube channel you
want to know what I'm grateful for today
I'm grateful for the fact that I
discovered books at a decently young age
I'm 21 years old and in the past 2 years
I've read over 20 self-improvement books
now I never thought I'd be able to drop
out of college and do my dream full-time
of content creation and Entrepreneurship
in freaking New York City I want to walk
you guys through exactly one of the
books that absolutely changed my life
which is mindset by Carol D I Promise by
the end of this video you'll finally be
convinced to pick up and actually finish
a book for the first time ever now this
book which is called mindset explains
one phenomenon that separates the people
who achieve their dreams and the people
who never end up achieving their goals
which is the difference between having a
fixed mindset and a growth mindset a
fixed mindset is the belief that our
traits our character traits are
determined by fixed attributes like our
genetics or maybe some kind of trauma
that we picked up when we grew up
however a growth mindset explains that
we are actually completely in control of
these character traits and and they are
completely determined by the effort we
put in to actually change and improve I
just had to text my friend that I'm on
the way running a little bit late New
York is so hectic by the way back when I
entered freshman year in college I was
very lost and I didn't really believe in
myself I operated on a fixed mind set
every single day and you're probably
familiar with what this looks like too
every time you fail a test every time
you don't feel like going to the gym
every time you see some piece of advice
on the internet from some handsome Asian
fellow you always think of some static
trait and some personality trait that
you uniquely have that makes you unable
to apply this advice to change your life
whether it's running an online business
getting consistent in Fitness getting
disciplined I have some magical
character trait that makes me unable to
apply this change and actually grow oh
my God now these sort of fixed mindset
beliefs pop up everywhere in our life I
used to tell myself I'm not hardworking
enough to actually study there's a lot
of nerds in my class who would actually
study for tests but I'm the type of kid
who's lazy so get away with it by
cheating on every test I was never like
a hardworking active kid so I would
never actually be consistent in the gym
your identity is just the product of the
ideas that you've told yourself growing
up and the worst part is once you start
taking pride in these identities because
they give you a sense of comfort once
we're so used to identifying by these
adjectives once you start doing actions
that break past this identity label
you're going to feel a ton of cognitive
dissonance and if you enjoy having this
label of you I take pride in being a
lazy person I'm the typee of person who
succeeds and gets stuff done while not
trying that hard good luck actually
trying to make any significant change in
your life that's going to amount to
anything any kind of goal that you
actually want to achieve there are
people way dumber and way lazier than
you that have achieved insane changes in
their life stop telling yourself you are
this type of person the solution that I
found and you're going to hate me for it
is simply fake it until you make it tell
yourself that you will change a year
from now you will be the type of person
who can go to the gym consistently who
does run a successful business who has
the confidence to speak to anybody and
speak their mind and speak their truth
actually be able to hop on sales calls
with full confidence and yes do the
actions that are necessary show up to
the gym force yourself to be in
uncomfortable social scenarios but
eventually you're going to become the
type of person and you're going to look
back and think wow that's how you change
genuinely for the first time in your
life and break past the limits that you
ever thought you would achieve in your
life hello squid game oh my way
BTS Esa espa guy no come back
Esa P yo are you the guy with the
girlfriend aren't you the guy with the
girlfriend Wait no that's supposed to be
a secret oh should think out the
boyfriend D you cracking one right now
yeah you're you're right you're
that's that's New York classic bro D it
yeah damn dude that's a lot of food can
you even finish that I feel like you
can't I'm a big boy bro I can finish I
don't I don't honestly that doesn't even
look that good you know that's like a
homie I feel like that look kind of
Welcome Back Vlog today in New York City
we are going to be yelling bomb into the
first person this was a good place to
end the Vlog we just got back to my
apartment showing Jus in her room he
brought me to his Diddy room yeah got
the red LED got he got the baby oil this
is nice to you got to take this off
first you got to take it off defense
mechanism it's okay oh I farted but was
so can put okay oh yo it's smells like
cologne bro it's confirmed Justin Han
farts butterflies no I was trying to
fart but there was nothing there was
like nothing there side Force really
hard what happened was like a piece of
thong like came out and went back in
Diddy bro Asian didy right
here thank you guys for watching yo
editor cut that part he's Diddy if you
cut that part off I swear to God I'm
coming after you thank you guys for
watching it is everyday bro that CH FL
get