it is currently
4:07 a.m. and I'm promising to you guys
I'm going to wake up in 5 hours at 9:00
a.m. it's 12:08 p.m. it is now 12:23
p.m. welcome back to day 13 of Road
$100,000 a month however today is no
normal day in our business because we
are finally relaunching our High ticket
Inner Circle for our coaching program
which means 15 spots $3,000 each you
need to sell within the next 3 days it's
going to be intense and I cannot be
waking up at freaking 12:00 p.m. every
single day so I feel like I'm freaking
oh I feel like the hardest part is
juggling between three different
products now that I'm running in this
business and also doing YouTube and
short form they say you just got to go
all in on one thing which is going to be
YouTube but this transition period where
we're getting absolutely poopy ass views
400 is crazy it's a tough period dude
but we're going to hope that things pick
up they will pick up wait no no no they
will pick up all right I've had enough
moping we got to step outside of the
[Music]
house all right we're back just got a
breath of fresher and got a smoothie
with protein powder in it but honestly I
feel a little bit better I think my mind
is a little bit clear I talk to my
parents who basically do accounting for
my business and they were telling me
that I owe $440,000 in taxes we have 37k
by the time we were going to pay taxes
we're going to be --3k I honestly didn't
think I would show you guys but there it
is I've just laid out all my cards I
just laid my balls flat on the table and
I'm stressed
dude there's you do we just booked a
call so there we go we have two booked
calls but we need probably at like a 75%
closing rate we need like 20 calls no
point in stressing though stressing is
not going to help the only thing that
matters is what are the actual acttion
things we get done today that's what
we're going to focus on all right it is
2:22 we just finished up our video sales
letter if you don't know what a video
sales letter is basically sells your
product in video form it's fair simple
and now we're going to meet up with our
friend Luke he's going to help me flesh
out my curriculum for the updated fullon
2.0 content academy one big Revelation
that I had is that I want to write a
book Meo what the [ __ ] you're like 21
years old why the [ __ ] do you want to
write a book right I'm like who do you
think you are I think I've realized that
as I scale this business right content
creation mentorship with 15 people a
Content creation Community with 400
paying members I want to be able to
reach and deeply impact more people and
books have been the medium in my life
that have genuinely changed my life I
freaking hated reading when I was
younger but content creation genuinely
genuinely changed my life concentration
has given me purpose in life it's
allowed me to meet such cool people it's
allowed me to feel like I can wake up
every single day so excited to work on
something bigger than me even today I
woke up feeling super bump and now I'm
really excited to work I feel like every
time I have this new vision for where I
want to take my brand or just new video
idea it lights me up with a level of
excitement never had when I was in
school and yeah that's why I want to
write a book because I can actually
deeply help and touch people so I'll
keep youall posted on the progress of
that book I don't know how long it takes
to write an actual book and publish it
let's go meet our friend Luke when's it
launch November 21st big launch for the
content Academy 2.0 all right it's
currently 4:15 p.m. we just got done
fing out the 2.0 launch for the content
Academy keeping it very hush hush cuz I
want to make it a really big deal on my
social media but now we're just getting
lunch at the same goddamn place we go to
launch every single day which is this
pasta bar called Market crits baby can I
get a possible with a
penny
1992 so a little bit of insight on
what's actually in the content Academy
2.0 we're launching a completely
revamped course on content creation it's
going to be a lot more structured going
to talk about editing storytelling
cinematography brand design we're also
launching an affiliate program we're
also going to essentially integrate
software every time somebody joins our
Discord they immediately get entered
into this game system where you're going
to be put on a leaderboard every single
time you post your score is going to go
up or down based on if you were
consistent that day with posting content
it's gamified learning I personally hate
just watching courses without any sort
of like tangible impact that it has on
my learning but being able to see my
score go up and down now that's fun and
I want to make this program fun and also
one big surprise as well we're going to
launch a $1 free trial for the $69 a
month membership it's going to be super
exciting holy [ __ ] we just posted this
Instagram story and we're starting to
get replies right now this is our
official launch for Inner Circle
currently we have only five booked calls
and we're hoping this story will get us
to 20 plus booked calls I'll update
y'all at the end of the night how many
booked calls we finished with but
currently we're at 5: and I'm feeling
super freaking pumped cuz I know this
story is going to freaking print we had
this song in the story bro of course
it's going to
print oh my goodness it's 9:33 and I'll
just show you what our calendar looks
like we pretty much got it fully booked
we have this many calls but the problem
is most of them only have less than the
required amount of $100 to $500 most of
them if you can see look on the right
hand side none of them have enough money
to afford a program so I have to
manually DM people and either say are
you available to make it or if not I'm
sorry we're going have to cancel the
call oh I can't believe this many
disqualified people book a call all
right it is 11:47 p.m. we're about to
end the day and we finished off the
night after one of the most slump
mornings ever 15 qualified booked call
each person has at least $1,000 ready to
invest I'm going to pray I'm going to
pray dude we have 15 spots to sell and
obviously not all 15 people will buy you
can even close half of them dude that's
still op we can figure out another
Instagram story that we can roll out to
put even more calls we'll figure it out
tomorrow I'm satisfied with what we've
got going I have to wake up at 6:00 a.m.
to prep for these calls cuz our first
call is at 9:00 a.m. thank you guys for
watching we'll see yall tomorrow because
it's every day I good morning guys it is
9:12 a.m. at a call at 9:00 so that is
an awful start to the day