so here's the deal I run an online
coaching business that teaches people
how to make quality content on Tik Tok
and Instagram and grow their personal
brand so they can start growing their
businesses this coaching product
specifically is
$3,500 in the next 3 days I'm trying to
sell all 15 spots let's [ __ ]
go [ __ ] dude so freaking
drained uh good morning guys it is 9:12
a.m. just woke up at a call at 9:00 we
just asked him to reschedule we have our
first sales call then at 9:45 that is an
awful start to the day missing a call
because I slept in oh my goodness we're
going to go take a shower [ __ ] we just
pushed back our first call to 10:30 a.m.
which means we have exactly 54 minutes
until our first sales call and I'm
[ __ ] nervous dude I don't think I've
been feeling great just mentally for the
past couple days to be completely honest
I think I've been feeling pretty nervous
and anxious about all this High ticket
stuff going on I've actually had issues
in the past of not wanting to do high
ticket coaching one toone because when
somebody pays you that much money it's
almost like they're relying on you to
make sure they get results we took on 15
students for the first time last month
and they've been having a great time all
of them have been very active they've
been very responsive a lot of them have
been showing up to all the group calls
but I think it's been taking a
subconscious toll on me pressure of
knowing that these people are heavily
relying on me is new new to me I'm
actually the second youngest person out
of the 15 people and I'm supposed to be
their teacher and Mentor which is silly
bro in these kind of times though I
think it's important to remember that I
have everything it takes to help these
people and achieve my own goals I'm
going to go read my morning affirmations
crack open this year a because we have
eight sales calls ahead of us today
that's [ __ ] Hefty I've never taking
that many sales calls in my life my
mental state probably feels at like a 4
out of 10 right now in terms of I don't
know mental health self-belief it's not
feeling good but the best way to reset
your mental before going into freaking
war is hitting the gym so that's exactly
what we're going to
do we got our first call now in 1 minute
let's get [ __ ] super pumped hello I
can hear you yeah all right we just got
off the second call of the day we're
going to Crackle open another can of
caffeine cuz we got a lot to do today we
got another call coming up in 28 minutes
oh my gosh dude that call honestly like
I felt like I had to I had to super
close there bro I was like I had to sell
him really hard he was looking for the
price a little bit earlier on but I was
like nah here's what's inside here's the
value you're going to get just kept
building up value being like dude this
program is going to be sick I see so
much potential in you as a Creator
genuinely I saw so much potential I
needed him to see the vision first
before then we just dropped the price
cuz a price without the value is just a
[ __ ] waste of money a price with
value is a banger ass product yeah you
would want to be doing content full time
as well that's the dream let's make the
dream happen dude [ __ ] dude the other
guy couldn't pay once that goes through
and we can uh awesome so it just went
through there it is okay yeah perfect
just went through we have another call
coming up in 22 minutes so I'm going to
eat lunch dude cuz I am completely
fasted it's on 300 mg straight of
caffeine that's all I've had to eat
today so I got to eat this Cobble bowl
that I ordered last last night oh my God
it's ly soggy it's edible whatever I
just have to step outside grab a protein
shake because honestly I I couldn't
stomach down a cob I'm freaking burn tow
we got another call in 5 minutes oh dude
I'm so freaking dreamed bro so it is now
12 a.m. and the question is how many
sales did we close today for the Inner
Circle and how much money did we make so
we took eight sales calls and I'll pull
up my sales info here for the content
Academy we ended off the day at 5 sales
and
$1,000 there we go mission complete for
day one we have two days left I'll see
yall tomorrow peace