shut up good morning today's the second
day of sales calls trying to make
$330,000 to save my business in 3 days 3
2 one let's get today is a much calmer
day because I only have one sales call
today at 3:00 p.m. but Justus in my
community manager is actually taking
four sales calls so we're going to see
how many we can close by the end of the
day but that being said I'm really
enjoying just journaling in the morning
sipping my EUR mate and we're about to
head out grab a smoothie go to the gym
so it's Montage time editor kick it from
the screen to the ring to the pen to
the yo quick update uh fortunate or
unfortunate happening but basically our
community man Justin sent out an email
to our email list and even though I only
had one sales call today now we have
seven we have seven freaking calls and
Justin has six so bro we have 13 calls
combined today what the heck and it's
been bro it's been an hour since we sent
that email I think we're lowkey cooked I
was thinking we might have to open up
more than 15 spots maybe a 20% C dude oh
my gosh I was stressing yesterday
because I thought we wouldn't close
anything now we're drowning in leads
guys this is the power of a personal
brand if you want to build your personal
brand go click link Down Below in the
YouTube description dog it was just this
we've just reopened for 48 hours click
here to book your call and that's it so
yeah now we got to start prepping for
these sales calls cuz our first sales
call is in 90
minutes oh [ __ ] I'm late to the first
call it's 131 call is at 1:30 joining up
right now on Zoom Zoom Zoom Zoom Zoom
but since you been good it's looking
like a noow hey it's just me just me hey
oh okay okay Google play Bruno Mars
Talking to the
[Music]
Moon I know you're somewhere out there
somewhere far away yo how's it going man
hey y hey I see it on my end let's go we
Clos late uh hi I really appreciate that
I want you to genuinely feel that it's
coming great talking to you n good
talking to you too Dam bro you didn't
close on the call you didn't right last
one got make this work good it went
through awesome dude see you take
[Music]
care let's go P baby 3K paid in front
let's go let's go last call of the day
we finished off the day at
6.7 granding F
Fe at the end of day two well Justin
actually has one one or two more calls
that he needs to follow up on but at the
end of day two how many people have we
closed we have officially closed nine
spots with a total of
$117,000 in the last 2
days SH now here's a little twist I
think I'm actually going about to buy a
$144,000 coaching program next week with
that being said we're actually because I
have to obviously pay Justin I have to
pay the other
employees and my editor we actually
might still be in the negative which
means it all banks on tomorrow if we can
close those calls and fill up all 15
spots because we made 17K but it's
actually $115,000 on a coaching program
then we're back down to 3K and then
after paying everybody it's going to be
zero we still need to close all the
spots tomorrow our business is actually
still probably cooked job's not finished
all right it's
8:17 p.m. I have only drank a smoothie
today I pretty much completely fasted so
I am freaking starving problem is I
don't cook ever so I have to find
something to eat obviously I'm going to
try and make it cheap if I'm eating out
alone why the [ __ ] would I ever drop
$100 on like some random K BBQ dinner
even if I was eating alone can I have a
table for one please so we're going to
do a review of each hon here this place
is Miss Korea it had $3 signs so that's
why we came here first let's try the
aluk here veryy good that's like A8 out
of 10 let's try the rice like a seven no
that's like a eight okay that's pretty
good we straight up ordered just one
quar of hler thinly sliced brisket I
think this alone was like 48 we're going
to be trying this brisket this [ __ ]
better be good I paid 45 goddamn do for
this is brisket
alone okay it's pretty good it's pretty
soft like it's got a good Che to
it all right we just got done with
dinner $59
alone we just got home I'm got in a
trunk oh [ __ ]
[ __ ] it was before so we're just de
working on our thumbnails to end the
night before we call my girlfriend
before I call my girlfriend why the [ __ ]
did I say we it's not your girlfriend
[ __ ] you just can't wait to