good morning it's 9:41 a.m. 3 days ago I
decided to launch a high ticket product
for $3,500 to5 people we needed to sell
all 15 spots or else my business would
be cooked because the IRS is pounding me
for tax money that I haven't paid yet so
far we've sold nine spots and today is
day three of three and we need to sell
six spots today my girlfriend's visiting
New York we literally spontaneously
planned this trip an hour ago and I just
bought her train it but here's the only
problem this is my bed I don't even have
a bed for him this is a twinxl bed and I
feel terrible housing her on this shoddy
bed like I invited her here to come to
New York just for her to my foot for
scale even more scale i i i my can't
even fit like look at this two arms and
I'm cooked it's great because I hate
sleeping cuz I need to grind but it's
terrible for my girlfriend obviously
feeling welcomed obviously she thinks
she's staying here and she's like the
sweetest Soul she like I don't even care
I could sleep on dirt and I'd be happy
and I was like how terrible of a
boyfriend if I would to actually let her
sleep on practically nothing a pancake
so I'm looking at hotels right now in
New York City and I realized how
expensive they are bro this [ __ ] is
$469 dude oh my gosh but anything for
the surprise we're also amidst the
launch of our high ticket coaching
business right now and even though boy
Prosper sold one earlier today he took
the sales call instead of me so just
called me let's
go it's so easy holy [ __ ] no bro thought
he was special bro thought he was
special I got one too D dud 469 for
night [ __ ] it let's do it oh my goodness
here we go
anywhere it's up to you New York so
here's the plan we're taking her to a
dinner place that's in uptown New York
that is one stop away from the hotel
we're going to bring her to dinner and
then I'm going to accidentally take one
stop too far up do you eat yet okay I
know the perfect place my first time
ever trying bone marrow wag you hot
dog CET you e catchup guys comment down
below that you need catchup so we are
headed to the desert place now in uptown
New
York you excited for
dessert the
island taking me to top of the got to
Rosevelt Island yeah it is an actual
tiny Island would you want to live
somewhere like
here away I think it's definitely like
better than where where the fu you are
right now D I thought it would be a
better damn it this is a really cool
hotel like you said you wanted a
simulation of living on this island oh
my gosh
crazy I'll make
it anywhere
it's up to you New York New York
[Music]