I'm 21 years old and as of today I have
made my first ever $50,000 month well
it's not exactly 50,000 but we're going
to hit it today in this process I
realized there were three stages of my
journey that I had to go through and one
crucial lesson that I had to learn along
the way which was getting from 0 to
$1,000 a month going from $1,000 to
$10,000 a month consistently
consistently is a keyword I'll explain
exactly what that means later and then
lastly $25,000 a month cons consistently
now to get to that first level of $1,000
a month I've realized the most important
thing is that you just simply need one
skill that you're really good at that is
it a lot of people misconstrue like okay
$1,000 a month it needs to be my own
business I need to hire people like no
you don't you just need to like work
with somebody and make some bread and
that's it okay it can basically feel
like a job you should basically feel
like you're freelancing your skill to
somebody else and there's four online
business skills that are extremely high
income right that you can make over 100
Grand a month with any one of these the
first one is ADS I'm talking like
Facebook ads Instagram ads the second
one is social media content creation the
third one is copyrighting and funnels
and the fourth one is sales it doesn't
matter what you learn but I've realized
that as long as you just specialize for
6 months in this skill and just go all
in on it and stop thinking about all the
other little things like you start
watching some business Guru online talk
about hiring you start thinking that you
need to start delegating like when
you're making 500 bucks a month like no
you don't you just need to specialize in
one skill one the reason why I say one
as well is because it's so easy when
you're not making any money to think
that you need to Pivot something else
like no you don't just need to
specialize in one skill and then work
really hard to sell yourself to somebody
else and that person will pay you
$11,000 in one month and ideally will
keep paying you $1,000 a month which
will be the momentum that you build off
in order to keep scaling and actually
grow a business but at the beginning
You're simply a contractor and a
freelancer and it's going to feel a
little bit demeaning and not worth it to
get paid $1,000 a month is nothing like
those internet business Heroes that you
probably watch that's not going to
happen when you're going from 0 to
$1,000 a month in fact you're probably
going to have to work even harder
because it's all new and when you don't
have extremely large leverage value that
you can provide to other people it's
going to be harder to get a job and it's
essentially what you're doing you're
getting a job and in order to do that
you just need to get really good at that
one skill now the lesson here that I
wish somebody told me though which would
have saved me so much time in this
online business journey is that yes you
need to stick to one skill for me that
skill was content creation on Tik Tok
making viral Tik Tok videos was my
specialty but I wish somebody told me
that it doesn't have to suck I was under
this idea that online business has to
feel really difficult and I have to
suffer through learning through the
skill like I was already making Tik Tok
videos and I got very lucky because I
stumbled upon it having fun with my
friends I was just like oh I'll make
some Tik Tok videos everyone else is
making Tik Tok videos I just want to
like play this little it looks like a
video game you can see how many views
you get that seems fun let me try it and
then I had a couple videos blow up I was
like holy there's like this is fun
like this is addicting and it kind of
just got hooked on it as a high schooler
okay when I actually got into online
business I was like no no no no I need
to like figure out this High income
skill that everyone else is talking
about like no if you have a high- income
skill one of the four that I talked
about it doesn't really matter which
permutation that you have of it I was
making meme videos about among us about
squid games I used to think that had
zero zero value in online business and
that was the furthest from the truth if
I walked into a room and told anybody
that I grew my personal account with my
face I grew a page 400,000 followers in
one month on Tik Tok and I think I got
literally like a 100 million views in
that month I would have gotten a client
literally anywhere but for some reason I
just couldn't get that through my thick
skull I should have just stuck to
content creation from the very beginning
pitched a client and then stuck with him
and actually provided a really good
service and put my all into that service
and once again it's going to feel like a
gr and a job because you're doing it for
the first time if you're providing a
service for the first time it's
essentially like your online business
internship you have to treat it like an
internship and you have to stop thinking
about it from the perspective of like I
could never do this forever yeah you
won't be able to do it forever you won't
be just doing a small little freelance
gig for $1,000 a month forever that's
not even something you could
realistically live off in the United
States but it's your online business
internship you're not going to be
working an internship either for the
rest of your life right the goal of an
internship is to build up experience you
can leverage that on your resume or in
the case of online business
realistically kind of is your resume
whenever you pitch somebody else you're
like I did this with this client I grew
this client's account from 0 to 10,000
followers hey go hire me and pay me more
because I can literally like show you
and stand upon these results now you're
not paying to take a chance on me you're
paying from somebody who has experience
so pay me good right and then you could
start pitching higher prices like
$22,000 a month that being said how do
you go from $1,000 to $110,000 a month
and not just $10,000 a month but $10,000
a month consistently and you need to
make $110,000 a month three times in a
row your metric of success not just 10K
a month because I made this mistake back
in 2022 I set this goal on my wall I
pasted it 10K a month I literally like
woried that goal I I sat every single
day and I was like I I need to hit this
goal it like once I hit this schal
everything's going to change I'm going
to have Financial Freedom I can finally
like talk to my mom and be like yo I
could drop out of college now I'm making
real internet money like I'm him now I
want be like Iman Gods you got that
Financial Freedom I'm going to be
traveling to Bali that didn't really
Happ happen because the day I hit 10K a
month right it was May 2023 the next
month I went right back down to $0 a
month realistically like how are you
going to pay for any kind of Lifestyle
if you go from 10K a month once to $0
the next month or 1K a month the next
month you need to hit 10K a month three
times in a row to really understand that
you have a real online business the
metric of success is not just for your
own Financial Security but it is simply
so much easier to resell an existing
customer than to sell somebody new every
single month so that being said if you
get five clients who are each paying you
2K a month do whatever possible to make
sure those clients stay the next month
which means provide a good service for
the other 29 days you sell somebody and
on day one you're like yo we're going to
provide you the best service and then
you ghost them for the next 29 days
practically of course they're not going
to want to work with you and pay you
again the next month and then you're
going to have to do this entire
difficult arduous process of hunting
down your leads right selling them dming
them getting their phone number closing
them over the phone and then like having
to deal with all their objections and
then finally once you're done in that
spot again just to know that you're
going to lose them the next month that's
an awful feeling and if you're simply
chasing that number that initial number
entering your bank account you're
playing a losing game where you're
constantly just going to be starving the
next month for that next customer for
the next 1,000 for the next $10,000 I
used to make this mistake when I first
got into entrepreneurship because I
realistically just wanted to prove to
people that I could make money so I did
it really quickly I went from like
$1,000 a month to like $2,000 a month
back down to zero and then went up to
10K a month the next month and I was
like yo I'm the I went from 0er to
10K a month in 1 month and I I thought
to myself like yo I'm him for that like
I signed five clients in one month I'm a
beast and then I lost them all the next
month and I was like oh why did
that happen well it's because I was so
focused on sales and marketing that I
couldn't focus on making a good product
or if you're simply selling client which
is what a lot of it will be if you're
hitting your first 10K month I wasn't
focused on the client experience I was
simply not focused on building an actual
good relationship with the client it is
that simple but once again it's still
going to feel like a job basically right
if you have five clients you're kind of
working five jobs and that's okay right
eventually to scale past that you're
going to need to know what I'm going to
teach you in the last lesson but that
being said a lot of it is just treating
your customers like your family and that
is lesson number two two that's so weird
which is treat your customers like your
family because that's the only frame
that's worked for me to genuinely be
like okay I'm actually going to treat
these people well I'm going to do
whatever it takes to get them good
results another frame I use is treat my
customers like my friends if my friend
wired me two grand today I would work my
ass off to get them good results that is
the level of experience that you want to
give your customers to make them buy
again because you would never burn your
relationship with your family or friends
right if they paid you money you would
do whatever you promised them cuz you
wouldn't just be giving them a mid
experience at you know scraping the
barrel and just doing enough no you'd be
like dude I freaking love you bro I'm
going to do whatever it takes to grow
your social media account to help you
out and reach your goals I set this goal
of 10K a month just personally because I
wanted to prove to my mom that I could
do this internet business thing
seriously and I could prove to her that
I could drop out and be this like
full-time guy who's going to do it but
your customers aren't there to be your
pity party and help you achieve your
dreams your customers are there to
achieve their own dreams not yours okay
so don't think of online business in
this purely selfish short-term lens of
how am I going to extract all this cash
shortterm what's going to happen in 6
months I don't know I'm an entrepreneur
I'm supposed to like you know be be
risky and just like take risks I'm not
supposed to know what's like I'm a
spontaneous guy I used to tell myself
I'm a spontaneous guy I don't really
have a six-month plan but it's okay
because we're going to run up our
business really quickly and then all my
opportunities will show themselves in 6
months like no my month one clients
should be my month six clients that is
the biggest biggest ideal and that is
how you hit 10K a month consistently
three times in a row when you know that
you've genuinely treated your customers
right realistically you are not going to
get anywhere if you are selling people
forgetting about them and selling new
people you're also going to burn your
reputation quicker than you could ever
imagine 10K a month multiple times
should be your metric of success and
treat your customers like your family
cuz that is realistically in my
experience at least the only way I've
been able to actually get people to keep
paying me every time now level number
three is 25k a month consistently I have
now made 25k a month consistently in the
past 3 months in the past 3 months my
business has made 128 Grand so you
divide that by three it's a lot more
than 25k a month from my experience
going from 10K a month consistently
having a decently chilling business
where I yes I was serving the same
customer but I was selling a low ticket
Community for $69 a month and I had like
200 people in that Community right
people would come people would go and it
was chill and I didn't really have to
think too hard about it because I had my
personal brand supporting this business
but to go from 10K a month to 25k a
month and now 50 bro I had to break
myself and rebuild myself and that was
the next kind of echelon of my journey
was that I thought I had it figured out
going to 10K a month I was like dude
like it wasn't that bad how hard could
like even 20K a month be mere essence of
doubling my business took so much out of
me because inherently we have a ceiling
in our time okay and yes we could tell
ourselves yo I'm just going to work like
tirelessly for hours I'm like I'm just
going to go 8:00 a.m. to 8:00 p.m. I'm
just going to work constantly and like
yeah I'm kind of doing that some days
right a lot of days I will be at my desk
for most of the day and I don't hate it
right because I'm doing a business that
I love which is helping people grow with
their content creation and during this
summer I was bottlenecked at around 10
to 15K a month I couldn't break past
that 15K a month Mark and the one reason
was because I was too scared to hire
people I was too scared to think of
myself as a leader to other people to
hop on calls every single week and
maintain this relationship with a
employee that I would like regularly pay
and in the process of genuinely being
like you know what no I need to make
this change and I need to be okay with
paying people every 2 weeks I need to be
okay with leading them with a mission
coming up with a grander 5year mission
for my company I'm 21 years old bro 5
years ago I was 16 years old I was in
high school I was taking the SATs I
didn't even know what an online business
was so to say like to stand on my two
feet and say I have a 5-year Mission and
I want to get us there that took a lot
out of me to be like holy that was
terrifying like going from 10K a month
which realistically I only had to call
my paid Discord Community once a week
and it was fine to Jumping to 25k a
month or 30 40K a month for the past 3
months it required me to take literally
like eight sales calls in a day
literally 2 days ago 2 days ago I took
eight sales calls in a day I also took
like three coaching calls yesterday I
have another two coming up today and I'm
pretty used to just working on content
for most of my day I'm pretty used to
just like propping up this camera having
fun and being like okay we don't have to
finish it on time it's fine it's chill
it's not that big of a deal now I have
to focus on calling people for half of
my day managing people and making sure
things are working using the freaking
slack app like I'm not used to using
slack but I feel like corporate doing
that okay I paid $3,000 in expenses to
my team just yesterday and that happens
every 2 weeks it's a lot that I realized
I like wasn't used to and I think in
this process of going from 10K a month
to scaling past it is just breaking my
own limiting beliefs is not necessarily
working longer hours because you're
always going to hit your human cap
regardless whatever whatever your
discipline level is and whatever human
cap you can endure you're going to hit
it and it's probably going to happen
before you can hit 25k a month you're
going to have to start hiring people
maybe it's just hiring contractors but
regardless you're going to have to hire
people and it's going to require you to
have this shift in your internal frame
of like being a people oriented person
bu building these soft skills of like
talking to people managing them making
sure they feel empowered making they
sure they like feel like they're still
being heard in the community for example
I had to lead a call of like 15
yesterday right and then immediately
after I had to lead another call of 10
right and these are people that had paid
me over one Grand at minimum and I was
like Wow each of these people paid me
and they expect me to show up with an
extremely high level of energy that
requires some like extreme leadership
skills and pressure that I was not used
to the pressure that comes from making a
lot of money also is a lot more right it
doesn't get easier at more money because
when people start paying you bigger
bucks the refunds and the expectations
become higher obviously I've never
processed a refund by the way in my high
ticket but like the fear of that the
fear of people leaving the fear of
people just on me and hating me
for the experience that I'm giving them
and the coach I'm giving them is real so
it takes a lot of breaking that limiting
belief inside and I'm still in the
process of it cuz I still feel like a
kid a lot of days there's nothing wrong
with feeling like a kid but
transitioning from being like lack
ofical to being a leader is something
that I'm still learning but I want to
leave you all off with like I guess one
encouraging message and a lesson here is
that even if it feels like it literally
breaks you you're going to rebuild
yourself stronger this is my second
month doing over 45k a month and it's
because I started running this High
ticket offer where I'm selling a package
for 3.5 Grand and to process
$35,000 from people puts a lot of
pressure on me to deliver not just
$3,500 worth of value but like $10,000
worth of value I have to see myself in
the mirror and hop on these calls and
think of myself as like a $10,000 value
kind of person and it's terrifying I
want to reassure you that whenever these
breaks and your internal belief systems
happen it's usually for the better you
can always go backwards but once you've
self-improved and reached new level you
can always choose to be like I actually
don't want this I can just stop running
the business I don't want to live in a
nicer apartment actually I don't really
care about being able to like go on nice
trips take my girlfriend out for like
nice dinners and not worry about it okay
I don't want those things okay and I
could genuinely sit here and be like
that okay but I chose this life and I'm
genuinely grateful I need to remind
myself that I'm grateful that I chose
this life and whenever these breaks
happen don't panic because everything
will be okay regardless of whether it's
doing your first sales call even this
could happen at 1K a month right we're
selling your first 10 clients and
thinking that oh my goodness I'm going
to fall apart managing 10 clients or
hiring your first contractor or employee
it's going to be terrifying and it's
going to require some break in what
you're used to that's good that sign of
discomfort is that you're growing and I
think in this whole game of online
business and in fact in life whether
it's in the gym or any Pursuit that we
have the goal is not necessarily the
number but it's growth that's what
really gives us that fulfillment as
human beings thank you guys for watching
see you guys tomorrow peace