holy [ __ ] today is November 21st and we
launched a new product content Academy
2.0 literally in the span of like 2
hours I think we made 24 Grand so I just
wanted to record my live reaction uh
this is the most amount of money I've
ever made just for context last year in
2023 I made less money than this so
seeing this is kind of surreal I worked
for the past 60 days on this launch for
Content Academy 2.0 the product and we
just did a live webinar which means we
just did one long 2hour presentation oh
my gosh dude you know it it feels crazy
because I put so much pressure on myself
to make this perfect man you can see
here I wrote down this date of today 60
days ago I wrote down this date and this
is today I've been counting on the days
ever since the month started to the
November 21st date man it's [ __ ]
crazy dude I was so scared bro I'm not
going to lie man I don't know I feel
like this might sound really out of
touch but I feel like ever since I've
put on this pressure to just keep
growing the business I felt a lot more
stressed than I used to despite the
business is doing better than ever and I
think it's because when we reach our
previous goals we just set new ones that
are even bigger and B the game
ultimately gets more difficult I don't
know maybe it's just this Chase of of
more and I've questioned a lot in the
past 60 days to like what am I really
doing this for do I care that much about
making millions of dollars because from
here it's just what's the next big goal
I don't know I I tried to feel really
grateful today cuz I knew today would be
just a really important day not because
we'd make a lot of money in fact I
expected to make probably less than 10K
from this launch but I I just told
myself no matter what happens I'm proud
of the work that I put in for the past
60 days and I think money really follows
that I was scrambling with my team
member just in literally 5 minutes
before we went live to get this
presentation done on our canvas slides
bro [ __ ] dude you can literally if
you're curious about actually what the
numbers look like by the way if you're
like a more business-minded person
basically here are our numbers this was
our webinar we had 2,100 registrants and
at Peak we basically had around 500 20
viewers and that converted eventually to
50 sales of our
$428 price point which converted to like
a little bit over 24
Grand it's [ __ ] surreal bro damn bro
I don't know maybe I'm just being corny
I'm not going to lie I celebrated with a
little drink after because I run all of
my business through my Instagram page so
I was stressing about views too I was
making sure I was trying to blow up in
the past month man and it feels like the
past two months came together in a way
that was better than I could have
expected I don't know I don't even know
what I'm saying bro I just wanted to
capture this moment
bro wow dude if I'm being completely
honest too I feel like the money doesn't
really like make me feel anything
because what am I going to I don't know
what am I going to do you know I worked
60 days for this you know it's not like
I can just keep snapping my fingers and
every day this happens yeah I'm grateful
man I'm grateful it's it's a blessing to
be able to run a business like genuinely
feel good while selling a product and of
course make like [ __ ] man I've struggled
with gratitude lately too and it's crazy
because obviously I'm doing what my
younger self would have literally prayed
to do man and it's weird but I've
struggled battling with presence versus
stress and i' I've tried to detach from
the numbers of money but you know what
this this is a moment that I'll look
back on and I'll think back to with
genuine fond memories I just I don't
want I don't know I don't want to record
this man and I feel guilty for for for
celebrating this amount of money but
dude I'm [ __ ] pumped bro like I'm I'm
excited dude I remember when I I I was
excited to make $250 in a month and now
we're at 25k in a day bro [ __ ] dude it's
crazy what we had 50 new members join
our business you know that's always a
freaking w i i chatted right after with
the actual members who joined and it was
sick yeah man it's a blessing bro yeah
that's it I'll see you guys tomorrow in
the road to $100,000 a month