let me guess this is your average
morning you wake up you instantly open
Instagram YouTube Studio Tik Tok
notifications you see your recent video
flop so you press the search button on
Tik Tok on YouTube and starts pissing
you off because how the hell did this
Creator who makes really boring videos
frankly get a million views now I've had
the privilege of being friends with many
creators with over a million followers
or subscribers I've also grown four of
my own personal accounts on Tik Tok and
Instagram to over 100,000 followers but
I think everything clicked when I had
this one conversation that really pissed
me off with a friend then the next day I
woke up and I was just like I don't
really care about today's video I was so
pissed I just like needed to get a
message out and it was this video and it
got 2 million views on Tik Tok I filmed
it in the span of 5 minutes I literally
just pulled out my iPhone and yapped and
I sat there for the next week just
thinking about why did this video do so
like literally 20 x of views 30 x of
views of any other video that I posted
for the past month it had so many
comments saying holy [ __ ] this video is
so relatable this video is so this
message actually hit like I need to hear
this today viewers are human beings and
the most compelling entertaining version
of us that shows up on camera is often
times the one that is simply how we
naturally are yet by over complicating
the content process with all of these
word for word scripts that we have to
follow this entire content pillar
structure you have to realize that there
are analytically productive thoughts and
there are simply thoughts that are
feeding into your own negative
self-perception and this version of us
that constantly over overthinks about
every single possible flaw in our
content sometimes in life things doesn't
go your way that doesn't mean that there
is some inherent flaw that you just
simply don't understand and the same
goes with learning the skill of creating
compelling videos that people actually
want to watch there's so many ways you
can optimize your editing there are so
many ways you can optimize the hooks and
the titles and thumbnails but every time
I speak to a Creator who actually knows
what they're doing and is growing at a
rate that I actually want to reach they
don't approach with this anxious energy
of holy [ __ ] there's so many things
wrong with my video oh my goodness I
don't even think I'm going to hit my
goal maybe this strategy will be the one
that actually gets me to no no no no
maybe maybe this one they're just simply
excited to create and they have this
passion to share and they make videos
about these topics that actually excite
them and yes they can have some sort of
structure to the content but they often
think much much less what I've noticed
is that whenever I'm anxiously thinking
about my YouTube strategy and I talk to
somebody who's actually got over a
100,000 200,000 YouTube subscribers
they're thinking way less than I am
about the strategy how does it YouTubers
operating at such a higher level think
so much less than I do about content
strategy and I have grown the most that
I ever have on Instagram this year this
year I went from 50,000 to 240,000 and I
spent way less time thinking about the
strategy of my videos and I just simply
kept creating what I felt compelled to
create I posted every day I posted a
video probably that took me 2 hours max
some days I would even post it within
just 1 hour and these short form videos
that I spent the least amount of time on
a lot of times got over 100,000 500,000
views but the one factor that I was
really conscious of this year was
managing my emotions and making sure
that my emotions and my negative anxious
thoughts of oh my goodness my future is
relying on my content doing well I
didn't let it spiral this sounds really
[ __ ] corny but I would journal every
single morning I would read this Vision
that I would have of me in 5 years being
the most prolific ambitious Creator
sharing the most authentic thoughts to
the world and having the most like
aligned impact that I ever wanted to
have on content and in my business and
doing this really silly logical exercise
where I'm doing this woo woo
manifestations was the one trick that
was able to rewire my brain to stop
overthinking so hard about the content
and simply post content that was
genuinely authentically meaningful to me
and when we make content that is most
meaningful to us not this hyper curated
Persona that we're trying to build
online of this perfectly welded content
strategy that constantly changes every
week because we don't have the right
like no when messy steps on the field he
doesn't [ __ ] angle and trajectory of
the curvature of his free kick he just
goes with what is now natural to him now
I'm not saying that you can just snap
your fingers and build that skill set
obviously practice is important but just
understand that a lot of times our
thinking about content is not actually
aiding us it's actually making us more
stressed and it's not giving us any real
answers cuz the real answers simply come
from posting more videos and getting
more data from the algorithm the answers
to the problems don't come from
stressing about the problem it comes
from Simply doing the actions which
means that instead of spending 8 hours
refreshing your inbox refreshing your
your YouTube Studio spend those 8 hours
reading a book talking with some friends
those are often times where the best
inspiration is going to come from if you
really want to pour that time into your
content spend 8 hours making the video
don't spend those 8 hours [ __ ]
refreshing your inbox dude your
analytics what is that going to help you
with and whenever I was in my most
analytical anxious state or I would
spend the most time Doom scrolling
through Instagram through Tik Tok not
actually doing the work I wanted to do I
felt the worst I created the least
amount of videos where I would spend 3
days not even posting because I was so
stressed about making the perfect video
spoiler alert the perfect video doesn't
come from Simply thinking about it more
it comes from when we're simply
energized and in a creative flow which
means you need to do activities that
actually put you into a creative flow
don't do things that stress you out by
checking the analytics of your video
that flopped because checking it more
times is only going to make you more
stressed and it sounds too good to be
true that the most prolific creators
simply spend a lot of their time having
fun let me put it into perspective Oprah
Winfrey one of the most successful
entrepreneurs and operators spends most
of her time in a day reading she spends
like 2 hours a day working when I've
created the most successful content I
spent probably equal amounts of time
consuming podcasts and reading books as
I did actually plugged into cap cut and
putting down my phone and opened with a
Notes app and scripting our best ideas
come from the best version of ourselves
so develop the habits that make you the
best version of yourself and let the
best ideas come to you and let the
execution come in a fun manner cuz
another thing to to with content do you
do you really want to watch somebody
that hates being on camera when you
suffer through so much stress in your
creative process that by the time you
actually show up to the camera you can't
even come up with coherent sentence cuz
you're overthinking about everything
that everybody's going to think about
what you're saying at every single
sentence you sound like a
discombobulated [ __ ] okay and I'm not
saying that to be demeaning I I
understand that too I've spent days
where I have literally tried to film for
2 hours straight and I could not sound
natural then I had days where I prop
down the camera for 3 minutes filmed the
entire video and it's gotten over a
million views so the question I always
ask myself is how can I develop the
habits to make me that version of myself
that in turn is a more prolific Creator
as opposed to trying to squeeze out a
viral video from a version of myself
that can't even think straight I hope
this was helpful if you're struggling as
a Creator I completely understand I've
been creating content for almost 5 years
now and I've been through the most
frustrating times where I felt like I
was flopping and my future was doomed
and it always turns out just fine
because content is a long game and you
have to understand we're not in it to
try and blow up in the next month cuz
what are you going to do after you blow
up this next month you want to be able
to do this with longevity in the next 5
years because you love doing it so stop
killing the thing that you love with all
this stress about it not working trust
in the process and the answers will come
to you all right see yall next time
bye-bye