back in high school I used to set goals
like an idiot I would set goals at 2:00
a.m. I'm going to lock in on my grades
I'm going to get all A's this semester
I'm going to get a 1580 on my SAT so
then I can get into an Ivy League school
and then impress my mom and I'm also
going to get into the varsity soccer
team because I'm actually going to lock
in on my fitness none of those goals
happened by the way like I was an
absolute freaking bum in high school and
I would set these goals the wrong way so
I'm saying this because I have now
actually hit pretty much all of my goals
goals for the past 3 years but then all
of my life before that I had never hit
my goals and I want to teach you how to
set goals the right way so you actually
hit them so just for some context I set
a goal to let's say bench 225 I used to
look like this I was super skinny bench
225 I also had the goal to get pretty
lean shredded physique I also set a goal
right before I entered College to make
$100,000 while I was in college I didn't
even know how I was just like you know
I'll do the Social Media stuff I guess
and I did hit that goal in fact I sit
here uh running an online business from
anywhere in the world I'm currently
traveling to Chicago making this YouTube
video and I have made
$50,000 last month in November of 2024
I've made around like 270 Grand this
year from my business I want to share
how I've been able to literally flip
that Switch and Go from a bum that never
was able to hit any of his go goals I
would set goals in the middle of the
night thinking that it would work right
after busting a nut to some prawn right
before I would hop on a game of Leal
Legend saying I would lock in on school
that's how I used to think that tomorrow
I'm going to flip a switch and lock in
that is part of what I want to share to
you of how to actually set your big
goals so going into 2025 you're actually
going to hit them and 99% of people
don't know how to set goals that's why
they fail again and again and again and
then it gets into their head it gets
into your identity where you think
you're just a person who is in capable
because of XYZ genetics XYZ parental
trauma oh I have a Korean mom and she
you know used to like be so mean to me
so let's talk about principle number one
of actually being able to crush your
goals and the first principle is that in
order to know if you've set the right
goal you have to be able to read it
aloud and genuinely picture it and feel
excited and you don't have to tell
anybody these goals okay it doesn't
matter if you say it to somebody or you
don't say it to somebody but it has to
be really true to you and what that
means is that when you write it down and
you say it aloud and you read it aloud
you can picture this Vivid image of you
in your mind and it actually makes you
excited now this is the problem with a
lot of goal setting especially if you've
set the goal in a state of negativity
where you've just hit some big failure
oh you just got your butt whooped on a
practice SAT test and then you set the
goal of the 1580 sat because you're so
angry right because you just got your 12
1200 on your SAT practice test and
you're like dude I need to lock in bro I
got a month until the SAT so I'm going
to I'm that's it I'm writing down the
goal and I'm changing everything tonight
because that is how I'm going to change
no picture the version of yourself you
will be because in order to go from say
a 1300 sat person to a 1580 sat person
you will be a different person you will
be doing different actions every day
because if you were doing those actions
today you would be there already so
picture the version of yourself that you
will be when you are hitting that goal
and do this weird practice of of
actually visualizing it cuz it's weird
okay it's weird to actually visualize it
because the power of visualization is
that your brain doesn't really know that
it's not real especially if you have a
feeling associated with it if you set
your goals also wait too logically and
there's no emotion associated with it no
positive emotion associated with it not
only are you going to lowkey hate your
goals subconsciously so you're not going
to want to actually work towards them if
there's not a positive Association to
these goals but also if you said it so
logically oh how am I going to make
$100,000 by the end of college nobody
makes that much money from an internship
nobody makes that much money from social
media I think you don't know these
things you don't know what you don't
know if I set this gooal of next year I
can't make a million dollars nobody at
21 years old does that then I would just
be operating on my flawed perception of
reality sometimes you just have to set a
goal that really excites you that you
have no clue how you are going to hit
and I don't have a logical plan to make
a million dollars in fact six months
from now I don't really know what my
content will look like I don't know
exactly what my business will look like
I can have an inkling of it I can have
an inkling of what making a million
dollars you know like tactically breaks
down to but that doesn't really help in
the big picture because life will throw
[ __ ] at you every single week okay for
example you're going to plan this entire
TW Monon study prep for your at if I
just take five practice tests every week
and I just you know in incrementally
increase my score each week well what
happens when 3 weeks in you haven't hit
that Benchmark that you wanted to to hit
you should be at, 1400 sat right now but
instead you're only at
1350 oh shoot what's going to happen to
your brain and your emotions then do you
really think you're going to stick to
your goals when life throws like
spaghetti in your face and says you're
not making good progress so you're not
going to know how it happens because a
lot of times too whether it's in
business in academics too and there are
so many intangibles that happen when we
try to set these big goals and in every
single goal that I've hit it's always
been a little bit different the process
of getting there than I initially
imagined and whenever life throws these
negative things in your face you can't
think logically you just simply have to
operate on the positive emotion and that
leads me to principle number two which
is that you have to reread your goal
every morning morning and when you
reread your goal every morning you have
to feel that positive emotion which
might take you longer than the simple 5
Seconds that it takes to read a goal you
can read something without internalizing
any of the information like you could
literally spend 20 minutes reading a
book and then realizing 20 minutes later
my brain just looked at the words I
didn't actually process it through my
brain the same goes when you're reading
aloud your goals whenever somebody says
read aloud your goals every morning it's
going to help you stay focused help you
stay disciplined it's not about doing
the action it's actually really easy to
read a goal every morning and that's why
people think it doesn't work you have to
actually visualize it every morning
which is a really boring and tedious
process setting your goals is really
exciting when you do it because there's
this shiny object syndrome where you get
really excited at this new thing because
you think reality will be different when
you've hit this goal the reality that
actually is there when you've hit the
goal shouldn't feel like everything just
clicked that one day when you hit the
goal the month leading up to that the
week leading up to that you should have
already felt that Joy of hitting the
goal because youve felt such positive
emotion every single day leading up to
it the doubt has become so crippled that
the lower score on the SAT prep a bad
day in business a bad day with your
videos and your content doesn't affect
you because you have reminded yourself
every morning of the positive emotion
that you will have when you actually hit
the goal and it's a really tedious
process but you have to read it aloud
every morning and you have to feel
something when you actually set these
goals or else you are doomed to repeat
the cycle of having some random thing
get in the way of your life oh I can't
really do the SAT prep today man like
I'm feeling too tired like what's the
point of studying today if I'm if I'm
feeling a little bit down and
unmotivated because I hate studying deep
down and when you also tell yourself
that you hate all of the processes that
lead up to it your brain's just going to
operate in this constant negative
feedback loop where you're just like I
don't enjoy studying therefore I need to
wait until I feel good in order to start
studying therefore I'm just not going to
study as much and the person who always
wins is simply the person who loves the
process loving the process doesn't come
it doesn't actually come that naturally
to a lot of people the difference
between somebody who loves studying and
somebody who hates studying and plays
video games all day I've realized it's
very very very very minuscule it's not
that one person was born inherently a
good studier it's not that somebody was
born inherently enjoying of studying
like really try to break that down what
do you think actually goes into the mind
of somebody who actually studies well
who actually does well in business we're
very very similar as human beings we all
operate on the same very basic
psychology which is that we do things we
enjoy and how do we learn to enjoy
things well we feel confident in them we
feel like we're actually making good
progress every day and a lot of days you
will have days where you just aren't
making good progress and you can be the
angry negative person and tell yourself
I suck guess it's cooked haha I suck so
what's the point of we've been trying to
study for this test what's the point of
even trying to work on my business today
dude oh my goodness I'm so tired I got
like 5 hours of sleep last night what's
the point of making this video I'm
sounding incoherent man I should just
give up on this video man does that Loop
of thoughts sound familiar does that
train of thoughts where you go from one
tiny tiny thing that you could have just
brushed aside by simply saying nope I'm
going to make a million dollars this
year and I'm very excited to do so and I
don't know how it's going to happen but
I'm very confident it will and I'm just
going to figure it out by any means
necessary and because I know I'm going
to hit that goal I'll just make one tiny
step today doesn't have to be a big step
because I'm going to hit a million
dollars this year maybe in a month's
time some some big click will happen and
it's all about trusting the process it
all connects back to the same principle
of Simply if you feel good about your
goals and you're reminded of them every
single morning morning is key because if
you do it in the afternoon you're your
mind is already bogged down by 10 videos
you've seen on social media that one
friend that you talked to and now
suddenly your brain can't your brain
literally can't just like forget about
those things and empty your brain a big
process of sleep is that it takes a lot
of your short-term memory a lot of the
things in your short-term memory and
moves it over to long-term memory so
your brain is kind of emptied every
morning genuinely it actually is kind of
blank slated which is why while I'm
filming this video I didn't check social
media I didn't check my email I didn't
check all of my notifications I didn't
even respond to texts because if I did
my brain would be ever so slightly
cluttered and I wouldn't be able to
speak as clearly I wouldn't be able to
speak as authentically and as myself
like the brain is very sensitive and the
tiniest tiniest things can spiral into
negative thoughts and negative thought
Loops so in order to combat that I
simply read aloud my goals every morning
and the version of myself I will be and
I wait until I feel good I just read it
and I'll close my eyes and visualize it
nope no I'm still stressed oh I'm still
anxious about my videos flopping and my
business had like a customer complaint
last week it's okay take I'll take my
time I'll take my time to actually feel
good about it because that's also how
you're going to motivate yourself every
single day the most motivated people are
simply the ones who enjoy doing the
thing because they feel good and if you
can feel positively reinfor forced from
an action you will do the action more
it's like if you give a dog a treat like
your brain's not that different as
intelligent of human beings we are
emotionally we're still very very basic
we do things we want to do and we avoid
things we don't like so if you associate
working towards your goal with all of
this negative emotion which it's really
hard to avoid okay the world will make
you want to feel negative about
everything every single day there it's
going to be a new problem every single
day so you have to combat that
by every single morning waking up and
reminding yourself of who you are
working towards and where you're going
to be and it's a weird process cuz it's
really corny to read aloud your goals
every morning and Gaslight your brain
into thinking that you're actually going
to achieve it cuz deep down you probably
have a lot of doubts you probably don't
see yourself as a type of person who can
hit 1580 on the SAT become an academic
weapon make a million dollars it's okay
it's okay just trust that with time and
doing these actions every single day you
can transform literally from the buest
of bums the type of person who never
hits a goal who sets this goal of I want
to lock in on the SAT I want
to like I want to I want to study harder
I want I want to get into an Ivy League
I didn't get into an Ivy League I was
hideously addicted to to prawn the
League of Legends to social media just
like scrolling through could never lock
in on the gym and I realized it's simply
because I had so much negative energy
associated with doing the action every
single day so to reiterate because I
want you to actually sit down right now
and write down whatever goal it is
because writing it down is a necessary
First Step first step out of 366 steps
because every single day there's there's
a new step of reading it aloud again cuz
your brain also forgets you're going to
wake up the next morning and if you
don't read aloud your goal and visualize
it and feel good you are doomed to feel
the negative emotion again because life
is going to throw a problem and our
natural reaction to problems is probably
going to be negative especially if you
have lived this cycle of thinking
negatively and giving up and then
eventually failing goals so every single
time a problem arises you're probably
used to thinking negatively so it's
going to happen very slowly so yeah this
is a 366 step process like 5 minutes
okay it it takes 5 minutes to really sit
down every morning read the goal loud
and visualize it and I don't think that
is actually really difficult it's just
that most people don't actually think
that actually works this video is
honestly just inspired by me setting my
own goal of making a million dollars in
2025 I'm posting this video online now
now I got to hit it which is really
scary like I think from my perspective
dude like I have a reputation to keep up
now it's kind of weird if I don't hit
this goal it's kind of like sad you know
um but yeah subscribe to this channel if
you want to surround yourself with
somebody who actually hits his goals I
wish I I had somebody telling me about
this back then I've had to read like 19
different books it's why these are the
two books I'm reading right now but like
I've read 19 different books in the past
uh two years as well which helped me
Excel very very far beyond yeah thank
you for watching subscribe I'm going to
be posting more updates on my business
journey and more lessons like this yeah
I will see yall next time peace