I just got off the back of crying
because I opened up about watching porn
to my girlfriend so I think this is the
perfect time to talk about how I've used
vulnerability as an absolute hack to
build an audience online of over 1.5
million followers across Tik Tok and
Instagram not only that but it's also
helped me build this cult-like
connection with my audience that also
makes me $50,000 a month from my
business that I sell on the back end of
my content so if you want to be a
Creator and you want your content to
actually blow up and resonate with a
genuine audience please listen up the
first case that I want to talk about is
porn addiction okay because I made a
video about that I really harnessed the
power of vulnerability when I made this
video in November look when I was in
high school I was horrendously addicted
I'm talking twice a day minimum and
whenever I needed to study for a test I
would always push it back to the last
night until like 3:00 a.m. I would start
studying and I couldn't read my textbook
for more than 15 minutes without needing
to stop and get some sort of instant
gratification like jack off or play
video games it was one of the most
uncomfortable videos to post in my life
that video got so many comments it got
over a million views on Instagram reals
as well and there's a lot of people who
followed me from that video and just
have kept following me since that for
literally 2 more years past that and
they don't understand how strategic of a
move it was because yes as uncomfortable
as it is to talk about vulnerable things
online it is the number one superpower
that 99% of people will never use in
their content creation Journey which is
why they're not resonating deeply With
Their audience and the interesting thing
about vulnerable stories they actually
increase Rapport and they increase the
connection like 10x because it fulfills
a human need that 99% of human beings
just walk around in their daily lives
never feeling fulfilled in the feeling
of being actually unconditionally
accepted and forgiven for whatever
shameful things that they have going on
in their life so I use this example of
porn addiction because it's one of the
most vulnerable things that like 99% of
men won't open up about even though 91%
of men I'm pretty sure statistically
watch porn and I thought I had conquered
porn addiction until you know it still
bites me in the butt some days I
probably watched porn like three or four
times this year it's not the coolest
thing to talk about in fact it's like
really weird it's really gross but when
you're able to tell a story that
resonates with somebody on a level that
they have never even heard on a personal
level before the algorithms are so good
they're just going to find the human
beings that resonate with it they have
so much data on every single user and
this is what like religious testimonies
are based off of too it's that feeling
of acceptance and unconditional
forgiveness that most people just never
get because let's be honest we have
these standards that we always have to
be perfect and we're never going to talk
to any of our friends about this kind of
stuff we're never going to talk to our
co-workers or classmates about these
embarrassing things that go on in our
life so when you can be the Creator on
the internet that fulfills this person's
longing of feeling accepted and forgiven
trust me it's going to resonate with
people and this is what like all those
creators who talk about raw and
authentic content get wrong as well CU I
know that word's trending in the whole
content creation space in 2024 but what
does that actually mean the raw and
authentic part that people are really
looking for isn't necessarily the fact
that it's not edited it's the fact that
people are actually opening up about
embarrassing and difficult stories
vulnerability is the core piece of this
raw authentic style of content that is
only going to get more and more popular
in 2025 because it will continue
fulfilling a human need that not only
90% of creators on social media won't
fulfill but it's 90% of human beings in
our day-to-day relationships don't
fulfill this I want to talk about the
Practical steps to actually being able
to achieve this in your content well
Step One is journaling about it because
it's not actually hard to actually film
this authentic style of content in fact
I have like five lines of text written
up on my notes app I I've barely even
scripted this but the first step is
actually feeling comfortable in your own
skin enough to actually talk about
things online that first step is just
self-awareness which comes from
journaling and simply being honest to
yourself even if you're showing nobody
else in the world Journal it down on a
piece of paper and write down what is
something that you're struggling with
what is something that you're feeling
really ashamed of so in my situation
it's watching porn 2 weeks ago even
though I talked about my girlfriend that
I'm never going to do it again okay like
I'm clean never going to do it again
then I still struggled with that problem
3 months later okay when work got
difficult I got stressed and I just
needed some escape from life that is
Step number one Journal about it be
honest with yourself you need some
Avenue to open up to yourself at least
because if you continue lying to
yourself in the mirror that I don't have
any flaws and I'm a pretty good person
and I don't have all of these issues
okay well then it's going to be hard to
actually resonate with people and build
that Rapport in a sense where you
fulfill that need of people seeking
honest human beings that they can
connect with online step number two is
then to Simply tell one friend like
whoever your closest friend is just
simply tell them like go up to them like
hey have you struggled with this dude
like you can maybe laugh it's it's going
to be really [ __ ] awkward you're just
going to be like hey I've been
struggling with you know porn addiction
and I'm I'm really scared to tell XYZ
person but you know I I really struggled
with with this two weeks ago and I don't
know I didn't really have anyone else to
tell so treat authenticity and
vulnerability as an exercise to yourself
to be able to reach tap into more levels
of honesty with yourself and more honest
self-expression and once you're able to
do that with even just one human being
that is the energy and the mental state
that you tap into when you actually then
film so when you sit down and actually
record you press record on your iPhone
or your Sony camera whatever simply
imagine that person behind the camera
and imagine you're talking to them and
try and settle as much into that flow
State as possible because when you're
able to settle into an absolute Flow
State where you simply think you're
talking to a real human being then the
video is just simply going to feel
convers ational and authentic that kind
of authentic style of content that most
creators are striving for in 2024 2025
because this is the mental internal and
external process that I want you to go
through and it's going to help you not
only forgive yourself and just feel more
light as a human being and feel more
expressive and feel more comfortable in
your own skin so as a self-develop
mental exercise I think it's great to be
able to journal your own thoughts if
you've never Journal before it's going
to be weird it's going to feel like
you're like Runing into a diary and
you're going to feel like really
feminine and and stupid doing it but
trust me this is what like the best best
creators do they simply have a really
strong self-awareness and they
understand what their strengths are as a
human being and just who they are and
then they're able to authentically
express it on camera okay so step one is
to journal about it and process it
yourself and feel okay with yourself and
forgive yourself step two is to be able
to Simply sell it to one person and then
step three is to talk about it online
but that process usually only happens
when you're so comfortable because you
already written it down on a piece of
paper and you're forgiven yourself and
then you can talk about it online when
we able to tap into that energy and
you're still freaking watching right now
it's not even about virality per se it's
just simply being able to sit down with
a viewer even if it's on a short
60-second reel being able to sit down
with that viewer for an entirety of 60
to 90 seconds and genuinely make them
feel like they're present with you and
they genuinely understand you as if
they've known you your whole life and
that only happens not by embellishing
our stories with 95% truth of how was
your day oh yeah my day was all right my
day my day was cool like no I came off
the back of crying literally 30 minutes
ago I was like crying my eyes out for
the first time in a month because I I
felt so ashamed of telling my girlfriend
that I'd done this something that I
literally promised her I I despise porn
addicts bro like people who still
succumb to that kind of stuff they're
weak bro that's not me trying to sound
all cool and like masculine and [ __ ] and
then here I am crying about it my eyes
are probably a little bit puffy because
of it it's a perfect time to make a
video because when I feel this peak of
Shame it's probably also one I'm able to
show up with the most emotion on camera
if it paints me so poorly I have a
business to run on top of these videos
so mind you too like this is great for
conversion oddly enough because you are
going to be the one Creator in your
Niche that your viewer can actually
trust because 95% of other creators are
embellishing their stories they're
embellishing their day and only painting
the best most pristine picture and you
have to understand that this Caked Up
pristine picture of an ideal life on
social media is actually saturated so
when you can simply be a creator that
does the difficult work of opening up
and doing the uncomfortable moves
speaking not just from the heart about
the things that make you happy but the
things that bring you shame and the
things that bring you pain like I'm
doing right now and that's still why
you're listening to me so this will
create a bond with you and your viewer
literally in that instant in the span of
a 60-second video that will not only
cause them to like and comment and get
engag with the video but it will also
cause them to hit that subscribe or
follow button please hit it and then
it's also going to cause them to build
that Bond or drop a product on your
Instagram story they're the first ones
to buy it because they feel like you are
the one person they can trust online so
that is the biggest hack that's how I've
been able to grow you know my Instagram
account now this year 190,000 followers
in the span of one year from posting
just raw authentic Instagram reals like
freak does that even mean dude it's just
opening up it's being uncomfortable on
camera and by the continual process of
being uncomfortable and sharing the
thing that really brings us the most
shame you're also comforting the one
person out there who really needs to
hear it today not this embellished story
that makes you look good that doesn't
actually help anybody but these stories
that show that you are just like anybody
else else those stories are the ones
that genuinely inspire people to take
action to reach their goals to improve
as human beings as well so if you are
the type of Creator who wants to
genuinely impact the world as well this
is a superpower not just obviously to
manipulate your audience okay that's how
I got you to click on this video but
it's the type of content that's going to
help you genuinely impact and persuade
lives and that's going to help genuinely
Inspire change cuz a lot of times people
have limiting beliefs as a viewer of oh
dude I could never hit the gym because I
have these Dee rooted parental traumas
of I grew up being called Skin all the
time by my friends in eth and nth grade
and then now like I I still feel this
insecurity every time I look in the
mirror like we weird stories like that
just try them and put out a signal to
the world because you never know who
that's going to reach and trust that the
algorithm is going to reach those people
and that those people will engage and
it's going to signal to the algorithm
back to you that you are a Creator worth
listening to that's how you can
manipulate the audience member but
realistically simply genuinely impact
somebody's life and genuinely get their
attention through authenticity and
vulnerability all right and if you want
more Tactical advice on content creation
I highly recommend you check out the
first video in the description it walks
you through more of the nuanced cont
like content tactical side but yeah this
video I just wanted to rant about how
important it is for creators to be
authentic because yes obviously it helps
them build an audience but not only that
but it helps you genuinely impact lives
in a way that most other creators simply
won't do so if you're still seeing this
video it's because you genuinely care
about your audience member too and I
believe that is the first step to
genuinely creating a beautiful impact in
this world through the medium of content
creation okay I will see you guys in the
next one bye-bye