In the past 12 months, I've posted 259
videos, started an online business, made
$260,000
from said online business, dropped out
of college, and moved to New York City.
And during all of this time, I also grew
from 50,000 to 250,000 followers on
Instagram. Now, I'm not saying all that
to brag.
I just want to show you what's possible,
cuz growing my personal brand this year
has literally given me a lifetime of
opportunity I would have never seen as a
21-year-old kid. And in this video, I
want to share with you the four
intentional tactics I use to gain a
following of 200,000 authentic true fans
without having to spend all day working
on my personal brand. And if I've
realized anything in this past year,
being one of those lucky few who
actually were able to blow up, it's that
this kind of viral social media growth
doesn't happen by accident. Because
these unique tactics I'm about to share
with you are these same tactics even
social media beginners have used to grow
their audiences past 10,000 organic true
fans. like Allison who started posting
eight months ago with just 400 followers
and after implementing these strategies
grew to 60,000 followers across
Instagram and Tik Tok and thing is once
you actually understand these strategies
growth actually comes consistently. My
friend Prosper who literally started
posting on Instagram this year grew from
2,000 to 60,000 followers in the span of
6 months. Now all these people didn't
blow up from having some fancy camera.
They all edited on Cap Cut on their
iPhone. It's just cuz they had access to
these four strategies. So let's begin.
Now, the first tactic that you must
master is the art of the hook. The hook,
for those of you guys who don't know, is
simply the first 5 seconds of your
video. And it's the most important. And
I literally put 80% of my time that I
spend scripting, planning, filming on
just those first 5 seconds. Now, for
those of you who think you understand
hooks and you're ready to scroll off or
get to the next part of the section,
like, "Oh, I understand hooks. You have
to be controversial. It doesn't apply to
my content. Just give me the algorithm."
If you aren't blowing up on social media
right now, if your videos aren't hitting
consistently above 10,000 views, you do
not understand hooks to the degree you
need to. And for all you data nerds who
just care about retention and
algorithms, let's explain why the hook
is so important in algorithm terms. Now,
the biggest determinant for the Tik Tok,
YouTube, Instagram algorithms on why you
get views or not get views is simply
your viewer retention. Viewer retention
simply means the percent of people who
are watching your video until its end.
Now, here's the difference. in viewer
retention between a video that got
298,000
views and a video that got 5,000 views.
This is the retention graph of the video
that got 298,000 views on Tik Tok. This
is the retention graph of the video that
got 5,000 views on Tik Tok. After 5
seconds, the difference in retention was
just 27%. Let's switch over to the
whiteboard. Let me really show you what
this means cuz it's kind of confusing.
So, after 3 seconds, the viral video had
22% more retention than the flop video.
This literally just means it was a 27%
better hook. Yet, with a 27% better
hook, the video got 54 times the amount
of views. You have to pay so much close
attention to those first 3 to 5 seconds
of your video. Or else, none of your
video matters because your viewers have
scrolled off, they found you boring, and
the algorithm is not going to push out
your video to new people. Now, you
probably understand that you have to put
way more effort into those first 3
seconds of your video. But how do you
actually reconcile that with the fact
that you want to make your videos
quickly and efficiently? And the secret
is I used AI, but not in the way that
most people use AI. I trained my own AI
chatbot, and I literally spent hours
writing down the hooks of my own viral
videos and the viral videos of my
favorite creators. And I'll show you on
my computer, actually, how to use it.
So, if I literally just type, give me
five hooks for a viewer struggling to go
viral on Instagram, it's going to
literally give me actual hooks that
sound like a real human being. If you
actually want to go viral on Instagram
in 2024, you need to follow this
strategy. I promise I'm about to
absolutely transform your Instagram
game. It sounds human and that's the
key. Most hooks, especially if you run
them through GPT, are going to sound
like absolute robots and they're going
to sound awful. Now, this content bot is
literally one of the biggest hacks that
I use. I could charge hundreds of
dollars for this. But if you simply go
to the link in the description, you can
find it for free. Now, I have more
guides on how to write more advanced
hooks in my private creator program,
Content Academy. However, just because
you understand how to write good hooks
doesn't mean you can actually suddenly
just snap your fingers and go viral. If
the game on social media to go viral is
to focus on those first 3 seconds and
come up with the perfect words to say,
how come the most eloquent speakers
aren't just going viral all the time?
It's not about what you say in your
videos. It's a lot more so about how you
say it. And this is the energy that
you're able to tap into when you're
speaking, right? Because one thing is to
have a really good script. But once you
have a good script, you can't just start
reading being like, remember, your hook
is your first impression that you have
with these strangers on the internet.
People on the for you page don't know
you. They're strangers to you. So, you
have to make an instantly personable
first impression because social media is
all about connection and relatability.
This doesn't mean you have to be super
loud and obnoxious. Let me actually show
you the hook of the video that got
298,000 views. You know, I really
thought life would get better once I
made 10K a month. I kind of think of
making 10K a month as reaching your
freshman year of entrepreneurship. My
tonality was calm and it almost sounded
like I was on a FaceTime call with you.
That is the exact type of energy that
you want to tap into when you talk on
camera, not this robotic sounding
wording. But that's actually so much
easier said than done. Like how do you
actually tap into the energy where you
feel like you're on a FaceTime call with
your viewer? And this leads me to my
second point which is absolutely
crucial. The second tactic that you must
master is understanding really
specifically who your viewer is. This is
where 99% of creator gurus will be
looking at the wrong direction when it
comes to content or they'll focus on the
wrong stuff like editing hacks and it'll
take up so much of your time and it's
not going to have an actual effect on
your retention or your views. Editing is
important, but I'll teach more exactly
on how to get the most out of your
editing in the next step. But I
personally focus most of my attention
when I make my videos on just really
understanding who it is I'm talking to
behind the camera. In this social media
game of trying to increase your viewers
retention, it's not about making your
video feel all, oh, this is so logical.
Like yes, obviously you need to have
very logical and wellthoughtout novel
ideas. Like that's important, but
especially for you guy creators out
there, cuz I I really want you to get
this through your logical a viewer
retention oftent times comes down to
simply how you make your viewers feel
when watching your videos, not what you
make your viewers think. Now, there's
countless studies on what makes content
actually go viral on the internet and
get shares. Now, I want you to try and
guess what the strongest reason why
content gets shared on social media is.
I'll give you a second. Okay, seconds's
over. It's simply when it evokes a
strong emotional response in the viewer.
Now, you might hear this and you're
probably going to instantly default to
thinking, "Okay, I have to be really
loud and angry and exaggerating and piss
the viewer off, maybe." And that's
actually the wrong way to go about it.
Trying to act like this character that
provokes emotion is only going to create
this uncanny valley effect where your
viewer's going to be like, "Oh, why is
this person talking to me like that?
It's a little weird. It's a little sus."
If you're trying to optimize for viewer
retention, that means you simply have to
do what most people will find
interesting and intriguing. And the
difficult game of social media, and this
is why most people don't succeed, is
because you actually have to develop a
genuine authentic connection with your
viewer. If you look at your favorite
creators, the ones that you absolutely
love the content of. Your favorite
creators probably make you feel like
you're actually in the room with them,
like you're talking to an actual homie.
So, how do you communicate in a way
that's authentically you and makes the
viewer feel like they already know you,
like a friend? And the secret is you
simply have to visualize a real person
that you're talking to, not some
imaginary, you know, hypothetical
viewer, one person that you actually
know, cuz that's how you're going to tap
into that natural speaking flow state
where you feel genuinely comfortable
internally. And as a result, the words
you say simply just come out of your
mouth. Pause. So, choose one person and
this person is going to be your ideal
viewer persona. And you have to
understand this ideal viewer persona
down to an absolute T. So, it helps when
you are actually close with this real
person. Like, what life problems are
they going through? What do they wear?
What do they believe in? What kind of
content do they already watch? You have
to know this person inside and out to
actually communicate to them like
they're a real person. Cuz your viewer
actually is a real human being at the
end of the day. Like, you're watching
this right now listening to me
communicate to you. In fact, this is so
important that I literally have an
entire 16-minute video breaking down how
to come up with your own ideal viewer
persona in my program, The Content
Academy. But in this video, for the sake
of time, I'm going to walk you through
exactly who my ideal viewer persona is,
as I am literally filming right now.
Let's go on to my computer. So, in this
video, my ideal viewer persona is
literally my friend. His name is Cle.
And he constantly talks to me about
wanting to develop an audience, but do
it in a genuine way. He wants to have
the audience so he can support his dream
of having financial freedom and online
income. And to that, I kind of came up
with a script like, "Okay, Instagram is
the only platform I personally needed
this year to start my business from
zero, grow to 10K a month, 20K a month,
and eventually 50k a month." Now,
envisioning this person behind the
screen genuinely helped me come up with
my script. Now, secondly, especially if
you're making a persuasive or
educational video, you need to
understand what this person believes in
and specifically, how will they object
to your things that you're saying in
your video? My ideal viewer of my friend
Cle would probably say, "Oh, you know,
this strategy sounds good, but I don't
have anything to sell." And then to
that, I would say, "Don't worry, you're
on the right video because I started
building my audience 2 years ago in July
of 2022, and only a year and a half
later did I finally have something to
sell them." You don't need to have
something immediately to sell them. It's
important to build your audience
regardless. Okay, another one. I am busy
grinding, socializing, and
self-improving. And to that, I would
say, yeah, don't worry. I'll help you do
it in this video with just 1 hour of
deep focus work every single day just
because of these four tactics. And I did
it during college with a business. And
my friend Prosper also did it. Grew from
2,000 to 60,000 followers, working
12-hour shifts, knocking on doors.
Another objection. Oh, I'm too lazy to
edit in this advanced way. Well, that's
okay. Watch part three of this video.
Now, once you have this ideal viewer,
how do you actually tap into the energy
that feels genuinely authentic? And I
have two hacks for you to achieve this
absolute homie like flow state when you
talk. The first hack is a pre-f filming
routine. Right before you turn on your
camera and hit record, I want you to
take a deep breath
and close your eyes and visualize that
ideal viewer persona right in front of
you, like you're speaking to them and
they're in this room right in front of
you. It's weird, but just follow along.
And if you still feel stiff, it's okay.
Just literally get up and start going
just shake it out. Shake out those
nerves. This is going to make you feel
uncomfortable. Like you're literally
just like getting out of your skin. But
that is essential. It's literally
something I learned in acting class.
This kind of weird bioenergetic
movements snap you into the present
moment and make you feel free flowing
instantly. cuz sometimes you feeling
stiff and you tripping over your words
is simply because your body is not in
this right free flowing state. The
second hack is simply hitting record and
not stopping until your entire video is
finished filming. The key when you film
is to settle into a flow state where you
essentially forget you're filming and
you just talk to the camera like it's
your friend. Once you actually settle
into this state, you will feel it in
your chest and it should be really fun
and you should feel like you're having
fun on camera. But it takes a minute to
settle into, which means for the first
1, 2, even 3 minutes while your camera
is recording, you're still going to feel
that stiffness. I usually sound really
incoherent for the first 2 minutes on
camera. And that's okay. I literally
just accept that as a necessary part of
the filming process. So, my entire
60-second videos usually actually take
me like 6 or 7 minutes to fully film.
So, just give yourself the space to be
free flowing on camera and mess up
because the desire to not mess up is
getting in your head. Now, you might be
thinking though, okay, I've just
recorded so much footage of me talking,
right? I have all of this footage. I've
talked literally for 5 minutes straight,
messed up a bunch of times. Isn't that
going to take a really long time to
edit? And this is where our third hack,
the minimum viable editing, comes into
play. Now, the minimum viable editing
strategy has three distinct parts. The
first part is B-roll, which is the
footage that you overlay on top of your
talking footage. The second one is a
very, very specific way of creating your
captions for your video. And the third
one is choosing the right music so it's
able to put your viewers literally into
like a translike state while they're
watching your video. Now, the first
part, B-roll. This is really important,
and you want your B-roll to change every
sentence, every new sentence that you're
speaking in your video, you want it to
shift to a new piece of footage. Now, if
you're making videos that don't involve
talking, that's okay. You can still use
B-roll and you have to match the B-roll
to the beats of the song, this is the
only important thing that you really
need to understand about B-roll. The
rest of it doesn't really matter. You
can put any random footage as long as it
generally correlates to what you're
talking about in the video, and it's
fine. Think of that kind of like subway
surfers at the bottom of your screen
kind of thing, but in a more authentic
feeling. The next one is my SLC caption
strategy. And it's the exact way that me
and every single one of my clients, my
students who blow up use in their
videos. And it stands for short, large,
and clear. And instead of me showing it
to you on this video, why don't I
actually show you a viral video of mine
that got over a million views on Tik Tok
breaking down my SLC caption strategy.
Here's how I add captions to my Tik Toks
so they go viral every single time. I
use a formula I like to call SLC. Now,
what the hell does that mean? After I'm
done editing my videos, I'll go into Cap
Cut and I'll add auto captions, but the
auto captions come out looking like
[ __ ] So, here's where SLC comes in.
First, I batch edit the captions to make
each caption short, as in around two to
three words maximum. All that matters if
you want to get views on TikTok is
keeping viewers engaged until the end of
the video. So, making the caption
segments super short keeps the screen
constantly changing, but also keeps it
satisfying to watch so viewers don't
have to read a paragraph on the screen,
cuz paragraphs of text are boring and
they scare viewers away. Then, I size
them up to make them large, so they're
extremely easy to read. Once again, Tik
Tok viewers want videos that are easy to
watch. So, large captions just make the
video slightly easier to follow along
to. And lastly, I make the text to a
font that is clear. So, white text in
the classic Tik Tok font with a blurred
black shadow works best. And the end
product, well, you've been watching it
this whole time. Now, lastly, for music,
you really specifically want to do two
things with your music. First off, you
want to choose trending songs because
that's going to trigger a familiarity
bias in your viewer where they're like,
"Oh, I've heard this song recently
before. I feel slightly more
incentivized to watch this video. And
secondly, you need to use trending song
instrumentals. You don't want lyrics
competing with the attention of your own
voice. If you have the song lyrics like
Kendrick Lamar spitting some bars under
your voice, it's going to be a lot
harder to hear what you're saying. So,
just use the instrumental of the song
and simply share a copy link on that
YouTube video. Send it over to YTMP3.
Download that MP3 file. Go inside Cap
Cut. Hit audio. Hit sounds. Hit device
and select from device. and you can add
the music from your own iPhone files. I
call this fully fleshed out system the
Academy editing OS. If you just want the
knowledge of which steps to take, I have
these two templates. Feel free to just
screenshot this on the screen and you
can just apply this straight to your
editing process. The last and most
important factor to your growth on
social media is surrounding yourself in
an environment of constant improvement.
So, I gave you the hacks on what to say
in your videos. I gave you the hacks on
what to visualize so you can speak like
a pro on your videos. and I lastly
taught you how to edit like a pro in
your videos. However, none of this
matters if you're not living the
lifestyle and the habits of a
procreator. So, at the beginning of this
year, I actually became good friends
with this other kid on my college campus
and his name was Prosper. And he
desperately wanted to make content
creation his full-time job as well. So,
we like naturally became really close.
We discussed things like personal
development, fitness, and content
creation. Now, what's crazy, like I said
before, is that he started posting from
literally zero videos on the internet,
and he grew from 2,000 to 60,000
followers on Instagram. Like, you've
probably heard this saying, you are the
average of the five people you spend the
most time with, yada yada yada. I know
it's cliche, but let me ask you a honest
homie to homie question right now, cuz
you're still watching this video, which
means we'd probably be friends in real
life, too. Do you think once you click
off this video, you'll be able to build
a solid audience like me or Prosper or
Alison? because you now see the road map
to getting your first viral videos. You
have the content tools that I've
literally given to you for free. And as
much as I believe in your success and I
want to, I highly doubt that you will
succeed. Now, hear me out. I know how
exciting it is to watch videos like
this, feel like we're learning together.
You think you are absorbing knowledge
passively by watching YouTube videos.
Okay, I get it. I do that all the time
while I like eat food. But like I said
before, this kind of creator growth
doesn't happen by accident. Like we
don't just luckily blow up one day.
growing your personal brand to the point
where you actually do these crazy feats
with it, like paying for 2 months worth
of rent from one Instagram reel. That
type of stuff only happens when you make
content a top priority. So, this last
tip, finding community, is actually what
separates the decent creators who see it
as a hobby, but then eventually fall off
from the great creators who became
great. Getting full-time creator income,
working from anywhere. Like, I have that
privilege now. And now approaching
personal branding from the perspective
of how I'm going to build generational
wealth. Like the dude Renzo I just
mentioned, for the past year, he hasn't
made less than $100,000 a month with his
business after he really dialed in his
viral Instagram real strategy. And he
had to really focus hard in our program
to actually achieve that. Cuz
surrounding yourself with creators who
actually want to take it seriously,
improve their content 1% every single
day, that is what changed my life. And
like I get it, okay, finding a creator
community of people who are also really
focused on improving their content is
extremely uncommon. Okay, I grew up in
rural New Jersey, bro. like who's
creating content, running online
businesses in freaking New Jersey. So,
when I think back to 17-year-old me when
I was a freshman in college, I was lost.
I was just looking for a way honestly to
escape this whole like internship race.
I literally think back to meeting one
person who changed all of my limiting
beliefs about what's possible with
content creation. It was this dude named
Young. He was a senior at my college,
but he also had a decent Tik Tok
following of like 500,000 followers. But
he showed me he literally got paid
$4,000 to post a Tik Tok video for a
brand. Or two years later when I was 19
years old and I was like, "You know
what? I really want to do an online
business." I was binge watching like
Hamza Iman Gazi videos on YouTube every
single day. And I thought watching
YouTube videos all day and passively
learning was going to somehow make me
rich. For the first 6 months of trying
to run an online business, I was running
in circles like trying drop shipping,
drop that after a month. I thought I
would try an agency and then drop that
after a month, too. But then in January
of 2023, I met this one business mentor.
He basically allowed me to like intern
for his coaching business. And I saw
making like $10,000 in a week from an
online coaching business. And I was
like, what? You are quite literally one
connection away from changing your life
trajectory permanently. And that is my
passion. That is what I want to share to
the world. And that is why I've created
content academy in the last 12 months of
my life. Work tirelessly to make it the
best creator community on the planet.
And every single success story, every
homie, Prosper, Renzo, Alison, Gabe, all
of these successful creators were
actually a member of the content
academy. And I'll let you in on a little
secret. The reason why we're actually so
effective in helping creators blow up,
even if they're starting from like
absolutely zero posts, is because I'm a
pretty anxious, anal guy. Like, I like
breaking down everything into systems.
And I've broken down the entire creator
journey from zero to getting your first
1,000 view video to getting your first
100K view video to getting your first
10,000 followers to getting your first
brand deal to getting your first client.
Literally, we've helped over a thousand
creators in the past year. All of the
parts necessary to the internal and
external growth as a creator, I've
mashed them together into one freaking
banger program. The first thing that we
do is meet six times a week on live
calls. Cuz if you're not meeting live on
calls, realistically, your head is not
in the game. This is where every single
one of our creators can unmute, get
direct feedback on what their videos can
be improved, and they can ask any
questions to our content experts, not
just me, but other coaches that I have
hired. You don't understand how helpful
this is. Like Gabe, for example, he
actually now helps other people monetize
after hitting 30K a month with his
agency. He started off with just 400
followers when he first joined the
content academy, but after 4 months of
consistently posting, he finally hit two
videos above 100K views and made $8,000
in digital product sales. Now, who are
the other content experts that I'm
absolutely glazing right now that will
help you directly on these live calls in
the content academy? So, I lead a
coaching call every single week if you
want to talk to me, ask me questions
about content. I grew three accounts on
TikTok to over 100,000 followers in
three different niches. Secondly, we
have Sam. This dude's an absolute goat
at optimizing content. He understands
the content optimizations and the
scripting, filming, and editing like no
other person I've ever met. And I know
this because he's gotten over 500,000
followers across Tik Tok and Instagram.
When he first blew up on Instagram, he
literally grew from like 1,000 followers
to a 100,000 in the span of a month. And
since then, he's been able to become a
full-time content creator through brand
deals and UGC. When you join the content
academy, you can hop on calls with him
twice a week and ask him any questions
about content. Get your content directly
reviewed and optimized by him. Next up,
we got another freaking content genius.
Her name's Eileen. She makes over 10K a
month with just UGC. She's also like 19
and in college and she's doing all that.
Also has over 100k followers on her
personal brands Instagram. She leads a
call every single week on personal
branding and UGC. So any questions on
that, she is the goat for that. And on
top of that, if you just want to connect
with the community members, which I
actually think is one of the more
helpful things than getting this like
coaching feedback, we have a bunch of
community calls every single week cuz we
actually care about fostering genuine
relationships, not just this like
schoollike very strict vibe and like
surrounding yourself with these
highlevel creators or entrepreneurs that
will help you see insane growth like
Catalin who was stuck for months at just
62 followers on Instagram. I'm sorry.
I'm flaming you here. But then in the
past month, he went from 62 to 10,000
followers in the span of 3 weeks cuz he
had a viral video. Now, once again,
hearing these crazy growth stories and
success stories with content and
business feels productive. You feel like
you're getting these unlocks. You're
feeling inspired because you get to live
vicariously through other people's
stories. So, I actually want to stop you
right there and I actually want to ask
you to pay attention. If you are
actually dedicated and serious to
putting in the work to improving your
content 1% every single day, if that is
you, please listen up. These are the
four key phases of going from literally
zero followers to 10,000 true fans plus
and monetizing through your content. And
I call these four phases fries, pebbles,
gem, and money. Starting off with phase
one, it's the learning phase. Now, the
goal in phase one is to simply get to
1,000 views consistently per video. This
is where you probably are if you're
watching this video, just based on pure
probability. This is where you just
simply need to show up and post videos,
even if you have no clue what you're
doing, no clue what the vision, the
grand vision of your page is going to
be, and you simply just need to get
proof of concept that your ideas are
valid. And 1,000 views is a great metric
to simply show that people are actually
interested in your ideas, but they just
simply need to be optimized past that.
Now, in the content academy, we have
this wins channel where people post
their wins every single day. And we
literally have like three or four people
every single day saying, "Yo, I finally
hit that consistent fries on my videos."
Now, in order to get the your consistent
fries, the consistent 1,000 views per
video, it's all about learning the
basics. So, in the content academy, in
the first two weeks, we literally walk
you through exactly how to post your
first seven videos, what buttons to
press in Cap Cut, how to script word for
word, and then on week two, we help you
master scripting, storytelling, and
hooks. So, you learn how to captivate
your viewers with your writing and
speaking. You don't need to just rely on
simply visuals and editing. Now, phase
two of four is the optimization or the
pebbles phase. Your goal here is to get
your first 10,000 view video. This is
where you start thinking about
optimizing the tiniest things like how
you cut your clips down to the
millisecond, how you're editing the
different camera angles and shot types
that you want to film. So, in week three
of the content academy, we literally
walk you through in depth all the
different types of shots to film, how to
light your videos like a pro, an
hour-ong breakdowns of advanced editing,
whether it's on Cap Cut on your phone or
even Cap Cut on your computer. And this
is going to help you take your videos
from decent to great. Like Matt, he
actually hit his first 10K view video on
his 10th day of posting, which is
actually pretty rare. It's very
impressive. It's at 62,000 views now,
actually. That's that's crazy. Now, in
this second phase, the Pebbles phase,
you are simply still focused on the
craft. Don't let your eyes off the ball.
You are still simply focused on making
your videos as good as possible. And
this is actually where our coaching
calls come really in handy, whether it's
me, Sam, Eileen, or any of the other
community calls. And this is where we
can literally give you those 1% 2%
improvements in your video from direct
feedback. Take your video to that 10k
view level, which we call pebbles in the
content academy. It's actually really
funny. Now, here's where it gets
interesting in phase three of four,
which is the phase that you probably see
all the time on social media of people
bragging. And this is the exponential
growth phase of your personal brand, or
the gem phase as I like to call it in
the content academy. Now, the goal of
phase three, the gem phase, is to get
your first 100K view video, which will
then eventually catapult you to your
first 10,000 followers. And now, that
maybe sounds a little bit out of reach
for you, but I really want you to
remember like this only happens after
you have completed phase 1 and two. You
can't skip steps. And I know there's
probably a lot of impatience in you that
just wants to like, "Okay, come on. Give
me the viral hack to go viral tomorrow."
And it really isn't that simple.
Especially if you are still in phase one
or two. We literally have creators who
spend like 6 months in phase 1 and two,
and that's normal. That's okay. Aaron,
he's been in the content academy for 10
months. And 2 days ago, this is crazy. I
don't even think I've seen numbers like
this. He posted a video that got 400,000
views on TikTok, and it gained him
30,000 followers from one video. It's
insane. And this is where our week four
program in the content academy is
extremely helpful. This is where we help
you master scripting, speaking to your
ideal viewer persona like they're
actually your homie, creating that
immersive experience with your viewers.
And lastly, in this phase, you find that
unique edge that makes you different
from every other creator in your niche
on social media and makes you the it guy
for blank. Like I mentioned Catalin
earlier, who jumped from 62 to 10,000
followers in 3 weeks. He actually just
got his second 1 million view video a
week after his first and he's grown from
10,000 to 38,000 followers in the past
week and a half. Now, once again, this
like sounds crazy, and I know you
probably just want to skip to this
phase. Okay, I get it. I'm really
impatient, too. but grinding through
phase one and two of putting in the
difficult and honestly annoying work of
showing up. That's how you reap the
outsized rewards of the personal brand
that you see people talking about all
the time. Like one of our members,
Thomas, 5 months after he started
consistently posting, that's when he
finally landed his first $1,500 deal
with a client. And that actually brings
me to the next phase. For those of you
who are interested in actually turning
content creation into a full-time income
or growing an online business on top of
your personal brand, we have lastly our
phase four, which is the monetization
phase, or I like to call it the money
phase. The goal in phase four is to make
your first $1,000 with content creation,
which seems kind of small, but that's
how you actually catapult to hitting
crazy numbers like 10K a month, 20K a
month, 50K a month, like I have done
with my business in the last year. So,
for those of you watching who actually
want to join the content academy, if you
join today, just to reiterate, we have
12 hours, 13 hours of video guides,
templates, script templates, tutorials
on how to script, film, and edit your
videos like a pro. Posting your first
seven videos, mastering scripting,
storytelling, hooks, filming, editing,
highle creator strategy, and finally,
monetization. This is how I've gotten
views like this. Sorry to flex on you.
Now, most creator programs that teach
this kind of stuff this indepth on how
to grow your personal brand, they
usually charge like $5,000. And on top
of that, too, it's actually funny like a
lot of programs don't even do this, but
we have these six live Q&A calls every
single week in our Discord server. You
can just unmute and genuinely vibe and
of course get your questions answered by
content experts. Programs with that much
support I've seen have charged $10,000
plus a year. Now, on top of that, we
also just throw some lit events twice a
year in New York City to really help you
meet together in person and foster those
real life relationships that can
actually change your life. This is not
just some like online course, bro. I I
hate when people say that to me, okay?
Cuz I feel like I'm genuinely building a
really tight-knit banger community. And
to make it even more fun and gamified
for all of our members, I recently spent
over $4,000 making software that tracks
everybody's Instagram, puts them on one
big leaderboard, and then we have
giveaways for the top creators. So, if
you want to compete, you're a video game
addict like I am. That's another benefit
that you get in the content academy. We
have these monthly accountability games
where we give giveaways to the top five
creators every month. Now, once you join
the content academy, too, if you have
any questions, you can simply ask our
support manager, Justin. He's super
active and he can answer any questions
onetoone as well. And that level of
support, right? Most content guru
content guru who give you so much less
support, who have frankly way less
experience. Like I'm not not to call
them out, but they have they're not good
at their job. They got way less students
winning. Like way less. They'll charge
like $10,000
a year. Like I even spend over $100,000
a year just to pay our talented team
that I mentioned before of Justin, Sam,
Eileen to give you this best creator
experience possible. Cuz I know you're
probably thinking, "Yo, Veno, please
don't kill my wallet." Okay, I got you,
bro. I really thought about, okay, what
would 19-year-old me 2 years ago when I
was really desperate to grow my personal
brand, get that authentic audience, and
then launch an actual online business,
doing what I love, sharing my passion to
the world. But once again, spending over
100 grand a year to run a exceptional
creator community like this is not easy.
It's not cheap for me. With all of the
new events that I also want to throw in
the content academy, I know the
operating cost is only going to go up
and joining the content academy will
increase in price as the community
experience and the program gets
exponentially better, more fun, helpful,
and valuable. This is going to give you
access to the 12hour content boot camp,
the 3-hour monetization boot camp, our
weekly live coaching calls, the entire
community calls, our live community
events, the community games that we
facilitate with software, and lastly,
just the entire online community. And
today is realistically the best time to
actually go all in on your personal
brand and commit to this. We're still
very early to the creator economy's
growth. Like the number of economic
opportunities in the creator economy is
only projected to grow. Like in the next
5 years, according to Forbes, the
creator economy's valuation is probably
going to go from 191 billion to $528
billion. So, as we wrap up this video, I
want to leave you with two options. You
can wait until the perfect time to
start. wait maybe a year or two when you
know it's a little bit more convenient
for you in life when social media is
probably going to be even more saturated
with more creators or you can actually
start committing and going allin on
building the most valuable asset in the
modern age and you can start today if
you want to supercharge your audience
growth get to those spicy 10,000 true
fans online start monetizing you can
click that first link in the description
below to join the content academy today
and I will see you very soon.