so we are here with liru Leu say what's
up yo how's it going just for some
context Leu 6 days ago on Instagram was
at 290 followers and I want you to tell
me exactly how many followers you are at
6 days later today I'm almost at 30k I'm
at 29k right now so in the past six days
you have grown 29,000 followers on
Instagram that is right that is right
dude that is insane and I I just wanted
to share some lessons that you've
learned throughout the past 60 days of
working together in the Inner Circle
like lessons that you've learned in your
content Journey you know consistently
posting every single day and finally
having that breakthrough with your
content and now you said you literally
booked like five sales calls today right
you booked that many calls in a month
and you booked that much today in one
day yep in just one day in just one day
it's it's definitely a good problem to
have you know not having enough time to
take all those calls but yeah basically
like in terms of biggest lessons I think
it's just just follow instructions to be
honest cuz when I joined the Inner
Circle you guys told me like post every
day come to the calls and that's what I
did H and these are the results I got
like I made sure not to miss a well
actually I think out of all of the days
maybe I missed four or five here and
there and I would make up for it on
other days I would post like twice or
Thrice to keep the count going and just
by posting posting every day I like
before this I thought posting every day
is actually a terrible idea this is
going to reduce the quality of my
content but I took it like a challenge
and I kept the quality high and actually
it was the opposite because every time I
posted I would have knowledge I learned
from the calls feedback that you guys
mentioned i' implement it into the
videos and it would just get better and
better and better every day I was I
started like 200 300 views when I joined
the Inner Circle slowly made my way up
to like 500 then it was like 800 then
th000 and then for some reason I could
just never Escape past 1.4k and then one
[ __ ] day it's like three
million and then it's it also like
increased the Baseline for all the other
videos and it's just yeah that is the
best possible way to get great results
from the N just [ __ ] show up every
day and keep getting better 1% better
every single day being doggedly
consistent with the content yeah dude
that's exactly that's freaking awesome I
mean obviously now you've reached the
point that most people will look at your
account and be like whoa like I want to
copy this guy's content like I like oh
that seems too far out of Reach For Me
Right like I'm I'm even struggling to
get like 10K views right now I can't be
like you know looking at these insane
results like getting 3 million views and
getting 29,000 followers in like 6 days
and I actually want to ask you I guess
about where you were when you first
joined the program and just like if you
were to take us back to that head space
that you were in cuz I remember one of
the goals that you said was to launch
your Fitness coaching program grow your
personal brand and leave your 9-to-5 job
so if you were to just describe a little
bit of the like head space that you were
in before joining the program before
going all in on your personal brand like
what did that look like for
you H okay good question so back when I
first joined it was I saw content as
very much like this other leg of my
business right just something to book
calls right but this was like a
perspective shift that I never even
expected and it was not the reason I
joined the Inner Circle but it's
actually like probably one of the
biggest benefits I got from joining
which was I I started to like fall in
love with making content and that is
actually what made it [ __ ] easy just
to show up every day cuz it didn't
really matter about the views did it
hurt a little bit that they were stuck
under 200 views yes it did but what
still matter is like I I like making the
videos and just making it was really
enjoyable and back then when I joined I
was also in a position where it's
like it was it was almost kind of like
desperation almost I was like [ __ ] I I
need to leave the 9 to5 like I [ __ ]
hatte it so much it's it's so bad and I
was like I I need leads okay I've been
watching Mino stuff for a while he he
knows about content he's got a program
about content let me jump in let me
learn and right now like Fast Forward
two months two and a half months dude
I'm I don't want to jinx it but I I
think I'm very much quitting my job the
end of this month if everything from
here goes goes as planned I I will
leaving and if if not like it will be
very very soon after like
I I've not only have I got
the following like a consistent amount
of leads I can generate and funnel into
my coaching program have an audience
that I can n but also it's like the
skills I've developed that won't go away
so even if my account was [ __ ] shut
down tomorrow I lost everything I can
just start again and I and I know how to
do that and I would enjoy doing that and
that's that's one of the biggest things
dude that's freaking powerful bro yeah
like and I think so many people won't
understand that like when they first
start like everybody's looking for the
the magic pill that's going to magically
help them spawn a thousand like 10,000
followers overnight like get the the
viral video that's going to just
generate them like you know 10 sales
calls booked right away get that $4,000
client like just signed overnight
and like what you just said the mindset
that you developed after being
consistent for the past like 60 plus
days of posting almost every single day
right it wasn't the external shift but I
really believe the internal shift
followed you just putting in the or the
external shift followed you putting in
the work the internal work of showing up
every single day like pushing yourself
to create better and better
videos and I think the luck like matches
is consistency that like you hear it all
the time but like I I genuinely think
you you deserve every every ounce of
success that's coming your way this past
five days like yeah it's it's
inspirational bro it's that's so
dope dude even I can't [ __ ] believe
it's real I feel like I'm kind of
dreaming I still have 290 followers like
like whoever's watching this right I I'm
still the same [ __ ] guy who had 290
followers was like a few days ago like
nothing really changed in those few days
like all that change was just
Progressive cuz even actually showing up
like I I was improving in ways I didn't
even realize at first like even how I
speak on camera because of how Mino told
me to do like more unscripted stuff
bring that unscripted energy and get
comfortable just speaking to that one
specific person now I'm like I was out
filming in public the other day like I
could not even dream of doing that like
two months ago and I was looking back at
the footage and I was like damn I
actually come across really well on
camera and the only reason that was the
case was because I showed up for so long
before that video to get the Reps in to
be able to do
that what do you think your biggest
limiting belief or fear was when you
first started this
journey this won't work for me that was
was what I was thinking a lot of the
time this is this isn't going to work
for me work for me like these guys that
blew up they they had something else
special about them it was just you know
special
circumstances there there was something
else at work there and my situation is
different right something like my
situation is harder it's going to be
harder for me the odds are stacked up
against me but honestly what I realized
what I knew at the time as well is like
you're not [ __ ] special and that's a
good thing right no one's [ __ ]
special because if you do the same
[ __ ] inputs you will get the same
output what about your life did you
think were unique circumstances that
were holding you
back probably the the job N9 to-5 job
and the fact that I didn't have much
experience with content I was like
dipping my toes into something I've
never really done before before and I
was like damn this is going to take a
lot of time cuz it's like when you're
learning any new skill you start doing
it and you're like [ __ ] I am [ __ ] with
this like I just want to be good already
and that's that's how I felt and I just
felt pretty pretty hopeless um which is
probably one of the reasons why I joined
the program to get rid of that feeling
because I just wanted to Fast Track that
growth as soon as possible and I mean
that's what [ __ ] happened that's
awesome bro I I love how you're framing
in the mindset of skill building cuz
that's something that we always try to
drill in and I Know It social media has
the outward perception that things just
happen overnight or things happen
luckily or things happen because she's
pretty he's talented he has more money
than me he has a better car than me
that's why they go viral and it's never
true it's always the skill
set and 100% I guess second to last
question here is if you could go back to
you on just literally less than two
months ago in
October like back right before you
joined the Inner Circle back before we
met right and get back into the heads
space a little bit talk to younger Leu
before you posted all of these videos
that you have in the past 60 days before
you went on this insane content journey
of literally just like a little over 60
days too it's not even that long of a
time frame but if you had any piece of
advice to that version of your younger
self just 60 plus days ago what would
you what would you say to that that
version of yourself that was like it had
these limiting beliefs that I have this
special reason why it won't work for me
what would you say as a piece of
encouraging or
advice that's a good
question bro just stick with the process
it will work it works for everyone you
are not special just stick with it as
simple as that
like it it can feel hopeless when you're
getting hundreds of views per video but
every single view is it is actually a
person like you hear that all the time
like all these business gurus will tell
you that oh like 100 views means 100
people like it is true like people are
actually watching your [ __ ] video and
as it grows and grows you get better and
better at making content it is literally
just a matter of time but if you give up
that is the only way you lose so no
matter how long it takes whether it's
going to be two 3 months 6 months 12
months just remember why the [ __ ] you're
doing this you H the 9 to-5 you you want
to be financially free you want to be
doing what you love making content
helping people transform their lives if
you want to do that this is what you got
to do to get there so just stick with it
and you will get there just show up know
that you're in the right place you're
getting help help from the right people
just stick with it that's awesome dude
and the last question thank you so much
for your time here um is good man what
parts of this journey do you think the
Inner Circle specifically helped you out
with everything and I'm not I'm not just
saying that because this is like a
testimonial video an interview or
anything like I'm I'm genuinely serious
like that literally everything like bro
I I made sure to get my [ __ ] money's
worth I joined every call I was there
for the entire call I would always
prepare questions before like everything
I wanted to ask and like literally all I
had to do was just show up post content
get feedback on that iterate improve it
repeat and yeah that's that's all I had
to do and obviously in addition to the
content stuff there's also monetization
help that I get from Renzo as well which
has been really invaluable I mean like
just an hour ago I already stole one of
his many chat sequences that I could
just copy paste and use for my business
like that that saved me days right um so
I would say everything in terms of the
direction on how to go with my content
like figuring out how to actually build
that momentum and know what kind of
Direction I need to go in to see results
how I should bring out my personal brand
how like even like things I didn't
expect to learn about like analytics
about stories or even like story Hooks
and seeing like all of these like
Insider Trends and Insider info that you
or like Prosper or Renzo are talking
about that like information I would
never have access to like the unknown
unknowns and I feel like that's also
been super valuable to me
um and then in addition to that the
network of the guys like I know this is
sounding so [ __ ] cliche already like
I can hear the words coming out like
Mino is not paying me to say any of this
like I'm saying like he's not holding a
gun to my head like I'm I'm genuinely
saying this because I mean it um you're
actually paying
me yeah exactly I'm paying him and um
yeah the network of guys is is also
really invaluable like I suggest like if
you do guys if you guys do join the
inner circle like schedule onetoone
calls with the guys in here as well
that's what I did I networked with all
of them and I've met some really cool
people people that have helped me a lot
and have made this journey even easier
for example the the viral video that
took off of me that got three million
views that would have never happened if
it weren't for the calls but also
because of the network because one of
the guys I spoke with from the inner
circle he sent me the the winning format
that I I've been using he was like hey
bro you should try this I tried it got
5K views I was like okay this was not
expected I thought it would do a little
bit better than this and then someone
else on a Content call Jack mentioned yo
file reels new feature popping off bro
you should try and split test some
videos and I was like hm okay let me let
me make some variations of this and then
one got 10K one got 20K one got three
million I if I was just on my own I
would have had that 5K video and I would
just kept posting probably got to the
same outcome but I don't know how how
much long it would have taken but I was
able to shortcut that because of these
ideas and feedback I get from the other
guys in the
community and yeah it's
just like if you join and you show up to
all the calls and you get feedback and
you're consistent you have no excuse to
not
succeed that's awesome aome dude yeah it
it really is the network I remember one
of our members Jack he has around like
20K followers on Instagram he mentioned
the trials feature I was there that day
and literally a day after two I posted a
video on trial reels that same feature
that he mentioned and I think the video
is also at like 400k on IG which is a
lot higher than some of my other recent
reels so like I even take advice from
the community That's How Strong of a
community I think we've built
um and I I I think it's also a testament
to you though heru of like living and
breathing the game cuz I know there's a
lot of people who come into content like
and maybe this was kind of the mindset
when you came in with like you know I'll
just try it out it's one of those things
that's just like on the side it's not
really a big Focus
right but if you're actually in the game
you're you're like constantly looking
for the tiniest of things which we help
facilitate in the community but you also
just you're always coming up with these
like okay how does this Creator go viral
why does this other Creator go viral
it's the constant mindset of learning
and I think that's a testimony to you as
a person just always having that growth
mindset I think that's what it takes to
win 100% 100% I think it's also
because I am and I was in a lot of pain
and I really needed to change my
situation badly and I think that's why
like the Inner Circle would really work
well for people that are in a lot of
pain and they want content to work not
the type of people that are like oh you
know what let me just you know try
posting this stuff like experiment and
just you know fck this thing out whereas
like if you actually want to dial the
[ __ ] in and you're serious about content
and you know this is what you want to do
instead of just you know dipping your
toes in the water like oh okay let me
let me check this thing out no like if
you're ready to [ __ ] lock in join
that's awesome dude yeah um that's all
the questions I have for you dude like
this is I genuinely believe just the
start right like 100k followers soon 10
K months and Beyond coming very soon in
the business we're going to dial in that
sales process it's going to be lit let's
go dude let's go I'm looking forward to
2025 yeah it's gonna be a mad here this
is awesome bro and just a quick message
to anybody else who's watching this
video who wants to meet me like hiru and
hop in the same program that we're all
working on together like just there's a
link in this description of this video
when I post it to book a call with our
team and see if you're a good fit for
the Inner Circle and see if you're going
to crush it in 2025 with personal
branding dude