[Music]
I don't know it's like it's interesting
to think that most most of these people
are like older than me so I feel like
you know leading a event of people it's
like I'm a kid you know it's just like a
you know to control a room of 50 people
like guide them through the event make
sure they like take it seriously like
you want them to mhm and like be engaged
and lastly have a good time all right we
are currently packing for the event with
have like so much stuff all of this is
prepared for giveaways or games or food
that's very nice my girlfriend's helping
us out we're like tus 2 hours from the
event so we about to hit a cold plunge
get the nerves shake the nerves out of
our system because what better way to do
that than to be extremely [ __ ] cold
let's go woo you know one of the things
that worries me a lot is that I think
more than half of the people coming to
this event are older than me average age
is probably like 23 20 around like 23
years old so that does worry me a little
bit one thought that crosses my mind is
that managing and like moving around
people getting people to listen when I'm
just like a young little kid like hey
guys please please stop talking we need
to continue with the event that scares
me a little bit for the event like what
if people just don't listen that's like
one worry going in cuz I we have like a
bunch of fun stuff planned my girlfriend
gave a really cool idea of like a
spaghetti game it's going to be fun T
minus 90 minutes until the event we're
about to hop in Uber to bring our
luggage of stuff for the event it's very
cold wow thank you guys for showing up
and open too like that I really
appreciate that this space should be
open because we're going to do some uh
let's just say like physical activity
games so like we need this little like
open space in the front woo
oh my God so everybody seated right now
I really don't have a [ __ ] plan but
like I have to Yap because we waiting
for five people before the game starts
so like look at hands of those people
bro I have I don't know what to do bro
cuz here's the thing we're waiting on
five people to start the game right the
game is where it gets fun but for now I
kind have to like make [ __ ] up while
like I'm a slide like introducing people
so I kind of just like had to make [ __ ]
up bro [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] I see d put in the
moves on Zoe right now
W all right we're about to start
presenting to everybody here and all
right let's make some [ __ ] up man let's
go thank you guys all for coming I think
we have like 45 out of the 50 in house
right now
[Music]
silence silence that works okay I want
to give like some quick thank yous real
quick to other people because like
obviously like I'm speaking on this
stage right now but like there's been so
many people who have helped immensely
I'll start off with Gabe Gabe's been in
the academy since like day one he's been
helping out in the calls like he's also
like I'm sure most of you guys have at
least seen or maybe chatted once with
Gabe inside the server so like you know
genuinely you help make this community's
Vibes fun I just want to like give a
personal thank you to you man Ty [ __ ]
like
yeah yeah G's the goat appreciate you
bro yeah he also runs like seven online
businesses the next person is Justin
Justin's our community manager
[Applause]
of so a lot of y'all probably like said
hi on the way up right and maybe guys
I'm chatted with Justin once or twice
inside the community right the fact that
Justin like you know takes calls once a
week he's also in Premed right in
college actually on a sigma grind set
dude it's crazy like but from the bottom
of my heart like I remember I first met
you I think like in August or July or
something yeah and we met basically at
like one of Daniel men's networking
events like literally like the day we
started working together Justin's been
like so on top of everything like
messages all the new members hosts the
call a week like make sure everything in
the community is running smooth and like
I'm a pretty sloppy person and Justin
helps like keep everything so organized
everything running smoothly like from
the bottom of my heart dude like
genuinely thank you man like this would
not be possible
without super grateful and I want to
give one last thank you she's not in
this uh crowd seated right now but my
girlfriend Sarah's been working
tirelessly
she helped plan out the itinerary she's
like organizing food there so we're
almost done getting that set up but
there's like a cute little Sherie board
over there so like once that set up
y'all can grab food all just like the
logistical stuff cuz once again I am my
like brain is a mess so like genuinely
this event probably like we probably all
just have like left by now because it
would be so disorganized so I genuinely
big thank you can we get a round of
applause for Sarah in the back he helped
so
much and yeah other than that obviously
if I had the opportunity I would shout
every single one of you guys in the
crowd but can we just get like one more
round of applause for everybody
[Applause]
else everybody who who made it out here
we picked out the two strongest people
one is a powerlifting Creator he's a
powerlifting coach he he coaches people
how to do deadlift
bench press soon pivoting into coaches
coaching coaches a genius
offer like so yeah I want to welcome up
the WRA
[Applause]
first we got contestant wants to R how
do you
feel I don't know a little nervous
who going against so okay okay and the
reason why he's nervous even though he
has the strongest bench here right
allegedly allegedly okay is because
we're actually pitting him against a
rock climber a rock climbing scen right
his name is Ben yo let's go what they so
you're probably wondering what's on the
line here between the world's strongest
rock climber and the world's strongest
powerlifter that's a good question it's
this hat right here for this hat Justin
could you play some uh actually let me
let me find the music I I pied out
okay okay all right I want a clean arm
wrestle no leaning okay no no no using
your no no doing any of any of this what
is that all right I want it to be all
clean all arm all rotator cuff all bicep
I don't know what other muscles are
involved but yeah you guys
ready done this before yeah three two
one
go oh [ __ ]
look at that bicep look at that
b as a prize you win this this glorious
hat awesome no
no [ __ ] it let's
go I'm about to get cooked bro Sarah
don't look three 2 1
[Applause]
[Music]
go that's a B10 climber right there for
those of you guys who know Ro climbing
that's like that's like Challenger in
League of Legends we can get started
with our very fun event and I'm going to
break you guys up into seven different
teams 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 the rules are you
guys might have played this in middle
school elementary school but basically
amongst your team whoever creates the
tallest structure possible with simply
spaghetti sticks and a yard of tape wins
so we're practicing our team building
here Team 2 3 4 5 6 seven will be in the
back but yeah team one please gather
right here don't don't okay okay I
thought you were throwing up gang signs
bro what team is
this ready do not start building yet no
hey hey hey hey
cheting call it right nown I'll take
that as a yes okay 3 two one go
[Music]
[Applause]
100 all right all right all right we had
some we had some crazy commotion going
back there but we got to start off with
team one who might just take it in the
end okay we're going to measure this up
wait where is it they are at a
staggering 6
Ines okay we're going to move on to team
two it's more than six 11 in from Team
two remember it's where the mark 19 in
let's
go team team four we got a lot of
personality
oh they do they they do oh hey one in is
a lot guys two Ines yo get to the Heavy
Hitters here team five team five has a
staggering
21 and a half Ines hey no get closer to
that fragile all right from Team Six
this could be the deciding factor cuz
I'm not going to lie team seven I mean
participation trophy team five was 22
Team Six no don't touch it was exactly 2
ft
[Applause]
24 Ingenuity right here Ingenuity we are
the future innovators of this world and
universe but yeah congratulations to
Team Six you know what hold on we have
Team seven we have Team seven there's a
bit of an optical illusion here actually
it's weird but this is a slanted
table Believe It or Not team seven is at
a staggering 30 no no no
cim Team Six
win now you guys are probably wondering
this was really strenuous there must be
an incredible prize for this game right
yall have to think really hard now real
quick I want to give a quick shout out
to my girlfriend Sarah she actually
planned like she gave me this idea like
I'm not smart enough to think of this
idea they actually do this exercise with
a lot of CEOs and they also done it with
little kids and what they found is
generally little kids actually do better
than CEOs lesson here is that the
winners are often actually really stupid
no I'm kidding no the lesson the lesson
no no no no no actually very valuable
lesson in content creation here that a
lot of times planning doesn't actually
get you anywhere and sometimes you just
have to act and that's what kids do they
just simply try stuff they just tape it
together and boom VA out they've
suddenly become Victorious so yeah I
want to congratulate you all once again
and present you guys with your Ultimate
Prize everyone drum
please you guys get to share febles
chocolate and I actually want you guys
to uh go back to your team positions and
huddle up you guys have to pick one
honorary member to represent your team
to reiterate who's here we got anelie
representing team one what do you say
freck yeah we're going to win
feminism feminism team two what do you
have to say David my name is say David
David goggin I got this David Goin wow
okay next up we got team three jald what
do you have to say name Geralds I'm
locked in more right now than my
accounting classes that's for sure you
got Daniel talk to me after I win this
so next up we got team five Renzo how do
you feel Renzo just uh chill guy trying
to do some planks you
know Team Six Sean uh yeah I'm just
going to do my best I'm going to make
Daniel proud he make Daniel proud
Aaron from Team seven what do you have
to say just give it just give it our
best shot let's
go can't hate that one okay okay so here
are the rules here are the rules I don't
want to see none of
this I don't want to see none of the
none of that okay if your butts go down
I am watching each and every one of your
butts pause okay so I will see if your
butt goes down so I'm going to just give
you a tap on the shoulder and be like
hey butt right well give like one of you
guys like a butt warning right three
two one
go okay it started there's like a lot of
stuff in
my wow okay one
handed yo oh wow he's confident 1 minute
has passed everybody is still standing
give it up give it up let's
go let's go R let's go Daniel let's go
D let's go keep breathing okay thatch
getting a little
hard team Three is
out you're doing great yo we got team
one
supporting where's the let's
go get that Ass Up Get That Ass Up
[Music]
[Applause]
is
out this guy just R the camera what the
[ __ ]
[Music]
come on just get started what do you
have to say team one how long is youring
we're going to
[Applause]
win team two what do you have to say I
want to take a soul
[Music]
[Applause]
he's lose he's going to
lose El out power come on
[Applause]
[Music]
that one was for Michelle Obama Rosa
Parks and Frank other women
[Applause]
women without my teammates helping me
Doom scroll giving me water like
couldn't have done it without him he was
yelling in my ear he was like you got
three more minutes you got three more
minutes even though in my mind I was
like I do not have three more minutes
but but them giving me water and letting
me Doom squirrel helps so
much WoW picking Onie as your honorary
member you each get one
[Music]
hat thank you thank you it's extra L
victory
hats you should get like 10 hats for
that that's crazy can we give went to
David of course yes now David I want you
to come back up here for lasting 10
minutes crazy you also deserve a hat
took my soldiers
[Music]
[Applause]
is it appropriate tomor right
now so if you guys are ready we just get
started with the first spin let's let's
go for it for a Content Academy
hat they're
losing oh my God holy [ __ ] what do you
have to say I love you so much man hey
thank you thank you
oh look I won hat Academy hat go I got
to join
now let's go okay
okay three more hats right here oh oh
it's
Ben has hat wein wein
Ben okay okay just for that cuz you won
twice we have another we have another
giveaway the next one was going to be a
journal have this journal mol skin bro
yeah mol skin Journal
thank Go Jack I know I know you take a
lot of
notes every call is taking notes so now
we've run through the baby prizes time
for the big prizes and the first up
these are actually practical like these
are going to be like super helpful so
the first stuff that we got is three
mfed phone cases
so end up your phone anywhere it becomes
a mini tripod super super super
practical you just stick it on the back
of your phone so we have three of those
I'm taking trades for this I won this
last
time I all right we're getting into some
big ticket prizes this is the second
biggest prize right here next up we have
a Beat Studio 4 be solo 4 these just
came out y we're going to need a drum
roll for this everyone
please oh my God oh my
God oh my God I'm so sorry
dude here you go sir hey thank you
man okay thank you so I have this prize
here I'm not going to reveal it
[Applause]
yet Iron Man
[Music]
what are your what are your thoughts
this is the best day of my life do you
have a message for Mino I love you oh
yeah Mino I love you follow me back on
Instagram
yooo what's good man thank you for
letting me come out here thank you for
letting me to plank thank you for
feeding me digging in um you know I met
some phenomenal people here content
Academy we up baby we up you know's a
goat took me from 10K followers and 55k
followers last year this year first call
we had literally went from no million
view videos ever to my first million
view video 2 days after your call had 61
million view videos that same month and
uh this year I went from 300K followers
and 430k followers on IG so whatever the
[ __ ] Mino says in terms of content is
listen to him I promise you he's going
to blow you up so Meo thank you so much
for everything pretty much um your event
was insired honestly super proud of you
bro I wouldn't be where I am today in
terms of content in terms of or any
business or anything uh truly from the
bottom of my heart I really wouldn't be
I guess like just anywhere in life
without you like without even like I
guess joining the Con Academy at the
beginning of the year um but yeah just
like take a look around take a look at
the footage everybody's like just I
don't even know everyone just is really
proud of you so keep it up well I think
it was amazing I felt really lonely on
this journey but I feel very empowered
and I feel very motivated and I can tell
everyone has a good heart thank you Mino
for this awesome event it's been awesome
working with you Meo the goat uh he
knows the [ __ ] bro for sure join the
community you won't regret it yo it's
not a testimonial like a message to him
not even in his
community thanks for hosting event um
these guys are chill yo Mino this was a
w event it was lovely meeting all of
these people thank you for setting this
up felt like the Avengers of content
creators just came through to this room
you know thanks for hosting us you're
super sick everyone flew out to go see
you man so thanks for hosting us you
know I just want to say you are the go
just want to say that that's all I'm
proud of you man here I I'll be real you
know I met you two and a half years ago
through one instagram DM and that one
instagram DM changed my life today
rooming with you has changed my life
just being around you has changed my
life um just talking to you about the
future and like what I should be doing
changes my life youve shaped my
perspectives a lot in just what I wanted
to do and yeah I wouldn't be here
without you and I think literally no one
here would be here without you either
like every single person at this event
has become who they are as a Creator
because of you this shit's really hard
to [ __ ] do like you Chang mine and so
many other people's lives so you should
be proud of that and keep pushing
forward through all your hard days but I
love you me know shoot this is a really
great experience it's like 10 out of 10
getting together with so many people who
are content creators almost towards the
beginning of their career this feels
like a college get together but for
Content creators so it makes any sense
like a bunch of people majoring in
content creation except that some of
them are actually like lowkey really
really successful the amount of
potential energy in this room is insane
like and so that's why I think like I
don't know it's just like a 10 out of 10
event really proud to see how far you've
come with content um ever since like the
project 50 Discord um all the way up
until now it's like this is exactly the
sort of pathway you want to see people
take this is exactly the sort of thing
you want to see people do or you to be
able to bring a bunch of people together
and get them to like support you it's
just an amazing thing so yeah I keep
doing it keep doing it right it's in
your blood I can't really think of
anything else to say except I'm super
super happy to be here and I'm super
super proud of what you've been able to
do I think it genuinely was a 10 out of
10 like could not have expected the
community to to mesh better than I ever
could I remember back in 9th grade I had
a public speaking project for the very
first time we had to do a speech in
front of the class and I got a I think I
got a 70% on the speaking portion
because it was so terrible look at you
now Mr Barrett [ __ ] you saying I
couldn't do eye contact yeah it's
surreal now being able to to bring
together a whole community of people in
a room 50 people bigger than my
classroom back then yeah I'm I'm so
grateful that I was able to do this
opportunity
[Music]