so a year ago I very specifically
remember it was January 2024 I had this
crazy goal of $100,000 a month and I
vowed to post every single day on
Instagram and Tik Tok until I hit that
goal exactly one year later in January
of 2025 AKA last month we hit that goal
as you can see on my phone that say
$100,000 in the month of January I wish
somebody came back and gave me a little
pep talk on how I should go about the
next year of my life cuz if you click
this video it's probably because you
wanted do something crazy like make
$100,000 in one month so I'm going to
order it from the crazy ambitious and
motivational lessons at the beginning to
then the more nihilistic and
philosophical lesson that I learned
towards the end but the first lesson I
learned in this process of chasing money
and chasing extreme success at such a
young age is that your income and your
success is directly correlated to your
level of knowledge and how much you know
not necessarily how much work you
actually put in so the average day in my
life last month literally just looked
like this I would wake up probably
around like 9 or 10: a.m. for the first
hour of my day maybe read a little bit
journal and sit in silence and reflect
on the fact that what I'm grateful for
and the fact that you know it's it's
nice to be alive those those kind of
gratitude Reflections and then after
that it's probably around like 10:00
a.m. by this point maybe I'll hit the
gym for 30 minutes maybe I'll check
Instagram see how well my videos
performed and then I'll check slack
maybe because that's where my team
members text me in my business the
content academ and we teach people how
to go viral on Tik Tok and Instagram
with their personal Brands that's the
entire business that I run the reason
why they buy from me is mostly because I
give them some sort of social support in
terms of growing their own personal
brand so I give them direct feedback on
live calls and the way the money was
split up between these two course
programs is low ticket for my $97 a
month program was we I think we did
around $33,000 last month and then we
did around
$67,000 with our high ticket program our
ticket price is around $6,000 a year
right so those are the ways we split up
the cash I'm explaining all these
Logistics to give you a little bit of
context that you're not going to make
those kind of sales for $6,000 a year
sales by just simply working harder like
you're not just going to like email more
people cold DM more people you know
maybe hustle hard and just like make one
more video every single day that's not
going to get you to $100,000 a month
right it might get you to like 5 to 10K
a month and that's realistically what I
did cuz I would consider myself a pretty
terrible business owner and I had to
learn all these skill sets of like
management right I'm a pretty sensitive
anxious person so management is not and
leadership are not like skills that come
easily to me and neither is even like
Finance or accounting right I was like a
decent mathematics student but the
reason why I was able to make that much
money in one month is because I had a
skill that people wanted I thought for
the longest time that the people who
make the most money were the people who
work the hardest the people who just
grinded and put the most hours and time
in and that's kind of what I was told
growing up by my mom who would always
tell me yo if you don't work hard and
study hard you're going to become
homeless you're not going to make a lot
of money and it's like true to a certain
extent right especially academically
because in school you're kind of
rewarded generally for the amount of
time you put in but to make this much
money at a young age right I'm just
emphasizing this is just to make
$100,000 in one month it's all leverage
it's all how you're able to delegate
work to other people I mentioned my team
members because I wouldn't be able to
make $100,000 in one month without their
help and that kind of ability to
delegate work is something that was
really foreign to me so the reason why I
say that knowledge is so much more
important than how hard you work is
because most of I would say my success
in growing this business to that level
is just because I consume information
now raply every 2 to 3 weeks I'll
probably finish a book and it's been
like a general content at the minimum
I'll finish a book like once a month
once every week I'll probably tune into
a podcast that's like an hour or two
long but the fact that you're able to
command more influence and command more
impact is the reason why you'd make any
more income to begin with so the reason
why you're able to command more impact
is because you have leverage so instead
of maybe impacting somebody who's going
to make an extra $10 in their business
now the leverage that I provide to a
business owner who's going to pay me
$66,000 a year is that I'm able to help
them directly make an extra $10,000
every month with their own business
because I'm able to help them grow their
social media and then the extra leverage
on top of that right because I don't
even think that's enough to get the
leverage to make $100,000 a month maybe
it is if you're like an agency owner but
the way I was able to do is then I was
able to also get even more leverage by
Outsourcing and paying my friend to do a
lot of the coaching so then I can focus
on bringing more people in and then
selling more people right because sales
is another really important aspect to
making that $100,000 it's not hard in
theory but the little things of like
okay how much you actually playay a
sales closer how do you make sure a
sales closer is actually incentivized to
work hard how do you make sure people
don't just call your program a scam it's
not actually can you sell people but can
you make sure it's not actually a scam
and can you make sure your program is so
good that people only leave five star
reviews and the ability to do that is
really hard and it's not hard in the
sense that you just have to be grinding
on your laptop all day because
realistically I'm probably spending like
4 hours on my laptop every single day
add in an extra 2 to 3 hours working on
my content which is just me tapping
fingers on my phone because I'm just
filming and editing on my iPhone that's
not a lot of actual time that I put in
so it's all leverage how do you make it
so you can get a lot from Just 2 hours
is a really important question and
content creation is undoubtedly really
really important but content creation is
something that I learned really early on
and that was a skill that you know gave
me a lot of Leverage but didn't require
that much of a headache to learn I'm a
pretty creative person so creative work
didn't come as hard but management a lot
of these left brain tasks being
organized in terms of being able to pay
people every two weeks and make sure I
never miss a payment it like took me
understanding Google calendar reminders
realistically but but those those small
things it's like knowledge man I sound
like Lopez in the freaking app but
knowledge is really important and
consuming a lot of books on these little
things not just for the tangible skills
of management leadership finances
Marketing sales content creation Service
delivery product I'm I'm Buzz wording
here but you get the point there's a lot
of little micro skills that you have to
learn if you want to run a business that
does $100,000 in one month and my second
point in order to get yourself your your
mind to be able to handle that much
pressure because making $100,000 a month
means people are paying you lots and
lots of money so regardless even if you
make a lot of money it's not like it's
just air Dro to you that's a lot of
pressure that's kind of put onto your
shoulders where you have to do a lot of
work and that's where the knowledge
comes in where are you able to get more
out of Just 2 hours of your time or 3
hours of your time every single day or
else you know your product's going to
fall apart your business is going to
fall apart so I had to learn a lot and
not to say that you have to figure this
[ __ ] out you know overnight it's a long
process I've been creating content for 5
years now I've been trying this old
online business thing for 2 years and
this Curr business that I've been
running I've been running for 13 months
it takes a long time and that's okay but
focus on learning for even the first 2
years of trying to make money online do
not focus on trying to put more time in
to making your day just last longer in
terms of work hours spend like maybe 3
hours working and then 10 hours like
learning don't obviously just mentally
masturbate to learning and just watch
podest for 8 hours every single like no
don't do that either okay right you
still have to put in some time but don't
prioritize just working and prioritize
like I would say at least 50% of your
time to just consuming information that
is relevant to whatever skill you want
to learn if you want to learn
concentration dude don't spend 8 hours
making a video every single day spend
like four making a video and then spend
four learning about how to make better
videos don't just like brute force your
way into a video every single day
thinking that something's going to
change because doing the same thing
every single day expecting a different
result is insanity now this brings me to
my second point which pertains to
consuming knowledge but what I've
learned in this process proc of making
more and more money scaling my business
from say making when I first started I
was making like $11,000 a month and that
was kind of my bottleneck right I was
hard stuck at $11,000 a month then it
took me a year to hit 10K a month and
actually like you know break past 10K a
month to make 10K to 11k a month cuz I
hit 10K a month once and then I the
business crumbled a lot of times too
being able to hit something consistently
takes actually changing as a human being
when I actually hit 10K a month
consistently back in around February of
2024 I realized there was one new
bottleneck that was keeping me from
hitting around 25k a month or 50k a
month cuz those are my new goals and I
realized the biggest thing that held me
back now in retrospect is I was so
stingy bro and I'm not talking about
like stingy in terms of like buying a
coffee or whatever cuz I'm Pretty
Reckless with my spending I'm talking
stinginess in terms of business I never
bought a course until like June 2024
kind of ironic for be for somebody being
a COR seller why was that well it's
because I was so scared of losing money
and I never hired somebody until like
May of 2024 and it was my head coach Sam
and it took me so long to make that
decision I was so scared of hiring
somebody why it's because I was scared
of losing money because paying somebody
say $2,000 a month right that's an extra
rent that you have to pay like obviously
it's scary but that's the necessary
price you have to pay I paid a
copywriter $2,000 one month when the
copywriter was not worth it so $2,000
just went down the drain I also paid
another agency owner $2500 three times
so for 3 months straight I paid him
$2,500 it was kind of a waste of money
I'm not going to lie it didn't really do
that much for me but still spending that
money in retrospect was helpful because
I learned how to delegate money better
so in terms of like Wells spent money
yes there's obviously like Well Spent
expenses and that's probably around like
10K a month right now is like Well Spent
expenses that kind of stood the test of
time in my business that was actually
useful but I've also spent in the last
year maybe like
$15,000 in quote unquote useless
expenses that didn't really amount to
something but you don't learn those
lessons by just studying it better by
like being a little bit more cautious in
your decision making if you make 10K a
month and your bottleneck you know is
around 10K a month don't be scared to
spend 5,000 of it on like your team on
just hiring somebody okay even it's the
worst hire in the world I'm talking like
yo this person could straight up just
come in and be like psych [ __ ] I'm not
going to do any work and then dip you
that's honestly still worth it because
you still learn a little bit about how
to like vet for people who are going to
do that in the future and yes it sounds
really stupid okay I I feel like I sound
so silly s baying this right now because
I'm telling you to lose money that's
necessary and I lost like 15 grand last
year on my just willy-nilly silly
expenses like a copywriter didn't really
make me much more money but it taught me
like what a copywriter should be doing
and now my community manager Justin does
all of our emails and he does it better
than what the copywriter did why was
able to come to that conclusion where my
community manager Justin is so op that
he actually provides such good value to
our community and our business cuz I
wasted money dude I wasted $2,000 wasted
I'm saying as a strong word but I spent
it and if you actually have a legit
legitimate business and you're the type
of person who's smart enough to get to
that level of like 10K a month you're
going to make it again you're not going
to like your business is not going to
fall apart tomorrow the second lesson is
to understand where it's actually fear
that's hindering your decision- making
and when it's actually just
intelligently being patient if you're
waiting on hiring somebody when you have
a gut feeling that you probably should
like set a goal to literally just end of
day today do it and that's how I ended
up hiring Justin the most important
person to my business is that I was like
screw it I'm going to get an agency to
find me of virtual assistant right a
virtual assistant from like Philippines
then I meet this guy Justin at a
networking event and he basically comes
to me with a pitch of like yo I'll be
your community manager like you don't
need a VA I'll do it for you and I was
like oh [ __ ] okay sure I'm sorry agency
I'm actually have to go with this other
guy Justin he seems really diligent and
he's willing to do it for a little bit
more of the price but he seems like he's
going to be so much better yeah it's
like nothing really worked to plan
because I just fortuitously met Justin
at a networking event but if I was too
scared to hire in the first place place
I never would have told him that I was
hiring a virtual assistant we never
would have been working together now
like now at this point he's one of the
most valuable people at my business the
content Academy because he literally DMS
every single new member yo what's up he
welcomes them in a weekly call and make
sure the community is running smoothly
he's the one who proactively texts me on
slack like when I respond on slack it's
because he's messaging me about
something going wrong in the business in
the content Academy right he's telling
me yo this bot is down in a Discord yo
can you fix that and I'm like oh [ __ ] my
bad I'm on vacation right now I'll go
get to that and being able to be the
person who hires them requires boldness
and requires this fearlessness of you
know taking big swings and mean like I
trust you man even though I don't really
know you yet that's how business
relationships are built with a swing of
trust really with a swing of Blind Faith
and yes oh you can be smart about
decision- making I know okay I know you
can be smart about the decision making
I'm just saying to just do it because
realistically your intelligence and your
level of knowledge towards the decision
is probably not what's hindering you
from hiring somebody ever it's just
because you're scared if you know you
have to hire somebody is because there's
a clear desire and need and a pain point
for it so stop putting off that decision
because you're not saving money you're
end just paying with time and paying
with lost growth in your business and
lost personal growth now number three
what I realized in around April of 2024
I don't think I have personally enough
motivation to chase 100K a month and
actually do it on my own and this is
like an interesting lesson that I
learned this is where it's going to get
a little bit from motivational to
slightly philosophical but I realized
that I don't personally need $100,000 in
one month like no [ __ ] duh like what am
I going to do with $100,000 in one month
like I I'm not really that materialistic
and honestly if you're still watching
this video you're probably not either
right because you're very similar to me
I don't have any dream car I don't
really have a dream apartment like my
apartment right now is $2,600 a month
it's a lot but I don't need $100,000 a
month to do that I can real pay for that
in like 10 or $20,000 a month and that's
how much my business was doing around
April of 2024 so why did I actually seek
$100,000 a month and actually lock in
for it because I reached the point of
$10,000 a month
consistently around February of 2024 and
then I was just chilling I was like yo
honestly I don't really need to work
that hard to like hit 10K a month I just
need to keep making content and like the
business can be all right the business
was honestly pretty shitty honestly like
we barely had any group calls at the
time in our community content Academy
the course was like not that fleshed out
and I personally wasn't as knowledgeable
in business so if people had business
related questions like had kind of just
guessed when I answered them but that
being said in the moment I didn't have
the foresight to see that I would learn
so much in the process make 100K a month
so all I saw was the pain and I didn't
really see the monetary reward for
making that much money it would be I saw
it as a it would be nice to make this
much money knowing and kind of seeing
the amount of work that I'd have to put
in and I really want to do it so what
changed what actually got me to lock in
and eventually hit 50k a month in
September of 2024 and then eventually
make $100,000 in one month in January of
2025 and it's simple I met my girlfriend
this is a story I don't really tell too
many people I guess but I'm in the
Bahamas right now on a vacation with my
girlfriend and this whole trip might be
around like
$4,000 to pay for the entire thing
something around that maybe right that's
that's like a lot of money I've realized
that without having another person to
really like push me to make more money
and I'm talking like she's not
materialistic at all in fact my
girlfriend is even less materialistic
than me I started working a lot harder
when I saw how hard she works for her
family like she works very hard to
supply for her family and to provide for
her family and I saw that and I was like
literally the day after I met her she
was telling me what her motivations are
to work hard she was explaining how it's
to like provide for a family I was
sitting there and I was like wow my
motivation is just like to travel the
world and like have a chill experiences
I guess you know I wasn't really
thinking that deep and then I saw that
and literally the next day even this
this was where when we first met not
even when we started dating this is the
kind of person I want to date these are
the values that she holds this is why I
should make $100,000 a month I
understand now the significance of the
weight of this goal and like the meaning
of money I guess it's because it's a
tool to actually provide for livelihood
and it's not just this willy-nilly
scoreboard number on a screen that makes
you feel all giddy when you you know
open up your [ __ ] or stripe dashboard and
you're like big number you know cuz
that's like you really sit and think
about it and think about the amount of
work that would actually have to go into
that it's a lot of work so why would I
do that you know I would just chill at
10K a month and travel the world on my
own and I realized that to be able to
provide for her and her family or my own
family as well like my own parents
requires this much more work it's so
worth it not only to like obviously be
able to provide for them like this cool
experience she said she wouldn't have
gone on this trip to the Bahamas you
know on her own I mean duh it's like
Valentine's Day obviously I guess what
I'm trying to say is that if you do feel
a lack of motivation you kind of just
feel empty towards your goals maybe you
just don't really have another person
there that you want to look after are
you just almost scared to take on the
responsibility of wanting to provide
from somebody else because that's also a
fear it's like do I have what it takes
to actually Prov for another human being
to cap off this point too I realize how
worth it it is to go through that
experience because on the other side of
learning to provide and learning to be
like you know a more capable leader I
wouldn't even say capable man just more
capable leader in making more money and
not just making more money but
commanding more influence because and
commanding more impact cuz that's kind
of where making more money stems from
it's worth it because you you learn so
much and you're able to unlock so much
more beautiful experiences like like I
said I wouldn't be here in the Bahamas
if I didn't have her alongside me she's
taking a nap right now in the hotel room
right this is what our hotel room looks
like I unlocked this experience because
I decided that I wanted to take care of
somebody else and that realistically
came not because like I was like yo one
day I'm going to just become like a
[ __ ] gigachad like no it's because I
met her and I I realized in that moment
that this is like the type of woman that
I actually want to date I I don't know
how applicable this I'm I'm not saying
like just start dating somebody for
motivation okay like that's that's silly
I'm just saying like I I feel very
grateful because the reason why I think
I'm even here is not because of some
selfish desire so don't rely on just
material desires to motivate you let's
move on to point number four bro I
realized I got to quit yapping man like
this this video is getting long and I'm
not intend for this video to get this
long but lesson number four is be
careful who you listen to in this grind
of chasing success at a young age okay
and I included at 21 years old in the
title to specifically make this point
when you're young I'm assuming you're
probably around my age fresh out of high
school/ col we in this college phase
we're kind of lost you know especially
if you want to do something out outside
of the norm like content creation social
media influencing it's weird because
it's not like this space has been
studied for decades it's a really new
space the internet business Space is
really new so when I got into it I just
kind of studied the first person I saw
on YouTube and these people that I found
on YouTube that I studied and watched
and they did impact my life a lot were
Iman godi and Hamza these two YouTubers
who talked about male self-improvement
and talked about online business a lot
as I've gone now in this journey trying
to make $100,000 a month and eventually
hitting it right checking off this
massive Behemoth of a goal that I never
thought would be possible at a younger
age I realize now I idolized them too
because they seemed like they had
everything in their life together they
made a lot of money but they were also
super pretty good-look dudes paw no homo
and they also had cool Lifestyles and
they seemed really confident and they
seemed to get girls too and I I
struggled to get girls it was a lot of
these traits that I really looked up to
and now that I've gotten to this point
where you know worked on myself to work
on my discipline my confidence my body
and then finally my money and I realize
now that a lot of the gurus that you'll
see on YouTube specifically who make a
lot of money aren't who you think they
are back in May or June of
2024 I was in like a group chat with
Hamza the YouTuber right he was talking
about basically running online paid
Community businesses and he was talking
about his school Community a school
Community is basically like a a paid
Community where you pay maybe $50 to
$100 a month to be part of a an
exclusive community where you learn
about a specific skill so for Hamza it's
just like self-development in general
for Ben he's got like a million or 2
million subscribers so I looked up to
him a lot I was like dude I want to
reach his level of influence I want to
reach his level of money right he's
making like six figures a month he's
just like super Jack and confident right
he's like yeah cool I want to be left
and then I realized like the insides of
his business my business was actually
having a higher retention rate and a
lower term than his at the time I looked
up to his business a lot and then you
hear about these other online gurus
there's a lot of people who jump through
a lot of Hoops especially selling
courses online and this is where gets a
little bit nihilistic but like as a
person who got into the core selling
space thinking that it's just like the
easiest way to make money online and it
quite frankly is I think there's ethical
implications of like making that much
money bro if you're selling a course to
like thousands of people which you kind
of have to do to make six figures a
month right you have to be reaching
thousands of people can you
realistically ethically do that without
making your product quality worse and I
thought they just had it figured out
until I you know saw hamza's turn wasn't
that great yeah it's cool to make make a
lot of money it's cool to like go on
like excursions like this but how can
you like in your right mind Flex that
you do all of this cool stuff and that
you're this like Giga chat of a man when
your business and the people that
trusted you that you made promises to
with their money are under served man it
just kind of felt really shitty so I
would just say be careful who you listen
to It's like the scorecard is not all
about money and I wish somebody just
told me that when I was getting into the
space that like I never wanted to be
like just a course seller online you
know I never wanted to be back guy you
do face a lot of this like dissonance of
like I love watching people [ __ ] on core
sellers on YouTube expose like when I
see like a coffeezilla video exposing a
guru I'm like yo let's freaking go and
then it's also this terrifying feeling
of like what if people perceive me that
way what if like college friends now see
me selling courses online and think I'm
just like some freaking prick who flexes
online to sell courses you know selling
courses is not a bad thing cuz a lot of
people put tons of effort into
curtailing genuinely really good
educational experiences because they
care a lot about their students and I'm
not even just going to like bloat and
say that's me like I've met some really
really brilliant people like this one
person for example Le fam she runs a
course SL coaching program teaching
people how to get into Ivy League
schools she also gets like really good
reviews she's genuinely driven by just
wanting to impact people and like having
spoken to her I'm like wow this is a
such a cool person and there's a lot of
people out there who aren't as big
online who do brilliant brilliant work
in the core selling space so don't just
listen to to the people who Flex their
money numbers online because there's a
lot of people who do it not just in a
really lucrative way and a really flashy
way like the lifestyle marketers but
there's a lot of people who do it in an
incredibly ethical way and an incredibly
like purposeful way I think it's really
easy to Lose Yourself when you make a
lot of money online that money just
starts to become this scoreboard and I
guess this this transitions to point
number five and lesson number five that
I'm learning now and this is going to
start to become my own therapeutic
session here I hope if you're on this
journey to become wealthy at a young age
this somehow provides some valuable
insight to you at this point after
making $100,000 in one month that
honestly sounds silly it's not like
$100,000 in one month change anything I
could have easily made 90,000 or 80,000
last month it would have had a similar
effect of like money just kind of
becomes a scoreboard number and at a
certain point you start to lose direct
correlation between you making more
money and it directly impacting your
life because at 10K a month going from 5
to 10K a month literally means you
probably don't to get a job anymore like
you can do whatever you love full-time
as a Creator if you go from $5,000 to
$10,000 a month you your rent is paid
but you can also start saving money
that's a huge huge bonus that you get
for making more money that's so awesome
you go from 10 to 20K a month and now
you can start treating the people that
you love to dinners right and that was
such a cool experience for me when I was
able to treat College friends to a
dinner it was like $800 it was like Fogo
to sh and I brought I think 10 of my
friends to go get dinner there and it
was one of the most like fulfilling
things I had ever done and it was right
when it hit around like 10 or 12K a
month with my business I was like wow
this is what I want to do and now it's
gotten to the point where like once I
hired my friend as a coach it's like wow
I can provide him with fulfilling work
but I can also help literally provide
for him and now our head coach Sam
literally got engaged not that that had
anything to do with me like if I can
help support him starting his own family
like that brings me so much fulfillment
right with the opportunities that our
business creates we can then have people
starting families in there you know it's
it's just like really fulfilling but
then from 100K a month to like 300K a
month why should I go for that and it's
a question that I'm still racking my
brain through right now because outside
of the regular business and sales
schedules why should I push to make more
money why should I push to grow the
business is a really weird question that
I really had to ask myself retiring my
parents money feels so far away and yet
like lifestyle money is kind of already
passed what I've already achieved so
it's this weird like Middle Ground at
$100,000 a month where it's like I don't
think I'm making enough to retire my
parents yet like last month profit was
probably around $50,000 so I'm not
saying that like we we took home
$100,000 last month it it becomes this
scoreboard number and I think that's
what happens to a lot of people in the
online business space like I I was
watching a podcast earlier from Iman
godi he's kind of just flexing on people
who talk about Revenue numbers online
saying how it's like stupid in the info
product space I'm using buzzword you
don't have to understand what I'm saying
to get my point but it's basically like
a lot of these people will brag about
how much money they make it's like a
soccer player boasts about scoring 30
goals in one season like that's great
but is that really what you dedicate
your entire life's purpose to obviously
at the end of the day yeah everything is
game nothing matters blah blah blah you
can go down this nihilistic train so why
not just seek to make a lot of money and
that's probably what I'm going to do but
how can I do it in a little bit more of
a fulfilling way if I'm taking it from
the perspective of like maso's hierarchy
of needs you kind of checked off the
point of esteem needs you've checked off
your kind of self-actualization in a bit
you know so what's next it's self
transcendental needs what is that what
are those self transcendental needs that
you have and gain Clarity on that even
if you're not at $100,000 a month like
what will you do when you have money
literally like yo this you can treat
this as a manifesting kind of exercise
but like literally map out what you
would do financially when you make
$100,000 in one month or a million do in
one year like map out financially what
you would actually do with that money
without that Clarity one year will have
less motivation back to lesson number
two right cuz it's harder to push for
things when you don't do it for other
people but number two as well is like
you're going to reach that point that's
why you're watching this video is
because you're ambitious and that's why
you're even here to begin with like this
video is going to be not that heavily
edited so you reached this point because
you genuinely see yourself in my spot
right now yapping to a camera talking
like he's the expert being a
philosophical stuff okay maybe you don't
picture yourself doing that part but you
picture yourself being in in a position
where you're like okay now I've made
$100,000 a month where do I go from here
do I do this with my money where do I go
it's like this is a position that you'll
see yourself in so ask yourself what
you're what are you going to actually do
with that money and like really like I'm
talking like if you think you're going
to donate like $37,000 to charity like
write that down you think you're going
to wire like 10% of your income to your
parents every month like write that down
too you know like and if you think
you're going to travel where how often
and write down exactly how much that's
going to cost I know it sounds so silly
I've reached this point where I was kind
of just so focused on the number because
I set this goal of $100,000 a month for
my content to be really interesting so I
reached this point and I'm like wait I
didn't even take time to think about why
I'm even here like what am I doing here
what do I do next like cuz my next goal
is a million dollars a month with my
business we're launching a new software
business that's an AI product right so I
think we're going to hit a million
dollar a month maybe in the next year
honestly like maybe and I don't want to
be scratching my head thinking like holy
[ __ ] I feel really lonely I feel like I
just aged internally to reach this level
of business all for what was there a
genuinely Noble reason true good reason
for me to reach this point or did I just
reach it because I didn't really know
what else to do with my time that's a
really harrowing thought and I don't
want to lose the rest of my life to a
freaking number on a screen because yes
money does have tangible value only the
tangible value that you genuinely give
it not this like hypothetical value
where you think you'll somehow find the
answers to life after you make the money
number in your bank account cuz that's
not going to happen and you might just
be sitting in the Bahamas feeling a
little empty questioning life and
ranting to a camera because you don't
know what else to do wow that was kind
of poetic at the end holy [ __ ] that was
kind of fire if you do want more
practical tips I do teach how to go
viral and how I grew 200,000 followers
last year on my Instagram account
creating authentic content if you want
more advice on that that's the first
video in the description below other
than that I'll see yall in my next
autistic rant love you guys