I posted this YouTube video 54 days ago
it's a vssl or video sales letter and in
this video I want to break down how that
video was structured so meticulously to
then convert
$67,000 in low ticket community sales
that means literally
$1,200 on average every single day since
I have posted that video literally like
the closest thing I've ever seen to
passive income because YouTube literally
givs me free views on this vssl and I
want to break down exactly all of these
systems in this video and it's recording
of a coaching call where I did a very
breakdown let's go take a look who else
here too is curious about vsls okay cool
okay we got to go to my people this is
my vssl it's posted onto YouTube as
opposed to host it on like your own
Vimeo Wisa or like Loom the goal is
basically to also pick up a bunch of or
like organic traction and just get like
free views I got an extra like
72% just from YouTube like YouTube Just
gifted me free views right obviously it
was optimized for the algorithm but
spending that extra time did pay off a
lot I got 48,000 views that I wouldn't
have otherwise gotten like and these are
like 48,000 High intent views as opposed
to like short form views right because
people actually like actively clicked on
this posting the vssl onto YouTube It's
like a why not in my opinion right
people are going to see it anyways on
your website or your school landing page
cuz you never know if you just optimize
the first minute a little bit it could
get like an extra boost from YouTube and
it also allows you then on every one of
your other YouTube videos If you ever
post Future YouTube videos to then just
be like you know watch this video next
and that just links to the video what's
your like structure for overall building
the vso so I can cover that next a video
that performs well on YouTube that just
has high retention will probably convert
better as a vssl why because if people
are interested they're going to watch
and if people watch they're going to buy
you're kind of playing the same game by
trying to make like a high conversion
vssl if you're also trying to make it
rank decently on YouTube yeah and
getting paid for the YouTube AdSense on
the vssl yeah like that's part of the
Strat too make sure it's not copyrighted
because this is supposed to be your most
viewed video now let me pull up my
script for the vssl so this was my like
structure and you can really see here
it's 19 Pages now mind you took I spent
a lot of time on this but I want to
highlight a couple things I started off
with an ideal viewer Persona who's my
friend I wrote down problems first
that's what I kept in the back of my
mind while I scripted the entire thing
and I think that's key the verbiage
changes based on like the icp's age this
is the first line I wrote on the page
second is I wrote down objections
because this is kind of the goal of the
vssl right or the sale you have to break
down their limiting beliefs on your
methodology or else even if you have the
most Banger product they're like oh but
I don't have anything to sell so this is
not for me don't worry like you know and
just kind of like I I listed out four
you could list out like up to 10 and
just make sure you try and sprinkle them
throughout your video because this just
valuable for educational videos in
general even if you're not even selling
anything it's the same methodology
because you want to persuade somebody to
take change in their life even if you
don't sell them to pay you with their
credit card you're still selling them to
like take action right it's the same
thing but just you pitch at the end
instead of just saying get after it guys
and like And subscribe I started off
with titles as well because I wanted
this to rank organically and then let's
let's talk about the script
so first off is the hook which starts
off with social proof I've posted x
videos I've made X th000 in this time
frame and I also added like some extra
you know lifestyle details right to
ground it in reality and during this
time this is the real result that people
are here for the hook starts with hard
social proof now I'm kind of just
talking about like so here's why a
personal brand is so important Domino
number one personal brand is so
important it's so important so important
here's who I was in the past I'll do a
quick rundown of the script before I
cover like the most important element so
the script structure in general followed
as follows it basically goes hook into
Point number one ha number one or tactic
number one and then it goes into hack
number two which is IDE of viewer
Persona then it goes into hack number
three which is community and basically
for hack number three it just turned
into a pitch because basically I said
hack number three is community where do
you find community and the truth is I
barely found one and that's why I
created the content Academy that's why I
created insert product and then I just
go on a long tangent on how the method
Community changed my life so I tell
stories about how I met this one guy and
he changed my life in my online business
Journey how I met this other guy and he
also changed my life in my content
creation Journey and then I just do a
bunch of social proof and then I start
pitching the actual product I give them
like Steps in the Journey of what they
can expect when they go on the journey
themselves and then lastly I say price
stack and then after the price stack
pitch at the end now here's a secret
that I got from Iman God's video that is
like the literal Gold Mine this one
trick made the vssl work and it made
like this vssl convert pretty well like
it it's been converting pretty well but
basically you just plug a client result
every minute or every two three minutes
these strategies are going to be S super
huge and they're going to help you do
this how do I know that boom client
result try and essentially plug a client
result after every Point that's the
secret cuz then at the end you can
basically say when you start pitching by
the way all of these people that I
mentioned they only were able to do it
because of this extra thing and the
extra thing is why I'm pitching you
because I wish I could be able to get
you to the end result by just this video
but I can't and the reason why I say
that is because of these people in my
program so it really does hinge on like
having some client results if you don't
have that one that you could probably
bandage is just like personal results or
friends that you've helped that just
helps you back your program in actual
truth as opposed to being like hey I
made this program to hypothetically help
you I'm explaining all these names
because the program is actually what
helped them not this video this video
was like step one of like five
realistically I'll be completely honest
with you if you were to just hop off
this video right now and were to say
goodbye I don't think this would work
because these guys had all of these
other things that helped them it's just
backed in truth specifically just proof
proof proof Pro proof and just
sprinkling in that every like couple
minutes that helps them stay in the loop
of like M there's other people not just
me other people not just me that's what
I noticed the Eman video like the Iman
godi vssl does that like I haven't
really seen any other vsls on YouTube
really do does that point straight to
just WAP to like the landing page to
like sign up and pay yeah so I even
specifically you can see this link has
like a little hashtag here and it's
because it like links to a section on
the page it's the same page I also made
this landing page super short I used to
have features on the page and I noticed
like I don't think it actually converts
better if you have a video explaining
how it works anyways it's like if your
video explains what the product does you
don't need it to be explained on the
page because then they're just going to
be like so how does this like 13 hours a
video guys and then you have like this
whole on your page like 13 video guyses
and they're like wait a minute video
guys I got I'm been buying a course like
oh like blah blah blah it kind of gives
people more hesitation because they just
have to read more and it's like
information overload and I realized that
like if people are just watching the
video first they don't need anything
else besides like I guess more client
testimonials boom those are on the page
and then just goes into pricing awesome
well I'm glad that was value any other
questions if vs SS for high ticket
onetoone coaching program should we lead
them to a page or book a call I would
book them to a call or I would send them
into like a type form that just has like
very basic qualify for this yes or no
kind of questions do you suggest making
it really long I was planning on making
a 5 to 10 vssl for for the longest time
on my content Academy like website I
just had it like a 10 minute vssl so
like you don't need to make it really
long this took like I said like 40 hours
it took me like 2 weeks to make this
this was super high effort and it was
also because I had like the minimum
viable vsls out for a really long time
and it's like you know it's about time I
like actually lock in and make this like
good so I don't have to remake it every
6 months editing these first 30 seconds
I also spent like maybe 4 hours editing
the first 30 seconds I kind of pretended
my first 60 seconds of this video was a
short form video and I like hyper not
hyper edited it but made it enough
editing where like every two seconds
something popped up and I'll just show
that too cuz I think that's worth
mentioning in making this video perform
better like I did this like 8020 where I
put like a lot more effort into editing
the first 60 seconds and then later on
you can see there's not as many visuals
on the screen but at the beginning this
is what it looked like in the past 12
months I've posted 259 videos started an
online business made
$260,000 from said online business
dropped out of college and moved to New
York City and during all of this time I
also Grew From 50,000 to 250,000
followers on Instagram now not saying
all that to brag oh I just want to show
you what's possible those two jokes of
the Rat and the oh hell no like I
genuinely think that might have like
increased My Views by like 25% this is
something that like my roommate Daniel
gave me feedback on like yo this
feels so salesy and I was like yo you're
right like it can't be a hidden vssl if
it sounds like a vssl and that's another
thing too is like I was studying like
Tech joice uh YouTube videos I was
studying like entertainment YouTube
videos I cannot make this feel salesy
and like obviously you're trying to
persuade somebody but at the same time
you can do that I think in like a non
like hey I'm Guru kind of way and for me
I think the a cool way of doing that was
throwing in jokes yeah I also F bro I
put books up bro no like this wasn't
intentional I put the books up there you
know do you have data on like how this
has converted since uh posting so prior
to this vssl uh because on the vssl I
specifically pitch also because it's a
longer vssl I was able to pitch a mid
tick price like it is actually want to
make this affordable for you so joining
the content Academy today is just 597
bucks for the the entire year I learned
this from my friend about uh price
dropping saying dollars sounds more
expensive than bucks it's a door to-
door sales trick pro my friend Prosper
told me that I was like whoa It's just
5.97 Bucks versus it is 1,000 so I said
normally they go for
$3,000 today I'm just going to do a $97
bucks I was reading the the entire pitch
section to like my friend prosper and he
gave me like so much feedback on like
everything that sounded really Terri
terrible and that was also helpful like
if you were to hop on a call with
somebody else and just like have them
roast your pitch which is the last 15
minutes of my video that helped me like
nail the tonality so I didn't feel too
salesy uh you give price in the vssl yes
all right back to your question about
like the data I never sold annual plans
prior to this vssl from my Instagram
page the only sales that would ever come
in were monthly nobody would ever have
committed to annual right because
obviously it's like they on a landing
page for 5 minutes and they're coming
from short form how can they really tell
that this is valuable of course not so
they're going to do the lowest
commitment like possible but this was
able to now consistently convert prior
it was probably one annual plan one per
month at most maybe it's like one every
two months annual planwise the rest of
the memberships would be $97 a month now
we convert maybe like one annual plan
every like two to 3 days so that number
of annual plans has bumped up
significantly it's the high ticket trust
like you're able to convey the trust in
this one video yeah and that I think it
only happens is because this is
basically like a you know a pre-recorded
webinar because I'm with them for an
entire like 30 minutes I'm just sitting
down and breaking down every possible
limiting belief as opposed to just maybe
a couple I believe this is just going to
get more and more saturated as this
method becomes more known and I think
it's like lowkey still a little bit
untapped right now let me know if you
guys end up building the vssl like I
genuinely I'm passionate about this cuz
I think it's like it's super untapped
and I think it's super op