if you want to start posting content but
you're afraid people are going to judge
you and talk [ __ ] about you don't worry
they will they're going to start sting
your video into group chats saying look
how cringe and try hard this motherucker
is your worst anxieties of what they're
probably thinking and saying about you
are true and I know this because when I
started posting content on Instagram
that's precisely what happened to me I
saw a text conversation basically saying
yo what are your thoughts on mino's new
content dude it's cringe bro it's pretty
[ __ ] cringe like high school friends
right in fact some of them I still keep
in touch with today and all I can tell
you this corny advice oh it's cringe
until it works out because I stand here
at this point where it has worked out
for me after now posting onto Instagram
over 400 videos across the past 3 years
I've grown a following of now 300,000
followers and I run a business purely
through Instagram that gets me anywhere
between $30,000 to $50,000 every single
month you probably hear a lot of these
success stories online because that's
naturally what Garners attention it's
what gets people to finally listen and
be like yo maybe this content thing is
worth it cuz I can make a lot of money
and that's not what's going to help you
actually reach success because I want to
walk you through the process the brutal
grueling first 6 months of posting
content and absolutely eliminate any
fears and misconceptions that you're
going to have in this video because when
I first started posting 3 years ago I
also had no clue what I was doing and I
was like dude I just want to like
Inspire other people bro I posted this C
ass stuff I wasn't even posting videos I
was just posting like picture posts and
it was basically me saying either here's
how to get locked in or I was saying hey
guys I relapsed in my bad habits I watch
porn I stopped going to the gym this
month and I'm really disappointed and
ashamed of myself and it was a slow
grind process here's a picture of me
celebrating getting my first 969
followers nice so the first most
fundamental truth that you need to
understand if you actually want to get
past those first 6 months of posting
content get past that major hump and
reach your first 10,000 followers where
you actually have a true fan base is
that you have to stop thinking so
logically about it because your
anxieties of posting content online are
actually very valid your videos are
going to suck at the beginning they are
going to be cringe they aren't going to
be making you any money you're just
going to be posting content into The
Ether going in blind hoping and
wondering when is my blowup Point
finally going to happen and it might
happen on week three it could also
happen on week 10 of posting building
that self-confidence in yourself where
you can genuinely stand in a room and
get laughed at and get tomatoes thrown
at you is a skill and you have to build
that up through months and months of
practice and EXP Ure therapy to
rejection so in order to build that
internal armor to rejection the first
idea that I need you to understand is
that today is actually the perfect time
to start posting content because every
excuse about your current lifestyle
right now not being a good fit for
posting content is a lie and it's a cope
to make up for the fact that your main
bottleneck is actually your content
skill set whenever I have a friend or a
client come up to me saying yo Mino I
like how you started posting content 3
years ago how do I get started the
conversation after I give them a bunch
of tactical strategy they're like okay
yeah I'm going to start after my next
midterm I'll start in the summer once I
start having more time and then that's
when I posting my first video and I have
like 10 ideas written down but I'm just
going to start posting in the summer and
the reason why it's so dumb is because I
blew up in my content during the busiest
period of my life during my college
midterms it's actually funny my most
viral content series on Instagram and
Tik Tok that's gotten over 30 million
views across both platforms is me
talking about how I studied for my
midterms and my finals in fact that
video series also because of Tik tok's
creativity programs probably made me an
extra like $6,000 too and gotten me like
50,000 to 100,000 followers across Tik
Tok and Instagram so if you are the type
of person that always tells himself hey
I'm going to start posting content after
I get just past this one thing that I'm
dealing with right now you are lying to
yourself like a child who constantly
tells himself I'm going to start trying
really hard in school and studying for
my tests tomorrow after I finish this
game of fortnite or an adult who tells
them yo I'm going to finally lock in on
my diet and become really shredded and
fit but next week after I go to this
party this weekend and get blackout
drunk It's procrastinating disguised as
this intelligent excuse of strategy I've
literally had a student in my program
start literally with just five videos
posted he was 15 years old when he
joined our program content Academy and
he started off with less than a th000
followers and now has over 150,000
followers across Tik Tok and Instagram
posting every single day in high school
one of my closest friends Prosper
started posting on Instagram while he
was working 12 hours a day knocking the
doors and we actually had a conversation
right before he started that job saying
hey Mina I want to start creating
content but I don't know if right now is
the perfect time because I have all of
this busy stuff you you think I should
just delay until I like finish the job
in 3 months and I said no right now is
the perfect time to start because the
busier you are the more interesting
things you have to film about your day
so he started that summer with 3,000
followers and he got through the summer
of posting by using a minimum viable
video strategy that's actually what I
talk about in the first video in the
description but it's basically having
the most short possible workflow to
create a video and using that system
every single day so you just simply stay
consistent with posting to grind through
that process of starting and he ended
that summer after knocking a do 12 hours
every single day selling pest control
with 30,000 followers on Instagram in
fact now because he's built that skill
set of content and he grinded through it
in the summer now he has over 120,000
followers on Instagram
about a year later after he started all
that to say don't wait for the perfect
time because the perfect time to start
is right now the perfect time AKA to
start building your skill set of content
creation which is the most important
thing not what life circumstance you're
in right now is today because yes you
either 6 months from now might have a
more interesting life or conversely you
might have a less busy life and you have
more time to post content it's not going
to change this part of your brain that
is so used to telling themsel hey let's
just start when it's a little bit more
comfortable tomorrow or next week it's a
part of your brain that lies to yourself
thinking that it's actually a strategic
decision and if you've kept up that lie
for longer than a couple months it
realistically has become like an
ingrained truth that you actually
believe that you actually believe that
you will be better at posting content if
you didn't have this if you didn't have
a more busy schedule if you didn't have
a less interesting life it's not true
because you're going to build an
interesting life too once you start
posting content posting content too has
opened up every single possible door in
my life I found my roommates I found
every single one of the team members
that I now work with in my business I
found a business partner through my
personal brand and yes I've made over
$400,000 in my business in the past year
all of these doors open with the skill
set so start building that skill set
today and stop putting it off and if you
want practical advice on how to start
building that skill set watch that first
video in the description down below bye