14 months ago, I was your average broke
college kid. I was watching all the how
to make money online videos on YouTube.
So, I was sold this lie of making
boatloads of money online. So, being
really naive, I took the one skill I
knew how to do really well, which was
growing Tik Tok accounts and I started
selling courses on slapped together a
4-hour video course, put that [ __ ] on
WP, and then started selling it through
my Instagram reels. And 47 days into
starting this business, we made our
first $10,000. But we got stuck there
for a little while. But fast forward to
today, after 413 days of running this
business, we have made
$491,000 total. But in order to scale my
course business from being stuck under
$10,000 a month to eventually hitting
$100,000 in a single month, there were
three key pillars that I had to
implement to make my course business
actually successful. And they're not
what you think. Cuz if you're either
running your own info business or you're
thinking of starting your own sort of
course program or coaching online, do
not follow advice that you've seen more
than 6 months ago. because the meta is
shifting. And I'll tell you right now,
as somebody who's actually succeeded in
the last year at Info, my business only
started growing when I basically pivoted
my business away from selling courses
and focused way harder on the three
pillars that I want to explain to you in
the next 10 minutes. These three pillars
are the pillars of an actual successful
legit info business. And I'm going to
teach you what these three pillars are
and how to implement them into your
business. Whether you're just starting
out your own course, coaching or
community, or you've been running it for
a while, you just feel stuck. You can't
get it to grow. You're plateauing around
10 5K a month. This is how I broke those
plateaus and it just kept scaling. And
it was not by going more viral. It was
not by running ads. I've never spent a
single penny on ads. And it has
everything to do with what you're
selling because most people think you
can just slap together a course and make
a ton of money on it. And that worked
maybe like 2 years ago. That doesn't
work today because with AI and YouTube,
information is a worthless commodity
now. If anything, just selling
information with this video course that
you can slap together in like 2 weeks
and then now you can start printing
money off of that is the easiest way to
get labeled as a scammer by your
audience and everybody who sees you
online. And as somebody who's been
studying all of the big info creators
who've crushed it in the course business
space like Joel Kaplan, Charlie Morgan,
Ian Godzi, these big names who have all
made over a million dollars a month with
info. They're either releasing their
entire course fully to YouTube, their 10
20our course, or they're just shutting
down their course business entirely
right now. Why do you think they're
doing that? If course businesses are
dead, they're useless and worthless,
what do you actually need to sell if you
want to succeed in info in 2025? Well,
let me show you. These are the three
pillars that you need to care about if
you are actually running or starting
your own info business and you actually
want to make it work as a community
business. So, notice how I made this
emphasis on community as opposed to
courses. Okay, so let's start off with
pillar number one, which is recurring
revenue. I have this little screenshot
of my MR. Now, why is this so much lower
than the amount of money that I've made?
Well, MR stands for monthly recurring
revenue, and that literally means this
amount is sent into my bank account
every single month, and that's what
makes a business actually possible to
run, especially an info business. This
is between April 2024 and April of 2025.
So, in the last 12 months, it has
increased steadily. Obviously, there's
some hiccups as opposed to a lot of
course businesses or a lot of info
businesses might do this where they're
going to start off here and then
suddenly they go whoop and then 2 months
later, boom, down. You want to avoid
this situation. And why does this stark
drop off happen? Well, it's because a
lot of people are optimizing just to
make a shitload of cash upfront and
they're like, "Yo, we're just going to
sell everybody. All you have to do is
pay one time." And they're optimizing
for the sale. They're optimizing just to
get people into the door and pay them
like two bands, three bands for their
course. And then what happens is that
boom, all the shitty reviews happen.
People don't actually get results. You
don't even care about them getting
results cuz you just made so much cash.
You just made so much dopamine for
literally doing no work of actually
helping people. So obviously your
business is not going to operate in the
spirit of like actually being valuable
to people. In a recurring revenue
business model, you're actually
incentivized to get people results
because if at any point all of these
customers, if they don't get results,
they're all leaving next month. The
reason why this keeps going up is
because a lot of the members are staying
because they're actually getting
results. It's what genuinely makes my
entire business possible. It's what
allows me to pay now $8 to $10,000 a
month to my team with all of my other
expenses. That is only possible to
genuinely run a real business if you
have recurring revenue coming in and
you're not just scraping and scratching
and trying to fight for the next sale
every single month. And I want to
actually quote Jeff Bezos here because a
lot of you might be taking advice from
like the wrong business gurus out there.
If everything you do needs to work on a
three-year time horizon, right? And in
info we can even short that down to like
3 month time horizon, then you're
competing against a lot of people cuz a
lot of people are just money hungry and
they're just trying to get as much money
upfront right here as possible. They're
not worried about the long-term time
horizon of like what what does month 11,
month 12 look like. If you're willing to
invest on a seven-year time horizon,
you're now competing against a fraction
of those people because very few
companies or really just entrepreneurs,
creators are actually willing to think
on a long-term time horizon with their
community business. So, what does this
actually mean? You want to get rewarded
monetarily for getting people results.
That's why you want people to
continuously pay you every month because
it's a sign that if they're not paying
you the next month, your stuff didn't
work and they didn't like working with
you. And churn, which stands for
basically the percent of people that
leave every single month from your
community. This is your biggest
determinant on whether your product
actually works. So you can see here when
I first started my community, I didn't
know what I was doing. And that's why
I'm so passionate about this concept
because when I first started, as I
started running the business up, I
realized, oh my goodness, people are
leaving like crazy. I peaked at 44%
turn. This was around April of 2024. So
about 1 to 2 months into my business
running for every month, I need to get
44 new people for every 100 just to make
the community stay at the same level of
MR. That's awful. You're constantly just
going to be on this hamster wheel trying
to find new customers every single
month. if your churn is this high. So, I
started introducing coaching calls and
you can see there's a constant battle.
There's constantly ups and downs. It's
kind of like a stock. But eventually,
you can see over time we get this
general downtrend and now we're here at
around 21%. We've hit lows of like 18%.
Look how much of a stark difference it
went from 44% to 21%. That is the reason
why my business has continued to grow
and has not operated like any other one
of those shitty scam online course
businesses that make a ton of money in
like month one and two and then
completely crash and burn on month 3,
four or five. Stop thinking about the
one month time horizon. Stop thinking
about how much money you're making this
month, how many sales you've generated
this month. Think about how you're going
to create a product that lasts a year.
If you are just a pure sales and
marketing optimized human being, that
makes you a grifter because you don't
actually care about the promise that
you're making and fulfilling on that
promise to your customers. Number two,
and that's reduced price. When you're
actually starting off your product, it's
not going to be that good. Always
undercharge. A lot of people like to
just like rack up their prices for their
courses and communities. Like, yo, I'm
going to sell my course for like $1,000
because that person over there sells
their course for $1,000. Like, no. A lot
of people get this massive mistake about
pricing where they just need to make as
much money as possible upfront. So, I
want to break down an actual pricing
strategy here that worked for me and
this is the way that I have increased my
price over time. So, when I first
started my like community/coaching, I
actually charged $597 a month. It was
this like kind of onetoone coaching
where I kind of texted them onetoone,
but I wasn't like always texting them
onetoone. So, it was this like group
coaching program that I charge $597 a
month for. And yo, we ran up 10K a month
for one month and then 90% of the
clients left. So, we literally went from
like 12 clients to like two on month
two. Ask yourself realistically, how
much would you genuinely pay for this
right now? And be honest with yourself
cuz a lot of people like to lie and be
like, "Oh, I think I would pay like
$2,000 for my product." Well, would you
pay for it right now? Like if somebody
came up to you with your product, be
like, "Hey, here it is. Pay me 2K."
You'd be like, "No, I'd probably pay
like 50 bucks for my own thing." And
that was the birth of my pricing
strategy of like, yeah, you know what?
Let's actually charge way less because
people are clearly hating that pricing
point. And I just charged $49 a month
when I first launched my product,
Content Academy, back in February of
2024. It was essentially like a relaunch
of the failed version earlier where I
just cut the price by 10x. And my churn,
you'll notice it was still high. It was
still 40%. That's really high. You want
to ideally get down to like 20% churn.
That's when I realized, okay, there's a
decent amount of people who like it. So,
it's not an absolute dud of a product
like this one was. It was decent. It had
some stickiness, but 40% sure is way too
high. And that's where it gives you the
space to have customers to continuously
serve. So, it doesn't feel like you're
just shooting in the dark by having
literally one or two customers every
month. And it allows you the space to
improve your product. That is the goal
when you are first starting your
community. Okay? Stop thinking so much
about how you're going to make so much
money this month. You're going to start
printing and start like living in Miami,
get a penthouse, start renting out a
Lambo. Dude, just focus on making your
product good. And the way you focus on
making your product good is by
undercharging than just focusing on
shirt. This is going to be literally the
best mentor you could pay for a business
mentor for 10 bands, 15 bands. Or you
could literally just charge really low
and see what people actually respond to.
See what the market responds to and
improve it around their feedback. And
that's when you finally are like, "Okay,
now that I've improved the product,
let's finally increase the price
incrementally." only increase the price
when you actually feel like you've got a
little bit of a hold on churn. So, I
increased the price to $59 a month right
when my churn started to go down. I was
like, "Okay, now that I actually feel
like I have a grasp on churn, I'm giving
them these coaching calls. I'm improving
the community after that." The only
reason why I kept increasing the price
was because I actually had to hire more
people because I wanted to make the
product better. If you're just
increasing the price because he he
increased the price over there and she
increased the price of their program,
like you're just following the blind
leading the blind. So, I want to go into
reasons why you should increase the
price and reasons when you should not.
Okay? So, when you actually do want to
increase the price, it's when you have
too many lowquality members, when you're
realizing, okay, a lot of the members
that I have right now in my program, for
example, are just too broke or they're
too young, okay? And they don't have
enough sophistication or experience.
Like for me, I want to work with
creators who actually have something
going on in their life that they can
create content about that they can talk
about. Maybe they have a domain of
expertise. So I generally like to work
with like 20some year girls but if my
price is too low I'll attract a lot of
like teenagers. Okay. So that's when you
want to actually increase the price. The
second one is when you actually are
onboarding a greater team or you're
onboarding more expenses because you
want to make your product better. Don't
just increase the price cuz you think
it'll make you more money. And then
lastly, if you're if your churn is above
30%, bro, don't even think about
increasing your price, bro. You got
other work to do. If you're selling a
$50 a month community and your churn is
like 45% like 45% of your members are
leaving every month, buddy. Oh my
goodness. Raising your price is the
least of your concerns, bro. People are
clearly not finding enough value at $50
a month. What What makes you think
people are going to like stay in your
community at a higher price point? So
once you have a lower like sub 30%
churn, that's when you should actually
start thinking about increasing your
price cuz that's how you know your
product works and that's how you know
maybe you actually are just charging a
little bit less than you can for the
value. What if your turn is above 30%
buddy? Like your your program's actually
overpriced right now. People aren't
liking it. When to not increase your
price, then one, you see someone else
charging higher. You're just like, "Oh,
that person is doing the same kind of
community I'm doing, but they're
charging $75 a month and I'm charging
$40 a month. Like, I should probably
match their price so I don't get like
out competed." Like, secondly, your
business has existed for less than 60
days. Don't even think about increasing
your price. Okay? For the first 60 days,
just focus on making your product
better. In the first 30 days, your churn
is realistically going to be like zero
because you don't know how many people
are actually staying because it's only
been 1 month. But around 60 days in is
when you actually learn what your churn
is. That's when you can actually start
making decisions of like, is my churn
above 30%, maybe I should increase my
price right now. If your churn is below
30% by that point, okay, product is
good, it works, people are loving it,
let's actually start scaling this now
and making more money from it. Like to
really really hammer this home, this is
like the complete playbook from day one
to like for me day 365. First is just
launch your product for insanely cheap.
Always undercharge at the start cuz
that's how you're just there to collect
data. You're just there to learn from
your customers. Stop having the scarce
mindset of, "Oh my goodness, I need to
make so much money up front because I
don't know how long this thing is going
to last." Start by undercharging like
charging to the point where you're like,
"How am I even charging this little?"
That's how you should feel. And keep it
at the price for 30 days. If your churn
is above 30% after 60 days, do not do
not increase your price. Then increase
the price incrementally. I'm talking
like by plus 10 or plus $20 and hire
help during this time. First, if you're
running this kind of course or coaching
or community business, hire a coach.
Hire another coach, ideally one of your
students or one of your like peers who
knows this stuff well. And then hire a
community manager. A community manager
just makes sure your Discord server is
running in order. They're active. They
make sure members are like having a good
time. They answer any questions that go
unanswered by you because you're focused
on doing the other parts of the business
and you're focused on making content.
And then allow your previous members to
keep their old price. So, we have we
literally have customers who are still
paying $49 a month. Now, later on, maybe
this is about like month six, you can
start moving to annual pricing. Make it
50% off your like monthly plan. It's
basically annual equals your monthly
price time 6. So for us, right, our
monthly price is $97 a month. 97 * 6 is
around like
59 something, right? I'm I'm not going
to do math here. I suck at math. But
like we charge $5.97 for a monthly or
for our annual, we charge 97 for
monthly. When you move to annual, you do
need a good VSSL and webinar. And then
lastly, if you do want to actually
hypers scale, like this is how we hit
100K in a month. When I hit 100K in one
month, we made $65,000 from high ticket
and just 35,000 for the low ticket
community. So, your low ticket is a
great mechanism to build up goodwill and
build up trust. So, eventually when you
do launch a high ticket program, people
are just like, "Yep, I'm bought in,
dude. Get take my money." You don't need
to go through this complex sales
process. You can literally just close
them on like a 15-minute call being
like, "Hey, here's what the program is."
They're like, "Done, sold. I trust you.
I literally got so much value for 50
bucks a month. Here's here's three
bands." And that's how he ran up 100K in
one month. Okay, so that's the power of
goodwill. Your community isn't just how
much money you're making right now. Your
community is also an asset for the
future. In fact, we're also working on
getting sponsors for a community right
now. Now, lastly, okay, we've talked
about pricing. We talked about how you
need to shift to a recurring revenue
model and don't just sell upfront costs
for a course. Lastly, how do you
actually get customers? Now, let's
actually talk about marketing and sales.
This is like my marketing and sales gold
mine and it's relatable content. So, a
lot of people think to market your
courses, you need to be flexing online.
And if you act like a tool online, your
customers will be even bigger tools.
I've seen this in coaching programs
where the coaching programs are flooded
and the communities are flooded with
just young kids who probably just want
to make money because they saw some like
brain rot content like this or they're
just like really low sophistication.
Like, I'm going to be honest, to succeed
in content creation, for example, for my
community, I don't want like a
12-year-old who has zero life
experience. I want to work with like a
22-year-old who has had decent life
experience, they probably went through
some stories that they can tell online.
Try to actually attract intelligent
human beings. And the reason why that's
important, okay, is because if they're
actually smart customers, they're going
to get results faster. They're going to
succeed. And if they're succeeding, that
means they're actually going to stay and
keep paying you cuz your program
actually worked. And lastly, if your
program worked, you're also going to get
better reviews long term. Because while
everybody else online was flexing to try
and sell their course, to sell their
program, I instead made really relatable
content about just like how sad I am as
a business owner some days or like how I
like feeling ungrateful some days. These
are the videos that perform the best.
But not only that, they actually made me
a good amount of money because when you
actually make content that's a little
bit higher sophistication, that's
relatable as opposed to just flexing.
Think about the kind of consumer that's
consuming like a video about Miami pen
houses and Rolexes. Like they're
probably not the type of person you want
to hop on calls with every week, right?
So, I'll show you the type of person
that I actually work with. This is just
a screenshot from one of my coaching
calls from my inner circle. You can see
like we have really high quality people.
Th this is literally a screenshot of
coach call. Here's me, a 21-year-old who
in theory a 21-year-old should not be
able to attract really highle people. I
am actually the young person in my call
in this entire call. How am I able to do
this? How am I able to attract highle
clients that actually want to pay me? We
have a cookie business owner who's been
posting daily. He's super consistent.
He's so fun to work with cuz he actually
cares. He's smart. Another one startup
founder who started in our program at
like 30,000 followers. He grew to
100,000 followers. I could take credit
for all that, but also he was just a
smart individual. Here's another
creator. My friend actually grew to
200,000 followers in a year. SAS startup
founder, 19,000 followers. He makes day
trading content. 20,000 followers,
right? He started off less than a
thousand and he makes $30,000 a month
with his agency. These are like smart
people and honestly, I just enjoy
hopping on calls with them. If you hate
the people in your community, bro, like
if you subconsciously just like dread
hopping on calls with them, how do you
expect to last long as a business owner?
Business is like serving people. That's
how you get people to actually pay you
consistently is when you actually serve
them and you provide them value. And if
you don't enjoy working with them, how
do you expect to not burn out? is just
brand yourself as the Harvard of
communities, not like the community
college of communities. Like no shades
community colleges, but like you want to
be like a highle education business
instead of just a shitty scammy course.
Actually focus on attracting highlevel
customers. That's what you do in your
content. It's the way you signal out
there to the internet. It becomes so
much easier to get results when you have
smart students and customers stay and
keep paying you. Your retention goes up,
your turn goes down because they get
results. And me being sad and relatable
actually has led to like me making super
high level connections because I've been
able to make just content that's
relatable and not just content that
flexes on beginners, but content also
tailored for just like people like me.
And lastly, to finish off this video,
just start posting. Don't overthink
looking dumb, weak, emotional, and
unprofessional. Because if you're so
focused on your perception online,
you're probably just going to compensate
and pretend to be way smarter and way
cooler than you are. As a result of that
compensation, people are going to sniff
out your BS. People going to sniff out
how lame you are, and you're just going
to like attract worse quality customers.
This video is getting long, so if you
want more helpful resources, I have a
60-minute class in the first link in the
description teaching how to make your
first digital product. The second link
in the description is just my other
YouTube video if you want to watch it.
It's a 30-minute guide on how to create
viral content. It's how I grew 200,000
followers in one year on Instagram. So,
those are some helpful resources. I
highly recommend you watch those videos
because they're going to save you so
much time when it comes to creating your
digital product or info business and
also just growing on Instagram and Tik
Tok so you can actually attract
customers and attract the right
customers. Thank you guys for watching.