In the past 15 months, I've grown from
50,000 followers to 350,000 followers on
Instagram. I have had countless viral
videos, as in videos above a million
views. But what I realized throughout
this entire process is that storytelling
is way too over complicated on the
internet. All these social media gurus
will tell you storytelling is the key to
going viral in 2025. They don't know
whating storytelling is, and it's so
frustrating. So, I have made the
executive decision to put every single
one of those scammy Tik Tok gurus out of
business and tell you the actual proven
framework to get a million views
guaranteed on your next Tik Tok or
Instagram reel. And this is the exact
framework that I use to get 2 million
views plus on all of these videos on
Instagram reels and Tik Tok. That's the
same format that I just spammed in the
past 15 months to grow from 50K to 350K
on IG. And yes, of course, I have three
different Tik Tok accounts with over
100,000 followers. And also, this works
for also building like an actual devoted
audience that wants to buy stuff from
you. Because the thing about this
storytelling framework that actually
works is that people actually get
invested in you and they start trusting
you, which is important for you actually
growing a business or just monetizing in
general. My business in the past 15
months has made
$525,000. Let's get into the actual
bread and butter of the storytelling
framework. And it's a five-stage
framework. If you know anything about
Tik Tok videos, the most important stage
is the first one. It's the hook. And
very specifically, you want to use a
relatable pain hook when you start off
your Tik Toks or Instagram reels to
really capture somebody's attention.
Stop their scroll, open an emotional
loop, and make the viewer feel
genuinely, viscerally that wait, this
video is about me. So, first use a
universal belief, fear, or shame thought
and try to use the word you. It's
actually really simple. And then lastly,
try to keep your hook under 15 words.
Make sure you say them within the first
1.5 seconds, which means you have to
talk fast, especially at the beginning
of the video. You want to fit as much
information into that first sentence as
possible, into the first 2 seconds as
possible, or else somebody will just not
feel stimulated enough to keep watching
your video, frankly. Okay, so what are
some hook templates that I have
literally spammed to get over a million
views on my videos? I don't know who
needs to hear this, but blank. I don't
know who needs to hear this, but the
idea that you can change your life by
simply working harder is [ __ ]
Here's why you still bad thing. Here's
why november is actually good for you.
Now, I know you're probably thinking,
notice a pattern here in blue, and it's
simply that it has the word you or in
this case, sometimes it will say who or
we or us. And the reason why this
wording specifically matters so much is
because a lot of times people think
storytelling means me me. Hey guys, this
is a story about me. The goal is to tell
a story that makes the viewer feel
understood and heard by whatever video
they're seeing. You want to use the word
you and be as embarrassingly specific as
possible with this hook. Secondly is the
backstory or setup. Now, this is really
important and this is where the actual
storytelling component comes into play
because a lot of people think that
storytelling happens on sentence one. I
actually don't think so. The hook needs
to be in sentence one to actually
capture your viewers's attention.
Storytelling starts on stage two in the
second sentence, which I like to call
the backstory or the setup more
specifically. And it's two to four short
sentences. One year ago, I promised my
mom I hit this crazy goal. She let me
drop out and pursue my dream of content
creation. This is the odd pattern that
has just repeatedly happened in all of
my scripts that have done well. And the
reason why you want to have two to four
short sentences is because the story
will progress quicker and especially in
the first 10 seconds of video. Now, you
still have to be very respectful of the
viewer's time. And if the viewer feels
like you're just wasting your time
dragging on and on about the story, then
they're just not going to want to watch.
You're competing on the explore page and
the for you page with a slot machine of
dopamine ridden brain rot videos of tomb
to tum sahur or brain rot memes that
literally switch the screen and the
visual on the screen every 2 seconds.
And always always try to inject specific
language into every one of these
backstory sentences. Always try to use a
location, age, or exact number. A lot of
times when I work with private clients
or creators who just want to improve
their views, they'll say wordings like,
"I used to believe that hard work was
important to success." Now, that sounds
like a pretty relatable sentence what I
just said, right? Why wouldn't we use
that in a video? And the problem with
using a sentence like that in the video
is because I used to is such a vague
terminology that a viewer can't actually
picture in their head. Instead, use
wording like 6 months ago. 2 years ago,
I was doing homework when I There we go.
Now we have a story. We have a visually
imaginable situation in the viewer's
mind. I have used this framework to get
millions and millions of views. And it
really is this simple. You don't need to
play stupid gimmicks. Just understand
the like bare fundamentals of what
actually drives human attention, which
is creating immersive video experiences
on short form video. Make the viewer
feel like they are actually there with
you. You have won. You've got their
attention. Now, that being said though,
once you've got your viewers attention
past the first 10 seconds or the first
five sentences of your video, what's
stage three? Stage three is crucial and
it's the breaking point in your story.
This is where real storytelling comes
into play. The purpose of stage three,
the breaking point, which is just one to
two sentences. It's a nice transition
from the backstory element of your
story. What was the breaking point? What
was the turning point? The moment
specifically that changed everything.
This is actually a really difficult
concept for 99% of creators to
understand. A breaking point is a single
moment. Like this moment literally
should have been described as if it
lasted like 5 seconds. That's how much
you want to zoom in onto an event when
you storytell because that's how you
make a viewer feel like they were
actually there. What's an example of
describing your breaking point in a
moment in one singular moment as opposed
to a long drawn process? Instead of
saying, "I started to realize," maybe
you'll say, "I was scrolling through my
Instagram reels and I saw this one video
of this one Asian dude who told me that
in that moment everything clicked." Try
and find the moments in your story, in
whatever process that you're describing,
where you actually did have a pretty
interesting moment. Maybe it was
watching a YouTube video, maybe it was a
conversation with a friend. really zoom
into that moment and don't disregard it
because the art of good storytelling is
zooming into moments and bringing your
viewer and your listener there with you.
Here are some templates for those kind
of breaking point languages. But nothing
ever changed until one day or I was
scrolling through my Instagram reels or
I was driving when he told me this crazy
line. And you want to really accentuate
how epic this moment was. this line that
your friend told you was insane. That
one line that your ex-girlfriend told
you on the phone shattered your heart.
Maybe you didn't give a [ __ ] in the
moment, okay? Like, actually create
drama out of that moment because that's
how you're going to make your viewer
feel like they actually got an insane
payoff and they still want to watch the
rest of the video. So, make sure to zoom
into your breaking point, describe it in
one moment that happened literally like
second by second and then dramaticize
it. Stage four out of five is the
takeaway. Now, this is the part that
you're probably already good at, which
is being preachy. If you make any kind
of like how-to videos, tutorial videos,
advice videos, where you want to be some
kind of thought leader and influencer in
your space, you're probably very used to
being very preachy, frankly, to your
audience member cuz you want to, you
know, teach them how to do this specific
workout, teach them this specific diet
plan. Maybe you want to attract fitness
coaching clients. So, what are some
rules for making a very satisfying
takeaway that makes your viewer feel
heard as opposed to hating you and
thinking that you're some cocky prick
guru preacher? Something I like to do is
actually inject a self-deprecating joke
to break this kind of guru tone. And
I'll describe like these weird speaking
mannerisms at the end of the video that
help you develop like a more authentic
voice on camera. give the ex actual
result that you saw in your life after
you applied this wisdom as well because
now that grounds your story in this
applicable result that your viewer will
actually get once they apply it. So
instead of just being like once I
actually locked in and became productive
I felt a lot better about myself. Eh
weak takeaway I don't really know what
that looks like when you feel better
about yourself. Well, what if I said
after I locked in, that's when I
actually was able to grow my business
from being stuck at 10K a month to 100K
a month. Doesn't that have so much more
weight now that I've literally told you
this piece of advice led to this
tangible result? That is the best place
to insert your social proof and to be
like, "Yeah, viewer, this can be you,
too." And I'm going to guess if you're
still watching this video, you actually
care about changing people's lives. This
actually works. People have DM'd me so
many times, yo, your content has
motivated me to start posting on Tik
Tok, to start posting on Instagram, to
start chasing after my dreams while I'm
a college student. And I would just
rinse and repeat the same exact
fivestage story structure. So, here are
some templates that are literally taken
straight from my own videos. The truth
is, shame doesn't make you more
disciplined. It just makes you hate the
prog process. These kind of oneliners
you should not put in the beginning of
your video because if you put it in the
beginning of your video it just sounds
really corny and preachy and that makes
them a lot more inclined to scroll.
Stage five is a CTA and it's basically
where you give your audience member an
ask. Every single time I work with
clients in my community they'll ask me
how do I get more followers? How do I
get my viewers to follow more? And
they'll be at like 10,000 views or 5,000
views on a video. And I'm just like dude
that's not your bottleneck here. I've
almost never asked people to follow me
or subscribe to me. Okay. people just
do. If they like you and they got value
from you, they will just do it. What
does however work is just using an
actual interesting framework of
storytelling that gets people to watch
your video that racks up watch time,
that racks up engagement, and thus just
pushes your video out to instead just
like a measly 5,000 viewers. Wouldn't
you rather have gotten 5 million views?
I know you probably have these limiting
beliefs like, "Oh, but I've never gone
viral before." Trust me, if you actually
apply this framework, like you can
genuinely repeatedly go viral.
Obviously, there are more components
like editing and filming. And I will
walk you through exactly what you can do
to actually improve those things and
what my own students do. I literally
edit all my videos on Cap Cut, by the
way. So, yeah, it's like not complicated
whatsoever. But yeah, don't worry so
much about the CTA is my main point. You
do want to make it sound natural and not
pitchy. Try to build your CTA or aka
your last sentence or your ask on
whatever your last sentence prior was.
So usually that means using a
conjunction like but and or so. So
comment monk mode if this is where
you're at. So there's a lot of also
subtle ways to ask for a follow without
actually asking them for a follow. So
you're not just asking please follow,
please follow, please follow. You might
be saying yo if you actually want to
lock in on your fitness goals this year,
I'm going to make a video about it
tomorrow so follow. Now it actually
feels earned because I'm giving you
something. if you follow as opposed to
just asking, asking, asking. That being
said, now I do want to cover something
really quickly before I go into some
other weird stuff that I personally do
to make my content sound authentic. This
is low-key like the most banger sauce in
this video. I do want to tell you if you
are interested in actually accelerating
your content growth 5x, you actually
want to have a community of people who
keep you accountable to posting on Tik
Tok and Instagram and growing and
growing your business as well alongside
your personal brand. learning from way
more lessons like this, like 10 plus
hours of video tutorials, live coaching
calls five times a week with me
literally reviewing your videos live in
front of you and other creator experts
with 100,000 plus followers or people
making 10K a month with content creation
and social media live coaching calls
five times a week and 10 plus hours of
video tutorials in my private creator
community, content academy. And if you
want to join, it will be in the first
link in the description. Also, we also
have like a popping community of
creators, like four inerson events every
single year in New York City. In Austin,
Texas, we just did one. It was super
lit. And there's creators who pull up to
these with literally hundreds of
thousands of followers. There's like
multiple people in here who make more
than 100K a month who just pull up to
this New York City meet up. It's crazy.
Like, we we cultivate such a crazy
community of creators. And also,
accountability is hard. Staying
consistent with content creation is
hard. We created also a gamified
Instagram reels tracker that rewards you
for posting and staying accountable.
still literally connects to your
Instagram, tracks your content progress,
right? And then also has missions and
gives you coins that then can be spent
on literal like actual items like one
year free of Stan's creator plan that's
worth like $1,200. Also, this like
hoodie that I'm wearing right now. It's
pretty lit. And some other like content
creator goodies, right? Just to make it
more fun for you to create content
because obviously script templates,
coaching calls, improving your content
optimization, that's important. But if
you don't even post and if you don't
even feel comfortable posting and
getting in front of your like camera and
just pressing record, pressing post,
nothing matters. So, we really want to
just make it fun for you to get
comfortable on camera. That being said,
okay, what are some other weird things
that I personally do to make my content
sound authentic and actually use these
specific tonalities? So, this is a
little bit more esoteric because it's
not just about like word for word what
you're scripting on your piece of paper,
but it's how you're saying it, which is
actually more important, right? Imagine
if I sounded really like boring and
monotonous during this entire YouTube
video. I'd probably sound kind of like
scary and scammy if I was just like,
"Use these tones." Best friend rant
tone, raw, slightly messy, no fake
polish. pretend your friend is literally
in front of you. Like, you know, it
sounds weird and obviously that's an
exaggeration, but like watch yourself on
videos. Notice that you might actually
just feel a little bit stiff on camera,
which is normal to start. And the way to
alleviate that kind of stiffness of
feeling like you don't sound like
yourself on camera is don't picture it's
a camera. Don't picture like a hundred
people watching you on social media
because that's going to mess with your
brain. That's going to make you feel
socially anxious. Instead, just picture
one person, one friend that is literally
in front of you. And that is the kind of
concept of picturing an ideal viewer or
ideal client persona, which is basically
the one person that you actually want to
serve with your content, with your
business, and the problems that you
actually want to solve for them. Okay?
So, picturing that one person helps me
so so much in actually sounding
authentic on camera. Because if I wasn't
picturing my friend with this video
right now, I'd probably get in my head
and be like, "Wait, what if what if my
girlfriend sees this?" Oh, wait, no, but
what if my mom sees this video? Wait,
like what if my girlfriend's mom sees
this video? Like, how do I even
communicate and sound like normal to
her? She probably thinks I'm really
weird and I cursed in this video. Like,
you don't want to have these kind of
overthinking moments that just mess with
your presence on camera. You want to
feel natural. You want to feel
charismatic. And the way to tap into
that is by picturing just a friend
behind the camera. Next one, and this is
a really interesting way of giving
advice. So, a lot of content out there,
especially if you're selling something,
like selling your information, selling
your coaching, selling your consulting,
selling your agency services, like it
comes off very guruy. And the last thing
you want to do is sound like a guru. And
something that I actually take a lot of
pride in is that in growing my
following, 300,000 followers in the past
15 months and growing a really
successful business on top of it, I
still haven't really like lost my aura
in my personal brand. Let me explain.
Basically, I discovered this hack where
when I give advice, instead of sounding
really guruy and scummy and scammy like
all those other gurus out there who try
to sound super professional, be like,
"This is the one Instagram real hack
that you haven't discovered yet that's
going to blow up your content in your
business." I assume this tone rather of
a kind of friend who just discovered a
hack. So, instead of being like, "This
is the one script template that you need
to use to blow up your business." I'm
like, yo, this is the stuff that worked
for me and I just discovered it. I'm not
saying I'm better than you. I'm just
saying that it's really interesting that
I found it and it's crazy that it
worked. Okay, so I want you to like just
think in the frame that you are simply
on the same level as your viewer. You
are not better than them. You are the
same level as them, but you just
discovered something that's interesting.
You just want to share it. And that kind
of gives off this very friendly, warm
tonality and also very charismatic and
natural tonality that you'd want to
assume on camera where you don't sound
robotic like a guru, but you're just
like, "Yo, this is lit. We're here
together." And it builds this kind of
feeling of connection.
Okay. And lastly, a self-roast kind of
tone. So, this kind of ties to these
slang phrases that I naturally use, and
this is something that like chat GBT
noted after seeing all my video
transcripts. It literally like noted
these specific wordings. I say pause
sometimes when I say something weird. I
say little stupid [ __ ] like I say, I
know this sounds cringe. I say, "Bro,
that [ __ ] is so sad." When I describe my
backstory or I say, "I'm not [ __ ]
you on anyone. I'm just saying." Or like
I say, "I thought I had to grind 247."
But and like the interesting thing about
reading this out loud and seeing these
slang phrases, seeing these like weird
not related to storytelling
interjections that I'll sometimes say is
that I think it actually builds great
rapport with your viewer. And I'm not
saying like go on massive tangents just
like trying to sound all hip and facts
yo yolo swag, okay? Like obviously use
terminology that you actually use on
day-to-day, right?
But a nice thing about interjecting
jokes into your script, even if you're
not like the most naturally funny
person, I have been told literally that
I am funnier on my videos than I am in
person. I don't think I'm a naturally
funny person, but I will like
mechanically interject jokes into my
script just so it breaks the tension of
sounding too much like a guru. Okay? And
it creates this like nice flow of the
story where it doesn't feel like your
viewer feels like they're being sold to.
Especially if I have a CTA at the end
that's like yo comment guide for my free
guide. Doesn't that sound like an ad?
Sometimes I'll say like comment poopy
for my free guide just to interject a
little joke so I seem a little silly so
they don't feel like I'm hard selling
them. Okay. And this is a nice way to
break the tension with your viewer.
Personal preference. Maybe you aren't a
jokester. Maybe you hate being perceived
as a silly silly goofy guy. Okay. Maybe
that's not for you. But that has worked
wonders for me. It's built pretty cool
like culture amongst my followers where
I actually enjoy talking with them
because I feel like I can be myself like
a 21-year-old kid and not just be like
the business business and content guru
guy all the time. Okay. And that's been
a nice little introjection for me just
like spicing in jokes like short jokes
with little slang short quippy jokes
that are self-deprecating. That's been
my methodology of maintaining my like
humorous personality in my videos and it
makes me feel proud of my videos because
now I feel like it kind of authentically
represents me which is a somebody who
doesn't take things too seriously. Okay.
And lastly, this is just like a really
interesting one that I noticed works
really well, but try to use short
sentences and repetition in general. Try
not to make your sentences abhorently
long throughout your video because what
will happen then is that if I have a
sentence that just has five different
clauses. So, first I went to the mall,
but then I realized that this one trick
that I was missing this whole time would
fall onto my lap right when I got into
my car. And then once I got into my car,
do you even know what I just said? Like
because the sentences had so many
different clauses, ands, buts, thens,
like you you've lost train of thought of
what I've just said. Okay. So, you don't
want sentences that drag on really long.
And sometimes just saying short
sentences and even repeating them helps
hammer in a point. So, an example, if I
were to give a backstory on like social
media addiction, I would say like you
scroll, you watch, you procrastinate,
and now you feel like [ __ ] All of these
short sentences, they hit, they're easy
to understand, and they still paint a
picture for you very quickly. Okay. And
I I believe there's there's a term for
this in literary devices. I'm sorry.
Like I wasn't the most academic child. I
did take AP Lang and AP Lit though. I
don't think I got fives on either one of
them. But like there is a literary
device for this. Okay. I'm I'm not
basing my entire storytelling frameworks
in like stuff I made up. I wish I was a
genius like this. But no. And also to
recap this entire storytelling
framework, you want to know what's crazy
about this entire storytelling framework
is it's actually the same storytelling
framework that literal Hollywood shows
and movies use and it's based off the
three-act story structure. So literally
this is act one. Okay, act two is like
this backstory and then act three or act
two like the climax of act two is the
breaking point and then act three is the
takeaway and the resolution of a story.
L I'll I'll literally show up
the threeact story
structure like th this is the three-act
story structure right you start off with
the hook the inciting incident and you
kind of give like the beginning
backstory then you start telling your
story describing the moments and the
obstacles that you had to overcome right
and then at the climax of act two is
when you go through the take or not the
takeaway the breaking point the breaking
point the moment where everything
changes that's like the Avengers all
coming back from the Doctor Strange
portals. That's like in Spider-Man Far
From Home, I think. No Way Home. In
Spider-Man No Way Home, when all three
Peters unite and they start fighting all
the big bad villains, right? It's Yeah,
I I could keep naming Hollywood movies,
but I'll probably sound like an idiot,
right? And then act three is the
takeaway. It's the resolution, the
conclusion, the descending action of
your video. And the cool thing is that
in a real, right, this isn't like a 90
minute even like 30 minute video. No,
it's just it's it's 60 to 90 seconds,
which means each of these acts are
really just like two to three sentences.
Like act one is summed up in two
sentences, act two is summed up in like
four sentences, and act three is summed
up in like three sentences. It's super
short and it it actually I I think it's
nice because yes, you have to have a lot
of attention to detail in each of these
sentences, but you don't actually sp you
don't have to spend that much time. And
the cool thing is that once you actually
get into the habit of using this
framework, then you can just like have
it ingrained in your muscle memory and
you don't even have to script it
anymore. You can just start riffing off
the top of your head like stage one,
what's my hook? Okay, I'm going to say I
don't I don't know who needs to hear
this, but you need to start scripting
your videos. And then you can go to,
okay, stage two. Now it's time to tell
my story. That's kind of where I've
gotten with my videos now, where I can
just whip out my phone, think for like
three, three minutes, just sit in
silence and think, and then just riff
off the top of my head, cuz I've
memorized this like the back of my head.
Okay. And yeah, I hope this video was
helpful in understanding storytelling
down to a first principles perspective
when it comes to Tik Tok and Instagram
reels. Hopefully, it was actually easy
and applicable to understand. And if you
want more advice like this, I also have
a 32minute video guide on how I grew
200,000 followers in a single year on
more in-depth breakdown on the three
systems I used to make really compelling
edits, really compelling video, and
actually just progress from a human
perspective because knowledge isn't
everything when it comes to succeeding
as a creator. So, go ahead and watch
that video. Thank you guys for watching
and I'll see you all in the next video.
Peace y'all.