These rich kids just keep getting
younger, man. In January of this year,
my business hit 100K a month. And I
thought I was impressing for this until
two days later, after hitting this
hercuan accomplishment, I found on my
for you page this 19-year-old who made
152K a month with just 30,000 followers
on Instagram. And this actually pissed
me off so much that I invited him on a
podcast to teach my community and you
guys today. All of these systems that he
used in his consulting business to scale
to
$152,000 cash collected in one single
month. This video was taken from a live
call in our private creator community
content academy. And if you want to join
that, just click the first link in the
description below. All right, enjoy.
Here's how it's going to go. We're going
to give a little quick introduction to
Sue. who he is, what he's about, his
dating status, uh his age, and what his
business is. Dway has like a little
presentation set out for us. He's just
going to break down how he grew a 151K a
month coaching business, right? Or
consulting business. Same thing. Same
thing. 151K a month. Did it with just
33,000 followers. I think you have
35,000 followers right now, but I think
at the time you have like less I don't
know like 33,000 followers on Instagram.
Yeah. But when I hit it, I had like 29K.
So, I didn't have a lot of followers.
This is his Instagram, right? He's got
his consulting business. This is his
funnel. This is his YouTube. I was
watching a little interview that he had
with a student before. Su, could you
tell us a little bit about your story,
how you got started? Of course. Of
course. Uh, first off, appreciate you
guys having me on. It's going to be fun.
I prepared a whole document and
everything. So, it's going to be it's
going to be really interesting to share
with you guys kind of what systems work
for me because again, I only have 30K.
If I had meal swallowing, god damn, like
it would be crazy. But a bit about
myself. I'm Malaysian. I grew up in
Malaysia. So, I have a a bit of American
accent because I went I grew up in an
international school and everything. And
I started in the online space when I was
16. I was an appointment setter. I was a
closer and yeah, I became a sales
manager and everything. It's funny,
Renzo's in this call. I applied for a
closing position in on one of Renzo's
offer way back then. I don't know if
Renzo remembers, but it's like a full
circle moment now. It's super super
cool. Um, and yeah, I was just heavy in
the sales background. Kind of
transitioned into kind of growth
operating. I don't know if you guys have
heard of that term, but basically just
bootstrapping coaches and taking them
from anywhere from under 10K to 100K a
month. We scaled like five coaches in
the first 2 3 months and then that's
when my consulting business kind of just
blew up and everything. A lot of people
just wanted my service and so I started
a consulting offer and we scaled it from
zero to 151k a month in 9 months. I'm
actually still in university. I'm
probably just going to thug it out. I
have like one more year left. So make my
make my Asian parents proud or whatever.
And yeah, that's a bit about my story.
That's nuts. I actually have a quick
question. Did you when you first started
the growth operating helping creators
scale their own businesses, did you see
it becoming such a big consulting offer
when you first started it?
Not at all. I kind of just did it. But
then I realized that, okay, if I can do
it for all these other guys, why can't I
do it for myself? You know, I was only
taking like 15 30% rev share. If I could
do it for these guys, for five people
and, you know, scale them past 100k a
month, I was like, okay, I just put all
my eggs in one basket, my own business,
I% margins, scale up myself. And that's
what I did. And yeah, I executed pretty
well. So, it was just I' I'd say the
skill set the skill set of being in a
done for you space was what allowed me
to kind of scale past that 100k month so
fast and we're sustaining that pretty
well now. So, yeah.
That's awesome. I actually want to make
a quick like note there that I think the
best offers that I've seen don't stem
necessarily from like yo this is my like
millionoll a month idea and like we're
just going to like we're going to build
it and I have nothing right now. I think
it starts from like genuinely helping
people and getting them results and that
momentum of getting people's results.
It's no surprise that you ended up
scaling this way, but it's cool that you
didn't start with the mindset of like
like money, money, money, money like
from the beginning because I think that
means that you actually care about your
clients and it I think those are the
people who succeed long term.
100%. 100%. And I think that it it
always ties back to your skill set,
right? Like the person that's best at,
you know, whatever they're selling is
going to win at the end of the day. And
I knew that I had a skill set that not a
lot of people had. If I just launch a
consulting offer, position myself the
right way. um it it was going to be game
over. And I'm going to show you guys
like the way that we've scaled is not
your typical traditional way where it's
like we're selling a 3K course. Like no,
we don't sell a course. Um we sell like
12K 18K packages. So we need low volume,
high quality clients. And that's the way
that I've structured my model. So it's
going to be really interesting cuz I
don't think a lot of people run this
model. But I [ __ ] love it because I
work with less people, I make more
money, and I get to actually work
oneonone with my guys. and it's like
super super fulfilling. So yeah, dude, I
need to take notes on this too. Do you
have any other information that you want
to share before you go into the
nitty-gritty specifics of your systems
of your offer or we can just jump right
into it? Uh, not really honestly. I'm
going to cover a lot and I'm going to
try and make it as actionable as
possible. I know a lot of you guys are
like, you either have an audience or you
don't have an audience. You're thinking
about starting an offer or you already
have an offer. So I kind of created a
whole presentation that's applicable to
as many people as possible. And so yeah,
I I I have a lot of theory, but then I
also lot have a lot of practicality. So
the best way that you're going to get
value from this actual call is by
actually implementing. You know,
whatever I say whenever I ask myself or
whenever I say, "Okay, do this thing,
actually write it down and do it."
Because you know, if you if you execute
on this call, the next 30 minutes of
what I present, like I'm going to
provide a lot of sauce that allow me to
scale up really fast. And if you
actually take what I say and actually do
it, like you'll make a lot of money. So
yeah, dude. Let's get started, bro. Yo,
everybody watching, whether you're
watching the VOD or like watching live,
bro, get out a pen and paper because I'm
I'm feeling the same right now. But
yeah. Uh yeah, dude, I'd love for you to
share your screen and just jump into
like what you have presented. Ready?
Yeah. Yeah. I created this whole pitch
deck or like this whole presentation
specifically for you guys in the
community and everything and it's going
to be really fun. I can't see the
Discord right now, so I can't see what
you guys are saying, but um you know, if
you can like if someone has a question
or something like something pops up,
just let me know. Yeah, that'll be
perfect. I got you. We can do at the
end. Yeah. Basically, I'm going to break
down my 151K a month salesunnel. Again,
I don't have a lot of followers. I have
34K followers, 3K subs, and we're going
to go over the top of funnel, middle of
funnel, bottom of funnel, and
everything. And how I've been able to
basically perfect middle of funnel.
That's my expertise. You know, I'm not
going to sit here and say that I'm the
best at content. Um, Mino is the best at
content, right? But what I'm really,
really good at is creating content that
really converts clients. And there's no
point of content in my opinion if you're
not selling or if you're not making
money off of it. And so with my small
following, you know, compared to Mino
and everyone else here, I've been able
to profit a lot because I understand the
idea of a funnel and what actually makes
someone want to spend tens of thousands
of dollars with you. Not just a few
thousand, I'm talking tens of thousands.
And I've been able to just really just
build a really, really good business. I
don't know if you guys have seen the my
my reels or whatever. I told my mom,
dad, and everything that I made 150k a
month. And it's like the full circle
Asian moment, you know, and I want you
guys to have that because a lot of you
do have that audience. You just don't
know how to capitalize on it. So, we did
151k a month at 85% profit margins. And
a lot of you aren't far from this. Okay.
The truth is I'm 20. I'm still studying
for university. I play basketball for my
team. I have, you know, a social circle.
And from the outside looking in, I look
like a regular Asian kid, you know, but
I made 151k a month because I started
when I was 16. And the difference
between, you know, me and a lot of
people is that I was just obsessed. I
was obsessed with the sales, I was
obsessed with the funnels, the
marketing, and what makes someone
actually buy. And it took me like 3
years and over $80,000 invested into
different mentors to learn all this
information to be able to make this type
of money. And the whole goal of this
presentation is just to make you just to
help you save the time and money so you
don't have to, you know, spend thousands
of dollars, so that you don't have to
spend tons of time. And I just want to
show you how I built a coaching business
from zero to 151k a month, how I make
more than certain creators that have 10x
my following, and the salesunnel that
converts clients on autopilot. Okay.
Now, I'm going to go into the funnel in
a bit, but the first thing that you want
to do is the is you want to create an
offer. I'm not talking about just a
generic 2 to 3k offer. Um, I've scaled
to this point because I charge 11.5K and
$18,000 for my service. my cheapest
service that you know if someone wants
to work with me the cheapest they have
to pay me is is
$1.5,000 meaning that if I take the
average client
LTV I only need seven clients every
single month to hit $100,000 a month you
know but if I had an offer that was only
$3,000 I would need 33 clients so just
by structuring my offer the right way I
can make my I can make it 10 times
easier for me to scale to 100k a month
just by actually charging more. Okay.
And so the idea behind behind an offer
is very very is very very simple. Your
offer just has to provide a solution to
a big problem that somebody has. And the
bigger their desired reality is then the
more we can charge. So think about what
your strength is and what think about
what your expertise is. Do people
actually want it? Right? The the most
important thing is the demand. You know
for make money online it could be Amazon
FBA, Tik Tok shop, drop shipping,
whatever. With this type of offer you
can easily charge 5K. With fitness
coaching, you could easily charge 4K.
Right now, what I would recommend, this
is this is a mid ticket. I I don't think
5K is a lot. Realistically, if you're
selling an offer that's helping someone
make money online, you're completely
changing the trajectory of their life.
And you shouldn't only charge 5K. You
should be charging like 8 to 10, you
know. And a lot of people say like, oh,
you know, it I always get the objection
the price is too expensive. The reason
why people say your price is too
expensive is because you have not
bridged the gap in their mind. And so
what I want you guys to do, an exercise
you could do right now is think about
the desired solution you're promising.
So for me, you know, it could be the
content, right? And list down every
single problem that is stopping them
from achieving this
goal. If you have every single solution
to every single problem they could
potentially face that is stopping them
from achieving their goal, you'll be
able to charge, you know, 5 to 10K. And
just by charging 5 to 10K, you make your
life 10 times easier because now you
don't have to go out and sign 30 guys or
whatever, you know, you can sign way
less clients, have way better of a
product, and actually get crazy client
results. And so my model is just low
volume, high quality, and just le less
work,
basically. Okay? So the goal is not to
get everybody. The goal is to get a very
select few group of people in your
program that can afford it and are
actually worth working with. Now, one
thing I would say is if you have done
for you systems, you can charge more.
And so, if if I was if I was running
Mino's offer that the first thing that I
would change is okay, if a business
owner wants to scale, right, what is the
number one thing that they want?
Probably an editor. They don't want to
edit their own videos. They don't want
to edit their own stuff. And so if Mino
just put a done for you editor in his
own offer, he'd be able to charge an
extra 2 to 3K just like that, right? And
I'm going to show you my like kind of my
my offer sheet and how I've been able to
charge this much. This is an 18K offer.
$18,000. Now, I'm not telling you that
you need to charge this much. I don't
want to kind of overwhelm you guys. But
the more problems that you can solve for
your clients, the better you can
actually the more you can charge and the
better results you can get them. And so
what are done for you systems or what
are done for you solutions that you can
provide in your offer to basically just
make it a no-brainer and make it so that
these guys will obviously achieve the
result. And so we do done for you
systems and processes. We do the done
for you offer blueprint. Content mastery
actually place an in-house editor. We
write their ads for them. We set it up
all up all up for them. We write their
VSSLs, we place a setter and that's why
we can charge 18K, right? And then the
best part is they can take all of our
systems and processes and everything and
widely for their own program. So it all
comes down to how many things can you do
done for you that is not going to kind
of make you spread thin and how can you
charge more? Because just by doing these
two things alone, without even doing any
more marketing, without doing any more
sales, just by having a more expensive
offer and a more premium offer, you're
making your ability to scale way, way
easier because everything is just like
you just need less volume. You know, you
don't need 30 guys now. Maybe now you
only need 15. And now you're just half
your workload for the fulfillment and
for, you know, the acquisition. and you
can work with a small group of guys that
want to get the result that they that
you promised them, right? And the thing
is I can guarantee that I can add an
extra 20k to the revenue which is why I
can charge the premium price point that
I have. Right? So this is the offer and
if you guys have an offer sheet like
this I like you guys don't have an offer
sheet like this where you can present it
on your sales calls that's going to make
your life 10 times easier. every like my
offer percentage if I if I pitch on a
sales call, our closing rate for this
offer is
60%. On on a 18K offer and you do this,
you can get this high of a closing rate
on such a premium offer by noting down
every single problem that your client
could potentially face, providing
solutions, and then creating systemized
done for you solutions for the biggest
problems that they may face. And so, you
know, if Mino was was selling an offer
and he pitched the fact that you could
place an in-house editor, he could place
an in-house editor for you immediately
his price would jack up instead of maybe
3K, it could be 6K now, just off of one
done for you system. Now, maybe it's,
you know, another one maybe is done for
you scripts, now it's it could be 8K,
you know. So, the more done for you
systems that you can add, the higher you
can charge and the less work you have to
do to actually
scale. Does that make sense?
You know, real quick, I I don't know
what the chat is saying, but yeah, this
this is everyone. Can I get it so far?
Yo, chat, drop a W if you if you're
[ __ ] Renzo said sauce W. Oh my. Okay,
W spam coming in. We got 50 people in
here. So, yeah. Yeah, they're spamming
W, bro. Don't worry.
All right. So, that's the offer, right?
charge more, work with less clients,
scale better, and that's how you
actually get client results. I don't
know if you guys follow me, but like I
have like at this point four story
highlights of just results back to back.
If I go to my community, if I go over
here, like there's a wins chat,
everything like what happens when you
build this way is that you keep your
reputation, right? No one actually calls
me a core seller. No one calls me a
scammer. No one calls me all these
different names because the people that
I work with, they get the result, you
know, like when you when you look in the
wins chat in the community and
everything, everyone's killing it. And
the reason why is because every single
one of these people have the attention
and everything, right? They have my
one-on-one attention, which is which
allows me to get better results, have a
better reputation, get more referrals,
and everything. All right, so now I'm
going to dive into the top of funnel,
minimum funnel, and bottom of funnel.
I'm going to quickly skim over the top
of funnel cuz this is not my expertise.
I don't have a lot of subscribers or a
lot of followers, but this is my
strategy. I post one or two times a day
on IG and I post once a week on YouTube.
My main driving factor is YouTube
because if you can sit down and watch a
20inut video of me talking about a
funnel or talking about a system, you're
going to you're going to trust me more
and you're going to be you're going to
be much more likely to transact with me,
right? And so there's a study done by
the uh I think social survey, social
trust survey, something like that.
People need to consume at least 7 hours
of your content on average before they
spend a penny with you. YouTube fills up
that 7 hours faster than Instagram can.
And so the more sophisticated your
market is, the more competitive your
your market is, the more that you
actually have to like kind of get in
front of them. And if you can get your
content to be bingeable and be
consumable on YouTube, on Instagram, on
whatever, then what's going to happen is
that these guys are going to go for you,
right? Whoever you consume most, I
promise you, like if you guys are
heavily investing into mentors and
everything, the next person that you
invest in is going to be the person that
you watch the most right now. I can
guarantee you that. And so your goal
with your YouTube and Instagram is just
to get people to watch that [ __ ] you
know? And YouTube is one of those ways
where, you know, because my market is so
sophisticated, I'm selling to online
coaches, right? I'm selling online
coaches. Everybody sells online coaches.
Because my market is so sophisticated, I
can't really stand out through
Instagram. I can't. So I What did I do?
I dropped a 7-hour [ __ ] free course.
7-hour free course. There's no other
coach that actually, you know, that
sells to my specific sells to my
specific niche that's doing something
like this. This course alone helped me
double my revenue from 75K to 150K. This
was the reason why because more people
are consuming my content. I get more
respect and I separate myself from
everybody else in my market. You have to
realize that you're the like your
markets and the people that you're
trying to sell to have been pitched time
and time again. And so if you want to do
something or if you want to make money
that nobody else is willing to make, you
got to do things that nobody else is
willing to do. I'm going to dive more a
bit into the middle of funnel in a bit,
but just know that this 7-hour course
made me an extra 75K a month, basically.
All right, so I post one or two times a
day on IG. I post stories every single
day. Stories is my bread and butter.
I've made probably like 80% of my
revenue through stories. And then I post
once a week on YouTube. I drive all the
traffic I have on Instagram to YouTube
so I nurture them even more and they
consume more of my content. All right.
And the content types that I post, four
types. Proof, education, beliefs, and
identity. Proof is just showing that you
know you know what you're talking about.
Education is just the value framework.
I'm not going to go over this too much
cuz this is Mino's thing. Beliefs is
just shifting your what your audience
believes about scaling. And so just
talking about your insights. And then
the last part is your
identity. This is so [ __ ] important,
right? You need to go over stories that
show who you are and why you're
different. You know, if you go on my if
you went on my profile a year
ago, you know, there's a reason why I
was only making like 10K in life because
I was just providing value non-stop. And
I think that a huge shift when I joined,
like if you guys didn't know, I'm I'm
actually part of content academy as
well, like I joined the low ticket. A
huge reason why I pivoted into the
personal aspect is because I realized
people buy coaches. They don't buy
coaching. They buy into who you are as a
person, not what you do. Okay? Because
there's dozens and h there's hundreds if
not thousands of people that sell the
exact same offer as you do. Completely
identical. And maybe they even get
better results. The way that you stand
out is by showing your identity and what
you stand for, your values and your
morals and everything.
If I show you a clip of me telling my
mom how much I made or me talking about
my clients and, you know, what I believe
in and everything, you're going to trust
me a lot more than just me sharing value
because now I'm different. Nobody else
can fake their mom's reaction or no one
else can fake their values and morals.
Like that's just that's just me, right?
And so you have to realize that people
choose you for who you are, not
necessarily what you sell. So yes,
provide the education, but also show who
you are as a person. Talk about
yourself, talk about your story, how you
grew up, and everything. You know,
there's a reason why, you know, my
community is like 40% Asian as well.
Like that's just how it is. You know,
sometimes I'm talking Chinese on my
reals. Sometimes I'm just talking about
the fact that I've grew up in an Asian
household. And you know, some Asian
coaches relate to that and they buy my
[ __ ] I have like 40% Asian coaches in
my program. There's a reason for that,
right? Lean into it. You guys all have a
unique identity that people want to be a
part of. You just got to lean into it.
All right. So, that's the top of funnel.
And this is where I really want you guys
to take notes. This is what I'm good at.
With 33K followers, I've been able to
make 150K a month. So, per
follower, I basically like I basically
have a $5 $5 per follower ratio. Okay?
And so I want you to think right now
what is your f what is your dollar per
follower ratio? And if it's not three or
five then I want you to listen up
because this is what's going to change
the game for you. Okay. I took this I
took this you know inspiration from
herozi. So you know what I want you guys
to do. I want you to give out your best
information for
free. I don't want you to sell the
course. I don't want you to put
information behind pay walls. just give
it for
free because you like ultimately the
service that you provide is the
implementation right you just need to
charge for implementation information
does not actually get someone the end
result it could get you know maybe 1% of
the your audience the end result but
that's the 1% for 99% of people if they
get the information for free they won't
implement it they won't implement it
okay so you don't have to worry about
them not needing you or anything because
what most people think
is I should charge for my best advice
and my best
information. If you think about the
biggest people in the space, the
industry leaders, the people that you
respect the most and everything, they do
the complete opposite. Like look at Alex
Herozi. There's not a single piece of
advice or a single piece of strategy
that he used scaling his businesses that
is not out on YouTube for free. Okay?
Because the truth is people judge you
based on the free value you put in the
world.
They don't judge you for how good your
paid program is. So, if you keep that,
if you keep your best information and
your best advice and all your strategies
behind a payw wall, guess what? Only 1%
of your entire audience is going to
actually respect you. But if you put
that out for free, everybody's going to
know that you're good at what you
do. Your free content should help your
ideal customers solve the first initial
problems to achieve a desired result
that they want. So, let's say you guys
are selling a make money online course,
right? Let's say you're teaching someone
how to do SMA or Tik Tok shop or
whatever. Your free content should
realistically make them their first 3K a
month without even you talking to them,
without even you helping to them,
helping them at all because that's
what's going to get them to pay you 5 to
10K on the back end. That's what's going
to trans get them to transact those big
payments on the back end, right? That's
what led to my 150k a month. If you guys
don't know, like like this is actually
my W dashboard, my fan bases and
everything because what happens is if
you watch my content and you make more
money with your coaching business, you
attribute your success to me. Okay? So
my free content takes you from zero to
5K a month. And when you want to scale
from 5K a month to maybe 30K a month or
50K a month, guess who you go to? You're
going to go to me, right? You're going
to go to me. So, my free value takes me
from point A to point B. Just off of
free value. I take you from 0 to 5K a
month. Point A to point
B. Once you've made 5K a month with my
free value, you will have no choice but
to transact with me if you want to scale
to the next level to 30K a month or
whatever. And you're not going to go to
anybody else because I'm the one that
took you from 0 to 5K.
I have trust that nobody that you have
with nobody
else. That is how you separate yourself
from the most saturated market. You
know, a lot of you guys are thinking,
"Oh, I don't know how to sell. I don't
know how to sell or I don't know if I
can scale to 10K a month."
Whatever. Guys, there's so many people
that are so selfish with their
information and so caught up with
selling courses and selling information
that you can just go into your niche and
dominate.
I'm in the online coaching space. I
mean, some of you, I don't know how many
of you guys are online coaches, but you
know, Mino can attest to this. Renzo can
attest to this as well. It's the most
saturated industry in the entire online
space. Everybody says they can scale
coaches. In 9 months, I scale from 0 to
150K a month in the most saturated niche
because I provided free value that
nobody else is willing to provide. And
if you go out there in your specific
niche and you drop a crazy free course
and you just put all your information
out there for free, what's going to
happen is people are just going to make
money with your free content and they're
going to DM you and you're not even
going to need a sales call and they're
going to want to pay you 5 to 10k
upfront just for your one-on-one time or
just for your community or just for your
program. So again, let me repeat it. I
take you from 0 to 5k a month with my
free value. And when you want to go from
5K a month to 30K a month, that's when
you pay
me. Make people get their desired
reality first. Make them get their
desired goal first and then charge on
the back end. If you want to separate
yourself from everybody else in the
niche in your niche right now and you
want to have more respect than everybody
else has, do this method. I promise you,
it's a game changer.
I'm uh I'm I've been yapping for a bit.
But does that does that make sense,
guys?
Let me check real quick. What is this?
Yo, drop a W in the chat if this is
[ __ ] sauce,
bro. Oh my goodness. I'm taking hella
notes, too. Hopefully this is helping,
guys, cuz I I just led with so much
value. And you know, when you lead with
value, people are just going to come.
people are just going to come, right?
So, don't be afraid to just give so much
value because there's no such thing.
There's no such thing as too much value.
You will get paid either way. And even
if you don't get paid, they will spread
good word of mouth which will get you
paid from one of their friends or
whatever, right? So, let's say like I'll
give you an example of this. Let's say I
hopped on a 1 hour call with one of you
guys.
If I dropped one hour of sauce, just
straight sauce and just pure value, and
I told you everything that you needed to
do to scale from 0 to 10k a month,
you're going to leave that call and
you're going to be like, I feel bad, you
know, cuz Sue just [ __ ] gave me so
much value and I didn't even pay for it.
And you're going to feel bad, right?
What that means is you put someone in
value debt. And when you put someone in
value debt, they're going to be more
inclined to do anything that you ask of
them. This is kind of like the
manipulative side of sales and
everything, but bear with me, right?
When you put someone in value debt and
when you give your free course for free
and you give information like that for
free, what's going to happen is that
these guys are going to reply to you in
your DMs. So, when you have a sender
reaching out to all your leads and
everything, guess what, your response
rate for your first initial outreach
message is going to be it's going to
skyrocket straight off the bat because
they have more trust with you and they
feel bad because they got so much value
that the least they could do is respond.
the least they could do is respond. And
if you have a good enough setter, your
setter can turn that lead into a booked
call that pays you 10K just like that,
right? But the it begins with the amount
of value you
provide. It begins with the amount of
pro value you provide and take making
someone their getting someone their
desired reality first or getting them
their desired result first and then
caring about yourself later. Just lead
with value. Serve first, you know, and
then the money will come later.
So, it's trust by saturation. I I I
mentioned the 7-hour content. Like, you
have to, you know, they have to consume
at least 7 hours of content. Another
thing is trust by
saturation. By the time someone books in
a call, they've consumed 20 plus touch
points from multiple platforms and it's
it's game over, right? It's game over.
Now, this is exactly what I did. I gave
away all my information that's part of
my 9.5K course for free, which is what
Mino showed earlier in the call, and I
got a [ __ ] ton of optins. I think
generally that releasing my free course
is the reason why I'm making 150k a
month right now. And y'all better start
doing it before it's too late and before
everyone starts hopping on it. Like
people are starting to realize it now.
And people are like all my competitors
are trying to like scramble their free
courses together and put out some
[ __ ] But if you can if you already
have
material like really really really
consider just putting it out for free
because you'll make more money than
ever. like you'll make more money and
you'll be able to just have such a
spotless reputation because no one can
talk [ __ ] about you anymore. If they
when people invest in me, it's not a
risk because they can actually go
through my program and everything and
know that I know what I'm talking about.
I've been talking to you guys for like
30 minutes, not even maybe like 20
minutes, right? And your perception of
me now is completely changed because
I've dropped value for 20 minutes. Maybe
at the start you're like, "Who the [ __ ]
is this Chinese guy?" Now, you know, 20
minutes after, you're like, "Okay, this
guy actually knows what he's talking
about, right?" Which is why 50 of you
are still staying on this
call. If you can just provide so much
value to these guys that you make it,
you make it so that their purchase of
your program, it's not even a risk. It's
just like they already know it's
guaranteed success. That's how you can
charge genuinely 5 to
10K. And so all the value and knowledge
I have, I just put it in this course and
I packaged it up into freebies, right? I
told them to DM me on Instagram and I
went a step further. The setter used a
freebie script to booked to book in
calls. So every person that opted in, I
got their name, I got their phone
number, and I got their email. If you
guys know anything about sales funnels,
all that stuff, um, that's kind of my
background. And so the first thing we
did, we I hired a dialer. I had a dialer
reaching out to basically every single
one of these dudes that opted in. And we
booked a [ __ ] ton of calls just off of
that. Again, because people are in value
debt, they got so much value for free.
The least they could do is have a
conversation with one of my reps, right?
And then my setter on my Instagram also
DM'd every single person that opted in,
right? You know, I want to send you more
personalized resources, blah blah blah.
And do you see how because I led with
value, now there's an opening for me to
actually book them in for a call now,
right? You don't just get what you want
straight away. No, no, no. You give them
what they want. You get them the result
first and then they'll be open to
hearing what you have to say and
everything. Especially with saturated
markets, especially with sophisticated
clients, you know, I did this in the
coaching space. So, if you guys launch a
B TOC and you run some [ __ ] like
this, I don't like I don't even know how
much money you could make cuz my ICP, my
ideal clients are super super smart. dip
and pitch time and time again. You know,
if you're selling to a B2C audience and
you run this offer or you run this
funnel that worked for my B2B
sophisticated ass market, it's going to
be wraps, right? And
so Setter uses the freebie script to
booking calls. Again, you know, I don't
know if if I if I ever DM you guys, like
it's not actually me, my Setter. I'm
going just say that right now. But, you
know, we have a few, you know, outreach
messages and everything, all that stuff.
And we just, you know, convert, we we
turn leads that want the freebies into
book calls just by hearing a nice
conversation, right? How long's that
been going on for you? Blah blah blah.
How's that been for you? What are you
currently focused on? I've got some few
times. Blah blah blah. Right? And again,
the opening is only there because I
provided that much value. And what this
leads to is a packed out calendar of
warm leads that are ready to just pay
you. I kid you not, some of my sales
calls in 10, 15 minutes, these guys are
just piffing 20K, right? Because again,
they've already gone through the free
course. This isn't even a call. This
isn't even a sales call. It's like an
onboarding call. You know, you want to
get your leads so warm to the point
where they're hopping on the call and
they already
decided. That's how you know if your
your middle funnel is dialed in. If
you're having hop on calls with your
prospects and they're still kind of
having to think or they're throwing, you
know, one or two objections out there,
your funnel is just not it's just [ __ ]
you know, like it's not good enough. The
moment that you can just have prospects
hop on call within 10 minutes and piff
your full amount, that's when you have a
dialed in funnel. Okay? And what this
leads to is huge pips in sales. So
11.5K, 10.5, you know, we did 130 cash,
all that [ __ ] So, it's crazy stuff.
It's honestly crazy stuff. And that's
what happens when you have a dial in
funnel. People just want to pay you.
People just want to pay you. I've had
countless inbounds where it's like, I
have 10K liquid. Let me know when you
have time for a call. Like, they're
telling me, can you imagine getting that
type of DM? Someone telling you that
they have $10,000 liquid in their in
their bank account ready to pay you, and
all you have to do is just hop on a
call, talk to them for 10 minutes, and
close them, and then deliver on the
service. Can you imagine how much life
would be, how how much easier life would
be? You know, you do this by just
providing first. You do this by doing
what nobody else in your market is doing
and just providing so much value that
people can't even fathom it and they
feel that so they respond to you. And
when you have a dialed in setter, you
have a dialed in closer, you have a
dialed in dialer, everything. Everything
is just easier. Okay? Middle of funnel
is what's going to make you your first
10, 30, 50, 100k a month. Like I haven't
even mastered top of funnel. If you guys
think that you have to go viral, please
look at my [ __ ] Like, please look at my
[ __ ] I'm only going viral now because,
you know, I like my whole angle now is
like I I made 150k a month at 19 and I'm
balancing university. That's my angle
now. But before this month, before May,
I had no viral videos. I I all my videos
hit 2 to
3K. If you have a few hundred followers
right now and a few thousand followers
right now and you're not getting people
to DM you, you need to implement this.
You need to implement this. All
right, beautiful. Does this make sense
for you guys?
Yo, W in the chat if this makes sense.
Dude, I have so many notes. I have a
couple questions and I know there's
probably a ton of questions in the chat.
So, I actually want to uh cuz I want to
respect your time, too. We got like 24
minutes left here. Um, yeah. You mind if
we just jump into questions here, Suie?
Oh, we could. Yeah. Yeah. Let me wrap up
the bottom of funnel real quick and then
I'll show you guys the bottom of funnel
super fast and then we'll drop in a
questions. So that's cool. Bet.
Beautiful. All right, bottom of funnel
closing. Guys, like I said, take calls
or pre-sold leads. Don't sell, you know.
Um, a lot of you guys think I'm good at
sales. I'm I'm very very average at
sales. I I like I'm very very average,
you know. I'm good at talking. I'm good
at using tonality and everything. Um,
but the the the power of my funnel and
the power of building a consulting
business is just, you know, in the
middle of funnel. That's where majority
of my of my sales and everything comes
from. Okay. So, I take calls of pre-sold
leads. This is the overall framework
that I use. I'm not going to get into it
because honestly, it's really really
easy. If you have middlefunnel dialed
in, you don't even need bottom of
funnel. You can say some [ __ ] on the
call and people will still buy from you.
It's crazy. All right. There's not much
objection handling needed if you run
this funnel the right way and the
selling is done before they even hop on
a call. Like I said, your calls should
last 20 minutes. I don't care if you're
B to C. I don't care if you're B2B. I
don't care who who the [ __ ] you're
selling to, right? Your calls should be
pre-sold. These leads should be pre-sold
by the time they hop on the calls and
they should be piffing.
I'm going throw a little snippet of like
what people are saying when they see my
offer and everything, but the number two
the two things that you should focus on
is your middle funnel and your offer,
right? Like listen to this. And the
reason why I say this because these are
the reactions I get on my calls
sometimes. But I mean like you know so
much more than me as far as fulfillment.
Like your fulfillment is dialed. I've
always
heard I've always heard very good things
in your name. And so that's why I was
like, I got to book a call with this
because that's my number one concern. I
want to have a good reputation. That's
what that guy said, right? The people
that the clients that I work with do the
selling for me. And in this one, you're
going to see the offer does the selling
for me. I don't even have to sell.
No, it's it's obviously them, but you
have some sort of [ __ ] knowledge that
I had to get myself on. I appreciate
that, bro. I appreciate that. But let me
run you through the two offers, then
we'll take them on, bro. Yeah.
Cool. So, let me show you this real
quick. You'll have pure clarity on what
you need to work on offer right now.
Correct. Hold up. This is your whole
process. Yeah.
I What's up? Oh, this is [ __ ] good. I
ain't seen an offer better than this in
[ __ ] ages, bro.
Okay, enough glazing from this guy.
Basically, if you just work on your
offer, you make it so different from all
your other competitors, people are just
going to say [ __ ] like this. And your
offer and your content that they consume
before the call is going to sell them.
You know, you don't actually need to get
good at sales and objection handling,
all that [ __ ] Like, no. You know,
I've been a very very midcloer and I've
been able to close 150K a month by
myself because of these systems. All
right. So, yeah. And another part is the
fulfillment, guys.
We're in the info space. We're we're in
the info
space. Everything is based on
reputation, you know? Everything is
based on reputation. So before you even
sell the product, get actually good at
what you do, you know? Get really,
really [ __ ] good at what you do. I
remember before I launched my offer, I
joined four of my different competitors.
I just bought their [ __ ] and I saw what
I like from them. I took it and put it
in mine and I made my fulfillment so
good and I had people making their money
back within the first 7 to 14 days.
Right? You got guys making 4K, 2K, 16K,
5K, 4K, all that [ __ ] And people just
getting their money back within 7 to 14
days. And when you make a risk, like
when you make a quote unquote risky
decision and you invest 12.5, 12K or 18K
and you make your money back in 7 to 14
days, guess what you're going to do?
You're going to tell your friends,
right? And so when I close a person, I'm
not just closing one person. I'm closing
like three cuz I know that that guy is
going to refer two more people in a
month from now when he gets the results
and 20% of my acquisition is through
referrals. So now not just my content,
not just my offer, not just everything
like not just that people are just
talking good about me, right? I have a
good reputation now and reputation is
everything in the game because there is
no there is no way to know if you're
really legit. You know, everyone can
fake testimonials. Everyone can fake all
this [ __ ] You can't fake a good
reputation. you can't. And so now I'm
posting client retreats. I'm showing me
hanging out with my clients in Dubai. I
brainwash them results. I post 5K
studies every single week. I show people
winning. And over time, when you start
following me, you're going to get FOMO
cuz you're going to be like, "Okay,
Sue's already made me an extra 5 to 10k
a month. He I want to go to Dubai with
his clients. I want to meet with meet up
with him and the guys that he's working
with. I'm going to
join." People don't buy information. Get
that out of your head. You're not
selling a course. You shouldn't sell a
course when you want to build a real
business that gets you, you know, real
results and allows you to scale really,
really fast. You can sell a course, but
the way that you keep a spotless
reputation is by selling the
implementation because no one can doubt
your expertise when all your expertise
is out there for
free. So, yeah, that's my presentation.
I know I went a bit too long, but I have
a bit of I I don't mind going past 3
p.m. EST. Like, I got time. So yeah,
hopefully you guys like that.
Wow, dude. That's that is freaking
crazy, bro. One more W in the chat
before we jump into questions and then
feel free to jump like drop your
question in the chat because I have like
two very quick rapidfire questions for
you, Su like Yeah, go ahead. That was
awesome. So these are like personal
questions of mine. Um the first one is
simply what software platforms do you
use for software for like CRM product
community funnels everything
I host all my websites and all my um
funnels on on go high level so that's
300 a
month I book calls through Cali I use
notion for all my systems and [ __ ] and I
think that's about it bro like I'm
[ __ ] yeah I'm a bot when it comes to
tech and [ __ ] I have my I have my like
VA just build everything out for me. But
that that's basically it. Yo, that's
fire, bro. Honestly, that's that's dope.
You said what do you use for like CRM
and email?
Um, I use ConvertKit for email and then
CRM I use go high level.
Fire fire. That's awesome. That's sick.
Next question is you said you had a
bunch of mentors and I saw this question
in the chat. Who are the mentors that
you've invested in? Who are the
favorite? And if you can just go in a
list of like best experience to worst,
bro, we'll start some [ __ ] drama in
here.
I don't know if I can do that, bro. I
don't know if I can do that. I don't
want to step on any toes. But I've
invested in a lot of people. I've
invested in Charlie Morgan. Um Ravi
Abua. Uh who else? I'm I'm Jeremy
Haynes. I don't know. Jeremy Haynes is
bro, that guy's [ __ ] good.
Um, Yousef Malcolm, I don't know if you
know these guys. I could be just like
saying random ass names you guys don't
know, but these guys like, yeah, I
worked with a lot of coaches. I'm not
going to rank just cuz I don't want to
step on any toes, but some of them are
good, some of them are bad. Who was the
best experience that you had? Like the
one that you felt impacted you the most
or you got the most value out of?
That's hard, bro. That's hard.
I think I'd say Yousef cuz Yousef taught
me all the skills Yousef and Malcolm
with the GA like the growth operating
stuff. Like that's how I got the skill
set that I have today. And I think that
com like the skill set that they got me
combined with my knowledge on how to
kind of position myself in the right way
and stand out from the market was what
made me the money that I make right now.
So yeah, that's fire. That's fire. Yeah,
I bet. Um, I have another question here
and I basically want you to pitch us
real quick,
but like framed in this question here of
what is your onboarding process? Like
what does it look like when somebody
actually pays you and they join? And
then my question on top of that is like
what exact SOPs do you provide?
And yeah, I I feel like if you could
even frame it as if you were basically
pitching us on what the client journey
will look like if I were piff you right
now, what does that look like?
I like that. I like that. Let me pull
pull some stuff up real quick. Um, and
if anyone converts, I'll give Mino a
nice little referral.
Let me just pull this up real quick. So
the first thing that happens is I send
you an email and you get access to
basically like everything, right? So
everything is automated. Yeah. Let me
show you real quick. Yeah.
So immediately once you get closed,
boom, triggers in the pipeline and then
you get the onboarding email. Onboarding
email is very simple. I congratulate you
to join blah blah blah. And then we fill
out everything. So you fill out an
onboarding form. Let me show you guys
what this looks like. It's detailed,
right? So, I need your name, email,
business, what's your backstory, what's
your offer, what do you want to use, who
are your competitors. And the thing is
like it's very personalized. And the
reason why I get the results that we get
is because we don't work with a lot of
guys. So maybe if you wanted to join,
you wouldn't even be able to, you know,
cuz if you're not if I don't see you
being that case study that gets that
doubles, triples the business in the
next 6 months. I don't want to work with
you, right? We said no to a lot of
people, which is why I can, you know, do
market research for every single one of
the clients that joins and that's why we
get the results that we get. So that's
what happens. And then you join the
community. And when you join the
community, everything just changes,
right? Everything just changes. And when
you see the wins chat every single day
popping off, you're going to ask
yourself, why am I not making the same
amount of money? Why are people making
more money than me when they're less
qualified and they work way less than me
and they're not working as hard and
everything? That's going to piss you
off. And so a lot of it is like yes, we
provide you the consulting, but it's
like when you're part of a community
where everybody is winning every [ __ ]
day and there's a guy getting 40k new
followers in 4 days and everyone's just
getting cash coming in, what's going to
happen is you're going to think to
yourself, okay, what am I doing wrong?
Because I have the same exact
consulting, support, guidance, and
everything that these guys have. What
can I do? And so the cool thing about
our community is that you can reach out
and it's tightknit. you know, we only
have 40 50 guys in here and you can
reach out to everybody. You know, Deon
was making 3K a month, now he's making
4.5. And so that's that. You know, you
get access to the video modules,
subscribe to the group calls, format
call, everything. And it's a lot. It's a
lot. But the main SOPs that you guys
will get or like my clients get is they
get their own notion dashboard. This is
where you can script all your systems
and everything. And we give you specific
appointment setting scripts tailored to
your offer. And so what we're going to
do, the reason why we get the
information from the onboarding is
because now I can get the information
and create a specific inbound, outbound,
postbooking, freebie script, everything.
The number one problem you guys struggle
with is book calls. What if I just
completely took over that process? I
wrote out your DM scripts for every type
of lead that you get and I place a set
that was qualified and trained by me.
You wouldn't even have to lift a finger
and you start booking calls, right? And
so that's why I mentioned the done for
you systems and everything. Instead of
getting my clients to script out their
own inbound script and their own
outbound script and hire their own
setter or learn appointment setting, let
me just find a setter or train the
setter the right way. Get him, you know,
accustomed to the scripts that we create
for the client and just manage the
setter for them. You don't need to lift
a finger, right? And that's what that's
why we charge such a premium service.
That's why we get the result that we
get. Nobody else does this in our space.
nobody, you know, but it's also why I
have to say no to a lot of guys because
I just can't do this for everybody, you
know. So, you get the inbound scripts
and everything and you know, you guys
ask about, okay, how do I create a
special offer and everything? If you
have worksheets where you're talking
about your offer and everything and then
going into chatbt and everything and
helping out, like, how can you not
create an offer that's worth 5 to 10K?
How can you not book three to five calls
every single day? Of course, you can,
right? So, a lot of it is done for you
and that's why people pay. It's the
money that we get paid. So yeah, I don't
know if that went on for a bit too long,
but that's a quick summary.
No, that's that's awesome.
And like I I feel like the fact that you
even just shared that was worth like
thousands of dollars to me at least, you
know, and that's Yeah, that's that's
sick as hell.
Um, one last question for me and then
I'll open the floor to a couple of
questions in the chat. I don't know if
we'll have time for like every single
one because I'm sure like we open the
floor, it's going to be
like tons of questions, but I have a
very quick question. What's your system
for getting referrals? When you say 20%
are of clients are referrals, that's
like that's awesome. That's insane. And
do you have any systems for like asking
for referrals or collecting them in any
way or is it just straight up like they
just did it? I was like I didn't even
know about that.
We have a system. We track referrals and
everything and I have a CSM where I
actually track how many referrals that
each client that he manages gets. If
that makes sense. So the thing is your
business is going to fail because of a
lack of tracking. Right? Every business
if you don't know what your bottleneck
is nine times out of 10 it's because you
don't have you're not tracking enough
numbers. And so when I know that I have
a problem I need to track. Like that's
another topic for another day. But one
thing that we do is as soon as someone
joins, we ask them, okay, like, you
know, I'm excited to have you on. You
know, um, by the way, Devon, do you know
anybody else that would love that would
actually like to make the same
transformation that you're about to make
today? Know, we found that people that
do join or people that do join with a
friend are just way more likely to
succeed and it's just, you know, you get
a nice referral bonus. You get your
friend help as well. You guys are going
through this journey together. It's just
much easier. So, when someone buys in,
that's the second time that they're most
likely to send a referral because
they're excited, they're nervous, and
they want someone to do it with them
because they're going to the unknown.
You can take it. You can actually use
that to your advantage by getting them
to sign up another person, and they get
a referral fee. Maybe they get one less,
one less payment plan option. So,
instead of paying 3K a month time four,
maybe it's only 3K a month time three,
you know, something like that that
incentivizes them. and we asked them
like right after they close. Another way
is we have a referral doc. So, this is
something that I created for one of my
clients, uh, Cruz. He runs a fitness
offer and it's worked [ __ ] wonders.
So, we have, okay, one referral, you get
$500 cash or an extra month of working
with me. Three referrals, you get $1,000
or an extra 3 months working with me.
Five referrals, I fly you out to Miami,
stay 2 days in a high-rise B&B, train,
get a dinner, and hang out. Now, I
scripted this all out for him, right?
The moment these guys join, they're
watching this
video. And then it's a Loom video of
Cruz kind of my my client going over why
he built this referral system, who
should participate, and then going over
specific ways a step by step on creating
a three-way group chat. And so again,
it's very very actionable. You know, you
can ask someone for referral, but if
they don't know how to create one or how
to actually take the action to do it,
they're not going to do it. Okay, so
this is a Loom video that all my clients
watch when they're in the program. So
they do know that they get incentivized
to do to send a referral. And another
thing
is asking asking a client for referral
when they've hit a record month, right?
So, if I if I get someone to go from 5K
to 40K in 30 days, what's going to
happen is they're going to be super
[ __ ] happy with what I have. And I've
created an SOP that basically gets my
CSM or gets me or my VA to reach out to
that person to get on a call and ask
him, "Hey, do you know anyone else
looking to make this transformation?"
You
know, and a lot of my money is actually
made through upsells and referrals. I'm
going to go on a bit of a tangent here,
but this is more advanced and I think a
lot of you guys that are doing 10K a
month, you guys will really benefit from
this. If you get a client 5K to 40K, you
know, and you do that, it's basically
like you going to a restaurant and
eating a [ __ ] steak, you know? You
eat a fat [ __ ] steak. You eat a fat
[ __ ] steak. You're satisfied. You're
you're full. You love everything. Now,
the last thing that you do in that
situation is you try and eat another
steak. like it doesn't make sense,
right? You do not upsell the moment that
you get your client the desired result
they want. No, you don't upsell. You ask
for a referral because when they're full
and when they just had that stake and
they're, you know, feeling good about
themselves and everything, what's going
to happen is that they're going to want
to introduce a friend. You just need to
make that ask. You need to assume that
they already have friends. Don't even
ask who. Don't even ask like if they
know anyone. Just ask who. Like, who do
you know that actually just wants to
have a steak as well? Okay. Boom, you
get the referral. And then you wait for
a few months and you wait till that wait
till that client is hungry again. People
only buy solutions to problems that they
have. When you scale someone from 5K to
40K, you don't sell someone once they've
already solve this problem and once life
is good. No, you sell them when they
have another problem that they can't
fix. So maybe it's sustaining that 40k a
month. That's when I upsell them, right?
So you upsell when the client faces a
problem and you ask for a referral when
the client is satisfied with their with
the solution or whatever. So in a stake
analogy when the client when you're full
or when your client is full with their
steak you ask for referral. When the
client is hungry again that's when you
upsell. Does that make sense?
Dude, that's sauce bro.
That's awesome. And Mino you have a
thousand people in here. So, I mean, if
you use this the right way, double the
business just like this.
Hey, we'll see. We'll see. You know,
we'll see. Uh, no, no promises, but if
you get a DM, bro, you know, don't get
surprised.
No, that's awesome. Okay, we have a
couple questions in the chat. I want to
rapid fire here. Um, yeah, first
question is, how many employees do you
have to handle all your clients? And I
guess I'll bundle in with that question
like full-time versus contractors and
like altogether how many?
Okay. Full-time I have a setter and a
dollar. I pay the guy 5% commission and
$1,000 base. So it adds up to around 4
to 5K a month. The other fulltime is a
VA. I pay my my VA is actually kind of
premium. He's kind of expensive. He's
like 1.8K a month, but that's just cuz
like I give him bonuses and I I like to
get treat my guys well. Um and then I
have a creative director. He's part-time
actually. So, he's just the guy that's
managing all my editors. He's posting
the content for me and I don't want to
[ __ ] like go on IG and just like post
write the caption like nah, you know.
Um, I just want to work on like high
leverage activities. So, I have creative
director that just handles all that. I
have a CSM that handles client work as
well. This guy is also my closer and he
is full-time as well. So, he gets a 3K
month base and then 5% rep share on the
entire business. And then also um 10% of
what he closes obviously. So like 15%
basically. And
then I have a manager who's just just
managing my setters and you know helping
out with with my client setters and
everything. And I pay him 2 or 3k a
month. So yeah, five people. And what
does that total out to?
Not a lot. Like 10 to
20. So margins are still very lean.
Yeah. more.
Let's see. Um, I think this is kind of
related to the question you just
answered, but what advice would you give
at younger you at 15k a month that would
have saved months of time and energy
currently running everything with no
leverage?
Well, enjoy the process first of all.
Um, the reason why I got to where I am
is not because I was obsessed with the
end result. I was obsessed with the
process. I genuinely like if I made if
you told me tomorrow that I'd make no
money doing what I do, I still [ __ ]
do it just for the love of the game, you
know, just because of fulfillment, just
because of impact, just because I
genuinely enjoy my my line of work. And
I think that if you can understand what
your passion really is and just love
what you do every single day, you're
going to get there, right? The man that
loves walking will always get to the
destination compared to the guy that
loves the destination. I took that from
Ramosi. And if you guys couldn't tell,
that's like the guy that I learned from
and [ __ ] Um, but just love [ __ ]
walking and you'll get to where you want
to be, you know? Love what you do. Find
a way to love it. You know, if you don't
like this thing, can you outsource it?
Okay, if you can't, then how can you do
it, you know? So, um, just love what you
do and enjoy the grind because when you
make 100 150k a month, all that [ __ ]
you're going to miss the days when you
were making 10 to 30 or you're going to
miss the days when you're making zero.
and it makes it that much better that
you've been through that phase because
15 150k a month is that much sweeter you
know so yeah I mean just and another
thing is don't compare your first step
to someone's 50th step guys I've been in
the game for 3 years I started when I
was 16 4 years now right I'm 20 if
you're comparing yourself to me and
you're like oh this guy's my age he's
making this amount of money don't make
that comparison because I've been in the
game for four years maybe it's your
first year All right. So, find someone
that's also been in the business and
been in the game for a year. Compare
with him and see what they're doing that
you're not. Comparison is good when you
make comparison that's actually
logical and then when you can actually
take what they're doing that you're not
doing and implement it for
yourself. That's what I'd say. So, don't
fall in the trap of just like comparing
and like, oh, this guy is making more
than me. Like, you know, I want to make
more. I want to make more. Like, if you
always think about how much you're going
to make, you're never going to be happy.
Just enjoy the process. Generally, just
enjoy the process.
That's
fire. This is a question that I I think
this is very applicable to a lot of
people. Uh Henry asked, "How did you get
your first clients and how did you
legitimize myself legitimize yourself
when you didn't have any social proof to
begin with?"
That's a good question. Um you got to
create an offer that's just so hard to
say no to, right? So what what does your
what is the risk of your client not of
your prospect saying no or what what is
the risk that they're thinking of? Okay,
you don't know what what you're doing.
You could have a guarantee in there that
states if you don't make them x amount,
you give them a full refund. Just like
that, you show your confidence, right?
So I'd put a guarantee first of all. And
another thing is it's your mindset. You
know, when I if you look back at the
videos where I was making like 5K a
month or even from zero, I talk the same
way. I always knew I was going to make
this work. I I I kind of faked it till I
made it, if that makes sense. And so I
had the way that I talked and the way
that I presented myself. You think I
have 100 clients when I had zero. It's
just how you present yourself, you know,
and if you're if in your mind you
believe like you think that you can hand
that you've you can get the result and
everything, show the confidence, you
know, have a bold guarantee.
Like my guarantee is if I don't make you
20k a month in revenue, I'll give you a
full refund and I'll pay you an extra 2K
on top of that. That's how bold my
guarantee is, you know? So, if a coach
comes to me and they're scared and like,
"What's the worst case scenario?" You
get paid 2K if it doesn't work out. I
take on the risk. You take on no risk.
So, it's about creating an offer that's
just so [ __ ] it's just so hard to say
no to and then ripping it and just
having confidence and believing in
yourself before it even happens.
Um, there's this book I'm reading right
now. It's called Outsmarting
Reality. You have to believe that you're
at this point before you're even at the
point, right? If like when I made 100K a
month, in my head, I was like when I
made like when I make 100K a month, it
wasn't if. There was no if. It was just
when. And so, believe that you're
already there and you're going to move
with a different type of energy. You're
going to present yourself differently
and everything and it's just going to be
that much easier.
I like that and I think that answers
another question I saw from John Kazama.
How did you develop your valuable skills
and how did you know when you have that
much value? Like I I think it's very
telling that you say it's not
necessarily just about like when will I
get to the point where I've like checked
off the box of having enough valuable
skills or knowledge in order to start
helping or to stop to start selling
and that point won't
come. Yeah. So, the done for you, the
done for you grind is where I developed
majority of my skills. Um, I was writing
VSSLs every day, was writing copy. I
mean, if you guys are watching my
stories, you guys know how [ __ ] good
I am at writing stories and [ __ ] Like,
I had a I posted a story the other day.
I got 500 inbounds and I have 33K
followers, guys. Like, it's just about,
you know, reps and reps and reps. And,
you know, a lot of these a lot of these
questions I can tell it's just mindset.
It's your limiting beliefs. But with
enough volume, you can basically just
have so much [ __ ] proof that you're
good at what you do that you don't even
need to convince yourself otherwise, you
know, cuz you've done it so much. The
the the actions that you've done and
everything has led to this result for
your clients and everything. And it's
like I mean, when I made my guys like
100K, when I scaled them from 5K to 100K
a month, like I didn't even have to
convince myself. It was just there and
people saw it. I was documenting it. You
know, you guys all have Mino to help
with the personal brand. If you document
it, people are just going to throw money
at you. I didn't start consulting
mastery in my consulting business
because I wanted to. I started it
because people told me that they needed
it. The market will tell you the offer
that you need to run if you document
yourself the right way and you present
yourself the right way. And your
confidence in your skill set will be
developed with enough reps and volume
and time in the game. All right,
let's go, dude. I'm going ask you like
one or two more questions. Um, yeah. The
first one is B TOC focused because I
know a lot of this is pretty much B2B,
right? You're working with people who
are doing like minimum 5 to 10K a month,
right? Do you have any experience or
anything to say about funnels for B toC
people like let's say like apps, right?
Or people just selling like B toC
coaching. Maybe it's just like um Yeah,
like a B TOC offer.
You talking about like funnels and
everything? Yeah.
or well it's it's the same thing because
if it works for B2B if it works for a
smarter type of demographic it'll work
for a dumber type of demographic. If
anything, your job is 10 times easier
now because you're selling to mass
market and they don't know the marketing
strategies that you're pulling on them,
right? So, if you generally take my
funnel and what I did to be able to
scale up and you implement it for a B2C
offer, it work like three times better
because my off my funnel is built for
sophisticated people. The people that
you're selling to in the B2C in the mass
market, they're not going to know what
the [ __ ] a VSSL is, right? They're not
going to know what a setter is. They're
going to think it's you, you know? And
so if anything, it'll work 10 times
better. It'll work 10 times better. Um
the most important thing that I'd say
that I recommend you guys set up is
have, you know, have a YouTube channel.
Like a YouTube channel is what's going
to separate you because if someone
watches you for 15 20 minutes, they are
10 times more likely to transact with
you. Put emphasis on YouTube, right? Um
and then have a like outreach to your
followers. You know, ask them what type
of content they enjoy. And the certain
people like they'll just naturally
transition into wanting to buy your
product. You don't even have to sell.
Like when my seller reaches out, we just
lead with value again. And sometimes
they just ask for the service
themselves, you know? So, I'd say just
the same exact funnel, bro. I I wouldn't
stress it. There's nothing different.
And if anything, it'll work
better. Got
you. Um would you say that advice
applies to like um physical products?
cuz we have a couple people selling
physical products here.
Yeah. Um I mean it just depends. It just
depends. Like I think for physical
products you just have to sell based on
emotion. I have a friend his name is
Junior. He runs 100K a month agency that
scales a lot of products and everything
like um ecom brands and everything. And
the way that he's scaled is not even
posting the product. I mean you look at
the biggest products they don't sell the
product. They sell the emotions and what
comes with products. I mean, look at the
Red Bull marketing and everything. Red,
there's not one piece of content that
Red Bull posts that shows the can that
they're selling or shows the drink. They
show the craziest [ __ ] ski stunts.
They show the snowboarding. They show
the, you know, like skydiving, all the
highend adrenaline [ __ ] and that's what
makes you buy. So, if you double down on
content and you understand what feeling
your product, your your product is even
selling and you just 10x that and you
find a way to separate yourself from
everybody else, that's what's going to
get you the, you know, like a oneofone
marketing. Just look at the biggest
brands like Red Bull, see what they're
doing, see how they sell on emotion, and
double down on that.
I like that. I like that a lot. I would
say like
um to to add on to that, right? I I see
this with a lot of like Tik Tok shop
creatives as well.
Like it's it's very high octane energy
in a sense where it's like they're not
saying anything crazy. You look at like
hair pomade products, product ads on Tik
Tok shop, they're not saying like, "Hey
guys, here it is." Like they're breaking
down all the ingredients. They're
talking about all the features. It's
usually some kid just being like, "Oh,
my hair is messed up. Oh, I'm going to
lose all my aura at school. Oh my
goodness, I found this thing." And it
looks really stupid, but it's just like
acting. It's a lot of like playing into
that emotion. And even if it looks a
little funny, silly, corny, it's like it
still triggers some literal like like
evolutionary
biology like trigger where somebody's
just seeing somebody else stressed or
seeing somebody else happy or seeing
somebody else scared and they're just
going to subconsciously respond to that.
They're just like going to watch it. You
see this like Mr. Beast feastable ads,
too. Like it's it's the simplest stuff
ever, but it's just that he gets crazy
reactions of people like geeking out
after they eat like a broccoli flavored
Mr. Beast Fastables chocolate bar. It's
It's simple, but it's showing the
emotion. And yeah, I I think that's
great advice.
Awesome. Um yeah, I guess I want to
finish off this episode with just where
can people find you? If people want to
work with you, what's the next step?
Yeah, I mean you guys can find me on IG.
Uh it's just my name, Su. Uh if you want
to work with me, just DM me. The thing
is we don't work with everybody. Um like
I said, I practice what I preach. So
it's it's very low volume, high quality.
We kind of pick and choose. I would like
I'm fortunate enough to be able to have
that luxury. And so yeah, just just DM
me. Just DM me. Say you came from Mino,
whatever. Um, I don't take my closing
calls right now, but if you came from
Mino, I don't mind running the call with
you if you guys want to work together.
And yeah, it's one of those ones where I
mean, a lot of my free stuff is out
there. You know, a lot of my free stuff
is out there. If it's your first time
kind of hearing me, watch my free [ __ ]
I have a 7-hour course on YouTube. You
know, if you thought this was valuable,
wait till you go through those seven
hours. You know, like I go through
everything in detail. I could only kind
of skim past certain things and kind of
talk about like the overall framework
and everything, but um the the real
sauce is on the YouTube. So, if you
found this valuable and you actually
want to learn how to implement it, go to
the YouTube, check it out. Again, it's
just my name. And yeah, that's pretty
much it. All right, dude. I want to get
one more W in the chat from everybody
who's watching in this uh in this
Discord server. This is also going to be
on YouTube. So, if you're watching this
on YouTube, you're watching the VOD
replay, you can check out all the links
to Sue's stuff in the like in the
description of the video. And little
plug here, but if you do want to join
these kind of live calls where you can
ask your own questions, listen in live
to people who are either making hundreds
of thousands of dollars with Instagram,
with Tik Tok, with social media, or like
learn from coaches and experts who have
hundreds of thousands of followers and
really know either side of those growth
elements of social media. You can click
that first link in the description to
check out what this community is about.
And yo, other than that, yo, thank you
so much, Sue, for for popping in,
dropping all this sauce. I got so many
DMs. I'm probably going to watch this
mod one more time just so I can like
really retain all these things, bro. But
yeah. Yeah. Thank you so much. Thank you
to everybody else who tuned in. Um, have
a nice rest of your day, everyone.
Ter