A hook, very simply, is the first 3
seconds of your video. And if you don't
get people past your first 3 seconds of
your video, your watch time will be
cooked and you're not going to be able
to get any views on your account. I
really want to connect the dot why
understanding hooks is going to lead to
you actually having a career as a
creator. If you do hear about hooks,
it'll always be some gimmicky BS like
this is a visual hook. This is a
challenge hook. Yo, like this is like
the new gimmick for a hook. Yo, use this
zoom effect. Yo, use this like jumping
up and down effect in your hook. I I
actually think that advice is pretty
awful because it's going to make you
rely on gimmicks for your content. You
actually feel like you don't really
understand like why videos actually do
well or don't do well down to their
core. I really want you to understand
genuinely what makes videos do well.
Now, to to really quickly recap why
hooks actually matter down to their
core, because a lot of people don't seem
to understand this either, I'm going to
draw a little graph here that denotes
why hooks actually matter. So, a lot of
times people think, okay, well, the hook
matters because I I don't know. It's
just like it's shocking. It It's got to
be shocking. It's got to be
controversial. But down to the core
principle, the only thing that you need
to understand about your hooks is viewer
retention graphs. Basically, what a
viewer retention graph means is the
percent of viewers that are still
watching, right? So, obviously, you're
going to start off at like 100%. At each
stage of your video, so we have maybe 5
seconds in, we have 10 seconds in, we
got 15 seconds in, we got 20 seconds in,
etc. Why your hook matters so much is
because even if the rest of your video
is great after second 10, your your
video gets interesting after second 10.
So, your retention's great after second
10. Like nobody really falls off after
they watch second 10. Why? Because
something interesting happens. You start
spitting like you actually start
revealing your value. You start like
actually getting into the meat and
potatoes of your video. But you're doing
it at second 10 and it's not really
engaging the viewer. Well then what's
going to happen with your viewer
retention is that even if you have the
most goated piece of video past 10
seconds, what's going to happen is that
you're already going to be at like 10%
retention by the time people reach the
interesting part of your video. And yes,
even if the viewer retention graph
stabilizes, what's still going to happen
is that Instagram or Tik Tok or even
YouTuber is going to see the fact that
everybody left your video, all of these
people, 90% of your viewership left
because your video's beginning was not
interesting. And this is why hooks
matter so much because the rest of your
video does not matter at all. If you
cannot capture their attention within
those first 5 seconds. So this is the
baseline of our entire presentation
today. You need to get their attention
and their eyeballs super hard early on
or else nothing matters. This is all we
are going to focus on in today's
presentation. It's not how to even tell
like compelling arguments. It's not how
to tell long stories. It's literally how
to captivate somebody's attention within
one sentence within 3 to 5 seconds.
Okay. So, now that we understand why
hooks are actually crucial to know, if
we talk about like the importance of a
video, of what actually goes into making
a video, you might think that it might
be like 50/50 like the hook and then the
rest of the video. No, it's
realistically like it's like 8020. It's
like 80% is the hook. Why your video got
a,000 versus 100,000 views. If you are
stuck in 200 view right now, if you are
stuck under 1,000 views, it's because
you are looking at the wrong thing.
You're looking at everything else that's
here. That isn't the hook, right? You're
looking at what music are you using?
What song? Maybe it's the camera
quality. Oh, I need to buy a more
expensive camera. Try some other
gimmick. And the truth is audio quality.
Audio quality is important, but at the
end of the day, actually, these are
still fundamentals that are important,
like audio quality. But nonetheless, if
your video isn't doing like well and
there aren't any glaring issues, yeah,
people think keywords and hashtags
matter. Like, are you serious? Keywords
and hashtags? Just make a better video.
Like why would Instagram or Tik Tok push
out a video that isn't interesting and
inherently like captivating to 90% of
their viewers? Bro, yeah, you can maybe
get an extra like 10% views by using
keywords and hashtags, but at the end of
the day, it doesn't matter. That's not
what's going to get you from 1,000 to
100,000 views. How do you play the game
of next video you get 100,000, a million
views? That is why you need to
understand hooks. And to prove it to
you, for those of you guys have not seen
my socials online, maybe you're new.
I've been creating content for the past
five years across three different
niches. I started off in comedy. This is
my self-development account, right? I
talked about productivity, gym, and then
I talked about social media advice and I
grew an Instagram account like
documenting my business journey, yada
yada yada, right? So, the in order to
grow any of these accounts, I obviously
had to understand how to keep people's
attention. Literally, my average views
on this account is like a million. It's
like 1.2 million views per video. You
average out all the views of every
single video I've ever posted, it's like
1.2 million on this account. So like
when I say I understand hooks like
please believe me it's because I have
been I have studied this voraciously bro
I have made over like a couple thousand
videos on the internet now by this
point. Starting off with C. Starting off
with C. You need to copy viral hooks.
And I don't care what anybody says about
being original, about being creative.
You are not going to learn how to be
viral. You're not going to learn how to
actually captivate people's attention
and move the needle online with your
following if you haven't copied and more
specifically studied why other people
are doing well. And as a result, you're
just shooting in the dark because you
don't have an understanding of what's
good. And if you're starting on social
media, the best best thing you can do is
speedrun your skill set of viral sense.
As in, you need to speedrun your
learning curve of understanding why what
works on social media works. And if you
are still in the frame of this is a
guessing game and nothing else really
matters besides luck or the algorithm
doesn't like me because like my account
is still new, you're you're blaming
these external factors. At the end of
the day, you're going to deny any
learning that you can actually learn.
Lesson number one is copying viral
hooks. Here is the three-step framework.
Step one is you go onto Tik Tok because
on Instagram, the search engine's not
that good and Instagram's algorithm is
actually not that good. It's not as
refined compared to Tik Tok. So go onto
Tik Tok and then scroll for any videos
that have over 50K plus likes. If all
the videos are less than 50K likes,
don't even just scroll them. Like you
can watch it, but like honestly don't
even bother. You want to train your data
set with the best data. Okay? And and if
you think of your brain and your viral
sense as this like kind of GPT
algorithm, right? You you think of your
brain as this kind of like like AI,
right? That's trained on your viral
sense. You need to download as many of
these quality data points as possible.
So, step one, go on to Tik Tok. Step
two, you're going to find all the videos
that have 50K plus likes. And number
three is you're going to make sure
they're all in the style of video that
you want. So, you need to understand
what format you're trying to create and
what niche you are in. Okay? So, for me,
for example, my format is talking,
right? And when I say format, I don't
mean like, you know, this complex
complex thing, you know, are you talking
in your video or are you not? Are you
vlogging or are you more so like
explaining? Are you educating or are you
doing like more of a music montage? That
matters. Like I'm not going to be
studying a cooking like montage video if
I'm trying to make persuasive talking
content about social media. Also, real
quick too, I know you might be thinking,
"Oh, but I only want to grow on
Instagram." Instagram is the only
platform that matters to me. What works
on Tik Tok also works on Instagram,
generally speaking. And the reason why
is because they both are measuring the
the same thing, which is engagement and
watch time. For me, for example, my you
need to know what your format is. And
you need to know what your niche is.
Format equals talking head. And then my
niche for me right now, I would say I'm
in the business niche. Your format can
be talking. It can also be like vlogs.
It can also be like montages with music.
Generally speaking, be able to describe
what you're looking for. We're all going
to use different terminology. Is it
talking? Is it talking head? Is it
how-to videos? Is it list videos? It's
generally we're talking about similar
things here. You know what you're
looking for. You're only looking for
videos with 50K plus likes. and you're
only looking through the format that
you're in and the niche that you're in
or at least similar niches. Like I might
still study videos, you know, talking
about like dating. I might still study
videos talking about fitness because
they're kind of related enough and it's
still a similar format. The the format
matters a lot more than the the niche
because the format is a little bit more
universal. Like if you are a day in the
life creator talking about college, you
can still study 9 to5s, you know, making
day in the life content. It's still
there's still a lot you can study. You
can even still study self-employed
people if you are making content about
your day in the life after your job. You
can still study how the other niche of
creators do it because then you can
transfer over those principles into your
niche. Okay. Most important thing is
identify what format of content you are
making and only study the videos that
you like want to make in that format.
Basically, once you go on to Tik Tok,
you scroll through until you find 50K
plus like videos that are in your
format. Write down all of the hooks and
copy them down. This is going to be your
bank. This is your bank of ideas because
now all you need to do once you have
this bank of hooks is to slap them
together with ideas. So this is your
list of hooks and all you need is a list
of ideas that you can mash together with
those hooks. You need to mash together
ideas with your hooks and then that's
the goal of having these frameworks. So,
for example, if you are tired of
throwing events that nobody else pulls
up to, here's the ultimate guide to
throw in bangers with thousands of
people. Take take notes and thank me
later. We just took one niche and we
combined it with a hook format and that
is a proven viral hook. You've taken
what's already worked on the internet
and you've made your own spin on it.
This is what they call this is what the
pretentious people call stealing like an
artist. And and this is what like loners
call uh the the [ __ ] framework, bro. But
it's really that simple. Note here
though I want to tell you is that you do
want to use words that are pretty simple
and easy to understand because when
things are hard to understand, a viewer
might scroll and you might lose your
viewer retention. Now this is the
difference between good and great hooks
is step three and step four,
understanding and maximizing. Because a
lot of people start with the C, but they
don't reach the [ __ ] and that's why they
don't finish off with a viral video. Yo,
bars, bars. Yo, bars. Bars. Holy [ __ ]
bars. Wow, that was a bar. You can't
just copy. If you just copy, you're not
going to finish off with a viral video
because you need to also understand why
it went viral and maximize your hook so
you can guarantee virality.
Understanding why they actually went
viral. This one is a little bit more
tricky because this is actually requires
you to fine-tune your viral sense. So,
we're going to do a little bit of a game
together here. Okay, guys. What I want
you guys to do with me is watch these
two videos and ask yourself these these
two questions. Okay, the first one is
what keywords did they use to make their
video go viral? Now, what is a keyword?
A lot of I I know there's like the
traditional like key use keywords SEO
blah blah use # SEO.
No, that's not what I mean by keywords.
I mean keywords as in words that trigger
emotion in your viewer. That's the game
we're playing here. We're in We're
playing the game of capturing attention.
I mean, what keywords are used in these
hook examples that I'm about to show you
guys that probably made viewers keep
watching? And I'm just going to play the
first couple seconds of these videos,
and I want you guys to answer with me,
okay?
>> You scared of talking to women? I hate
to break it to you, but it doesn't
matter if you get buff or if you were
taller or if you made a lot of money or
had an
>> There's not just one word that's going
to make or break a video. It's the
combination of them. Okay? I hate to
break it to you. Now, what I want you
guys to do when you study these videos
and see these keywords is write them
down for yourself. If you are in the
niche of dating, of confidence, of
personal development, this is a video
for you to study. Study what words he
used. Oh, he's walking. Let me walk too
in my videos. You know, that's like
level one gooner thinking. Level two
viral sense understanding is knowing
what words triggered the emotions of the
viewer. Does that make sense? Is that is
that sticking? When you see creators
talking about social media advice saying
200 view jail, 300 view jail, like
what's another one? Algo pull. After the
hook of scared of woman, he talks about
common objections. Perfect. Yes. And
once you start understanding the
patterns why this video did well, that's
when you can start training your viral
sense. I'm going to pull up one more
video example.
>> I passed the last year of law school
with high honors despite being an
absolute academic assault rifle and
procrastinating literally every single
exam. And here are the three.
What words are we noticing here? Law
school, high honors, academic assault
rifle. Like, yes, every single word can
be like a, you know, somewhat
interesting word. But there's certain
words that you want to note that did
well and and made it really interesting.
So, what you what you should do now that
you see these examples is take note of
these words and if they're in your
niche, write them down. Use them next
time because you you need to develop the
bank of words that resonate with people.
Okay? And and this is literally what I
did for one of my previous accounts. I
I'll pull it up. when I first started
this account to go from zero to 100,000
followers in a single month. I'm not
even kidding. That actually happened
because I was just printing video after
video after video doing well. Okay. And
literally the format is I took one hook
that did well, which was this one.
Here's how to stop waking up in the
morning, looking in the mirror, and
hating what you see. Stop using your
phone. It was here's how to stop blah
blah blah blah. Here's here's how to
blank. It's here's how to blank. And
once you have the hook framework that
does well, you inject your keywords.
Know what keywords work well in your
niche. If you master this, I can promise
you, you will blow up because this is
the difficult game of content is
understanding what words resonate with
people and what words don't. And oftent
times it's the slightest slightest
tweak. This is a difficult skill. You
want to start practicing this. And I do
want to emphasize this takes practice.
It's not it's not the most attractive
answer. This kind of like repeated
virality comes from a lot of practice.
This is my second account. That that's
why I was able to grow this from zero to
100k followers in in a month. Um, pull
up some examples. Here's how to break
your shitty habits. Clean your
environment. What key word was used
there? Shitty habits, right? And you
could have e I could have easily said
instead of saying break your shitty
habits, I could have easily said
something like here's how to develop
better habits or here's how to become
consistent. But breaking shitty habits
is a type of wording that we go around
saying, "Yo, bro, I just got to break my
shitty habits of drinking every weekend,
bro." No, to be honest, I just want to
break my shitty habits. Like there's
certain wordings that people use that
resonate that are more relatable. And
that's the thing about being relatable.
It's not necessarily, oh, I am a
relatable human being. No, it's like how
do you word things that resonate
emotionally with people? It's like
talking to a friend and not holding back
precisely. It's the words that provoke
emotion. So, it's more about being
casual. Yes. But it also has to be
specific. It's got to really hit. And
this is more of the intuitive process
where you have to start watching a lot
of Tik Toks, a lot of Tik Toks that did
well and seeing why did why did they use
that word? Yo, what was the word that
they used there that just worked? And
and I'm going to show you one more
example here. Mental masturbation.
Chances are if you're watching this
video, you're probably guilty of it.
Mental masturbation. Yeah, I wonder what
the key word was there. I feel like this
is so important and crucial and nobody
else talks about like the hooks like
with this this much like specificity.
Like I wish I got this uh this kind of
training instead of watching those
Robert Benjamin how to get stuck at best
posting times. Oh, post at 3 p.m. and
you're going to get more views.
Bro, I posted half my videos here at
1:00 a.m. Bro, I was filming at night. I
am not going to wait until 3 p.m. Best
posting time, bro. The algorithm does
not give a [ __ ] about what time you
post. Oh, and hashtags, bro. Find a
video where I used the hashtag, bro.
Find a video where I used the hashtags.
It It's not that deep, okay? what you
really need to focus on making good
videos or else you're not going to have
any longevity as a creator because the
thing is you want to get paid by a
brand. You want to scale a business,
right? I really want to connect the dots
between learning this skill and
practicing it because the last thing I
want you guys to do here is leave this
and be like, "All right, I feel
inspired. I feel inspired." And then
like, you know, you don't really take
the action of practicing this because
it's going to take a lot of practice.
You want to do coaching. You want to
sell your books, scale your business,
get design clients. You want influence
and options, create a business, scale a
business, become financially free.
You're going to play at EDC. scale UGC
business, sell digital products, help
people quit their 9 to5, right? You want
to build cool businesses, you want to
create your own freedom, content will
help you do that, but only if you do it
like genuinely with the skill set of
knowing how to consistently go viral.
Guys, this was back in 2022.
This was back in 2022. I I understood
this game back in 2022. And this whole
concept that you're going to fall off on
social media and like social media is
this temporary thing is only true if you
don't understand the game at its core
fundamentals. So guys, if you understand
the game at its core fundamentals and
one of the mo like this this is
literally one of the core tenants of
virality and social media is hooks.
Because if nobody watches past the first
3 seconds of your video, nothing else
matters on social media. I'm sorry. It's
the harsh truth. So understand this and
study this. And here is the [ __ ]
framework to understand how to go viral
with hooks. First, copy the viral hooks.
Write them down. Study the ones on Tik
Tok because Tik Tok search engine is so
good and Tik Tok's for you page
algorithm is really really hyper
tailored. I want you to only find videos
with over 50,000 likes. Yes, you can
write down videos with like over 10,000
likes, too. But like you you want to
train your data set. Like if you're
studying 10 hooks, make sure all of them
went super duper viral. Write down what
format you're doing and then only watch
the videos and write down the hooks of
the videos that performed well in the
format that you're doing. So, if you're
doing vlogs, only watch videos that have
over 50,000 likes and they're a vlog.
And then you're going to culminate a
list of hooks. And yes, hooks can
actually be written down, too. Let's say
even if you're a creator like this guy
and he makes videos that don't really
talk all the time, you know,
right? These videos aren't talking.
These still have hooks. You guys still
have to understand these are hooks. Like
hoax is just writing at the end of the
day. Like so let's find a video that did
actually pretty well. 2015 insecure cuz
the only Asians on screen were nerds and
losers. Guys, how many key words are in
here, bro? He's spamming keywords. He
knows what he's doing when he uses the
word nerd, uses the word Asian, uses the
word insecure, and use the word loser.
And then he pairs it with a picture that
very clearly depicts him looking
younger. All of these stack up so you
can actually make the video hit really
hard. So, you got to understand that
like this skill set too transfers over
not just to my style of content. I I
want you guys to understand that too
that I am not just speaking from like my
day one day X series. Low-key half the
people who do like day one of road to
10K a month, day one of Road to 100K a
month, you have to realize that that's
not a good hook. Like day one of Road to
10K a month is not a good hook. Day 17
of Road to Millionaire is not a good
hook. Yes, it's copying one viral hook
that was used once, but it probably like
it's also just not the best hook in my
opinion. This is somebody who's used
this hook like a bunch of times. It's
not that good of a hook because it
doesn't understand like it doesn't play
into the core principles of why things
actually go viral. So for my niche
before, right, the keywords for example,
right? And the if you if you want to hop
off of this call afterwards and like
this is your literal homework. You want
homework afterwards. Like bro, write
down a bank of keywords and write down a
bank of hooks because you really want to
download what works. So keywords, what
are keywords for for my niche, right?
Like you can even go on YouTube and find
the YouTube titles that use all of these
words like dopamine detox, productivity
hacks, morning routine. These are all
key words. Like 6 a.m. is a keyword, 5
a.m. is a key word, right? This is the
in the productivity niche. And and I say
this because I've been in the
productivity niche. That account I just
showed you was in the productivity
niche. But don't just say like uh get
better or improve. It's very broad. It's
not the best key word. Maybe it's like I
I've seen this one desexualize your
brain. Like that's a key word that just
hits. I actually think mental health
I'll be honest. I don't know if it is as
much in the productivity niche. Like
people like the words like lock in more
than they do mental health from what I
have seen in the in the productivity
niche. Yeah. Like there's certain words
that I think just resonate too. And this
is also might be based on like the age
demo. Like specific words work better
than others. And another thing too is
you just have to doom scrolling. Like
one of the videos that I did recently
that did really well. This one. If
you've been laying in bed scrolling for
the past hour and you feel like you just
ruined the rest of your day, so you have
zero motivation.
>> Zero motivation scrolling. Okay, so
look, understand why they go viral.
Coaching clients have paid me like
thousands of dollars for this and what
I'm about to do with you guys right now.
I genuinely mean it. I I I'm not the
biggest fan of people are like, "Oh, I
give you like a bajillion dollars of
value." But like genuinely, this is like
really advanced. It's really niche.
Okay, here's what I do with my like
coaching clients who pay me thousands of
dollars. I make them do this framework.
this checklist of things that make your
that make your hook hit harder. Number
one, clarity. Is this the most clear and
concise way of wording it? So, how do we
figure that out? We have our hook here,
right? This is our like rough draft of
our hook. Now, we have to rewrite it and
revise it until it's perfect. How do we
do this? Okay, if you're tired of
running your business 24/7 by yourself,
boom, it's a little bit wordy at the
beginning. And I know we're going to
we're about to get super like pedantic
here. It's going to be a little bit
like, bro, like you're so OD, bro. Why
are you looking so closely at those one
or two words? Guys, this is the reason
why certain videos can get 100,000
views, the other one will get 5,000
because it just it there's something a
little bit off about the first few
words. And and I know that sounds so
weird to say. Like I genuinely sound
autistic saying that, but like the
difference between 100,000 views and
like a million views perhaps too can
literally be the matter of like one or
two words. I would say there's probably
another way of wording running your
business 24/7 by yourself. there's just
something that like doesn't resonate
with me. If you are tired of running
your business 24/7 by yourself, and here
is where I would like I would just play
around with different wordings because I
don't know if this has any keywords. Add
keywords that add specificity. What What
are some business keywords alone instead
of by yourself like running your
business 24/7 alone? Like maybe it's at
like 10K a month. Like I know I'm just
I'm spamming keywords at this point. 10K
a month. I like that. I like that a lot.
Burning out. burned out. Yo, if you're
burnt out running your business 24/7
alone, yo, we're getting there. We're
getting close. We're getting close. M we
can we can we can get a little bit
better here. We can get a little bit
better here. If you're broke running a
dying business alone, if you're going
broke running a dying business, automate
your business fully with AI. What words
like are sticking here? Autopilot.
Passive income. Passive income. That's a
word that you could use. Passive income
is associated with automating
everything, right? And sometimes too, we
can even go on YouTube, but let's say we
search up a a niche online or a word
online and then we can just start
studying what all the titles are.
Passive income scam. If you want passive
income, you need this passive income
ideas. $2,000 a day, 67K per week. Boom.
That's literally what that's our sign
that some people like for for some
reason the XK per week. XK per day. If
you're going broke running a dying
business alone, here's how to Here's the
ultimate guide to making your business
fully passive with AI. Passive and
automated with AI, take notes and thank
me later. To building a fully passive
income machine. Building a passive
income machine, fully automated with AI.
Take notes and thank me later. Yo, low
key, that's kind of fire. Like this is
your sign to like start using AI agents.
AI agents. Oh my gosh, bro. People love
the word AI agents right now. Uh we
don't we don't need AI anymore here.
It's redundant. Take notes and thank me
later. This is the ultimate guide to
start using AI agents to build a passive
info machine. Take notes and thank me
later. I The thing is it feels a lot
more specific. You could also do this.
This is the ultimate guide to to start
using AI agents. We've dwelled a little
bit on the clarity and I've introduced a
couple other principles of hitting
harder. Another one is specificity and
numbers. Now, not every single one of
these principles are going to apply
every single time, but you can apply a
lot of these principles of what makes a
video do well. Clarity, specificity, and
numbers. Does this actually align with
the video idea or are you just saying
the hook to like rage bait people?
Because that's also not good. If you get
people to a second three and then after
that the video is completely different.
Obviously it's not a good hook then it
just lied to the viewer. Like clickbait
isn't actually that effective. Who is
your ideal viewer is another one too. We
we we're kind of exploring these things.
We're we're thinking about who we're
talking to. I do want to dwell on this
real quick. Purple cow effect. And it's
a concept called purple cow effect. What
purple cow effect refers to is when
something seems novel. And when
something seems novel, it generally will
stick out and capture somebody's
attention. So, when you're driving, for
example, you're not going to to notice
90% of the cows and cars that pass by,
but if you notice, if there is a purple
cow, even if it's in the distance,
you're going to notice it. That's kind
of what you want to create your video
into if you want it to truly stand out.
It needs to have some sort of
uniqueness. And this is where
specificity and numbers actually can
help because specificity and numbers
helps your video stand out. So, if you
have a personal result and number tied
to this, it would be even better. Take
notes and thank me later. I like taking
notes and thank me later. It's a little
bit of a super hook there. [ __ ] you,
money in your sleep. Perfect. Perfect.
And now this also kind of leans into
this like purple cow syndrome because
it's just different. Like who has said
that you're going to use AI agents to
make [ __ ] you money in your sleep? And
who's who's ever made an ultimate guide?
Like maybe if you just said start using
AI in your business, it wouldn't hit as
hard. AI agents specifically makes it
stand out. So there we go. Yeah. And
then you can follow up with a sentence
like thousands of kids just like you are
using a AI agents to make 10K per month
but you're just too lazy to set it up.
Then you have to back the claims that's
true. So obviously you need to have this
kind of video and hook alignment because
if it's just straight capping then it's
not going to work. And then lastly, can
we use visuals to make it easier to
understand or more captivating? If this
is making sense, okay, if it's starting
to click, I know we're covering a lot. I
I know it might feel like a good amount
where there's a lot of work ahead of
you, right? We learned why hooks are
important. Because if you don't
understand hooks and you focus on the
20% that doesn't [ __ ] matter, then
your video's retention is never going to
reach past 5 seconds. And Instagram and
Tik Tok are never going to actually deem
your video good to watch because it
doesn't make it past 5 seconds. And then
in order to write good hooks, the number
one thing you can do is to copy the good
ones that you see online. After that,
right, we learned about why it's
actually helpful. We we learned how to
understand why things go viral. We
practice finding key words and then
after that we learned how to maximize
our hook and make it 1% better. And
another practice you can do is just read
it aloud multiple times. It's kind of
tedious, but read your hook aloud five
times. Does it just sound like it it
feels right? Does it does it sound like
it makes sense or is it still a little
bit iffy? Okay, ask yourself that. Here
I'm going to actually draw a graph of of
uh what what happens when you actually
want to grow on social media. So each of
these is going to denote a month. Okay,
and and I know that's kind of annoying.
You have to take action, bro. You have
to take action. Okay, so look at this.
Look at this. Ready? This is going to be
your average views, right? And here it's
going to be like uh 10K, right? This is
going to be 100K. I know the graph is
not like mathematically accurate
looking, but just bear with me. So, I
want to show you a trend that I have
noticed from literally observing. We
have 520 creators, 530 creators actually
in our program. Half of them are like
starting off for the first time fresh
when they join. And then some of them
have like posted a little bit, but they
want to gain traction. they want to get
better. So, here's what I generally
notice from creators in our in our
community. So, let's say you're starting
off here. What's going to happen is that
on month one, you're basically going to
get no traction. You're going to be at
like 1K average views, right? It's going
to feel like, bro, like what what am I
even doing? It's a waste of time. And a
lot of people at this point, they're
going to reach this like sticking point
where they're learning the hooks,
they're learning cinematography, they're
learning filming, they're learning
editing. We all here want to hit like
10k followers here. We want to make all
these big metrics, but but look, a lot
of times we're going to set these big
goals, right? Right here is where a lot
of you guys are, right? And all of these
things are making it really really hard
to stick with it and learn. So, a lot of
times what I see with people in here and
and I I say this out of genuine love is
that at a certain point it just gets
difficult and tedious. And that's why
all of this learning is low-key like it
it might actually just make you
overthink. Now that we know what a good
look is, it actually can still feel like
daunting because now we're like, [ __ ]
we're a perfection. We're in the
perfectionist mindset now. And we're
like, you know what? Maybe I won't post
for the next week and I'm going to
figure it out. I'm I'm going to figure
out what a what a good hook is. I'm
going to I'm going to learn. I'm going
to like get better. And then what ends
up happening is like now we're trying to
get back into it. But then we we start
back up and we're like, "Ah, it only got
1,000 views. Yeah, you know what? Maybe
I'll take another break for a little
bit. I got other stuff to work on. I got
like exams coming up." And then we tried
a little bit there and then boom. It's
like, you know, and and what ends up
happening over the long term is we just
have these like, you know, the the
breaks become even longer in between and
it ends up just we're in the we're in a
loop. It's a cycle. And I know this
because the biggest thing that people
talk about is unlocks, strategy, hooks,
bro, but you haven't even posted past
like one or two months consistently. And
it's just like it it's literally edging
your learning. Like unfortunately is
just like what it's like to learn any
new skill. But I want to show you what
happens when you actually stay
consistent with it. Month one and month
two are still going to look generally
the same, right? It's it's literally
going to feel like this. But at the very
least, you are being consistent through
these plateaus. Okay? So, you're not
quitting when it gets difficult. You're
not coming up with these weird excuses
to not take action and you're just
staking through it. What happens during
this actual one to two month phase?
These are the things that happen. start
to actually learn what makes a video
good versus bad to the algorithm, right?
You're going to start to learn that the
basics of editing. Like a lot of people
don't like editing, too, but you're
going to learn the basics of it, and it
gets so much easier once you actually
learn it. Okay? So, even when you do
learn it, it's still going to be
difficult. You're going to start to
learn hooks. You're going to start to
learn scripting, camera confidence, and
all of these skills might not translate
to directly more views in month one or
two, but I genuinely see it all the time
that there is this weird effect that
genuinely happens on like month 2 to
three where things just click. But Edd's
a great example. He just hit 10K
followers, right? After being constant
academy for 60 days, right? Just hit 10K
followers. Let's [ __ ] go at 66 posts.
Damn, he's at 11.9 already. This can be
you. However, he posted 66 times. That
means or maybe a couple of these aren't
like post posts, but like around 60
times in 2 months. It's been 2 months
and he's posted 60 times. Do do you see
the correlation between that consistency
and actually having that growth? Because
once you actually learn the
fundamentals, what ends up happening is
this. You hit your flow. And this is one
of those things where it's genuinely
really hard to reach that point, but
once you get momentum, it just does like
the ball is rolling. You know the
fundamentals now. You know what makes a
video good and bad. You know the basics
and you're going to think like, bro, I
exhausted all of my good ideas on day
like between day one and day 30. Bro, I
don't have any ideas. All my good ideas
are bad. And you got to understand that
the first 30 days, it really doesn't
matter what you're posting because
you're just learning the fundamentals.
So, I know it can be very discouraging
and that's probably why a lot of us are
here to learn hooks because we think
that the unlock is going to come from
just like one tuning one tuning into a
call, one tuning into a class. It's
going to change everything. But what
actually works and this is the way we've
even designed Content Academy is to
focus a lot more on the daily
iterations. That's literally why every
single day we have people posting
content into our content reviews and
then getting it getting feedback from
other members because it's a lot about
the iteration and it's not just about
this like bro if if I could give you a
product if I could sell you a product if
I could give it to you for free even if
I could teach you one hour of a class
and then help you go from here to here I
wish I could and somebody would have
already developed it by now okay like
unless you want to buy followers which
in which case like what the [ __ ] is the
point of buying followers you know
you're not actually building anything
subst substantial. There is no magic
pill that's going to do that's going to
make this. Okay, that doesn't exist.
What really exists is this green graph
of growth where things might actually
look like this for even like 6 months on
and then later on it can take off,
right? This is another example. Prosper
started his first 60 to 90 days of
creating content at 3,000 followers and
he was stuck there. He was stuck there
for a while, not getting even 10,000
views per video cuz he was working a job
12 hours a day in the summer knocking on
doors. He was literally knocking on
doors, selling pest control for 90 days,
but he still posted every single day. He
only took like one week off during that
time. He's inspired so many of our
creators to to actually take action and
grow. But what you guys probably don't
see past him literally having grown like
20 or like what like 250,000 followers
since like the start of this year or
300,000 followers since the start of
this year is this base. And trust me,
we're going to keep going back. We're
going to keep going back. We're going to
keep going back to the phase where he
actually was just starting out. Prosper
used to make videos knocking on doors
with a road to 60K series. And you might
see his blow up now. Yo, how do I
replicate that today? And yes, we can
learn from what other people have done
right and wrong. But you have to
understand day 18, day 17, day 16, day
15. Bro, he was so consistent. He was so
consistent. and he and these videos
obviously have more views now because
they were kind of inflated after like
you know he gained followers and whatnot
but like for the first like 30 days
there wasn't much growth and it was this
like tough plateau but you what you have
to understand about committing to this
journey results aren't going to come but
you're going to learn so many of the
fundamentals during these kind of videos
you're going to learn the fundamentals
of lighting right he's standing in front
of good lighting he's going to learn how
to do B-roll he's going to learn how to
put captions with the little shadow
behind it and you can tell the videos
are definitely not as good-looking as
they are now right same with every
single other creator who's ever grown.
Now you look at his page now and you're
like, "Oh my goodness." Like these
videos are so well shot. You see this
one and you're like, "Wow." Like, like
it looks cinematic. The lighting is
crazy. The colors are crazy. The editing
looks good. What you don't see is this
phase of the first couple months. Okay?
What you don't see is the phase of the
first couple months. And that's why I
really want to emphasize as confusing as
it is right now, I just want to
encourage you practicing is just as
crucial to learning as it is like you
know just actually just sitting here and
learning and and these are actual
examples from the content academy where
a lot of people right we teach people
how to get views right and a lot of
people might just see oh you know one
video what what is that going to give me
dude you know one video with 30k views
one video with 40k views a video with a
million views even right like that might
seem like okay it's not that crazy right
just getting like a couple Like these
are all from our wins channel, but that
eventually translates into the follower
growth, right? Like Aaron who hit 10,000
followers. Alex who hit 10,000 followers
and then Henry hit 16,000 followers.
Like after 77 days of posting, Thomas
went from 500 to 10,000 followers. Kevin
woke up with 40,000 followers. Look, he
was printing. And you you might see all
these crazy results now, but what I just
want you to understand is that it's
built from this turultuous grind. And I
want you to keep your northstar as well.
Why do you want to like if you actually
grew the following that you you wanted,
right? A lot of people said 10,000
followers, 25,000 followers by the end
of the year, if you actually achieved
that, what would that look like in your
life? What what would that change? And
then I'll show you what it changed for a
lot of our our members after they hit
their follower goals, after they hit
their growth. But what would that
tangibly change in your life? Because I
think it's important to remember why
you're doing this content thing. And
it's not just you're like shooting in
the dark hoping for something to work,
but then you don't even know why you're
doing it. Content has honestly been one
of the best like personal development
tools for me as well because I genuinely
feel like it's forced me to understand
myself, push me past like these social
anxiety that I used to have. But I was
scared of even raising my hand during
like class discussions in high school. I
want you to remember that. I want you to
remember your purpose because genuinely
when I say content changes lives, like
these are all people in the content
academy as well. Joe, he raised his
first check for his business, right?
After spamming videos on reals. This is
literally at 6,000 followers. He raised
a check for his business and his
business. It's like a uh it's an AI SAS
called Flutify and I think they're doing
like 70K a month, right? He started off
literally at zero dollars a month with
this SAS and just by posting content he
was able to grow it. Another one, this
dude just got recognized on Hinge. I
thought that was funny. Anderson, he has
like 10K followers or something on on
Instagram, but he just got recognized on
Hinge. I thought that was funny. Rajan,
you guys might have seen his content
before. Rajan Cheetah, he started off in
Content Academy, too. Like I I want to
say less than 10,000 followers. So, he's
an absolute beast as well. He was
literally saying how content because he
put in those reps of posting how many
times? 185 plus posts. He started
collabing with Bill Gates's daughter.
Like the amount of rooms that you're
able to get into too, it it genuinely is
life-changing. Henry making his first
dollar online after he grew 16,000
followers in like 90 days. Leo, he did
UGC for a pub and literally got 1.5 bans
just to make a video having a pint with
his boys. Gave made $80,000 in a single
month just from his agency. Like a lot
of the leads came from his personal
brand. book. Paul Wilkinson made a
$20,000 B2B sale. It's genuinely
life-changing what you can do with uh
with building your personal brand. But I
don't want you to focus on this. I want
you to focus on this. Focus on just
improving your skill set video by video.
And over time over time, it's genuinely
going to stack up. Okay? I want to give
you guys a couple a couple hacks for
actually staying consistent, too.
Because none of this actually matters if
you're not able to stay consistent. And
if you genuinely do feel like you you
want that extra push for staying
consistent and improving and get the
same results that all of these people
have gotten, that's why we have content
academy. And this is literally why like
we have this entire program of content
academy and this entire community this
entire community that all of these
people like sending wins literally every
single every single day. This video
across all channels had over 600,000
views. We host our inerson events. But
the reason why we do everything that we
do in content academy and we don't just
have like these kind of live classes or
or we just have course modules for
example like yes we have an entire like
fiveweek boot camp where you can watch
videos just like this breaking down not
just like hooks but everything else from
filming to editing filming to editing to
scripting to storytelling. We we do
cover all of that and monetization as
well. But the reason why we don't just
have that is because it doesn't actually
help you take action. And one of the
most important things when actually
growing in content, like I said, is
being able to stay consistent. So if if
Content Academy was just a 5we boot
camp, we would not get the results for
our clients and for our students that we
actually do. The reason why Content
Academy actually works for people is
because we have our support system.
Okay? And this is something that like
I'm genuinely so proud of. But
basically, if you are looking for that
community who's actually going to keep
you accountable on a week- toeek basis
when things get hard, when things get
busy, when things get confusing, is our
three-point support system in Content
Academy. We have a one-to-one support
manager, Justin. We have live coaching
calls four times a week with me, with
Gabe, who I pulled up his uh his win
earlier. He has 20,000 followers, but he
also has an agency doing $100,000 a
month. So, if you want any business
advice or monetization advice, he's a
great resource to talk to. We have Sam
who has over 200,000 followers on
Instagram, Prosper who has over 350,000
followers on Instagram, and then I host
one live weekly call as well in the
content academy. So, if you want that
weekly support with literally four touch
points every single week live on calls
and of course a popping freaking Discord
community of people who are actually
bought in, people who are actually
locked in, then Content Academy is
probably like has the exact support
system for you. And that's why we've
designed it in the way that we have
where we're so focused on community
because at the end of the day, if you
just have knowledge and you have this
bank of information, but you don't have
any way to continuously implement it, it
really is useless. And and I I genuinely
wish I could give you one dime of
information that would help make this
happen, but it doesn't. It happens with
your effort and it happens with you
actually staying consistent and
continuously learning. So we have these
systems to help you continuously learn,
but we also have these systems to help
you stay accountable and also
continuously improve with the inputs of
everyone else who has already walked
that journey. So if you do want to join
content academy, uh you can join in the
hashtag upgrade channel. If you want to
write your hooks with AI, it's trained
on these viral hooks, but it's also
trained on Claude for Sonnet. So, it's
like it's one of the best like models
for writing.