This is my honest advice if you want to
start a personal brand in 2025. For
those of you guys who are a little bit
new here, am I just another personal
branding guru who sells a course? Yes, I
am. But I actually do have 5 years of
social media experience. So, for those
of you guys who don't know, who haven't
seen my content before, account in
comedy, account in self-development/
like vlogs, a one last account that grew
to 147k followers about Tik Tok growth,
about personal branding advice. So, I do
want to assure you guys that you're not
taking advice from somebody who
literally like blew up from making how
to go viral on social media content. I
[ __ ] hate that. This is going to be
my honest advice from 5 years of posting
on social media. I've gotten over 500
million views across all my accounts on
Tik Tok and IG. And I've also made
$500,000 via Tik Tok and Instagram. It's
probably a little bit more like we round
it down because five is like hella hella
cool and stuff like the whole theme of
this presentation is five. We have five
phases in this presentation. So, the
first step to building a personal brand
is ask yourself why. I know it sounds
corny, but hear me out. Is it clout?
Impact? Is it money? Is it purpose? Ask
yourself this. What is your genuine
authentic reason why you want to grow a
personal brand? And like, be honest with
me. Like, if it's money, it's funny. If
it's cloud, it's clout. If you actually
do want to make an impact, be honest
about that too. Own that [ __ ] If you
actually do want to make an impact, if
you want to have purpose as well, like,
oh, you feel a little bit purposeless in
your life. That was me when I was
starting my content as well. So, for me,
I would say it genuinely was like a
purpose- driven personal brand. But when
I first started, bro, I wanted clout so
badly, dude. I was a 16-year-old who had
zero motion in high school. Never had
any like kind of motion or whatever you
call it, bro. Like, I just wanted clout,
dude. I saw kids who had like hella
views across from the town across. I was
like, damn, bro. This guy got a million
views on a Tik Tok, bro. He's famous. I
want to be Tik Tok famous. So, it's
okay. Like, own your purpose because if
you like try to deny what you really
want, I actually think that can like
[ __ ] up your motivation. But guess what?
It doesn't really matter why you want to
build a personal brand when you're first
starting. I know that sounds crazy, but
it does not [ __ ] matter what your
like goals and purpose are with your
personal brand when you are first
starting. And the reason why phase one
of building a personal brand is posting
random [ __ ] Your goal in phase one of
posting content online is to lose social
aura and post a 100 times. I am not even
kidding. Your goal should be to lose as
much social aura as possible. [ __ ] all
of the content strategy that you content
gurus out there will tell you to say to
do. The three pillars of the content
strategy. Shut the [ __ ] up, bro. No.
Your goal is to lose social aura. And
the reason why is because in phase two,
you will actually find what you actually
want to do. But everybody wants to like
jump to phase two for some reason where
you're like a hella like, "Oh, bro, I
had the most like fire content. Like,
everybody loves me and I have hella
clout." But you cannot do that without
losing your aura first. I know it sounds
backwards. No, your goal should be to
lose social aura. And to prove it to
you, I'm going to show you the first
ever post that I ever posted on social
media. It's about to be hella
embarrassing, bro. 2020 of April. And
let me just show you what the hell I was
posting, bro. What the hell yeah I was
posting. I was posting these random
duets. I was like, bro, this shit's
going to go viral, bro. Yo, this Yo,
this one's going to go viral, bro. This
one's going to go viral. It's not okay.
This was actually like, you know, it was
just like a normal ass video, low key,
but you're going to see like all like
the weird [ __ ] I posted, bro. I think
the song here was like monsters.
how you feel.
>> Bro, it's April 2020. I'm a 16-year-old.
Zero motion, bro. Zero girls interested
in me, bro. But it was chill because I
was losing hella social aura, bro. What
the [ __ ] was this, bro? 26 likes, too.
Like, most people don't don't know this,
right? Cuz you see like me posting like
hella serious content now, right, on my
page. But like, this was what I was
posting in 2020. The trending audios,
random like me lip-syncing videos, the
duets. Bro, that is what you should be
doing right now. Have fun and don't give
a [ __ ] about how how you're being
perceived. I know that sounds like so
simple, okay? But I I'll show you the
connection to why this actually helps
you build a personal brand. You can see
this is the same banana I was I ate the
banana
and then I [ __ ] threw it out the next
video. What even is this video, bro?
2020 April, bro. What even is this?
And you can see after you post like a
bunch of videos, you're going to start
getting like, oh [ __ ] this one got 800
likes, bro. The algorithm actually
picked up my video, bro. I got like 10k
views on this, bro. And then the next
one, I got 47k likes just doing like
random [ __ ] This is hella random, bro.
So, this is what it's going to look like
when you first start posting. Maybe it's
not like this. Like, I was literally 16
posting memes, but like like this is
what your content's going to look like
early on, bro. Bro, are people going to
come up to me and be like, "Yo, like
bro, you make fire content, bro." Then
they're going to be like, "What is this
kid doing? Half of these videos,
>> bro. This is too funny. This is phase
one. You have to lose your social aura.
Dig yourself into a hole socially so you
just stop giving so many shits about how
people perceive you, dude. And I swear
this matters. Okay, this actually helps.
It's corny until you make it, you know?
It's corny until it works. As cliche as
it sounds, but like you have to like
bask in the art of being corny. And I
think like phase one is just practicing
that. No, you don't have to make this.
But I tried a ton of different content
styles and this is one of them.
>> I ain't never seen two pretty best
friends. It's always one of them got to
be ugly. So, this was 5 years ago, okay?
16 years old. And you start to learn how
to make videos. Like, I learned how to
edit with this video. I learned how to
match cut, bro. Okay, that was pretty
tough, actually. I [ __ ] with that video
heavy. [ __ ] I do kind of look like JP.
JP is known in the K-pop industry to be
like the ugliest [ __ ] Like a
guy who looks like an absolute goblin.
The goal is to lose social aura. And I
like genuinely made that unintentioned
because my goal back then in life was
just to become more confident as a human
being, like as a person. So I wouldn't
be as embarrassed talking to strangers,
making friends, talking to girls. It was
literally just to lose social aura. But
it actually correlates to your content
success, too. The less that you actually
give a [ __ ] about how you're being
perceived, le the less you're going to
care if your videos flop, the less
you're going to care if you look stupid
and actually try in your content. And
that's a huge thing. Yes, obviously this
like I was being like a hella unserious
here. It gave me the practice of like
showing up online and just having my
face seen online. This made me zero for
the first two years. I literally made
like no money for the first two years.
Okay? And you can see here too, like
this is another example of losing social
aura. This was September 2022 when I
actually started my real Instagram
account. Now, that was related to my
purpose. Okay? And this relates back to
phase two, which is find what you
actually want to do. Finding the niche
that you actually want to go into. So
for me, I was like, "Okay, I want to get
into the niche of self-development. I
want to get into the personal growth in
proc in the process of starting this
personal brand about what I genuinely
wanted to do. I made posts like this. I
actually turned off the comments because
it was like hella embarrassing, bro.
Like I had like friends from school
seeing this. I was just like, "What am I
doing?" But read, you can read it here.
I think I owe anyone who follows this
account on apology, bro. Who the [ __ ] am
I apologizing to? Like 200 people. The
reason why I haven't been posting is
since August 9th, I've fallen off my
good habits and I haven't recovered any
momentum. I didn't meditate throughout
most of August. I jacked off multiple
times a week. TMI, I know. I'm sorry,
bro. I would like talk about how I like
I would like relapse to porn addiction.
Like, yes, this is actually being
recorded. DS is being recorded. You can
see I was literally just posting like
journal entries when I first started.
And this is another example of like
losing your social aura, bro. Like, this
was my like this was me when I first
started content, too, by the way. But
yeah, like I would just post like hella
embarrassing [ __ ] on myself. And yes,
there was actually purpose behind it.
But what I want to highlight is that
like I did make a very conscious effort
to push myself past my like comfort zone
in terms of I was comfortable sharing
online. And I think that's like a huge
key with content especially when it
comes to personal branding like impact
driven personal growth kind of content
or even if you make content about
business even if you make content about
like other things like fitness. I I
think the people who are genuinely the
most real online succeed and I think
that's a skill that you can like build
up. I would view phase one before you
even find out what you actually want to
do. If you don't know what you want to
post about yet, you don't know what your
like grand life purpose and vision is,
that's fine. Just lose your social aura
and post a 100 times. If you have a
passion for posting content, this is one
of those necessary candid events that
you're probably going to go through,
which is either like posting some hella
embarrassing [ __ ] or getting hella hate.
So, phase two is then when you find out
what you actually want to do. And this
is where you choose a niche. Okay, this
is where you choose a niche. Now, here
are examples of valid niches. We got
fitness, lifestyle, college vlogs, high
school vlogs, 9 to5 vlogs,
entrepreneurship, marketing, Amazon FBA,
tech reviews, intern vlogs, if you're
working like a summer internship, comedy
skits, cooking, Arabic content, poker,
dating, traveling, language advice. The
reason why I'm saying all these niches,
and yes, there's many, many more, right?
Because the method today we'll learn
works in all of these niches. And the
reason why I know this for a fact that
it works across all these niches. And I
know a lot of people in the chat right
now said their niche is somewhere along
the lines of these is because we've
literally taught creators in our
community in all of these niches.
Prosper, he made study content and then
he made content about dating. Right.
This is Thomas. He made content about
Amazon FBA, productivity content, poker
content. Uh this is the Arabic content I
was telling you about. Yeah. Like
literally content in Arabic. We I told
one of my clients in the past like, "Yo,
switch up your content. don't like it's
actually okay to do it in Arabic. And
then he did it and then boom, he blew up
because he was making content in Arabic
about his entrepreneurship journey.
Aaron, Techline OG, shout out the boys.
He's in the community too. He makes he
makes tech content, tech review content.
And then we also have Allison who made
high school studying content. Now once
you understand what you actually want to
do and you have posted 100 times, so
you've like successfully kind of lost
what like you don't have anything to
lose anymore. Okay? And that's like
lowkey kind of important in my opinion.
It's the same concept as like burning
the boats in business or burning the
ships. If you simultaneously are trying
to juggle getting consistent with
posting while also trying to maintain
like a semblance of like not looking
embarrassing, you're fighting against
like the fear of failure simultaneously
because on one end you're you're afraid
of failing. You're afraid of flopping
and for everybody seeing your videos
with less than a,000 views. And I I say
that fully being me. So, you're
simultaneously afraid of posting stuff
that doesn't get motion, that doesn't
have views, and it looks embarrassing
cuz now your page is flopping and
everybody's seeing your content and
they're like, "Yo, bro, like I like the
content stuff you're doing, bro. Keep it
up low, bro. Keep it up low, bro. I'm
supporting you from afar, low, bro." And
you're just like, "Fuck, bro. This is so
embarrassing. I'm trying my hardest.
Okay, I get I don't have that much
motion right now. Chill. Okay, chill."
It's hard to balance the desire not to
be perceived that way and also to show
up consistently because you have to
choose one. you're either going to suck
at the beginning and lose your social
aura in the process of becoming good at
this social media at this content
creation thing or you're just going to
not post consistently. So phase three,
however, is once you've gone through
that brutal phase, finding out what you
actually want to do by posting a [ __ ]
ton and then flopping a [ __ ] ton is when
you can double down on what actually
works for you. So phase three is
doubling down and specifically doubling
down and learning, bro. Okay? Cuz your
goal in this phase is to understand
content creation as a science. And I
actually think it's okay to start caring
about views at this point. Once you know
what you want to create content about
and you actually have a little bit of
proof of concept, I'm talking videos
around like 1 to 10k views is when you
can start trying to consciously care
about views so you can learn the science
of attention and the psychology of
attention through scripting, through
filming, through editing. You want to
get to phase three. You want to get to
phase four where you can double down on
the content that works. Learn content
creation as a skill set and then start
getting better better views and you
start having traction. This is when like
you actually can like start growing a
personal brand. And everybody looks at
the at the creators who have a good
amount of views. Oh, they have a
personal brand, but nobody ever talks
about phase one and two, which kind of
sucks ass. It kind of suck. It It sucks
d where you're just like, bro, like this
sucks. I'm losing my aura and I feel
like I'm not even learning. I feel like
not even progressing, right? And
everyone sees the Daniel Dalens, oh, I
want to copy his content strategy, not
knowing that he like lost his social
aura first before he got social aura
because you get socially validated once
you make good content. unfortunately or
fortunately. And you can see here now
the views are actually good. But that's
after I've skill stacked for like many
many repetitions of my content looking
really weird. And once again, by my
content looking really weird, I I mean
literally like just posting random [ __ ]
And mind you, I actually had another
account while I was posting this one. So
I was posting on two different Tik Tok
accounts about comedy and random [ __ ]
posting. Even though this period looks
like it was only 30 videos, trust me, it
was around like 200. I actually posted
around 200 videos in this phase, posting
a bunch of random [ __ ] But then because
I lost it, it was like really really
weird. I was scared that my college
admissions would get rescended, so I
deleted that account. But I actually had
a fourth Tik Tok account, believe it or
not. That's the sign that somebody
actually will like go long-term as a
creator when they care about their
internal state more so than just how
many views am I getting? How many views
am I getting? Because you're going to
burn out if you're just motivated by the
views. Especially because you're not
going to like you're not going to be a
content genius when you first start.
Like I'm sorry, your viral sense is not
going to be tuned. You're going to be
editing stuff in Cap Cut for the like
first and second time. It's just going
to look not that good. And it's
obviously embarrassing when you post
stuff that isn't like super your your
vision for your content is up here and
you have all of these artistic visions
about these beautiful shots that you're
going to make, these beautiful poetic
scripts that you're going to write and
the most expressive version of yourself
that you want to show on the camera, but
then you show up on camera and then you
just sound really anxious and you sound
really awkward and then you write out
your script and it doesn't really make
sense. And then you film, but then for
some reason your shots just don't look
like these cinematic creatives that you
love and you you're trying to figure out
what the actual disparity is. So phase
three is doubling down in learning. But
in order to actually get through that
phase of doubling down in learning, I
think you do have to lose your social
aura first. And that's why your goal
should be to lose social aura and post a
100 times. Losing your social aura,
posting really random [ __ ] right?
Posting really embarrassing [ __ ] Like
what the [ __ ] is even like what is this
account? Just posting and forcing
yourself to show up. Express yourself
online. And I think that like really
matters. I had never posted like any
pictures of myself like with my shirt
off ever on the internet before this,
you I didn't want to be like one of
those like cringe like oh like bros
trying to be a gym influencer. Bro's
trying to be a fitness influencer. I was
like [ __ ] it bro that's like hella
cringe but like [ __ ] it. We ball. Now
this is a question of the century that
we're about to ask ourselves here. When
can I start making money from my
personal brand? Like don't think of this
as like, bro, I have to make it like my
full-time job. No, but you can start
making money from social media. And I
think a lot of you guys have probably
seen stories of people online talking
about how they make a lot of money from
social media. I talk about it very
often, right? So, I am guilty of this,
but it kind of plants the seed probably
of you being like, "Damn, I want to
start making money from social media,
right? We got Jojo here, who got paid
for his first ever UGC opportunity." We
got John, who also got his first ever
UGC check. They they were both dropping
their wins in the chat. We had Ned, who
I think in his first month's earning of
UGC was he made I think 1.6K. And then
also Andrew in his first ever month
doing UGC, I think he made like 12K
total in his first ever month doing UGC.
These are all Content Academy members.
So, you're probably wondering like, "Yo,
when can that me be be me, bro? How does
that work? How does that work?" And I
actually think like UGC is the best
opportunity if you are starting out like
content creation. You're in like le
you're less than six months in. I think
instead of like trying to sell digital
products, instead of trying to attract
brand deals, I think UGC is probably the
best opportunity in my opinion from what
I've seen running a community of people
who are all trying to learn how to make
content creation into some sort of
income for themselves. And my answer is
like lowkey you could start now. Like I
know a lot of you guys like probably 50%
of everybody here is like still in like
phase one. And the thing is like you can
still learn like you can start
monetizing now. I actually do want to
like make that clear. You can start
monetizing now. What is UGC? You see
these people that I'm bringing up in the
content academy like John who was
posting about his first UGC check,
right? Making his first dollar online.
UC is simply making money for brand or
making videos for brands and then
getting money for it. You're getting
paid because you made a video for a
brand. And it really is that simple. So
the two things you need to know is
simply how to attract or how to find
opportunities rather whether it's
through outreaching to brands who are
looking for creators or applying through
partnerships or applying through
websites. So a good website that I've
heard of is Sideshift that allows you to
look for these UGC opportunities that
are listed online. We actually also do
have a UGC guide in Content Academy,
right? And we also do post like
partnership opportunities inside content
academy in our Discord server. So if you
join a community like Content Academy,
subtle plug, right? Or if you can go to
a website that's free like Sideshift as
well. You can apply to these
opportunities. Now the thing about UGC
like you might think oh [ __ ] John might
have like bro like bajillion followers
like maybe it's like oh [ __ ] like you
just got to be goated and stuff like no
you lowkey don't. A lot of these brands
who hire UDC creators they don't even
require you to have like 10k followers.
They don't even require you to have 5k
followers. They require you to simply
know how to make good content. Right? I
want to reiterate this too. Back to my
point before double down and learn, bro.
like posting on your personal brand is
one of the best ways to learn content
creation. Then you can also start
applying that skill set into UGC and
then start making money from it. So a
lot of these guys had like maybe 2 3
months worth of content experience from
their own personal brand and then they
applied to a UGC opportunity. However,
I've seen UGC o UGC creators who
literally never posted content before
and then they joined programs like
Kulies for example. Clue is like an app
who it's running a UDC program as well.
And they literally hired a creator who
had never posted any videos before.
Those some of those creators actually
have become excellent at creating
content for Cluey and they've made tens
of thousands of dollars now. There's
this one girl, Clueless Mags. Yeah,
actually, let me pull up her app, bro.
She She's lowkey like a hella goated
creator. This is Cl's, I believe, like
best UGC creator at the moment and she
grew 30K followers in the last like 2
months doing UGC. They basically hired
her without her having any content
experience. That's the That's the crazy
part. However, she practiced really
hard. She worked on her skill set of
making good UGC content. And at the
beginning, like it wasn't going crazy,
right? But then eventually you're going
to have that same phase where you can
find that viral format, you copy it, and
then you double down, right? Here's
another thing, too, like having met her
in person too, she's like very good at
just like being herself as well. So, I
think it really does go back to that
like skill set of like you have to be
confidently yourself on camera and be
okay with being perceived because even
as a UDC creator, right? It like in
order to make viral content that sticks
out, like it's got to be funny. It's got
to be kind of like out there. It's got
to be kind of embarrassing like this
one.
>> How many eyes do I have?
>> One, two,
five.
And by the way, like if you get from the
view bonuses from UGC programs, like she
probably got like a good $1,000 from
posting this video. And she was a brand
new creator when she first started. So
that's the thing, like I do want to
emphasize, don't put this on this
pedestal of making money through content
in this like out there place. Understand
that it is possible for you today.
However, you still need to go through
the phases of practicing and posting.
And yes, you can do that today and
accelerate your timeline, or you can
wait and not put in those reps. But as a
result, then you're just never going to
build up the skill set of being a good
creator and improve over time. Make your
videos 1% better every single day by
learning scripting, by learning filming,
by learning editing. Stop relying on
stupid hacks because TS does not work.
Instead, learn scripting, learn editing,
learn filming and tonality. That is what
phase three of social media is all
about. I I know I sound like a broken
record a lot of times on these kind of
lessons because it's like bro like you
just have to like phase one lose your
aura. But that's the thing like it's
pretty simple but it's not easy. Like
going out there and filming in public is
not easy. Going out there and posting
knowing like a hundred of your mutuals
are going to see your post is not easy.
But I actually think it's such a cheat
code because what's difficult for 99% of
people to do means you've already like
eliminated 99% of your competition just
by simply doing what's hard. Because if
it was easy, everyone else would be
doing it. And that's why one of these
opportunities like content creation and
UGC is so lucrative right now. And these
brands are literally starving for better
creators. Like I live across the street
from Culie, right? The UGC program. Bro,
they are starving for good creators
because there's startups that got funded
like $15 million who need to spend that
money on their marketing. They need
creators who are hungry to make quality
videos to improve. And that's that's
really all it is. This is probably the
best opportunity that exists right now
for making money through social media.
Now, I will say too, yes, you can make
faceless content. It is so much harder
to monetize because think about it from
like a UGC perspective too. Like these
videos actually convert. They actually
go viral because there's somebody's face
attached to it. Like yes, these are kind
of ads for Cluey, right? These are
literally advertising the product, but
you wouldn't buy an ad unless you
actually saw somebody's face. Like it it
looked like a real person reviewing a
product. So yes, like you you can try to
make content and you can go viral
without your face in it, but it's so
much harder to make any money from it.
And and that's also like a really
important thing about losing your social
aura. Everything regarding making money
on social media honestly requires you to
lose your social aura because if you're
selling something, people are going to
criticize you. If you're becoming a UGC
creator, making ads for like Cluey, bro,
you are going to get like probably
flamed in your comment section. Oh, nice
drive, Diddy. Oh, bro is just filming an
ad. But I mean, that's kind of what it
takes to make social social media money.
It's inevitable when you put your face
out there to millions of people.
Obviously, it's not going to be easy to
be perceived. So, yeah, I want to do a
quick announcement. We actually just
released a UGC guide inside Content
Academy. It's a 13-minute mini guide,
but it walks you through how to get
started literally from scratch. It's not
going to teach you how to become a
growed creator in 13 minutes because you
can't do that in 13 minutes, but we
actually have a beginner's blueprint to
UGC. Okay, but I I'll play the first 5
minutes of this. I don't want to drag
too long on the UGC part. I know like
we're we're dragging a long time on the
like making money with UGC part, but I I
do want to like emphasize how possible
this is. Okay, I'll play the first 5
minutes. This is the beginner's
blueprint to UGC, or as I like to call
it, the beginner's blueprint to making
money as a content creator. It's how you
can get started with UGC in just one
week. And it was made by Prosper after
Prosper literally made over $1,000 in
his first week on a brand new account
doing UGC. And this brand new account
was started with zero followers with
zero inherent advantage on his account.
And with the sheer skills that we are
about to teach you in this module, he
got his first 1 million view video
literally within like week two. And he
also made $1,000 literally from that one
video because of the view bonuses that
were paid with UGC. So that being said,
we've had creators in the content
academy as well literally hit 10K and
even 20K plus months through one UGC
opportunity alone. So you're probably
wondering, what is a UGC opportunity?
How do you get it? And what even is UGC?
UGC or user generated content is simply
when you as a person, not even as a
content creator, as a regular person
makes videos for brands to promote the
brand's product. This can be an app like
Cali or like Cluey, right? Or it can
even be like Tik Tok shop. But in this
video specifically, we're going to cover
how to make viral UGC for apps because
that is that has been the most lucrative
opportunity that we've seen and the
opportunities that we are giving out
every single week in our content academy
opportunities channel. Now, typically
this is done on a separate account,
which means all you have to do is start
a new account. And we'll walk you
through all the steps on how to do that
in this video. So, you don't have to
worry about selling out on your main
personal brand. So, your friends are
going to see you and being like, "Yo,
why you selling out?" Like making brand
videos. Like, they're not really going
to see it unless you go buy one. If you
go buy, you're going to make hell money,
so it doesn't even matter. So, brands
typically pay UDC creators per video.
Anywhere between like a minimum $ 20 $30
per video starting out. And they get
view incentives. You can see the view
incentives down here. Right? Lean
landing your first UDC gig is simply a
numbers game. But specifically, it's a
numbers game where you just have to try
really hard to hit the view minimums
that these brands have set. Okay, so
that being said, apply to every
opportunity that you can in the hashtag
opportunities channel in our Discord
server. Now, our UGC partners are
willing to literally hire any creators
who have the skill level, okay? Any
creators. It doesn't matter if you have
100,000 followers. It doesn't matter if
you have 100 followers. I am not even
kidding. This is one of the most
untapped opportunities right now,
especially if you're first starting out
and you don't have like friends hitting
you up all the time. That's what we have
made the opportunities channel for. So
brains are literally they are starving
for hungry creators who actually put in
effort to learn improve their videos and
actually make really high quality
videos. So we're going to teach you
exactly how to do that right now. So
what's the most important is that you
build the skill of good UGC. And you can
see literally if you get a million views
on one of these UGC videos which you
might think is really hard. Oh, a
million views is a lot. But we literally
will teach you the formula. And if you
actually try in these programs, trust
me, those programs will teach you
exactly how to get lots of views in
programs like let's say Cluey's, right?
Cluey is an app that does UGC
opportunities. They give them out and
they literally pay like up to $1,000 per
million views or if you get 5 million
views, you can get up to $2,000 for a
single video that you post onto their
page and they have coaches that will
train you every single week in their own
program as well. So, first step once you
get into one of these UTC opportunities,
which all you have to do is apply in the
opportunities channel is to warm up your
account. So, all right, I will stop
right here cuz this is like pretty long.
But if you are in the content academy,
feel free to check out that video. And
then if you want to apply to any of the
opportunities, it's in our opportunities
channel in the Discord server, which is
on the lefth hand side, probably like
right over there. Uh, and if any of you
guys are interested in Content Academy
and you want to learn more, you can
simply book a call with one of our
onboarding specialists, Allan, and he'll
walk you through the entire process,
what's inside Content Academy, and like
how you can make the most of it, and
whether it's actually a good fit for you
and your goals as a creator. Okay, but
just to reiterate to stop relying on
stupid hacks. TS does not work. Instead,
learn scripting, learn editing, learn
filming and tonality, which takes a lot
of practice, but that's what phase three
of social media is all about. It sounds
like really annoying that like, "Oh,
[ __ ] dude. I I thought it's all about
these like quick strategies." TS is this
[ __ ] That's ultimately what it is.
Because you can go viral in a multitude
of different ways, a multitude of
different niches, but if you don't have
the discipline and the tenacity to
actually consistently post and lose your
aura, it doesn't matter. So reframe
reframe content as a science and a skill
that you can learn and improve. I know
you said no hacks but what are your
thoughts on trial reels hack of spam
posting same video until one of them
hits. I mean you can try it but at the
end of the day if a video doesn't hit
like you can spend like an hour trial
reeling the same video five times just
reposting it but ultimately like if a
video is good it'll probably get
traction regardless on social media. So,
I would just like rethink the strategy
of like, "Oh, we need a quick hack. We
need a quick hack." Bro, a quick hack is
going to help you maybe go from 1,000
views to 1,500 views. Yay! Hooray!
Hooray! We got 500 more views. Hooray!
What is that going to do for you? So, I
personally think spend that time making
a new video, thinking of a new idea.
Maybe even spend a little bit more time
filming or editing. Try like three
different hooks, but at the end of the
day, ideas are often the most important.
It's like a YouTuber could be like, "Oh
my gosh, like we have to re-edit my day
in the life of a of a Boston college
student video 20 times and it's going to
go viral." Like, [ __ ] no, it's not.
Nobody cares about a day in the life of
a college student. You know what I mean?
But then Mr. Be's can like poorly edit a
video, but it's like $1 yacht versus $1
million yacht. But the idea and the
concept itself is so interesting and so
inherently viral that it's still going
to get millions and millions of views.
Yo, let me actually shout him out real
quick. Jojo Jojo maxed out the number of
trial reels you can literally post in a
month. So Jojo started off in like
literally a month ago at I think like I
want to say like 4,000 or 3,000
followers, right? And he literally maxed
out the number of trial reels you can
post. He's probably like the most
consistent person that I have seen as of
late in terms of content. He's spam
posting so much. But literally in the
last month, he's like tripled his
following from like 3,000 now to he hit
8,000 followers I think yesterday. So
like big shout out to Jojo. He's been
maxing out the trial reels. Uh if you
want to learn how to get trial reels, we
if you're in the content academy, we
have a thread on that in the # sauce
channel. Uh it's like a little bit more
in-depth, I believe. But somebody posted
a sauce like thread in the content
academy sauce channel like explain how
to get trial reels even if you have less
than like 100 followers or something.
But reframe content as a science and a
skill that you can learn and improve.
The only cost that you have is like you
lose a little bit of aura every time you
post. But then like you don't really
lose that much if you just post more.
Making more videos doesn't really cost
you that much time. I think the main
bottleneck, at least for me, has always
been social anxiety, which is why I'm so
bullish on like losing your aura. Like
half the reason why like this video,
these videos like didn't do as well, is
because they weren't as clear of in the
first 3 seconds versus like a video that
started going super viral like these,
right? They're very much they very much
leaned into like a viral concept that
already existed like dance trends, dance
alerts. Oh man, the the sound got taken
down. And you can see here too, this
another thing too, like the videos when
I first started posting them on this
account did not have that much traction.
Like now they have a little bit of
inflated traction because people
probably went back and saw my oldest
videos, but when I first posted them,
they had like 2,000 views. One one of
our members, Henry, told me in person
recently at one of our events. Yo, Mino,
like low key, I spent like my last
$1,000 like I I spent like 500 of it on
Content Academy and then he made it back
within like 3 months from doing UGC from
also like selling digital products
online. We we've had members and this is
Henry now. Henry literally in I think
this is him like 4 months into Content
Academy, he grew from less than like
literally zero pretty much, you know,
like starting out and now he's at 29,000
followers. We're giving away five 4.5K
to uh to everybody who's most consistent
right now in the content game. But Henry
was posting about saying he was going to
win, bro. We we had people in the
comments saying, "Bro is not going to
make it. You you beat me in 4K." Yeah,
we also do live challenges like that in
content academy. Like something I'm so
proud of in our community is that like
people actually like are hella
consistent. Let me pull up our wins
channel. Bro, people are so consistent.
Like of course they're succeeding. Uh
Jojo, you know, he hit 8K followers
yesterday. Denny uh careerhigh almost
10k views. And like you got to
understand celebrating those wins that
it might not be like, yo, we hit a
million views. We hit like 100,000
followers. Like bro, celebrate your
small wins because you want to
congratulate yourself for the small
progress that you're making. Bro, even
posting your first five videos online is
such a huge win and that's really hard
to do. It's really hard to do it. It
pushes yourself out of your comfort zone
and that's so important. So, like Denny
literally getting his first 10K views
videos is so far. Seb hit 500 on Tik
Tok. Cole also posted like a huge W.
Yeah, a video he posted that's now over
140k views, but he's been hella
consistently posting in Content Academy,
too. So, like yes, we do accountability
challenges in Content Academy that like
help you push so you can like actually
stay consistent. All it takes is $4,000
prize to get people to show up and
posting daily for real. But yeah, we got
Kevin who got a he got a full-time job
as a content creator at Stan. That's so
fire. He's literally like I remember
when he first joined a year ago and he
was like first starting content. He was
just posting daily about his like
journey as a NYU student who did a D1
golf. Bro, now he's made full-time or
content creation full-time job. The
amount of growth you can have in a year.
So many people overestimate what can be
what they can do in a month and then
completely underestimate the amount of
growth they can have in a year. In the
first like 6 months of this page
existing, I think I was stuck around
2,000 followers since January of 2024.
So that's like around 20 months. I went
from 50k to 400k followers. A lot of
people like vastly underestimate the
amount of growth that happens over the
long term because they don't see any
results in like month one, month two. Do
you recommend starting another account
just for UGC? Yeah, when you join UGC
programs, I would recommend that like
you make a new account for them. The
thing, bro, if you have a good hook,
it's hard for the rest of the video to
suck. Unless your hook is straight up
lying. Like, if your hook is straight up
capping and lying, then it's not going
to do well because people are going to
watch for the first 3 seconds and then
scroll off on second four once they
realize it was cap. So, if your hook is
like really good and actually true,
that's important. Like, I can't just
say, "Guys, I made a million dollars yet
last night." Like, good hook, right?
It's like, "Oh my like, I made a million
dollars in one day." And then like a
second later, I'm just like, "Just
kidding, but today's a day in my life as
an entrepreneur." It's like, bro, of
course you're going to lose watch time,
like 90% of your watch time on second
two. It's like clickbait videos. Like,
it's literally like clickbait where
people will watch they they'll click on
your video, click as in they'll watch
past the first 3 seconds and then
they'll realize it's a it's a load of
horseshit and then they'll scroll. So,
don't think of it as like, oh, your hook
should be clickbait. Your hook should be
true. It should be accurate, but it
should still present curiosity and
conflict in your video where it makes
people like need to watch the ending.
Like, no glaze. But I personally think
we got like the best creator community
out there for improving your content
skill set as fast as possible for
learning scripting, learning editing,
learning filming tonality. So then you
can actually start like making money
from it. Cuz I think a lot of these like
creator programs out there, they'll like
tell you like these like hook templates
and they'll give you like a notion
template, but it like doesn't really
work because you don't learn the
fundamentals of how content works. Like
what we do in Content Academy is we
literally have a fiveweek boot camp that
teaches you how to actually script,
film, edit, post your first seven
videos. Here's our day one guide, how to
post your first video onto Tik Tok and
Instagram, right? And I walk you through
how to script it, how to film it, right?
All the basics as well, how to edit, how
to add your captions and stuff. I don't
know. I I think a lot of the content
gurus out there, my gripe with them with
them is that they don't actually have
like solid content experience. So, they
can't really teach from first principles
like how to think like a creator, how to
actually add like B-roll and footage in
a way that actually captivates
attention, how to make unscripted videos
that are still like exude your
personality authentically. All of these
small things, these small skills that
really matter as a creator, like setting
the proper goals as a creator, cuz I
think long term, if you actually want to
smash your goals, like you need to know
how to think in the right way about your
goals so you don't get demotivated. I
don't think like just saying that you're
going to do stuff and like writing down
like goals like numerically like I'm
going to hit 100k followers actually
serves you that well. Like I personally
think some one of the the things I love
about the content games is that we're
rewarding people not for getting a [ __ ]
ton of views. We're rewarding people for
actually like showing up and putting in
the work. Like everyone here is actually
doing the work of posting. Like that's
so awesome to me. Like everybody here
actually posted. Harry, Xander, Elite
Footy, Chang, Sebastian, Kevin, Sophie,
me, Indigo, Nathan, Omar, Braden, Jay,
Denny, Allan, Jojo, like FHY, Arena,
Diana, like you guys all posted and
that's so awesome. One of our one of our
coaches now, Gabe, he runs an agency
that did that hit 100K in a month
actually. Let me find it. Uh I think
this it was this month. Like he hit 80K
in a month, but I'm pretty sure he ended
up hitting 100. But this is one of our
coaches. He teaches monetization. He's
literally done like all the monetization
guide or like methods in content
creation, but he's like now essentially
runs a creative agency. He runs a
creative strategy agency. So, if you
want help like scaling your agency as
well. Gabe is a great resource. He he
scaled his creative agency to 100K a
month. Oh, this is this is what's inside
Content Academy. If you want, I can
explain it. I mean, I feel like it's
like pretty self-explanatory. Like, we
have our content boot camp. It walks you
through how to make content. When you
join on day one, we'll welcome you with
a welcome call. Uh, you can post your
first video using the guide. And then we
have our three-point support system with
our coaches. Sam, who teaches UGC, I
teach content and business. And then
Prosper teaches content growth. We have
our onetoone support manager, Justin,
who's actually right behind me right
there. And he answers any questions that
you're going to have about anything.
Like it could even be content related
questions. He he will answer them. In
our Discord community as well, we have a
content reviews channel where you can
send your videos reviewed, get them
reviewed by other community members. We
have in-person meetups like four to six
times a year. We got monthly
accountability games. You also got
another event in San Francisco next
Saturday. By the way, if you're in
Content Academy, pull up so you can meet
all the other creators. And then we send
weekly trend updates in the emails as