These are the four stages you will go
through starting off as a beginner to
content creation to eventually becoming
monetized and making content creation
your full-time income. And the reason
why I know this is because in January
1st of 2024, I was stuck at 50k
followers making just 500 bucks a month
and I was a 20-year-old college student.
But I tested this one thesis. If I just
posted once every single day and
followed this four-step formula, what
would happen? And after 20 months, I
grew from 50,000 to 410,000 followers on
Instagram. My coaching business in the
past 20 months has gone from zero to
$760,000
made. And I've been able to charge five
figures for brand deals that I posted
onto my Instagram page. And this growth
process has been proven to work in all
of the following niches: real estate,
guitar, rock climbing, high school, UGC,
self-growth, founder, building and
public relationships, Amazon FBA,
travel, software engineering, golfing,
tech, productivity, SMMA, make money
online, Christianity University. And the
reason why I know this is because I've
coached over 1,500 creators now in the
past 20 months. I'm not saying this to
brag, okay? I'm lowkey kind of [ __ ]
bragging here. I'm genuinely saying this
because this will be the complete road
map, the fourstep road map to go from an
absolute beginner to hitting 10K
followers and monetizing with your
content. It's the same road map that
people that I've worked with, like
Henry, who is a literal 17-year-old,
pause, posted his first video in April
of 2025. And in just 32 days and 27
posts, he hit 10K followers. And he made
his first dollar with content creation.
And if you're curious about the program
that all of these people have gone
through and Henry to go from 0 to 10K
followers and start monetizing with
their own content, this is my private
community content academy. And if you're
interested in joining, just book a demo
call right down below. Anyways, step one
when you are starting out with content
creation is simply to post your first
video because you need to try different
formats and see what you enjoy with
content creation. And you should expect
zero growth. I know a lot of people came
onto this video thinking that, okay,
what's the like the biggest hack so I
can 2x my content growth instantly
overnight. And what you have to
understand is when you're posting your
first 30 videos, the most important
thing is consistency. And you need to
find a community of people who actually
keep you accountable to posting
consistently because I've seen so many
people who ask me, "Yo, Mino, how do I
get into content creation? How do I
start? How do I start making money?" But
then they quit after like 3 days, 2 days
of posting or they never even post their
first video. Another reason why these
people never actually end up posting and
how to prevent yourself from becoming
one of them is understanding your why.
Ask yourself really why now? Why do you
actually want to get into content
creation? Why do you want to build a
personal brand? And the reason why I
believe that so many people should start
creating content is because learning the
skill of content creation is the best
skill you can learn in 2025. Even if you
are just learning it part-time, so many
people that I have worked with came in
as literal college students who had
maybe like 2 three hours a day of spare
time and they were able to turn those 2
three hours of spare time learn focus on
their content creation and after 60 to
90 days land jobs from content creation
or even get paid 10K a month from brands
to make videos for them. This skill of
content creation is literally the most
high value skill that you can learn in
2025. And if you can just simply learn
it, it will pay you dividends literally
in 6 months. But we'll talk about the
monetization in a second because your
number one thing that you need to focus
on right now if you're in the first
stage of posting your first video is
think of content like a skill that
you're actually going to train and build
up. But once you actually get into the
groove of posting content, you've posted
your first video online, which props you
if you have, that's genuinely very
difficult to do because you have to
fight against all the judgment of all
your peers who are going to be looking
at your content and thinking that you're
[ __ ] cringe and weird for doing it.
Step two is to make it a habit. And the
way that you can level up in this is
learning the basics of scripting,
filming, and editing by posting
consistently. And once you have gotten
to this groove of posting consistently,
you can find the one to two videos that
actually get over like 10k views, which
is actually much easier to do than you
think. I know that seems like a huge
number, but Jojo, after posting 67 days
in a row, he got his first 100K view
video on his Instagram. And then
literally in the span of about 2 weeks,
he turned his first 100K view video into
300k view videos. But the most important
thing is just posting your first 30
videos during this period and making it
a daily habit. Because odds are if
you're not making a daily habit, then
you're probably not going to excel at
this skill set of content creation. Then
step three, after you've made it a habit
and you've posted your first 30 videos
consistently, is something I like to
call micro optimization. And by the end,
you should be able to master content
creation and hit 10,000 followers by day
60 through 90. I see this as a pattern
with all the creators in my community
that I work with. Once you double down
on the videos that are actually doing
slightly better than the others, right?
While making your videos 1% better every
single day, you focus on the editing,
trimming dead space. You focusing on the
scripting, removing redundant sentences.
You focus on the hook. Does your hook,
your first 3 seconds of your video
pattern interrupt. Is it unique in any
sort of way? Does it use specific words
that trigger viewers emotions? What do
your visuals subconsciously communicate?
And does your tonality, the way you
speak on camera, show emotion or
authenticity, or are you just reading
off of a script kind of dead inside? And
once you focus on improving all of these
skill sets for 60 to 90 days of
consistently posting, Jojo, the creator
I talked about before, he went from
1,000 to 10,000 followers in just 47
days. Jojo posted like 200 times during
this period. He he made it so quick. But
you can genuinely master the skill of
content creation in just 90 days and get
your first 10K followers. And at that
point is when you can actually start
monetizing from your content. So Jojo
also got a hundred sales or $4,000 on
his guitar course in those 30 days as he
was growing his personal brand from 1K
to 10K followers. And even if you aren't
selling directly through your personal
brand or through your Instagram because
I know a lot of you guys don't have a
product to sell yet, don't have a
business to sell yet, that is okay.
Andrew did not have a product to sell
and he just applied to one of the
opportunities from our brand
partnerships in our Discord server and
in 2 weeks went from zero experience in
UGC to making $4,000. And he ended up
hitting a 12K month in his first month
creating content for other brands in
this opportunity known as UGC, which if
you're curious is a super untapped
opportunity where so many brands apps
are looking for creators to literally
just make content for them. These
businesses with millions in funding and
millions in marketing budget are looking
to pay creators tens of thousands of
those dollars just to make viral content
on Tik Tok and Instagram. And the
craziest part of building this skill set
and the craziest part of building this
skill set and monetizing it is that it
doesn't allow you to just get paid by
brands to make videos for them. It can
even help you land literal job
opportunities when you're literally just
3 or 4 months into content creation.
This is what happened with Andrew since
he started UGC just two months ago. He
went from zero to 10K a month and now
he's literally getting CMO job offers
from his skill of content creation that
he scaled up in literally just 2 months.
The job offers that people are offering
to pay him as a college student are
between a h 100,000 a year and $250,000
a year. Most people pursuing marketing
degrees in our age are getting cooked by
the job market and they won't even touch
six figure salaries until they're 5
years in. This is the power of grinding
content creation. And by day 150, I
think you should set a very realistic
goal of making 5K a month with your
content creation. As long as you take
the first step and you post your first
video, then you make it a habit, then
you improve your videos 1% every day,
focusing on the scripting, focus on the
editing, focus on the hook, focusing on
how you're showing up on camera. All of
these things that you can improve 1%
every day once you treat content like a
skill. So, now that you actually
understand the road map that has helped
all of these creators go viral and
actually start building their online
income with content creation, if we
parted today, do you see yourself
crushing your creator goals? Because you
have two options once you click off of
this video. You can try it alone. You'll
have lonely nights pushing against
judgment. You won't have content
direction. And you'll be burning out
trying to balance all of it. And I know
this because I spent 5 years making
these mistakes before turning content
creation into an actual income. So you
can try this lonely option or you can
join the best creator community on the
planet today and learn from experienced
creators in live weekly calls. And this
is the kind of community and program
that I wish I had access to even just
two 3 years ago when I was first
starting out in this journey when I was
so lost not knowing what to post, what
direction to take my personal brand and
my content every single day. And that's
why I've created Content Academy, a
community where you can learn from the
most experienced and dedicated creators
in live weekly calls where you can hop
in, ask your questions to experts like
our monetization coach, Gabe, who went
from literally zero followers a year ago
to making a 100K a month with his agency
just a year later with his niche
personal brand. Or Prosper, who
literally grew from 3,000 to 370,000
followers in a single year on Instagram.
or Sam who specializes in content and
UGC and he helps train the best UGC
creators. He grew from 1,000 to a
100,000 followers in 30 days on
Instagram. And you can also hop on live
calls with me. And I've also grown three
accounts on Tik Tok to over 100,000
followers across multiple different
niches. This is my comedy account. This
is my personal development account. This
is my social media advice account. And
I've been creating content now for 5
years. and I've distilled everything
I've learned into this one single
community where we have many more secret
tools and sauce used by the top 1% of
creators. And if you're interested and
want to 10x your creator growth and
learn all of these secrets and join the
best creator community on the planet,
just book a demo call below. So, that
being said, these are the four steps to
go from a beginner to making your first
dollar online with content creation. And
I want to ask you, are you going to
partake in day one or put it off for one