How to make 10K a month on Instagram as
a beginner. I've been posting content on
social media now for the past 5 years.
The way content creators make money now
is changing. I've noticed a couple
changes in the last couple years.
Follower count no longer matters. The
algorithm favors watch time and
engagement. The platforms are starting
to pay way less per view. Now Tik Tok's
creativity rewards program, the last I
checked on my own phone was 32 cents per
thousand views. They've literally cut
the pay by like 5x 6x. However, there
are a small subset of creators who are
making 10K a month with close to no
experience, and it's all because they
learned one skill. It's learning viral
conversion content. I started off on
TikTok in 2020, and I made 40 bucks in
my first year. I was 16 years old. Uh I
ran up an account to 100K followers in
the comedy niche and then I made 40
bucks from brand deal, from a single
brand deal. And then in 2021, I made 9K
from Tik Tok's creator fund. That was
its old version of its creativity
program and it paid 1 cent per thousand
views. It paid close to nothing. Okay.
And then I got three brand deals for 2K
each. But mind you, by this point I had
around like 5 600k followers on this
account. I had a ton of followers on
this account. 9,000 bucks for making for
getting around 100 million to 200
million views is in my opinion pretty
low. Actually, no, it's it's close to
around 15 actually. I don't know why I
said 11. I made around $15,000 that
second year in content creation. And
that was by running up like a shitload
of views in year three of content
creation. Now I'm three years in. I made
$10,000. And that was from one brand
deal. I had to make two videos for them.
And I paid I got paid 4K. And then I
made some money from Instagram's fund.
And then I started selling a course,
which you can see was not very
successful. If you can see that
Teachable number, that's 572 bucks that
I made from a course. And that's also
because my audience at the time was
literally this account. I only really
had this account. So then I decided,
okay, I should probably start a new
account and that's when I started my
other account. So if you search up my
name here, that's when I actually
started this account, right? But I
honestly barely made money from this
account either. Like I'm talking about
people who made like 10K a month in like
month three, bro. You got to understand
I was making like 10K a year for the
first 2 years, first 3 years. Okay, so
you have to understand like this takes
time. I do want to preface that. Now,
mind you, too, like my niche was in
comedy, so the niche matters. And this
is just like a little side note, but
like you can't really like it's a lot
harder to monetize certain niches than
other ones. Is that I started selling
coaching in 2023. And that's when I
actually started to make money. Like
this is when I actually like I would say
became an actual semi full-time income.
Like 50,000 a year is like it's
basically what I would have gotten paid
if I went to a marketing job. So at this
point in 2023, I took a year off from
college. I finished my first year of
college here, right? And then I went and
take took a gap year and I started
selling high ticket coaching. This was
onetoone. I was literally just helping
pretty much anybody who wanted to be
helped on social media who wanted to
grow. And I was just like, "Yo, like pay
me, bro. I know how to go viral, bro. I
will just like help you out." This is
like year four and five. Last year, uh,
we basically switched over to a paid
community model and that business is now
known as Content Academy. Uh, these are
like our literal, this is literally from
my bookkeeping sheet. I don't know if
this is like necessarily valuable input,
but I do want to be like incredibly
transparent with uh with how much I've
made. So, this is 216K in rev last year
with about 100K in profit. And then this
year so far, we've done about 326K
in revenue and then about like 176K in
profit. Okay? And this is year two of
running Content Academy. Now, the reason
why I say this too is because I'm not
necessarily saying, "Oh, just because I
made money just through coaching means
it's the best opportunity." I was
basically monetizing off of the skills
that I had built up from like 3 years in
advance. And that's when I actually
started turning that into like a skill
set to teach. So, I do want to like I do
want to preface that the amount of time
that it took to get to this point or or
rather to get to really like this point
is a massive barrier to entry because I
was literally monetizing off of like 3
years of social media experience. That
being said, right, I've compiled all of
the different ways that I've made money
through social media and I want to
actually walk through what actually then
is the best beginner model to monetize
on social media. and it's not what you
think based on what I've like walked
through so far. These are the four
different methods I have done to make
social media money. The first one is Tik
Tok's creativity program. This is not my
screenshot actually. I just got it off
the internet, but I think I've made
around like I I think I've made around
total maybe like 9K from all of the
programs that have existed. Now, Tik
Tok's creativity program actually does
still exist. If I can actually pull up
my creativity program on my phone, I
I'll show you how much I'm making right
now from the creativity program. my
overview in the last 60 days, I made
$170 bucks. And that's from maybe like
one or two videos doing well. That's
like kind of absurd. And then in the
last year before that, right, in 2024, I
made $516. It's like for the amount of
followers, like you would expect an
account like this to like, yo, like you
probably make like, you know, a couple
bands. Bro, I made $516 last year
through this program. I'm I'm not to
[ __ ] on it. Like I have friends who are
making like a good like 5 to 10K a month
on it, but they also have millions of
followers. It's really hard to monetize
a Tik Tok creativity program because if
you just crunch the numbers, right?
First off, you need 10K followers to
even start. So, the barrier to entry is
so so so high. And on top of that,
because you have to be consistently
going viral, unless you have like a
consistently super viral format that's
pulling in 100K views minimum every
single video and you're posting like 30
videos a month, bro, it is not a stable
income. And for anybody who has like a
lot of fluctuations and creative freedom
in what you post, like it's not that
stable in my opinion. And then your
month one to three earning potential, in
my opinion, after you hit 10K followers,
and this is after you hit 10K followers,
I still think like the most you'd
probably make is like 1K a month, unless
you have some exponential chart on
TikTok, but realistically, it's
somewhere going to be closer to zero.
And that's that's been my experience as
somebody who has pulled in a lot of
views and then also pulled in like not
an insane number of views. I had a video
before get 10 million views on TikTok.
And yes, that's probably netted me like
four or five bands, but I lowkey got
paid like five bands to study for an
exam. So, this video probably made me
around like four to 5K in Tik Tok's
creativity program. So, it's not awful.
Like, if you go like, sure, if you want
to try going this viral every single
video, if you want to hit 5K a month, go
for it, man. Like, go for it. You try
it, man. You try it. So in my opinion
because you need to learn a really
difficult skill of virality and then
continuously be up on date of it and you
also have to mind you 1 minute plus
videos.
Your videos now have to be over a minute
long. They didn't used to be now they
do. So yeah like even if you go viral
you have to go super duper viral too on
a minute long videos. Like these are
long out videos bro. So it's it's a lot.
It's a high high barrier to entry. So,
in my opinion, like if I were to rank
this, if I had to give it like out of
10, I'm personally giving this one like
I I actually think it's probably like a
two out of 10. Like the amount of people
who are actually making full-time
incomes from creativity creativity
program is genuine influencers. It's
like the actual influencers that you see
who are like who are genuinely printing
views. And like this is probably a good
example, but like
like this is probably a good example of
an influencer who is probably making a
full-time income from creativity
program, but that's because he's
printing so many views. Like this is
probably like in the influencer
celebrity category of creator and even
then I guarantee they're going to make a
lot more from brand deals. Okay, so in
my opinion it's probably like a 2 out of
10. Now method number two which has in
my opinion more stability is a coaching
business. stability is actually pretty
high in my opinion. Like if you're
running a business, it's probably one of
the most stable ways to make money on
social media because you're not at the
mercy of views at m as much. You you
still are kind of at the mercy of views
if you're running a business, but it's
not as much because now the people
paying you like aren't just going to
leave you if you get less views. It
takes a long time. Like the barrier to
entry is a lot. I would say don't even
consider it unless you have a,000
followers just because you at least need
some base to monetize off of, right?
people who would be interested in
anything you'd sell. And the month one
to three earning potential is actually
pretty good. I think you could make like
an easy 1k a month in your like first
two first two months. You that's
literally like two clients. However, I
would say two caveats. One is that you
actually have to love it. Like it's a
small thing, but it's like it takes a
lot more work to run a business than
just make like content on social media.
But you do have a lot more like scalable
earning potential. Like I do think
coaching business coaching businesses do
have the highest scaling potential. Like
I know people doing like 200 300k a
month with coaching businesses. Like it
does a lot. However, it's really hard.
Like it's like pretty hard because you
have to have a high valued skill. So
content marketing, sales, fitness. I've
seen people do like day trading courses,
crypto courses. If if that's your thing,
I'm not saying like to do that though.
If you are interested in the game of
like entrepreneurship, you have to think
about it like entrepreneurship. It's in
every other skill set. You just have to
learn this. But in terms of this
business, you now have to learn sales.
You now have to learn marketing. You
have to learn product. You have to learn
coaching. You have to learn hiring. If
you are interested in learning that
skill set and you actually like want to
become an entrepreneur in that way, I
would say it's actually worth the skill
set to learn. But if not, I don't think
like just to make money, it's like the
best method to start because you need
the prior experience. It takes a lot
more like experience as well and like
stacked learning. Okay? So, I'm not
going to recommend it to everybody cuz I
genuinely don't think like I'm going to
tell everybody, yo, everybody should
start this like coaching business, bro.
Like, it's going to be a lot harder to
generate sales if you have nothing to
sell yet. Okay? So, I'm going to I'm
just going to put that in the back of
your mind. But, that being said, I still
think like it's so much better and more
predictable than the creativity program.
So, for that, I'm going to give it like
a solid 6 out of 10. I think it's great.
I think it's great. The only caveat is
that it's like genuinely really hard for
beginners. And trust me, like I've tried
coaching people and starting coaching
businesses. And maybe it's like a six or
a seven.
Maybe it's like a six or a seven out of
10 difficulty, you know, or or rating.
It's like pretty good. I wouldn't say
it's that bad, honestly. It's like
pretty good, right? But it's just like,
you know,
next up, and this is one that we've been
talking about for a while. Also, this is
an example of a a creator in our in our
community though who literally he has
under 10k followers. He's been growing
really fast. Um, but yeah, in the in the
first month of him like launching this
new digital product, he's made around
4K. So, I will say like there are he's
in the music niche, by the way. He
literally sells a music course. Jojo,
shout out Jojo if you're watching this.
There are also a lot of beginners who do
this other method known as UGC. Now,
this one I would say is probably like
the best for beginners. UGC is known as
usergenerated content. In like simple
terms, it literally just means you're
getting paid by companies to make videos
for them. So, let's say, for example, we
have a company uh we have Coca-Cola,
right? Let's just draw the Coca-Cola
logo here. Yo, Loki, that was kind of
gas. So, let's say Coca-Cola is looking
to make videos for ads. They they need
videos for ads. They need videos for
just their organic socials, right? Their
Instagram page. So, they also need
Instagram videos and maybe they want to
put some videos onto their Tik Tok. Now,
how do you think they're going to get
these videos? Coca-Cola, who probably,
mind you, spends like multiple millions
of dollars if not billions a year on
marketing. I just want you I I want you
to keep that in mind because the biggest
companies have massive massive marketing
budgets. Okay? So, keep that in mind. A
company like Coca-Cola,
how much do you think they're going to
pay creators for making videos for them?
It's probably like an insane amount for
an absolute beginner. As long as you
know how to make videos and you know how
to like decently pitch yourself too if
the brands like need to be pitched to,
you can get paid by like big companies
to make videos like this for them. So
all you really have to do is find an
opportunity in UGC and then literally
make the videos for them. So it's like
one, it's like find the opportunity.
This is like a hour like a magnifying
glass. Just pretend this means search.
But then part two, you just have to make
a video like that. All you have to do is
like be good at making videos. So then
they don't like feel like, "Ah, I'm
never going to pay this dude again." And
certain UGC programs, the way they work,
right, for certain companies, like this
is Coca-Cola. Another company that uh
the company that Andrew, for example,
ran up UGC with was this company named
uh Cle. Yo, Loki, I kind of nailed their
logo. But basically, Cle did the same
exact thing. They basically wanted
videos for Instagram and they also
wanted videos for Tik Tok. And what they
did basically is they just hired like I
don't know like 20 creators and they
were just like yo we'll pay you 35 bucks
a video and if you get a million views
we'll pay you like an extra 1k if you
get a million views. That is a so much
better opportunity than like any of
these. And you might think that's hard
but also a lot of these UGC programs
what's great about them like at this
point I'm just blazing right? But a lot
of these UGC programs also like they'll
train you. They'll they will literally
help you out. So I actually think like
that being said, UGC is one of these
like golden opportunities if you are a
beginner to learn to earn still while
you are learning and also start with no
barrier to entry. And the best part is
it requires you to literally have no
followers going in. There are literal
like programs that hire creators even if
they have zero followers. And this
connects back to my initial hypothesis
which is just that follower count no
longer matters. What's most important
now is skills. It's not gimmicks. It's
not nepatism or or like relying on
previous fame. You actually have to be
good at content. Okay? You actually have
to learn how to make good content and
learn the skill of making high
converting viral content. That is the
main skill that you need to learn
instead of thinking about these like
gimmicks about like steal this viral
hook and like use this posting time and
hashtag. If you actually learn the
science of social media, right, and how
to make decent videos, you can actually
start making money very quickly. And
there is no barrier to entry that
literally numerically requires you to to
have like a ton of followers going in.
Every opportunity that I'm describing
here requires you to have a lot of
followers or at least some baseline
skill. UC is one of those things that is
low skill to start and zero barrier to
entry. Month 1 to3 earning potential is
not going to be insanely exponential,
but I genuinely do think it's pretty
predictable. If you actually put in good
effort, you can make your first dollar
with UGC on month one. It's just going
to take a lot of learning because once
again it's a skill set. So I'm not going
to promise you that on month one you're
just going to make like 10k a month.
Like Andrew is actually very good at
content and that's that's the thing like
these videos were actually very wellm
made. People think that you need to
become a famous influencer in order to
make money from social media and that's
not true. So the barrier to entry
genuinely can be just like having no
followers. That's okay as long as you
can show that you have the skill set. So
it's still helpful to practice, right?
You still want to practice making
content. I'm going to draw a P here for
the practice. You want to practice
making content. My best recommendation
if you want to simply start today. If
you want to start UGC today, go out and
start making videos on your personal
brand. Just start making videos talking
because all these UGC companies want
talking creators because that's what
exudes the most trust and that's what
converts the best. But you can start
scaling up to like bigger numbers
because you can not only do you can you
actually just make money from like high
performance bonuses, but you can also
charge uh like more than just 35 bucks a
video too for certain brands. Now, you
might not be guaranteed like 30 videos
in a month, but I've seen people charge
up to like 500 bucks for a single video.
And the cool thing is you don't need to
have an existing follower account once
again because you're not posting it onto
your page. You're posting it onto a
different page for the company. And then
the skills that you actually want to
learn is simply UGC style content
creation. And you actually don't even
really need to learn viral content like
that hard. You just need to learn
decently how to make viral hooks. Okay?
And that's really the basis and the gist
of doing UGC. You still want to have
good lighting as well. You want to do
like uh decent scripting, very clear
wording, good pacing, and good editing.
But other than that, it's a lot less of
a barrier to entry. So, if the previous
one had a 67, I'm g have to give UDC
like a solid eight, bro. And to even
test this thesis, too. Um, I tried UDC
for a week. Uh, and I got qualified
literally in one week of trying it on a
new account, uh, my friend Prosper as
well, who's also a coaching content
academy. He tried it for a week and he
literally made $1,000, I believe, in
like the first 10 days of doing UGC
because he had a video hit 1.8 million
views. So, he literally got paid for
this video, I believe, like 1,500 bucks
or like 1,200 bucks, and then obviously
like 35 bucks per all of these videos as
well, right? But literally, like it's
just copying this format, copying a
format, and then just trying it out
multiple times, iterating it on it 1%,
all of these very basic things of
content creation.
And once you do that, you can actually
apply to these programs and then just
learn while you're triing in one of
those programs. Now, you do need to have
access to those programs, right? And
like I would say like genuinely Content
Academy does have a great opportunities
list where we're pretty much connected
with like all of the big brands now
doing UGC programs. So, if you are
looking to join like a UGC program and
also learn, I would highly recommend
Content Academy. Now, lastly, brand
deals. Brand deals is a tricky one. So,
most people kind of know what brand
deals are. Brand deals are basically
when a when Coca-Cola, right, they're
not just paying for you to make the
video, but they're make they're paying
for you to make the video and then post
it onto your page. They're they ask you
to post it onto your account. So, I've
done like two brand deals in the past
year, very transparently. Recent brand
deal, I got paid $14,000
and there were a couple other
stipulations, but I got paid 14 $14,000
for like one video plus one collab post
and it was this one. And then a previous
video, brand deal. I got paid $6,000 for
one single video. But that being said,
like you also have to have a follower
account to attract brand deals. So once
again, this is one of those like extras
that you can do, but don't rely on it to
be the only thing unless you are like
genuinely excellent at negotiating brand
deals. Cuz if not, I wouldn't say this
is the most predictable source of
income. Literally, with brand deals, I I
got one brand deal this year and one
brand deal last year. That's it. That's
it. And I I'm not optimizing for it.
like I don't have my email in my bio,
which you should if you're looking for
brand deals and UGC opportunities to
come to you, but it's a nice
supplemental income for so for that
reason, I would give it a five out of 10
because I know a lot of creators too who
do a lot of brand deals, but even then
they'll get maybe like like at the very
minimum like only one a month that
they'll even sign with, maybe even zero
in some months. So, they just won't make
any money from brand deals from that
month. And that being said, I genuinely
think in order to even attract a brand
deal, you need around 10K followers. And
if you don't have 10k followers,
realistically, a brand's not going to
pay for your reach. They're going to
probably pay for UGC more so, but then
at that point, you didn't really need
the 10K followers. You could have just
done UGC. So 10K followers is like the
minimum bar that you probably need to
even start doing brand deals. One brand
deal when you're at 10K followers might
give you like 500 bucks, right? And then
once you're at like maybe to get a 2K
brand deal, I think you probably should
be around like 25 to 50K followers,
right? So to get 2K you probably need
like 50k followers on Instagram and Tik
Tok. Instagram or Tik Tok rather, right?
Because each brand deal or each platform
will be specific to a different brand
deal price. But if you want to get like
an 8K brand deal, dude, you need to be
at like 100K. Now the good thing is once
again like talking about the barrier to
entry, follower count doesn't really
matter as much because brands are
realizing that the social media
algorithms are simply optimized to push
out good videos, not just people with
high follower counts. skills genuinely
matter so much more now because if you
can learn how to make a viral video
tomorrow or even a video that hits like
100K, that's so much that's worth so
much more than having even 100,000
followers at times or even like 10,000
followers. Like that's genuinely better
than let's say having just like a 10K
follower thing because like brands are
now smarter and they're smart enough to
the point where they're like, "Okay,
this person who gets 10,000 who has
10,000 followers but gets like literally
like 2K views on a video. That's
literally worth nothing. That's That's
poop, bro. Why would you pay like a
person who has 10K followers $1,000 just
to get 2K views when you can pay a UGC
creator to get 2K views? 35 bucks. Like,
don't you see from the brand side, it's
so much better to pay for UGC creators
who have the hunger and these skills.
Now, you could try on your own and say
stuff for years, right? And this is why
I built content academy. I' I've
mentioned it earlier. I mentioned some
of the students who have gone through
it, but you can try on your own and stay
stuck for years. And that was me. That
was literally me. And that's why I made
content academy.
It's to learn from other experienced
content creators so you can 5x the speed
of learning. And I have a bunch of
examples here of people who learned in
content academy and grew so much
quicker. So first off, we have Rajan who
joined. He was like going to hit 10K
followers around December of 2024. And
if you guys have seen his content, that
was 8 months ago. 6 months later, this
was 2 months ago, he hit 200,000
followers. And then today, he's at 374.
Bro, it was about to pass me in follower
count, bro. And I'm not like going to
take credit for his own learning. He put
a lot of effort in. Once again, all of
these people that I'm about to show you
put a lot of effort in. But like
learning from other experienced creators
and going out of your way to actually
surround yourself in a community of
people who are also focused on learning
is one of the most powerful things you
can do. And if you don't have a network
yet, right, one of the best things you
can do is just go out and proactively
look for one because it's a lot easier
if you have like 200k followers. People
are going to reach out to you. But if
you don't have that yet, one of the best
things you can do is join a community so
you can you can jumpst start that
process and you can also learn from
people who have more experience, right?
Another example is Thomas. I remember
when he joined, he was at 500 followers,
right? This was back in August of last
year. And after 77 days of posting, he
went from 500 followers to 10K. And then
7 months later, this was in March, he
launched his coaching business. He made
$42,000 in what is that like 8 days? 7
days. Okay. And that's only because he
was able to expedite the process of
growing from 500 followers to 10K. And
then lastly, Andrew. I I saw his like
intro post, right? I remember when he
sent this. He was uh he's at 5K
followers. He's just a college student.
I mean, Andrew is still a college
student. This was, bro, this was like
May 2025. It was only like 3 months ago
and it's crazy the come up he's had but
he was talking about just like judgment
and fear when creating content was the
biggest thing he was dealing with like
remembering his why and focusing on the
bigger picture and he was literally just
like yo let me just try a UGC
opportunity right so last minute he just
hopped on a like call for UC opportunity
that he applied through like our
opportunities channel in uh in content
academy let me find it so this
opportunities channel it's it's only for
the content Content Academy members
because we don't want to send these
opportunities just to like any any
beginner, right? So, it's for it's
generally for people who are in content
academy and want to start, right? But he
applied to this one, right? This Cluey
opportunity. And basically what happened
then was like he just took off and he he
grinded that [ __ ] bro. Like I I'm not
going to take like any credit for him
learning the skill set. I'll just say
like he found the opportunity from the
Discord server. I know he was active
before and he was actively learning in
the community. Um, and and that's just
like the most important thing is like if
you join a community, please be active.
Like if you're going to join Content
Academy today, like please be active,
you know, please interact with the other
members genuinely so you can learn
quicker because anybody who joins a
community but doesn't interact and kind
of just like lurks. You're not going to
actively learn and like get the
improvement, get the feedback that you
want from other people. Okay? And then
that led to him making 4K a month
without bonuses, right? But that was
early, right? That was early in the
month.
30 days later, literally 30 days later,
right? The 28th and the 21st, he hit his
first 10K month ever through UGC. But
yeah, seeing stories like this, it's
like, holy [ __ ] Genuinely, like this is
the power of just learning from people
who are experienced from you and then
applying this opportunity and working
hard. Like these are some of the hardest
working people in our community. Some of
the most consistent people in our
community. And that's why like Thomas
did 77 days of consistently posting. And
you'll see if you look at our wins
channel, I believe anybody in the uh
content academy server can look at the
wins channel, you can see you can tell
like who the people are who are
genuinely super dialed in because not
only are they going to be posting their
wins, but they're also going to be just
actively chatting. You're probably
wondering now what is actually inside
Content Academy. And I'll just do a
quick outline. If you do want to join
and you have any more questions, just go
click the upgrade button and you can
simply book a call. Uh if you're on the
fence and you're not sure, you can just
book a call. You can apply. Even if
you're not even a good fit, we won't
even take you, right? But if you're
interested, just apply and then we'll
see if you're a good fit, okay? And then
we'll have somebody hop on a call, one
of our team members, Allan, and he can
just answer any questions for you. But
basically, here's what's inside. We have
four weekly live content coaching calls.
This is from me. This is from another
content coach, Sam. He's also a coach in
another UGC program as well for this
company called TurboLearn. So, he's like
very experienced in teaching how to do
good UGC. And then we also have Prosper,
who's bigger on Instagram, but he has
64,000 followers on Tik Tok, and he grew
from like 3K to 370K
followers on uh Instagram as well. And
they hop on live coaching calls once a
week for an hour to answer any of your
questions live. And I also do one. And
then also, we have another coach, Gabe,
who makes 100K a month with an agency.
So, if you are interested in the
monetization side, he can answer any of
those questions. We also have all the
premium channels in the content academy
discord. So right now you might only see
the start here and the free channels.
But basically what you'll unlock is
first off you might have used hooker AI.
You can get unlimited usages of it. You
also get access to the general chat.
You'll actually be able to like type in
the wins chat. We have this cool game
going on called the content games where
basically uh if you post daily,
everybody will split the money based on
how many people are remaining at the end
of uh 21 days. So right now we have 22
people surviving with 80 bucks each. And
then we also have 247 one-to-one support
from our creator success manager,
Justin. And then lastly, we send a
weekly trends email breaking down the
most recent viral creators and sounds
and also opportunities sent straight to
your inbox like UGC opportunities. If
you do want to join and upgrade, just
simply go into our Discord channel
and you can just simply click upgrade
and then
you can just apply to join.
So, we only take people who are actually
qualified. And the program itself is 997
bucks for the entire year.
And programs like this generally go for
like four or 5K. Like I've seen so many
personal branding programs go for so
much more. I wanted to make this to
introduce the idea of monetization to
you if you're a complete beginner to
social media. And I want you to know
like the barrier to entry is not that
high because I started social media, you
know, I had an account with 100K
followers. It was a mostly a meme
account, but bro, I made 40 bucks. And
if these kind of opportunities were
around when I first started and I was 16
years old, bro, I would have eaten that
[ __ ] up, bro. I would have grinded so
hard for that. And even then, like, bro,
talking about how Andrew made like 12K
in a month, bro. I made 12K in a year,
bro. Are you kidding me? These
opportunities now are so insane. Yeah.
If you are interested in learning about
these things, like please go after and
like actually seek out the knowledge,
seek out the learning that you can do
about UGC, about any of these business
models really and then just start start
posting. Like if there's one piece of
advice that everything links back to to
to finish off this free class, right?
It's literally start start posting
today. Okay? If there's one piece of
advice that I can give you, it's
literally just to start posting today.