On January 1st, 2024, I was a
20-year-old broke college student who
had one burning question. How much could
you possibly transform your life if you
just posted one reel every single day to
Instagram? Now, at first, I saw this
daily posting experiment simply as a
challenge to fight my social anxiety and
get over my fear of inaction. But what
happened next changed my life
permanently. In 60 days, I doubled my
following to 100K followers. I started a
business and ran it up to 10K a month in
15 days. All because I dedicated myself
to the craft of posting every single
day. So, this 3-hour course is not only
a live walkthrough of how I scripted,
filmed, and edited several of the high
performing Instagram real videos that
built the core of my personal brand
during that daily posting challenge. But
this 3-hour course that you just got
access to for absolutely free is the
same course that over 1,500 students
paid for and used to grow from zero to
10,000 followers on Instagram and Tik
Tok. with many of these students going
on to make their first dollar from
content creation and hitting even bigger
milestones like hitting 10K a month. But
after helping thousands of paid students
in my program, Content Academy, I've
decided today to release the seven most
popular, most helpful first modules
completely for free. This is a complete
guide to scripting, filming, editing,
and posting your first seven videos to
start your personal brand as a complete
beginner. Now, right before we get
started, I want you to promise me that
you're actually going to take action on
the modules that I have released here.
So, please bookmark this video and come
back to it over the course of the next 7
days. Cuz if there's anything I want you
to take away as a beginner, it's that
content creation must become a habit
before it becomes a skill and before it
becomes a income. Your dream life,
making your first dollar from content
creation can literally be just 30 days
away. And I know this because I've seen
it firsthand with students who have
joined my program. And some of them got
their first 10,000 followers and made
their first $1,000 with content creation
with literally within the first 60 days.
But crazy results like this starts with
you simply right now taking action and
going down to the first link in the
description to get the cheat sheet to
follow along this entire 7-day course to
starting content creation with me. So
without further ado, let's create our
first video together in the day one
module. In this module, I'm going to be
walking you guys through exactly how to
make your first video for Tik Tok and
Instagram reels, how to script your
video word for word, how you're going to
be filming and recording yourself on
camera, exactly what buttons to press
while you're editing, while you're
filming, exactly how to edit your video.
Let's just jump right into it. We're
going to start off with four very easy
questions. This is going to take you
probably less than 5 minutes. But first
of all, welcome to day one of your new
life as a creator. Get ready to change
your life and change lives. I wrote this
here just as a little bit of
encouragement because it's an internal
game as much as it is an external game.
And I know this because I only started
my personal brand 2 years after I
started creating content online. So, I
started off just making memes online,
Among Us jokes, Squid Game memes. But
the thing is, I never actually put
myself out there. my genuine self. As a
result, really struggled to monetize.
Could never sell anything or convert for
my life. No sales. There's no way I
could have run a business through this
comedy content. And even though the
views were decent, actually pretty good,
it meant nothing. So, I had to start
from absolute scratch again. And then I
realized how difficult it is to actually
put myself online. So, we're going to
start as easy as possible. And we're
going to make these four questions and
four answers. Hi, my name is blank. I'm
blank years old and I am currently a and
I want you to put your occupation here,
your very service level occupation. And
I'm not a big fan of these service level
things, but it really is like an easy
way for people to get to know you,
especially in your content. So for me, I
would say, "Hi, my name is Mino. I am 20
years old. I'm currently a sophomore in
college." Very simple. I could even say
a sophomore in Boston College. Another
thing I could say is, "I'm a business
owner and sophomore in college." Just
put one of those labels or multiple of
those labels. Then let's move on to the
next question. And this one gets a
little bit deeper, but why am I starting
content creation? And even if you have
already started content creation, I
still answer this one sentence two for
this one. So I put two examples. One is
I'm starting this content challenge
because I want to show people that
content creation doesn't have to be this
high bar thing and all it can take is
putting a camera down and talking. So
because I've already started content, by
the way, like this content challenge
really is just me posting my first
video. And what we're going to do with
this whole week, day 1 through 7, is
post one video every single day. I know
you're probably thinking, I'm a little
busy. I don't know if I have time. This
is going to take 1 to 2 hours every
single day. If you're telling me you
cannot block out 1 to two hours every
single day. Really? Really? Come on.
Like, come on. Try and find the 1 to two
hours every single day to go through
these day 1 through 7 modules cuz I
think this is really huge. And this is
where 90% of people fall off as creators
is they'll post one video, two videos,
and they'll be like, nah, it's not for
me. You know, I'm not really getting
views. And the intention of this first
week is not to get views, which is why
we're starting off with such an easy
four question prompt. And we're going to
use this as inspiration for our video.
So, don't even think about content.
Don't even think about any of this. Just
answer really honestly in one sentence.
Why am I starting content creation? And
another answer I put is, I'm starting
this content challenge because I want to
train myself to believe I'm worthy of
helping people. Now, third question and
I want to answer in one sentence as
well. What is my biggest fear with
content creation? Well, personally, I
have two fears. I'm scared of what
people at college will think of me when
I post my videos. And two, I'm scared
I'm not capable of impacting lives and
genuinely helping people. And lastly,
you want to write a message to someone
else out there who has a similar fear in
one sentence. And this can be either an
encouraging message, something that just
simply says, "Hey, you're not alone."
Or, "Hey, keep going." Something
encouraging. Or you could say a call to
action like follow for more if you want
to say it in your video. Or you could
say join me on this challenge. Or you
could say put yourself out there. I know
it's going to be hard but you should do
it too. Or you can do it too. And it's
often times they might be similar but
basically I have two examples here. The
first one is a call to action. If you
have that same crippling fear of being
perceived as cringe, feel free to join
me as I play this weird game of trying
to be a content creator for the next
seven days. An encouraging message could
be if you have that same imposter
syndrome that you're not good enough,
just know that you're not alone in that
journey. And one encourages them just to
say, "Hey, it's okay to feel this way."
And the first one is a call to action
saying, "Join me." I want you to write
out your answers. And then after that, I
actually want you to take those answers
and go to Discord. And I've just copied
and pasted all my four sentences. So,
first we're going to say it. And because
I'm actually the first person to uh say
this because we're writing the module as
we speak, I'm just going to reach out to
the most recent person who said
something and his name is Joe. He said
that he actually runs a YouTube
distribution network. So I'm just going
to simply rightclick his profile and
message. And then I'm just going to be
like, hey, ask a question, say hi. We're
all here to connect to build a community
of fellow creators. You know, you could
say literally anything. You just be
like, yo, what's good? going to send the
message and you know take the time to
actually get to know this person cuz why
not? I'll add him as a friend as well.
It's a lot easier when you have somebody
else in your corner on that same
journey. This is probably one of the
most impactful things that you can do.
Literal conversations from content
creators that I've met back like 3 years
ago have genuinely changed my life. This
one time I had a friend who said,
"What's your dream with content
creation?" At the time I didn't have a
dream, so it really made me think maybe
I should be a little bit more ambitious.
He told me his dream, which was like
move out to a content house and start
traveling the world. And he did that. So
like it's so cool to meet genuinely
inspirational people because you realize
they're not just people on the internet.
Like these are real people. So it' be
even better to like hop on a call.
>> Yo,
let's go. Let's go.
>> Okay, we are back here for step three,
which is the video portion. And
basically, we're literally just going to
take the answers to these intro
questions, literally just copy and paste
them into this very, very simple video
format. Now, I know you're probably
thinking, well, like, there's no way I'm
going to actually film this and post
this. Like, there's no way I can just
copy and paste my answers and make a
decent video. Maybe it will be a decent
video. Maybe it won't be a decent video.
But the point of this is simply to get
yourself out there and actually post. So
the hook, today's day one of posting
every day for 7 days as a blanky year
old label. So this is a very easy way
for people to get to know you. Instead
of saying something like, "Hi, my name
is blah blah blah." Simply give them a
reason for actually getting to know you.
Today is day one of posting every day
for 7 days as a 20-year-old uh content
creator in college or sophomore in
college. I'm starting this content
challenge because and then you're just
going to take your answer from question
two. I'm starting this challenge because
I want to show people that content
creation doesn't have to be this high
bar thing and all it can take is putting
a camera down and talking. Personally,
I'm scared of what people at college
will think of me when I post my videos.
So, if you have that same crippling fear
of being perceived as cringe, feel free
to join me as I play this weird game of
trying to be a content creator. I'll see
you guys tomorrow for day two. Boom. And
that is the script. So, you're going to
write it out. You're going to have that
literally just copied and pasteed down.
and then we will move on to actually
filming our video on our phone. So, I'll
see you guys on my phone. So, now that
we are on our phone, the first thing
we're actually going to do is open
Google Docs on our phone. If you don't
have it already, just like download it
or wherever you honestly did this script
on if you did it on a different app and
we're simply going to highlight this
entire script
and then copy it. Right now, what we're
going to do is download the Cap Cut app
if you haven't already, cuz this is
where we're going to do all our editing
and also a lot of our filming. So, we're
going to download it and then open it.
And now, what you're going to do is
press that expand button in the top
right. Expand. And then we're going to
go into the camera button right there.
Press camera. And then, now that you can
see my beautiful face, we're going to
turn it to 3 minutes. So, we can
actually give ourselves the luxury to be
able to talk for 3 minutes. even though
this video should not be any longer than
20 30 seconds. And we're going to press
that cool little teleprompter button
right up there. We're going to press it.
There we go. And we're going to press
that edit button because I already have
my other script there. And we're going
to clear all if you have something there
already. And simply press it and paste.
Paste our script and press done. And now
we can actually record ourselves while
reading off our script. And this is what
I do for all my videos that are
scripted. I can stare directly at the
screen as well, which looks natural. And
if you're wondering like, oh, how can
you like resize it and like how quickly
does it move? You can press that
settings button. I'm at like 14 speed
and like a size 16 17 font. You can
adjust it how you need, but those are my
settings. We're going to click settings
again. And now, if we simply press that
record button, we can actually start
recording. It's going to give us a
little countdown. But before we do that,
find yourself some good lighting. And
we're going to go through more complex
lighting in the future. But I really
just want to make this very simple.
Stand in front of your light. That light
is in front of my face. But like if I
turn around, right? And there's not much
light coming from that direction. So if
I turn around, you're going to see my
face just looks a little bit weirder.
Like it looks a little bit darker. And
the iPhone camera is going to have to
work a little bit harder to make my face
look brighter because those lights are
behind me and they're overpowering the
light that I'm getting from the cloudy
window. So, if I turn around, much
better. My face looks a lot brighter.
This is the kind of lighting that you
want to get in your videos. Front
lighting. Just analyze your
surroundings. Where is the brightest
light coming from? And just like stand a
little bit behind it so it's in front of
you. And we're not even going to hold
our camera. We're just going to plop it
down on that water bottle. And then I
want to take you guys through one more
practice. Take a deep breath.
Hold for 6 seconds.
and then exhale for eight.
And it's a really good way to calm your
body, calm your nervous system because
naturally, if you are new to this or
even if you are decently experienced,
you will get some sort of anxiety in
front of a camera. It's super natural.
It happens literally to everybody. It
still happens to me to this day where I
feel like, oh my goodness, like this is
a camera I need to sound good. I I
wonder what people are going to think
about me. This feels so weird because
there's a literal freaking metal box and
I'm not used to talking to a metal box.
It's okay. You need to play tricks on
your brain so you don't get in your own
head. And one of the easiest way to do
that is simply take a deep breath, hold
it for 6 seconds, and exhale for eight.
And often times we'll also record when
we're out of breath. So make sure you do
that to calm your body. And then right
before you hit record, take another deep
breath where you just like inhale. like
now you'll have lungs full of air and
you can actually read through your
entire script. So, we're going to do
that. Just going to press that button
and we're actually going to take a deep
breath first.
[Applause]
Today is day one of posting every single
day for 7 days as a 20-year-old
sophomore in college. I'm starting this
content challenge because I want to show
people that content creation doesn't
have to be this high bar thing. And all
it can take is putting a camera down and
talking like this. Personally, I'm
scared of what people at college will
think of me when I post my videos. So,
if you have that same crippling fear of
being perceived as cringe, feel free to
join me as I play this weird game of
trying to be a content creator. I'll see
you guys tomorrow for day two.
And that is it. Now, you're probably
wondering though, I've messed up
already, right? Like, I messed up on the
second sentence. What do you do? Well,
simply put, say I did mess up on the
second sentence. I want to say I'm
starting this content challenge again.
You simply press record again. Okay,
I'm starting this content challenge
because I want to show people that
content creation doesn't have to be this
high bar thing and all it can take is
putting a camera down like this and
talking. Personally, I'm really scared
of what people at college will think of
me when I post my videos. So, if you
have that same crippling fear of being
perceived as cringe, feel free to join
me as I play this weird game of trying
to be a content creator. I'll see you
guys tomorrow for day two. Peace.
And there we go. So, now that we have
two clips, we can actually just press
check. And now that we're here, we're
just going to press that edit button in
the bottom left with the scissor next to
it on the bottom left right there. And
just press it. And now just like press
the clip. And the first step we're going
to do in editing is simply cutting up
the clip today. So the first thing
you'll probably notice is that there's
probably a little bit of dead space
right at the beginning right before you
start talking. So simply play it today.
And we want to find the exact part that
you actually start talking. We're going
to find that. We're going to split right
at that moment that I think I start
talking. And maybe it's a little bit
off. That's okay. And then we're going
to zoom into the timeline with two
fingers so we can get a little bit more
detailed view. We're going to press that
first clip that is not anything that we
want in our video and delete it like
that. Now we can just watch it again.
Today is day one of posting every single
day for 7 days as a 20-year-old
sophomore in college. So now say at this
point right here I want to actually cut
it and I don't want to include any more
of this clip that's 20 seconds long but
only at the 5second mark I want to cut
it and not use the rest of the 21
seconds of this clip. What we're going
to do is we're going to go to the exact
moment that the sentence ends. So right
here where did my sentence end
or in college? Right about here. And I'm
just going to press the clip again and
split. And then the rest of the 21
seconds, delete. And now I have the
second portion that it cuts to.
I'm starting this content challenge.
There we go. So now, where does this
sentence actually start? I'm now you
could probably cut it here and it'll be
okay. And I'll show you what that looks
like. Split. Delete. College. I'm
starting. You'll notice there's like a
little bit of space in between right
here. The two clips more in college. I'm
starting this. And what we actually want
to do in this first challenge in
editing, cut the minute details. So, I
probably start talking around here. And
that's probably like a few milliseconds.
It's less than a second of dead space at
the beginning. But we're going to do the
same thing where we want to find exactly
where I start talking. So, right about
like here is probably where noise is
made. It's like margin of error of like
a few milliseconds, but say around here.
We're going to press the clip, split,
and delete the part in the middle. We're
going to see how it transitions.
Sophomore in college. I'm starting this
content challenge because And there we
go. When we cut those minute parts, it
really feels like a very snappy,
well-paced cut. Today is day one of
posting every single day for seven days
as a 20-year-old sophomore in college.
I'm starting this content challenge
because I want to show people that
content creation doesn't have to be this
high bar thing. And all it can take is
putting a camera down like this and
talking. Once again, we can do that same
cut here and talking. Personally
talking, right, where there's a bit of
dead space, we can split again right
when I start saying personally. Cut that
0.2 seconds and it'll sound cleaner. And
talking. Personally, I'm really scared
of what people at college will think of
me when I post my videos. So, if you
have that same crippling fear of being
perceived as cringe, feel free to join
me as I play this weird game of trying
to be a content creator. And right here,
I can also cut one more time. Content
creator. I probably stopped talking
around here. I split.
And we can split again right here. Cut
that space in the middle. And the pacing
should feel really good. Crater. See you
guys tomorrow for day two. Peace. And
then right here as well. There's
probably a good like 1 second of me
stopping it. That's like that little
millennial moment. We can just cut it
right here when I close my mouth and
delete. Now we can watch the whole thing
and just see how it feels. Today's day
one of posting every single day for 7
days as a 20-year-old sophomore in
college. I'm starting this content
challenge because I want to show people
that content creation doesn't have to be
this high bar thing. And all it can take
is putting a camera down like this and
talking. Personally, I'm really scared
of what people at college will think of
me when I post my videos. So, if you
have that same crippling fear of being
perceived as cringe, feel free to join
me as I play this weird game of trying
to be a content creator. See you guys
tomorrow for day two. Peace. And now,
the last thing that we're going to do
with this very simple video is go to the
beginning and press that text button
right here. Press that text button and
press auto captions right here. And
these are the settings for my auto
captions, but these are simply default.
It's video. There's no template on and
bilingual captions, none, identify
filler words off. and generate.
And there we go. Now we have these auto
captions that look pretty cool. And we
can watch the whole video again to see
what it looks like. Today's day one of
posting every single day for 7 days as a
20-year-old. Just press that last text
box. This is a weird thing that Capot
always seems to do with its auto
captions. Press that last text box and
just move it forward a little bit so it
ends before the actual video clip ends.
Cuz if you'll notice, there's a little
bit of black space at the end. So I do
that. And now that should remove that.
And I want you to check for any typos.
So for here, there's one typo. It says
all I can take. Now, obviously, I don't
think this is like make or break the
video, but I just want to get you guys
in the habit of actually fixing these
typos by showing you. You press this and
you press that edit captions thing right
there with the three lines at the
bottom. And from here, you can access
all the caption lines and you can
actually just edit them in bulk. So,
what I want you to do is find a typo and
and all it can take simply just retype
it. All it can take is putting a camera
down like this talking. Now, I also want
you to never allow two sentences, two
different sentences to actually be on
the same line. And that happens once
here. Oh, watch it. Today's day one of
posting every single day for 7 days as a
20-year-old sophomore in college. I'm
starting this content challenge because
I want to show people that content
creation doesn't have to be this high
bar thing and all it can take is putting
a camera down like this and talking. So
now you can see it says and talking.
Personally, these are two separate
sentences. So all I want to do is press
return. Personally, I'm really scared of
what people at college will think of me
when I post my videos. So if you have
that same and right here too. So if you
have that same crippling fear of being
perceived as cringe, feel free to join
me as I play this weird game of trying
to be a And right here there's also a
typo. It says I am when it should be of.
And there you go. I'm trying to be a
content creator. See you guys tomorrow
for day two. And then I'll cut it here
as well. And there we go. And talking.
Personally, I'm really scared of what
people at college will think of me when
I post my videos. So if you have that So
right here, let's just say like it's not
terribly misaligned, but I do want to
make this like slight edit.
Right here is when I start saying so.
What we're going to do is press that
green caption box, move it, that end
portion with that white scrubby thing
and move it to the line where the word
actually starts. And then we can take
the second caption box and move the
leftmost white scrubby thing to where it
should go. And boom, these little
alignments. Obviously, this is a very,
very small misalignment, but like you
will have to make these slight alignment
fixes just a lot of times through bigger
errors. So, if you have that same
crippling fear of being perceived as
cringe, feel free to join me as I play
this weird game of trying to be a
content creator. See you guys tomorrow
for day two. Peace. And there we go. The
last thing we want to do before we post
this video, I know last last edit for
these auto captions is take any one of
these pieces because they all get edited
the same way. And I want you to press
one of them and with two fingers on the
screen in the uh actual visual part, I
want you to resize it. Make it very
slightly smaller. So it starts off like
this. Make it very slightly smaller with
two fingers by pinching it closer and
then moving up a little bit like there
where it's about 30% up from the screen
because if it's down here, there's the
caption part right here on these social
media platforms, the like Instagram or
Tik Tok username plus caption. So you
don't want it to be down here and you
don't want it to be big to the point
where part of the caption is blocked on
the right side by the like, share,
comment button. So that's why you make
it slightly smaller. And then move it up
to about where it's like 30% up on the
screen. Right about here. That is much
better. That's how you actually make the
captions just not be obtrusive or
blocked in any way. And finally, now
press any one of the clips, press
volume, and just increase it to 200.
Today is day one of posting every single
day for seven days as a 20-year-old
sophomore. And what this does, it just
increases the volume of the clips for
all of them. Generally speaking,
obviously like don't make it
earlastingly loud, but a slight increase
in the volume will help a lot. And just
being a little bit more audible cuz a
lot of times our audio might come off as
quiet, especially when we're not loud
talkers. So yeah, up your volume. You
can even do 300 or 400% if you need to.
Now we are officially done and we can
press our export settings in the top
right where it says 720p or 1080p or
whatever. And we actually just want to
do it to 4K. Now I know you're probably
thinking, do the platforms actually
accept 4K? I believe Tik Tok accepts 4K,
but Instagram only accepts 1080p. So
like doing 4K will just allow you to get
like slightly better quality and it
really doesn't hurt. Make sure your
frame rate is no higher than 30. I
really recommend 30. Do not do 60
because it'll just come off really
choppy. The apps actually cannot
showcase 60 frames per second footage.
Only Instagram I think is able to, but
Tik Tok it comes out really choppy and
weird when it's 60 frames per second.
So, just do 30 and then do a recommended
code rate. And finally, once all
settings are checked off, that top right
button with the arrow is the export
button and it'll simply export.
Sometimes it'll take slightly longer,
but once our video is done and ready to
share, we can simply close the app cuz
we're not going to post it through Cap
Cut. We're going to close the app and
then we are going to go to the app
itself. So in Tik Tok and we're going to
press that plus button down there. We're
going to press it and then we're going
to press the upload button right here.
That's where all our videos from the
camera roll are saved. So we're not
going to actually record a video in Tik
Tok. We're going to upload and then
we're going to upload this 24 second
clip. From this point, simply press next
cuz it is fully edited. And once that is
done, then we can simply type our
caption and post it. So for this one,
it's just going to be a very short
caption. In the caption, it really does
not matter. And you don't need to use
hashtags either, but I would recommend
just using like one niche specific
hashtag for this one. It could just be
simply like #content creation. Um, but
we're going to write out our caption.
I made this video in five minutes.
and then
#content
creation
and boom.
Now that that's done, we can simply
press post. Congratulations on finishing
your first video in the content academy.
That's one of the hardest things ever.
So now that you've set out the
foundations for your exact personal
brand and you created your first video,
it's time to actually hypers scale your
brand. Get your first 30 videos in.
build that vibrant community around you
for your content journey. So, if you
want full access to the content academy
courses, the full Discord community, get
your content reviewed, get feedback on
your videos every single day inside the
academy, you can just go into the video
description and there'll be a link to
join the content academy right there.
Welcome back to day two. I'm so glad
you're still here because a lot of
people do not make it to day two after a
very grueling process of putting out
your first video. But today, our main
objectives are going to be learning how
to make personal story content. We're
going to be learning how to add more
aesthetic looking auto captions in the
Cap Cut app. We're also going to be
learning how to add our first B-roll.
Just make sure you have at least one
piece of B-roll that you could use in
your camera roll. And then lastly, we're
going to learn how to make aesthetic
looking custom thumbnails in Tik Tok and
Instagram. So, get excited. I am very
excited to share this module with you
guys. Today, I think we're going to make
our first like pretty decent video. So,
I'll see you guys there on the computer.
Welcome to day two. Let's actually get a
compelling video today. We're going to
make it a self-reflective video. And the
objective internally is to make a
relatable video and overcome our own ego
that comes often times from opening up
online. When we make content, what we
look for as viewers is something that
resonates with us. All comedy oftentimes
reflects something very niche and
interesting about ourselves and honesty
about ourselves that we didn't know
before. With the creators that we follow
online, oftent times what we really
resonate with them is simply one part of
their story or one part of their
thinking that really resonates with us.
So just forget completely about making
content though. And I always like to do
this with our scripting process because
when we approach content creation, when
we approach ideation with the like, how
can I make a video? How am I going to
make a content that looks like this
creator that I watch or I want to make a
video like this and then I like just
scrap it. Scrap it all because once you
start thinking that way, you lose your
personal touch to the video. So, we're
just going to start with some
self-reflective questions that are
really simple. First one is list the
three most interesting things that
happened in your life in the last 7 days
and try to pick the three things that
caused the most emotion. Realistically,
you could list 10, 20. If you just
listed out all the things that happened
and if that is what you must do, then go
for it. But I chose the three most
interesting things to me. Or at least I
tried to. Like there were definitely
more interesting things. Like maybe
there were like five that were equally
interesting, but try to pick the ones
that incite the most emotion within you
one sentence. So the first one is I
started really liking a girl. The second
one is I called a guy named June
yesterday. And the third one is I did a
group call for my coaching program.
Extremely simple sentences. Now, you
might be thinking, shouldn't I expand a
little bit more? Like, these things on
their own sound pretty boring. And
that's okay. That's okay. That's the
point where we're going to try and
extract the interesting points from our
boring life parts. Because often times
events on our own are not boring. It's
how we spin them to be more interesting.
And this is the basis of all my video
ideas. They're just boring events. I
started really liking girl. I called a
guy named June yesterday. Okay. Who's
June? Why should I care about June? Why
should I care about the fact that you
called him? Then I did a group call for
my coaching program. why I should care
about these things. That's what we're
going to try and spin out of these
things to make interesting videos. So
then we can let viewers into our lives
and actually let them be interested in
our stories. So second part is what is
the strongest emotion you felt during
these three moments? And it's just one
to two words to describe that emotion.
For the first one, when I started really
liking girl, I put excitement. The
second one I put excitement and
curiosity after calling my friend June.
And the third one is anxiety. The next
question is, what made this moment so
special to you that made you feel this
emotion? Two sentences. This one we're
actually going to try and write a little
bit more elaborately, but focus on what
was new to you. What details from the
moment were specifically interesting to
you? Now, for these previous two
questions, once again, pause the video
if you haven't done it already and just
answer these questions. But this next
question is going to be a lot more
expansive. It's probably going to take a
little bit more time. the first one when
I started liking the girl and I started
feeling excited. The reason why this
moment was so special to me and I felt
this excitement is because it's the
first time I think I ever truly liked a
girl. This is a new feeling to me. This
level of clicking with somebody. Second
one, I called my friend June and I felt
excited and curious. Why? It's because
June grew from 1,000 to 30,000 followers
in the past 2 days on Instagram. So
that's what made it really interesting.
But detail really made it interesting to
me. I asked him if he felt different
because of the sudden numbers and he
said no. He simply focused on his
purpose with the content. Now, this was
an hour-ong call and there were so many
other things that I could have taken
away from it and I could make like five
videos on this conversation. Not that it
was like the most insane conversation in
the world. Like you guys never had like
these are just conversations at the end
of the day. From every single moment
there are interesting things that
happened. I chose to pick out the
conversational piece that we talked
about of do you feel different about the
numbers cuz that's what just stuck out
to me as an interesting part. In the
last part of I did a co group call for
my coaching program and I was feeling
anxious. Why was this moment so special
and made me feel anxious? It's because I
feel like I've been letting down my
coaching community for the past month.
So I was really worried that people
wouldn't really be engaged in the
lesson. That's why I was anxious. Then I
was pleasantly surprised when 30 people
showed up and the Q&A lasted the entire
hour. Pause if you haven't done those
questions and answer these three. But
the last one is a life lesson you
learned from this experience. And I'm
not saying to like extrapolate this to
make it sound extremely deep, but just
like what is something you learned from
this experience? And it could be even
just a reminder of a previous lesson you
learned in a book or a video. Or maybe
it's something that is a reminder to
self to do this. I learned what liking a
girl is like. And I learned that it's
really something you kind of feel sure
about in the moment. And also what is a
prior belief that changed from this
experience? So what did you think before
and then what is just something that was
slightly changed after this experience?
So before I thought maybe love is
something you have to settle for because
finding someone I really like who really
likes me is too impossible. Second one
with calling my friend June with content
creation creating with purpose to
genuinely help people is the most
important. This was a reminder or this
reaffirmed the idea in my head that the
algorithms don't just reward catchy
hooks and retention hacks but reward the
people that actually care. And I believe
viewers can sense that through the
screen. And the last life lesson that I
extrapolated from my coaching call, I
learned that even though we might feel
this need to be perfect when we serve
others, it's more important just to show
up. Before I thought I should only show
up to calls if I'm ready to be energized
and motivational for my clients. And
what we're going to do is Mad Lib style
literally just copy and paste our
answers to make our video script. So,
I've literally just formatted it using
this copy and paste structure recently
or in the past week or yesterday or
today or X days ago. We start off with
the interesting event which is literally
number one. And then we go on to what
made this so special which is question
number three. So, we're skipping over
question two for a second and then we
say this is honestly so blank emotion
from question two because in that moment
I realized and then we insert question
number four the life lesson. So, I know
this might not make the most grammatical
sense for your answers, and that's okay.
We'll revise it very slightly at the
end, but this was designed to largely
make sense. Okay, so I have them posted
here. Video number one, liking the girl.
In the past week, I started really
liking a girl. It's the first time I
think I ever truly liked a girl. This is
a new feeling to me, this level of
clicking with someone. And it was
honestly so exciting in the moment
because I learned that liking a girl
really is something you kind of feel
sure about in the moment. Before I
thought maybe love is something you have
to settle for because finding someone I
really like who really likes me is too
impossible. Now let's do a quick
revision here especially with the first
three sentences because usually like
past the first three sentences we
shouldn't really worry too much about
it. But like first three sentences are
the most crucial for any video. Notice
here we don't say like hey guys or
welcome back. It's a very obvious cue,
but just like never say those things
because you're making your videos appeal
to a random audience of strangers who
have never seen your face before. That
is the goal. Therefore, don't feel the
need to like exchange pleasantries with
your existing audience of like, "Hey
guys, welcome back to my video."
Especially with troll content, nobody
really cares and nobody cares enough
about you to watch through and wait for
you to just dillydally around on camera
until you actually get to the point of
the interesting meat of the video. In
this case too, in this past week, I
started really liking girl. It's the
first time I think I ever truly liked a
girl. I think the goal when we do our
revisions is to one, make it feel like
it flows well, make each sentence feel
like it flows well into the next and cut
out any parts that are actually
redundant. I feel like I really started
liking girl. It's the first time I think
I ever truly liked a girl. So instead of
splitting up in two sentences,
oftentimes we can simply I started for
perhaps
the first time ever. In the past week, I
started really liking a girl for perhaps
the first time ever. This is a new
feeling to me, this level of clicking
with somebody. And this is honestly so
exciting in the moment. Instead of
saying this, I'll say it. And it was
honestly so exciting in the moment
because I learned that liking girl
really is something you kind of feel
sure about in the moment. I say in the
moment twice.
And it was honestly so exciting because
I learned that liking girl really is
something you kind of feel sure about in
the moment. Before I thought maybe love
is something you have to settle for
because finding someone I really like
who really likes me is too impossible.
Now, mind you, these videos are only
going to be 30 seconds. You can add one
or two more sentences like at the end,
especially to put like a call to action
or a motivational affirmation at the end
for your viewers. Cuz it's often good to
end your videos on a positive note
because then that's like positive
psychology. When people feel good at the
end of their videos, they want to come
back and watch for work. But now I
realized the patience
really did pay off. So this one I want
to be motivational for people creating
content as well. I'm going to address
the viewers who are also creating
content cuz this is most likely who it's
going to be most relatable to. These
videos are most relatable to people who
are going through the same situation as
you. People who are going through caring
about love or feeling like they have to
settle. This video is relatable to
fellow content creators who maybe want
better numbers or are confused about how
purposeful they should be in their
content. And this last one is for fellow
business owners. The numbers follow
impact like that very motivational call
to action saying do this fear.
And there we go. Now we have three very
compelling video scripts. And from there
now we can simply just choose one and
move over to our phone. So I think the
second one is the most compelling. So,
we're going to just choose this one and
we're going to move over to our phone on
Google Docs. We are back on our iPhone.
We're going to Google Docs and we're
going straight into our document with
our script. Scroll down to our script
and we're just going to copy our entire
script. You know, the usual
copy. I'm going to go into cap cut. You
know, we're going to speedrun this
process cuz we already learned it on day
one. Camera teleprompter. Edit. Clear
all. Tap. Paste. Done. Boom. Bada bing.
Bada boom. Switch. Three minutes. Cap
Cut has this weird bug where like the
first time you record, the audio gets
messed up. Like the first 3 seconds of
the take when you open the app, audio
gets messed up. So, we're just going to
delete that. Okay. Quick little
pre-filming warm-up. Of course, too,
we're right next to our ring light this
time. And the lighting is really good
because not only do I have the ring
light, but I also have highly colorful
lights in the background. So, I would
recommend always try to put color in
your background and stand very close to
your primary light. The further I stand
away, the worse the lighting on my face
gets. The closer I stand, the better,
and it looks a lot clearer and clean.
So, we're just going to put our phone
down, take a very quick deep breath.
Let's record.
Yesterday, I messed up.
Yesterday, I called a guy named June who
grew from 1,000 to 30,000 followers in
the past two days on Instagram, and I
asked him if he felt any different
because of the sun and numbers, but he
said no. And a lot of times when I do
these scripts, I'll often like just do
one to two sentences at a time, just
because you'll notice after like one
sentence, you'll get out of breath. you
might start slipping up over your words
and your voice starts to start
constricted because you don't have as
much air. Taking a deep breath, chest up
so you just feel more confident. Subtle
bodily signals of power posing.
And it was honestly so exciting because
it was a nice reminder that with content
creation, creating with purpose to
genuinely help people is the most
important. This reaffirmed to me that
the algorithms don't just reward catchy
hooks and retention hacks. Uh, don't
just reward catchy hooks and retention
hacks. That's kind of a tongue twister
there. So, we're going to have to reread
that. Starting with this was,
and this was honestly so exciting
because it's a nice reminder that with
content creation, creating with the
purpose to genuinely help people is the
most important. This,
okay, I'll just start with this
reaffirmed.
This reaffirms to me that the algorithms
don't just reward catchy hooks and
retention hacks, but reward the people
that actually care. And I believe that
people can sense that through the
screen, not people. I'll just start with
and I believe that.
And I believe that viewers can sense
that through the screen. So stop
obsessing over the numbers when you
create content and just focus on trying
to help the people through your videos.
The numbers follow impact. And there we
go. It's a very short video. It's going
to be less than 37 seconds. We're going
to chop it up. So, let's just jump right
into it by pressing the check box right
here. Yesterday, I called a guy named
Edit. Now, let's start our editing
process. Cutting up when I start saying
the words, trying to be as quick cut as
possible.
>> Yesterday, I called
Yesterday, I called Yesterday, I called
a guy. Yesterday, I called the guy
Yesterday, I called a guy named June who
grew from 1,000 to 30,000 followers in
the past two days on Instagram, and I
asked him if he felt any different
because of the sudden numbers, but he
said no.
No. Ends right there. No. And this was
honestly
No. And this was
No. And this was honestly so exciting
because the most important I tripped up
the word there. So, we're just going to
cut it here. Maybe cut a little bit off
of it. Important. This reaffirm. We're
going to use the white scrubby things.
We can just press and hold it and then
move it down. You can also pinch the
timeline with two fingers. Oh, I did not
mean to do that. Pinch the black space
on the timeline with two fingers. And
you'll see you can zoom in or zoom out
to make more fine cuts like this is the
most important. This can cut a little
bit off here. Important. This re a
little bit more. The most important.
This reaffirms to me that the algorithms
don't just reward catchy hooks and
retention hacks, but reward the people
that actually care. And I believe that
people can sense that through the
screen. And I
>> There we go. They actually care.
>> Split. Delete. Care.
care.
I'm going to trim this
care and I believe that viewers can
sense that through the screen. So, stop
obsessing over the numbers when you
create content and just focus on trying
to help the people through your videos.
The numbers follow impact.
There we go. A very 30se secondond
piece. We're just going to watch it one
more time to see how it sounds.
Yesterday, I called a guy named June who
grew from 1,000 to 30,000 followers in
the past 2 days on Instagram. And I
asked him if he felt any different
because of the sudden numbers, but he
said no. And this was honestly so
exciting because it's a nice reminder
that with content creation, creating
with the purpose to genuinely help
people is the most important. This
reaffirms to me that the algorithms
don't just reward catchy hooks and
retention hacks, but reward the people
that actually care. And I believe that
viewers can sense that through the
screen. So, stop obsessing over the
numbers when you create content and just
focus on trying to help the people
through your videos. The numbers follow
impact. And there we go. Perfect. We
have it all cut up. First thing we're
going to do, we're going to press the
first clip, go to volume, and increase
it to around 200 to 300. Like 200 is
actually okay. And then just press
loudness adjust. Yesterday, I called a
guy named June who grew. And now that
should adjust all the videos to just be
slightly higher volume, which is always
good. Never want the video to be overly
quiet. So the very first thing we're
going to do is simply press text and
auto captions. And these are the
settings. Never change them on this
screen. and just generate. And there we
go. Now we have all the auto captions
generated. The first step we do is press
the green box, pinch with two fingers,
and move it slightly up so it's about
30% height from the screen right there.
Just above that third quadrant of the
screen right there. Yesterday I called a
guy named June. We're going to remove a
little bit because it always gets black
at the end because the capture cut auto
captions for some reason always go a
little bit over the video which is
really annoying. So we're going to trim
that. Yesterday I called the guy. And
what we're going to do is go into style
first and choose our font of choice. So
I'm going to go into fonts and then
search. And I'm just going to choose the
classic font. This is the classic Tik
Tok font that is always used
automatically on Tik Tok. Close it. And
then go to styles and then press that
like no style thing. And there we go.
Yesterday I called a guy named We're
going to press the first caption box.
pressed edit captions and then we're
actually going to do one new editing
tactic for today's video. Today we're
simply going to make sure all of the
lines are only one line long. So, first
we're going to edit a spelling error
there. And every time you see the
sentence get cut off and start a new
line, simply press return there. And you
can see they're both one line.
yesterday.
Actually, I'm going to I'm going to
correct the capitalization here. I
called a guy named June. His name was
actually June without an e. Who grew
from 1,000
to 30,000? Actually, I want to put a 30k
there. Who grew from I'm going to
actually stop it from who grew from
1,000 to 30,000 followers. Like that.
Who grew from 1,000 to 30,000 followers
in the past two days? in the past two
days
on Instagram just returning every single
time.
So now we can rewatch it and see where
the captions get misaligned because
every time we press that edit captions
button it'll just get slightly
misaligned. Yesterday I called a guy
named right here named starts about like
here.
Yesterday I called a guy named June who
grew from 1,000 to 30.
>> I think 1,000 grew from
>> Yeah.
1,000 right there.
from 1,000 to 30,000 followers in the
past two days on Instagram. And I asked
him if he felt any different because of
the sun in numbers asked because of the
sun and numbers
the numbers follow impact. And now I'm
going to do one more optional part and
you don't have to do this, but I'm just
going to show how it's done. Tomorrow
we're really going to focus on the
B-roll, but because I do talk about
yesterday
and I'm just going to add a B-roll clip
on top of the talking head portion. So,
I always film my talking head portion
separately. What we're going to do is
simply press overlay. We're going to
press add overlay and then find the
clip. There it is. 33 seconds and then
add.
And then from here, we want to first
mute the B-roll clip. So, mute it.
and then use two fingers and pinch it in
and do that. And we can just watch how
it looks and decide when to stop using
the B-roll clip.
>> Called a guy named June who grew from
1,000 to 30,000 followers in the past 2
days on Instagram. I asked him if he
felt any different because of the sudden
numbers, but he said no.
And I'll just cut it off here by
pressing split on the clip and then
deleting the second portion. So it looks
like this.
>> No. And this if you have a corresponding
clip to whatever story you're telling or
even if it's just a random clip, it's
okay. Try to make it loosely relate to
what you're saying. So like for example,
if I say with content creation creating
with purpose to genuinely help people,
right? These are all sentences with
meaning that can correlate to like
random things. For example, genuinely
help people. Maybe I can have a clip of
like me talking to a friend or like I
don't know, me being wholesome with a
cat. Like I honestly I'll just include
this one cuz why not? So I'll just
include that there. Zoom it in. Volume
down to zero.
>> It's kind of ironic, I guess, because
I'm saying genuinely help people and I'm
looking at a cat.
>> The purpose to genuinely help people is
the most important. This reaffirms to me
that the
>> And yeah, I'll just cut it right here.
And there we go. Like the the B-roll
doesn't really have to completely
correlate to what you're saying. It just
has to like be interesting enough where
it's like, okay, I could see how it kind
of could relate. Maybe, maybe not even.
Like most of the time, people are going
to be caring way more about what you're
saying and the A- roll. and the B-roll
kind of just is added there to make it
more stimulating. Now that the video is
done, simply going to press the 1080p or
720p, whatever it was at, move it up to
4K, press the arrow button, export. Now,
I want to show you guys right before a
little hack that I do for my Instagram
thumbnails and my Tik Tok thumbnails.
So, what we're going to do is we're
going to go to say any clip in the
video. Honestly, I'll just show this
one.
And what I'm going to do is press text
again, and we're going to take any text
box that already exists, double tap it,
change it to whatever thumbnail text we
want to have. So in this case, I would
want a day 105 for my series, and then
move it towards the middle where I
always put it, zoom it in in the preview
button, in the like middle left of the
screen right there, and then screenshot.
And then I'm just going to like crop the
screenshot for the bottom and the top
and press done in the top left and save
to photos. And once we're done with
that, we don't even have to save the
video or anything. We just X out. Go out
and then go to Instagram or plus in the
bottom. Press our
>> Yesterday I called a guy named June who
guy named June and then we're going to
edit cover add from camera roll and then
press that thumbnail and then done in
the top right. And there we go. We're
just going to write our caption date 105
of road to
100k a month.
And then we'll just put one hashtag
hashtag content creation. You can also
add a tag because I do mention the
friend June. I might as well add a
little tag there and press done. And
there we go. And now that it is done, we
can preview it one one more time if we
want by pressing that preview button.
Yesterday I called a guy named Jude.
>> And there we go. We can just press
share.
Um, and there you go. It is up. Another
quick hack I'll show you guys is you'll
notice it is on my front page, but not
every video is pinned to my profile. And
sometimes you want to keep like a clean
profile of like just pictures. What you
do when it shows up is you press it. You
press the three dots in the top right
and then you simply do remove from
profile grid and it'll remove it from
your profile grid. And there we go.
Let's go over to Tik Tok. Press the
plus. Upload. Yesterday I called a guy
named June who grew and we're just gonna
immediately go to our caption day 104.
Now mind you I almost never use hashtags
but for the sake of new accounts I would
recommend just to like get picked up on
the algorithm a little bit quicker. Why
not use a hashtag? And for select cover
I'm just going to add my text through
this. And since you can't upload your
own custom thumbnails from your camera
roll on Tik Tok, you have to kind of
like write them out yourself. So, that's
what I do on the Tik Tok app using this
little text adding button. You press
save. And there we go. And I'll just
press post. Takes a bit longer to
upload. So, we're just going to wait a
second. And there we go. It is uploaded
to our page. We're going to refresh a
couple times because you'll notice if
you actually check the video, there's a
chance it might just be not actually
uploaded for the first one or two
minutes because it is under review all
the time when you post a video.
Yesterday I called a guy
>> and I'll show you how you can check that
out. If you just press the bottom three
buttons here in the bottom right, the
three dots and you go to copy link,
it'll say the video is under review
right now. It can't be shared. So the
video will not start getting views until
this process is over and that takes
about a minute. All right, as you can
see, it's up. It's now getting views.
Congratulations
on completing day two. Pat yourself on
the back, okay? Because I know progress
might feel slow. You might have come
into the program with these expectations
of, "Oh my god, we're going to get a
first vir video right away. Oh my god,
we're just going to blow up." I would
say a proper expectation in the first 30
days to get your first video over 10K
just to simply see a 10K on either a Tik
Tok or Instagram real video. Very
simple. The reason why I say this,
right, and that might sound a little bit
underwhelming, is because content
oftentimes works like an exponential
graph where you're not going to see most
of the results because you're still in
this building phase of improving your
skill set as a content creator. You're
still learning how to feel extremely
comfortable on camera, feel really
comfortable in your communication style,
learning the editing, learning exactly
how to make your videos as engaging as
possible using your life and your
stories. And it's okay for it to start
off slow. first few videos I would only
get like like a thousand views, 2,000
views and I was over the moon. So set
your expectations low and still work
really hard because it is a long
journey. I've been creating content now
for 4 years and only now have I really
started making money. Like it took me 3
years to hit my first 10K month in
anything content related. So like it's a
long journey and at the end of the day
it really is just time. So I want to
give you guys a little bonus module
before you guys leave off. Go into the
Discord real quick. Just leave somebody
a positive message. Or what I want you
guys to do is simply go to the content
review section. Find somebody especially
try to find somebody who doesn't have a
review yet. So say Adam Slaw. We're just
going to check out his video. Leave a
little piece of feedback and just say
congratulations on posting today. Good
job. You know, make somebody else's day.
So then they probably feel motivated and
I guarantee somebody else will come in
and just give you some valuable feedback
as well. So let's just quickly watch.
>> This is day 25 of posting every day as a
videographer and college student. I
started this content challenge because I
wanted to posting. Okay, I like it. I'm
loving the multitasking. And then I'm
just going to leave an encouraging
message. Keep it up. Love the
consistency, bro. And boom. Make
somebody else's day. I will see you guys
tomorrow for day three. You know, we do
not stop. [ __ ] congratulations on
completing day two. You're a beast.
You're awesome. I'll see you guys
tomorrow. Now, if you're in this
program, you are here for a reason. It's
because you chose to take action. It's
because you know you have potential to
create to actually impact lives. I know
what that feels like. I felt like that 2
years ago when I first wanted to
actually get into personal branding
content. So in this module specifically,
I want to explain how your mind honestly
is stopping you from becoming a better
creator. Now I know you probably came in
here because you really want the
scripting templates that I have or you
really want the video tutorials on how I
create my content, how I edit, how I
script, how I film, what times I should
post, but realistically none of that
matters. Yes, they matter past a certain
threshold, but once you reach a certain
threshold of a minimum quality for your
videos, which you will hit very quickly,
you will learn minimum within the first
week. That is at most how long it will
take, like seven videos to learn this
content strategy. But the main thing
that might be holding you back that
honestly held me back for so long is
simply not feeling comfortable enough in
my own skin and believing in myself
enough to really understand that I can
actually lead online. So, there's three
misconceptions that I want to break down
first because the content strategy you
will be doing in our program is very
simple. You will only be making talking
head videos where you are talking to the
camera, talking about your life, your
experiences, and your knowledge. That is
it. Now, before you have any objections
like, "Oh, I don't really want to put
myself out there. I don't really want to
talk." Personal branding literally only
works when you are being so
embarrassingly, humiliatingly,
terrifyingly yourself online that it
attracts the people who will genuinely
love you for you. And I guarantee you're
going to feel resistance towards it. I
felt resistance towards it for so long
because I was so scared of putting
myself out there. I had three fears that
I had to overcome. And the only way I
overcame it was through the systems that
I will teach you later on in this video.
But the three things were a fear of
being seen, imposttor syndrome, and
lastly a lack of faith and discipline.
Now for the first one, a fear of being
seen. I simply did not believe at the
core that I was worthy enough of being
seen and being respected and being
helpful and impactful to thousands of
lives, let alone even like 10 lives. I
couldn't imagine sitting in a room and
just talking to 10 people and genuinely
helping them. That's how little I
believed in myself. Now, if you feel
relatable to this, don't worry. That is
completely normal. And that is honestly
the reason why most people don't even
start content because they feel, oh, you
know, I'm not old enough. I don't have
enough experience. I grew my page from
zero to 100,000 followers about
self-development, about personal
development, about fitness despite only
having done it for six months. I grew an
audience of 100,000 people in one month
from my words, from my influence, even
though I wasn't the most qualified
person in the world. But I want to
highlight one thing. If you feel that
you're not qualified, good. That's
actually the point. Even if you feel
you're only on step two of some sort of
journey, there are hundreds of thousands
of people out there who are stuck on
step one. and you are the best person to
actually be able to help them because
you know what it's like to be at step
one. You've recently been at step one
and you are the best possible person to
help that version of yourself of your
former self out there because no one
understands your unique problems, your
unique limiting beliefs, your unique
pains, traumas like you. You're not here
to create content like me. You're not
here to build a brand like Alex Ramosi,
like Iman Godzi, or like any other
YouTuber that you love and watch. You're
here to build a brand about you, helping
the people that you know how to help
best, which is simply people who relate
so so deeply to your former self. And if
you're still not convinced and you still
have this kind of irking imposttor
syndrome within you that doesn't want
you to actually speak out and be
yourself on camera, just know this. All
you need is a thousand people. You don't
need an audience of 100,000. All you
need is a thousand people who truly
understand you and your problems and you
have genuinely helped even just a little
bit from getting to step zero to step
one. If you're talking about fitness, it
doesn't have to be how to get to Olympia
and win a bodybuilding competition. What
you're trying to teach people oftentimes
can just be how to get started with
lifting. That's what the content I was
making was in that first month. How to
get started with lifting, how to get
started with discipline. And it worked
because I really understood that person
who just couldn't get started. I was
helping specifically the version of
myself who needed somebody to simply
hold their hand and say, "It's okay to
take things slow. It's okay to not
understand where you're going. All you
need to do is get started." So, if you
feel you're not qualified enough yet, I
guarantee hundreds of thousands of
people who need your guidance to even
get to the next step. And most people
try to be the entire guide for their
entire life. No, that's not what TikTok
is about. That's not what short form
content is about. You're simply guiding
them to take action. Take one step in
their journey. If you can motivate
somebody through your short form
content, to step into the gym one more
day, to actually rethink about their
relationships for one day, you've
changed their life more than 99% of the
other content out there. So accept that
fact and just know that you are 100%
worthy of leading people on the
internet. Now, however, that being said,
it's going to be a long grueling
process. You're going to be posting once
every single day, and that is tough.
You're going to have school, you're
going to have work, you're going to have
every single excuse and reason not to
make a video in 2 weeks, and you're
probably going to have this insane
resistance to actually fall off. And
when that happens, I have certain
systems for myself to get me through
those rough patches because sometimes I
can't just will myself into working.
Sometimes I need a routine. Sometimes I
need a literal journal entry that I look
back and read at every morning just so I
don't lose that fire within me. And
that's the one thing that stops most
people is they lose the fire eventually.
They start listening to everybody else's
voice out there who tells them, "No,
these videos are cringe. You should stop
this content creation thing. You're only
getting like 100 views per video right
before you make a breakthrough. It could
be on month two that you make an
absolute breakthrough. You get your
first video to hit 100,000 views." and
you wouldn't know because you don't get
past that initial hump of resistance
where you're still improving at the
content, where you're still finding your
voice.
It's a long process and you have to
accept that and it's okay because if you
really want this lifestyle, you want to
actually build a business around your
passion of creating content, of
impacting lives, you're not going to be
stopping after a month. Even if you do
hit your first $10,000 month within the
first two, three months, so what? You're
going to still continue it, right?
Because this is what you want to do. So
view it from a long perspective. Okay?
And here are three systems that I like
to do to actually keep that fire alive
every single day. The first one is
simply writing down my goals and putting
them somewhere that I see every single
day. So, I want you guys to actually
whip out a piece of paper and write
these three things down. In 6 months,
how many followers do you want to have?
What do you want your income to be? And
how many times a day are you going to be
posting in order to reach those goals?
Those are the three. And write them
down. I recommend at minimum one post a
day. Right now, I'm doing one post a day
on these two accounts. And remind
yourself every single day that this is a
long process. You're not in this for the
short run. Having a six-month goal and
focusing specifically on the
action-based goal of how many times
you're going to be posting every single
day grounds you in congratulating
yourself for taking action and removes
that short-term gratification thinking
of I need results to come right away and
I'm relying my motivation and my faith
in the process on simply results.
Because if you think like that, no
matter if you have insane success in the
first month, that motivation will die
off immediately once the results start
dying. Greatness and great personal
brands is not built on short-term
thinking at all. I've been doing this
content thing for now almost 4 years.
Four years, even just 6 months of doing
this consistently will completely change
your life. But I just want to put that
perspective to you that it's a long
process and you can't expect to blow up
immediately. So write down those three
goals and put them either on your phone
wallpaper, your computer wallpaper. I
put them on my notebook that I plan
everything, take my school notes and
take my business notes on and before I
put my goals on my actual wall in my
bedroom. So, anything works, but just
constantly remind yourself that this is
your purpose. These are your goals and
you don't forget them and get distracted
by all the other voices outside that
will tell you to do other things that
will tell you to give up. It's normal.
It's resistance.
It's the world telling you what they
think is true. But the only way to block
that out is to simply remind yourself
every single day what your vision is.
Now, the second one is very simple, but
it's daily action. Post once every
single day and only congratulate
yourself for showing up. That is it. Do
not congratulate yourself for how many
views you get. Don't start patting
yourself on the back for posting one
video in a week and getting 10,000 views
because you didn't show up for the other
6 days. Content is simply a game of how
often you can show up. And if you can
show up once every single day and do
that on repeat, your content and you as
a communicator, as a person will become
so unrecognizable
that you will become the creator who
actually deserves thousands of
followers, who deserves a business
that's serving thousands of people. Now,
the last thing I want you to do is
simply lower your view expectations.
Don't expect crazy views in your first
month. In fact, congratulate yourself.
Every time you hit a video, even over
a,000 views, I congratulate myself. I
made a decent video that reached a,000
people. Imagine a,000 people in a
lecture room. That is an entire lecture
hall times two that you just got the
opportunity to speak at. That's how cool
it is to be able to reach a thousand
people through the internet. Lower your
expectations in that sense. Even if you
get two comments on your video, that's a
W. Two people saw your content and were
like, "This guy is cool enough for me to
engage with." This idea of expecting
virality and being so emotionally
attached to it is so irrational because
the way the internet works is that you
can reach thousands of people through a
single video. And that in and of itself,
even if it's not high thousands and
viral, is still an insane number. And on
the business side, let's just think
about it for a second from a business
perspective. Say you're selling a $100
info product and you reach 10,000 people
in your next month of posting, but you
convert 1% of them to even go down your
funnel. And then 10% of those people who
even go down your funnel actually
convert to a customer, right? So 0.1% of
10,000. How many people is that? That's
10 people paying you a h 100red bucks.
That's $1,000 you just collected from
10,000 views on TikTok. Something that
doesn't seem insane to you at first.
That's how the business numbers work.
You don't need millions of views. You
just need to impact those small number
of people to the core, which is why you
need to speak authentically from the
heart, from your unique experiences,
because that is the only way you'll
genuinely impact people and actually get
them to engage in the first place. Don't
shoot for viral bait content. Simply
shoot for people who genuinely vibe with
you. And I guarantee there will be way,
way more than you actually think. The
science of audience building is not the
science of trying to figure out what's
popular. The science of audience
building is being your authentic self.
So much so that you touch people so
deeply that through the power of the
internet and the algorithms, through
that depth of engagement, the algorithms
will simply push out your content to
more of those people out there who vibe
deeply with you. That is how you build a
long-term influence. That is how you
become an actual creator with a personal
brand and impact lives. Welcome back to
day three. You're still here?
Congratulations. Seriously, I don't know
the exact statistics, but I know like
most people quit any kind of new
endeavor within the first two days. One
day they can show up and charge
themselves. Second day they're already
like, "Ah, this sucks." And then third
day, third day, they are gone. They
didn't even like watch this module. So,
congratulations on getting here. Today's
main focus is going to be a message to
our former self video, which is
basically what all my content, all my
viral content is predicated on. It's
messages to our younger self. So, we
provide value to people who really
resonate with us. A big theme with the
message younger self too is that there
are a lot of people out there with the
billion users on Tik Tok, the billion
users on Instagram that are super super
similar to our younger self. Aside from
that, we're also going to be learning
how to add way more B-roll because
that's going to make our videos really
engaging. And by this point, it's going
to be the complete essential workflow
that I do for all my videos. And we're
going to be learning how to add
background music. So, specifically also
have five to 10 B-roll clips. I'm
specifically going to be using nine
bureau clips in this video. So, a decent
amount. Just collect them throughout our
day. I'm going to be sourcing all this
bureau that I already exist in my camera
roll, but if you don't have it already,
just collect like 5 to 10 second clips
and I will see you guys on the computer.
Yo, what is up guys? Welcome back to day
three. We're going to jump right into
it. We're essentially going to
brainstorm five different videos. But as
per usual, we're going to start off our
brainstorming process on the piece of
paper or on this Google doc by
forgetting about content completely. And
I know I put example videos so you can
feel free to watch them just so you get
a sense of what these kind of videos
will be like. But I want you to
completely forget about content when you
write these questions. And the reason
why is because there's no way you can
genuinely be present with your answers
and be present with your script to the
point where you actually spill some
valuable personal sauce if you're
thinking about how can I structure my
video like our favorite credit like
don't worry I'll give you guys a script
template. Don't worry about it. Okay. So
just focus on giving honest honest
answers that are genuinely true. So the
first thing we are going to do is think
of yourself exactly one year ago because
our video is going to be a message to
our past self. In fact, almost all my
videos are messages to my past self
because that's who I can help the most.
So, think about your past self from
exactly one year ago. Today is April
16th, 2024. So, when I mean exactly one
year ago, I mean like think of yourself
from April 16th, 2023. And that's what I
did. And I want you to pause this video
real quick and close your eyes for 20
seconds and remember this person, what
she he or she really wanted, what they
thought about, what was top of mind for
them all the freaking time during this
time. What were they really stressed
about? What do they really want? And
just sit with it. Okay, pause the video.
20 seconds. Go. And once you've done
that, I want you to list five specific
things that have happened in your life
that your younger self would have been
hyped and excited about in the past
year. The first one is I now run a
business that I don't need to hop on a
sales call to sell. That is personally
exciting to me because I didn't really
like sales calls. They were just like a
lot of pressure. And another one, I hit
four 10k months. At this point, a year
ago, I'd never hit a single 10K month.
So, I would have been like,
third one, I got my mom to finally
approve of me dropping out of college.
Past self back then, I don't even think
would have fathommed that. The fourth
one, I hit 100,000 followers on
Instagram for lifestyle content. Now, I
don't think I would have had a massive
like mindblowing moment if I heard,
yeah, in a year you'll have 100,000
Instagram followers. But if he said, for
lifestyle content, he'd been like, what?
I am way too insecure for that. How did
you do that? And then the last one is, I
went on three separate trips with
creators and entrepreneurs. And I don't
even need you to explain in these
sentences why they were so impactful or
why they'd be so cool to your younger
self. Just simply list them. So, pause
it right now and answer it. Okay, you're
back. The second question I want you to
answer is, what is one specific change
it took for your younger self to get
there? Also, one sentence. You can make
it two if it's like a very long lengthy
change. But for the first one of uh
running a business I don't need to hop
on sales calls to sell. It took me
putting down my impatience for quick
money for a second and focusing on the
product. Now that is a blanket statement
that probably would have raised a lot of
eyebrows and questions from my younger
self as does any piece of unsolicited
advice. My younger self would have been
like what the heck explain more. And
that's what we're going to do in the
next question. But don't really think
about that right now. Just list five of
them. Second one, uh, for hitting 10K a
month four times, I would say it took me
learning how to fall in love with the
work and letting go of the egocentric
obsession with results. Okay, fall in
love with the work and let go of the
egocentric obsession with the results.
The third one for getting my mom's
approval of dropping out of college, it
took over 20 discussions and continuing
to work on myself with patience and
detachment from what from my mom's
approval of my results. Little typo
there. And the fourth answer is uh to I
hit 100K followers on Instagram for
lifestyle content. What did it take? It
took me posting a reel once every single
day specifically during school when my
schedule and stress would be the highest
which also took a strong sense of
purpose and desire to help others
through my content. And the last one
which is going on three separate trips
with creators entrepreneurs. What did it
actually take? It took me saying yes
despite my fears of committing the money
or time away from my business or life.
Now I want you to note that I am fairly
specific about what it took. I don't
just say like work hard or keep
believing in yourself. I want you to be
a little bit more expansive because we
have very simple affirmations when we
talk to oursel. But here we're
specifically trying to stand out to our
younger self. What uniquely did it take
that your younger self also didn't
really know? And I could have easily
said, you know, just work hard on your
business. But instead, I said like put
down your impatience, right? Because
that specifically I never correlated
impatience with not being able to build
a business that I actually enjoy working
on or fall in love with the work, right?
You can just say that. But I also
expanded by saying let go of the
egocentric obsession with the results
because I actually thought that being
obsessed with the number and just like
banging my head into like I'm going to
hit 10K a month. I'm going to hit 10K a
month would actually be the main thing
that would drive me towards it. But I
actually didn't know that I had to stop
caring so much about the freaking
number. The third one too, like I could
have just said, you just keep talking to
her and keep working on yourself. But I
expanded it to with patience and
detachment from my mom's approval of my
results. And the reason why I say that
is because like that part too would have
surprised me of like really I I was
motivated by what my mom thought about
me and like I used that as motivation
and fire under my ass. And that's
interesting that it took detachment. So
these are really like specific changes
that would honestly surprise your
younger self too. Now the third
question, pause to answer number two if
you haven't already. But the third
question is now imagine you literally
took this sentence and told your younger
self to make this change. What is one
doubt your younger self would have said
and word it like your younger self. For
example, right? If I said to my younger
self, if you want to run a business, you
don't want to hop on sales call to sell,
put down your impatience for quick money
for a second and focus on the product.
What would I have said back then? I
thought Horoszi told me to sell before
you build a product. I would have said
that or I would have thought that. Next
one. If you want to hit 4 10K months,
learn how to fall in love with the work
and let go of this egocentric obsession
with results. I would have said, I've
heard that before, but why does that
correlate with hitting a 10K a month and
actually making more money? So, these
doubts are probably really weird. This
question specifically, answer it well
because this is quite possibly one of
the biggest hacks that I have for
content scripting and making my videos
actually hit and be engaging and go
viral. So, answer those questions. And
for number four, at this point, you're
in a conversation with your younger self
and you hear your younger self say, "I
thought her tell me to sell before you
build your product or I've heard that
before, but why does that actually
correlate within a 10K month and
actually making more money?" Imagine
your younger self said that to you right
now. What do you say back to your
younger self's doubt to convince them of
your point? Write extensively and
detailed here and use specific numbers
when you can. And this one's going to be
the longest portion of the video, three
to four sentences. So, in response to
the first one, I thought told me to sell
before you build your product. Look,
you're never going to be able to sell in
good conscience a product that doesn't
exist. And people will sense in your
content in VSSL that you don't feel that
passion towards your product that you
would feel if you simply built it first.
Besides, building out a video course
will take like a month of focused work
that you'll actually enjoy, too. And
when you actually love your product and
business, creative ideas for selling
will flow, and they'll feel natural.
You'll feel way more motivated to keep
working on the business long term, which
is way more important than that first
month's revenue number. Okay? And you
can feel free to read three, four, and
five, but at this point, it'll get long,
so I won't read over those. But now, a
final short message to your younger self
you needed to hear back then. simply
just inspire or reassure or motivate
them or suggest that they do an action.
So for the first one, right after I say
you'll feel way more motivated to keep
working on the business longterm, which
is way more important than the first
month's revenue, I would simply say
right after as a final note of
encouragement, just trust that you'll
sell after you've built your product and
go build the most beautiful product you
possibly can. So it's a call to action
and it's a reassurance just saying like
trust the process, you know, but I don't
just say trust the process. I'll go a
little bit more in depth and say like
trust that you'll sell what you've built
after you've built it and just go build
the most beautiful product you possibly
can. And then of course there's three,
four, and five. Once again, I'm not
going to read them because at this point
it would get very long. And yes, this
process might take a while especially to
go like in depth if you haven't done
these kind of exercises before of
personal essay writing short questions.
And this might feel really freaking
annoying like oh my goodness, why do I
have to script so much? I have to write
so much. This will also be good fodder
for the next like four videos. and we're
going to reference this tomorrow and the
day after. So, work hard on these. I
know it'll take a little bit more time,
but you're going to come up with such
compelling ideas if you sit down and
answer these questions. And once you're
done, take your answers and paste it
into the script at the bottom. So, I
ended up choosing the discussion with my
mom and successfully convincing my mom
to allow me to drop out from college. I
just literally pasted word for word
using hook two and then question three,
four, five, and question two. I
literally just copied and pasted them. I
didn't reformat it at all. So, this is
what the example script looks like right
now. I'm going to move this here. And if
you look at it, you'll realize it really
makes no sense grammatically. Like,
let's just read the first sentence. I
have now successfully getting my mom to
finally approve of me dropping out. And
I realized in order to do so, I actually
had to. It took over 20 discussions and
continuing to work on myself with
patience and detachment from what my
mom's approval of my results. You might
have already reformatted and made it
grammatically correct, but let's just go
through that process really quickly. I
have now successfully uh instead of
gotten my mom to finally but instead of
gotten I'm going to say convinced I have
now successfully convinced my mom to
finally approve of me. Finally sounds a
bit redundant and in the first sentence
or in the first like two to three
sentences we want to make it as quick as
possible when like we do repeat words
just cut them out because the first
three sentences are the most sensitive
part of the video. It's where the
retention is hanging at the absolute
thread and people aren't completely sold
on listening to you yet because they're
strangers on the internet at the end of
the day. That's how the organic content
reach has to work. So, we're just going
to eliminate any repetitive redundant
wording cuz I have now successfully
uh you know what I'll say I have now
finally instead of saying I have now I
finally convinced my mom to approve of
me dropping out. Actually, I want to say
of college just so it's a little bit
more specific. And another way we're
going to improve the hooks is make them
more specific in these niche ways where
people will relate to them a little bit
more. Another way I'm going to do that
is simply saying, I finally convinced my
Korean mom to approve of me dropping out
of college. And I realized in order to
do so, I actually had to It took over 20
discussions. Do over 20 discussions.
You know what? I'm actually just going
to admit this part entirely. I actually
had to the 20 discussions part isn't as
important as the second part of the
sentence which is I had to continue
working on myself with patience and
detachment from and from here I'm
actually going to emit this part as
well. I actually had to detach
myself
detach myself or actually no just detach
from uh instead of what that was
incorrect from my mom's approval of my
results. There we go. The hook is now a
lot shorter for one, and it's a lot more
concise, and it gets to the point, the
real important point, quickly without
dillydallying on these weird things,
like weird unnecessary details that
don't contribute as hard to the point.
The purpose of this video at the end of
the day is a message to our younger
self. And I could even say, I convinced
I finally convinced my Korean mom after
20 discussions to approve of me dropping
out of college. And I realized in order
to do so, I actually had to detach from
my mom's approval of my results. Now,
we'll just move on to the rest of the
three points and just fix any
grammatical hiccups. Now, I know you're
probably thinking, do you think your mom
changed? Instead of saying thinking,
let's say asking. Now, I know now you're
probably
actually wondering, you're probably
wondering, do you think your mom changed
her mind because of the money and income
numbers? But honestly, and instead of
but, I'm going to say and. And honestly,
yeah. But I realize you can't expect
your 50-year-old Korean immigrant mom to
understand the opportunities you've seen
in the creator economy and the internet.
So, just forgive her for not
understanding, but also be okay with
disagreeing and thinking she's wrong in
certain ways because of that information
gap. And don't try to motivate yourself
to make more money out of spite to prove
your parents wrong because it's fickle,
insecure motivation. You won't create
and believe in yourself at your highest
potential if you have that insecure chip
on your shoulder because it's basically
saying your parents are right. Uh
instead of saying so
honestly, I'll just say and if your mom
never told you you're good enough to
achieve your superly ambitious dream, I
believe in you. After all, somebody
who's naturally dumber and lazier than
you, I guarantee has done it before. And
there we go. That is the script. And now
it actually makes grammatical sense. And
if you read it aloud, just make sure you
don't find these like weird hiccups that
like, okay, that doesn't flow as well as
I want it to. Let's change like a but to
an and or an and to a so, etc. Or just
cut out like an honestly. So if there's
a slight hiccup, yes, change that
grammar. This structure is the exact
structure that I basically use for my
viral videos. I start with the hook that
encapsulates a very specific outcome and
then I explain what the solution is or a
trick or tip that I use to get that
outcome. And then I delve specifically
not into just explaining what that tip
or trick was, but convincing the viewer
why their doubt is wrong. And that's
really key because the key with a short
form video is not to walk them a through
Z through this entire process guide. The
point actually is honestly just to
convince them, hey, think this way and
just change your mind about this little
belief that you have. That is enough
value you'll provide in your video to
actually make somebody really enjoy your
content and really get invested because
you can't expect to deliver the most
massive PhD dissertation through your
videos. Even if you do feel this desire,
if anything, that's safe for like long
form videos. But for short form, all you
can do is really just convince viewers
to think differently about a very slight
thing that they have. If you can achieve
that, then you've done your job through
your short form content. So now that we
are done with our scripting, let's move
over to our phone and film it out. Okay,
we're going to start off by copying.
Going to cap cut and then camera. And
then we're going to go into the
teleprompter. Press that edit button and
uh paste instead of that and apply. And
there we go. We're going to move it to 3
minutes. We're going to position
yourself with good lighting. Um like
right here is pretty good lighting. and
I'm facing right next to the window,
which means I'm just getting a ton of
natural light, which completely
overpowers the lighting that's behind
me. Just make sure obviously your most
overpowering light that in your 360
degree peripheral is in front of you and
not if you look at this behind you
because then my face just looks darker
and it looks a little bit more
off-putting on camera. So, we're going
to turn around and face our camera. And
once again, we're going to do our
prefilming warm-ups. Sometimes you can
just go like or do some tongue twisters
if you're feeling just a little bit like
your mouth muscles haven't been warmed
up yet cuz you haven't been talking much
today. Peter Piper picked a pe of pickle
peppers. Peter picked a pe of pickle
peppers. Peter Piper picked a pe of
pickle peppers. And I want to do one
more emphasis today. Try to incorporate
your hands if possible because sitting
completely still like this can constrict
you. Try to incorporate your hands if
you can. I just get into a more
conversational flow state and that's the
goal. And one more thing too is I want
you to visualize this camera is your
younger self. Close your eyes if you
really have to and just imagine your
younger self is right there sitting in
front of you.
Genuinely visualize in a really weird
way that my younger self is right there.
And then you can take a deep breath and
press record. I'm just going to do the
quick like little cap cut thing because
the audio always seems to gets messed up
in the first take.
I finally convinced my Korean mom after
20 discussions to approve of me dropping
out of college. And I realized in order
to do so, I actually had to detach from
my mom's approval of my results.
And usually we like to do like one to
two sentences at a time just so we don't
run out of breath.
Now, I know you're probably thinking, do
you think your mom
I read it wrong. Oopsie.
Now, you're probably wondering, do you
think your mom changed her mind because
of the money and the income numbers? And
honestly, yeah. But I realized you can't
expect your 50-year-old Korean immigrant
mom to understand the opportunities
you've seen in the creator economy and
the internet. So, just forgive her for
not understanding, but also be okay with
disagreeing and thinking she's wrong in
certain ways because of that information
gap. And don't try to motivate yourself
to make more money out of spite to prove
your parents wrong because I did that
and it's a very fickle insecure
motivation and you won't create and
believe in yourself at your highest
potential if you have that insecure chip
on your shoulder because it's basically
saying your parents are right
>> and never told you you're not enough to
teach your stupid ambitious dreams. I
believe in you. After all, someone who's
naturally dumb than you, I guarantee
that the work. All right, please.
>> And there we go. I feel pretty good
about that take. Let's just press that
check box.
I can press edit. Now we can hop right
into the editing. I finally first thing
we always do is we cut off that dead
space at the beginning right by
scrubbing with that white scrubby thing
of my results
right there. My results. Now you're
probably
Now, we're going to do two very specific
new things with our edit today. The
first one is we're going to more
aggressively add B-roll. And I already
have a bunch of B-roll saved up in my
camera roll. And we're going to be
sourcing more B-roll for my camera roll.
We're also going to just film one new
piece of B-roll today. All I'm going to
do is film myself working next to my
laptop. If you can see right here, I'm
literally just going to prop my camera
next to the window and then press
record. And all I'm going to do is just
like go on my laptop and do a little bit
of medial tasks for probably like a
minute. Not even that long. I'm just
going to like look around.
Now, the clip is like 30 40 seconds
long. That's okay. And yeah, just going
to stop it right there. Press stop.
And now we're going to go into Cap Cut.
And this is what we're going to do with
the B-roll. Every 5 seconds, we're going
to change the B-roll or specifically
every like sentence or half sentence. So
right here, we're going to change the
B-roll. So we're going to do a B-roll
clip for the first 5 seconds and then
another from 5 to 10, another one from
the uh 10 to 15, and so on. So, we're
going to start with the zero to five.
And we're just going to go into our
camera roll. And very specifically, I'm
going to find my B-roll uh of me talking
to my parents, which is about in like
August. So, this footage right here, I'm
going to use that add, which might take
a second because it's 24 minutes long.
So, this could very well take 3 minutes.
Okay. Now that the B-roll is
successfully added in, we're simply
going to mute the B-roll first. finally
convince my Korean mom after and we're
going to cut it right here at the end of
the sentence. So, split and then delete
the second half portion. And then we're
going to find a new bureau clip for the
next sentence, which is going to be me
hugging my mom
right here. And we're just going to zoom
in. We're going to find the spot exactly
in the B-roll where I hug my mom, which
is going to be about like here.
And what I'm going to do is I'm going to
split and start the B-roll there. So,
we're going to take that first half
portion and delete it. And then we're
going to simply press and hold it and
scrub it until it meets that part and
kind of clicks into place right after
the first B-roll clip. So, there's no
space in between. And then we're going
to mute this B-roll.
And we're actually going to zoom in a
lot more because I want this to really
show and be really visible. even if it
does get a little bit blurry because of
the zoom out of college. And I realized
in order to do so, I actually had to
detach from my mom's approval of my
results. And then we're going to cut it
right there. Split and just make sure
that aligns with the end of the clip
right there by just mag kind of like
magnetically attaches to it. Just use
the white scrubby thing at the right
side. Results. Now, you're probably
wondering, do you think your mom changed
her mind?
And when I say because of the money and
income numbers, I'm going to add a new
B-roll clip. Add overlay. And then any
video of me kind of just showing my
laptop screen really. So this one can be
right here. Add.
I might zoom in a little bit more just
so it's visible. Once again, mute it
because of the money and the income
numbers. And I'm going to cut it off
right when it says end. So once again,
find that exact point by finally tuning
with your thumb and then split at that
point and delete the second portion
numbers. And honestly, yeah, but I
realized right here it's a new bureau
clip. Uh Korean immigrant mom. I'm just
going to add another overlay. And this
time once again, uh find another clip of
me with my parents right about here. And
this one is another one.
Add. And then we're going to find the
exact part of the B-roll. I'm I want to
show both my parents in this. So yeah,
my mom walking, I think, is a good
action point that I want to show cuz I
don't want the B-roll to look static and
almost look like a photo. We want the
B-roll to be in the dynamic portions of
the shot. So here, when my mom is
crossing and moving, we're going to take
that and start it right when the
movement happens. split. I take out that
first half part of the B-roll once
again. Mute it. Volume all the way down
to zero. And then scrubbing it all the
way until it hits that beginning of the
clip. Yeah, but I realized you can't
expect your 50-year-old Korean immigrant
mom to understand the opportunities you
and when you see when I say you've seen
in the I'm going to also split there.
Add another overlay. I'm going to use a
plane because I think that represents
opportunity just like flying.
And I'm going to move the volume down.
See in the creator economy and the
internet. So
we're just going to scrub it to there.
The internet. So just forgive her for
not understanding. And use this one.
Going to mute it. But also and I'm going
to start it not when I'm talking to the
camera, but when I actually start
working like there. Split. Delete the
first portion. And then move it to where
I want it to start. which is but right
when it says but move it to there
understanding but also be okay with
disagreeing and thinking she's wrong in
certain ways because of that information
gapom
one like this one
>> that and then just add cuz I think that
represents me creating at my highest
potential and believing in myself so
volume down to zero
and you won't create and believe in
yourself at your high
and split there. And then we're going to
add one more B-roll clip right here.
And this one is a little bit more stern.
So, we'll just use this one of me
pouring yerba mate into my orange juice
cuz why not? We're going to add that.
And once again, these bureau clips don't
even relate. Like in this sentence, I
say, "Your mom never told you that you
can achieve your really stupid ambitious
dreams. I believe in you." This clip is
just me pouring juice or tea into juice.
Like that has nothing to do with
believing yourself yet. I think the
randomness too just gives it a very
authentic feel. So, I'm going to start
when the juice starts pouring in just
cuz I like capturing those dynamic
action moments. Scrub it there. All
right. And if your mom never told you
you're good enough to achieve your
stupidly ambitious dreams, I believe in
you. Dreams, I believe in you. And then
after all, I'm going to cut it. So,
split. Delete the second portion. After
all, someone who's naturally dumber and
lazier than you, I guarantee has done it
before. All right. Peace. And here I'm
going to add one more overlay just
because I wanted to cut to me pointing
my the finger at myself and cut off the
B-roll only at that point. I'm just
going to find a clip of me like
dillydallying, being lazy, me
dillydallying.
Yeah, actually this one's not bad. Me
collecting B-roll. We're going to add
that
and then just throw it in there like
that. Volume to zero. After all, someone
who's naturally dumber and lazier than
you.
and then split and delete the second
portion. Then you I guarantee have done
it before. All right, peace. And there
we go. Now we have successfully added
our B-roll. And the last thing we're
going to do is actually add music. So
what we're going to do, choose any song
that you want from YouTube. So go into
YouTube and just search any song that
you want. And I like using songs that
are familiar to people. If I really want
to viral max, you have to use a song
that is at least slightly familiar to
somebody. And I don't like using
lyrically loud songs because then it
obviously obstructs your a- roll of
talking. So maybe instead of Q KT HR cuz
I want to use a very popular song, one
that would be recognizable to a lot of
people, I will use only by Lehi. And so
what we're going to do is simply share,
copy link, and then we're going to go to
a website called YTMP3.
We're going to search up on Google. And
literally all of these are the same
exact thing. Although sometimes one of
them is down, so you just check the
other one. But basically, go to any of
them and you paste the link to the
YouTube video there and you press
convert. You're probably going to get
hit with some ads. So, let's just close
that. Might take a second to load. And
there we go. We have a download button.
Be prepared for another ad there. So,
just close that. And it's going to ask
you, do you want to download this
official audio? Just make sure it has
the YouTube title in it because if not,
it might just be like a virus. So, make
sure it has that title of the YouTube
video. We're just going to download it.
And there we go. If you see in the
bottom left, the blue arrow is now
completed. So, we're going to go back
into Cap Cut. And don't allow paste.
Just like I don't know why it always
does that, but then what you want to do
in order to add music is simply go into
audio and then go into sounds
and then press that file button right
there in the middle. And then you want
to go to device and select from device.
And then from there you should see your
downloaded file right in the top left of
recents. But if not you can simply
search it up and you should be able to
find it and press open. And there we go.
Now it should be listed in your library
of songs in Cut that stay there forever.
So if you can notice this is my entire
collection of songs that I use in the
background.
[Music]
>> We're going to use this one. cut the
beginning just because sometimes songs
have like half a second of dead space
for some reason at the beginning. I
don't know why. Artistic choice maybe.
We're just going to cut that and scrub
it to the beginning. And one last thing
you'll notice is that sometimes the
audio of the song is way too
overpowering when you listen to it while
editing. I finally convinced my Korean
mom after 20 discussions to approve of
me dropping out of college. And I
realized in order to do so, I actually
had to detach from my mom's approval.
just in case cuz you really do not want
the music to be too loud that you cannot
hear your voice. If anything, shreds
slightly on the quieter side. I usually
change the volume from 100 to around
like 60% in cap cut for the music. I
finally check. And even if the music
becomes faint, it's better to tread on
that side than literally just have it
absolutely blasting to the point where
you cannot hear your voice. Convince my
Korean mom. You can't really hear my
voice at that point. So yeah, I like to
tread with caution and just go to like
60. This song's a little bit quieter, so
I might do 70.
Me dropping out of college. And I
realized in order to do so, I actually
had to detach from my And there we go.
But now you should see if you see in the
in the middle left of the timeline, it
actually says the video is 4 minutes and
2 seconds long because it'll get
extended after with all this extra space
that the screen just becomes black, but
the audio keeps playing and the video
becomes really long. So, you just want
to cut off the audio right when it's
like at the end of the video and just
press split and then delete that second
portion of the audio than you. I
guarantee I've done it before. All
right.
And there we go. That is our finished
video with a ton of B-roll, background
music, and that is my complete content
creation process right there for all my
most viral videos. This is the same
exact process has gotten me like a
million views. That process is that
simple. And you'll notice it really just
comes down to how compelling you're able
to script and answer those personal
questions and how deep you're able to
get into your own past self psychology.
Cuz the better you can write your
messaging and speak your messaging, the
more compelling and the more relatable
to your target audience, which at the
end of the day is going to be your
younger self and people who really
resonate with you and your personal
story. If you do have any hesitations
towards writing advice towards your
younger self, I just want to leave you
off with one last piece of
encouragement. Everybody is an expert to
somebody. You might think, I don't feel
right giving advice online. You know, I
feel like there's people who are smarter
than me, more successful than me, etc.,
etc., etc. And you have to realize with
personal branding, yes, somebody else
has made more money than you. Yes,
somebody else has done whatever
accomplishment with a bigger number or
to a larger extent or whatever. But even
if you're just one year into this
journey that you're helping somebody
else out with in your content creation,
that's actually better than somebody
who's 10 years along the journey because
you'll be able to relate to that younger
self better than somebody who's 10 years
down the line who's jaded, doesn't
really even remember the psychology of
their younger self at that point. And
when they give advice, they can only
give advice to somebody who's only one
step behind them. It's better to give
advice to somebody who's one step behind
you than 20 steps behind you. cuz then
advice gets lost in translation and then
the steps get messed up. So, you're
always an expert to somebody else out
there and everybody is an expert to
someone. And the last thing I want you
guys to do after you've uploaded it is
simply copy the link to it and go to
copy link. Go into our Discord,
specifically the content reviews section
right
in the content reviews.
And then this is my day three video from
the course. And then simply paste it
there question mark and post it. And
then after that go back to the content
reviews and simply leave somebody else
one more review message. So for Turbo
Warbo specifically try to choose
somebody who doesn't have a review yet.
So Turbo WBO I'm going to go check out
his video. Not now. We're not going to
open.
>> This year is going to look the exact
same as last year and next year is going
to look the exact same as this year. If
you don't learn to allow uncertainty in
your life to
>> I'm actually going to say very
specifically I would flip the look the
same as last year part of the sentence
without the word you.
And there we go. And other than that,
congratulations on finishing day three.
This one's definitely the hardest day by
far, but pretty much the best video that
we've made so far. And if you actually
check out my numbers on the Instagram
reels that we've posted in the past 3
days, this video is actually has been
the best performing. And I knew that
would happen simply because the message
to our younger self format is, in my
opinion, the most effective way to
actually engage and get people to relate
and get people to get genuine value from
your content, which in turn will help
you grow. So, pat yourself on the back.
Congratulations for finishing day three
genuinely and I will see you guys
tomorrow. Peace. Before we move on to
day four, I do want to go over this
quick little mini module on collecting
B-roll. And I'm going to make this as
short as possible because B-roll is not
something I plan. I get asked this a
lot. Do you plan out your B-roll? Do you
have a shot list? No. But I do have a
list of shots that I will frequently
take and go to. It's not like an actual
list I plan out ever because that is way
too much work. That is way too much
thought, especially for the quick
production time in order to actually be
consistent with this. One of the biggest
things is not to overly plan it out.
That also lets authenticity flow through
the shots that you collect throughout
your day. So, I want to start off with
the first type of shot, which is a 0.5x
shot. And I will just literally set down
my phone, press the 0.5x button, put it
to the side. It'll always be of me like
in specific times of day doing actions.
for example, working on my laptop,
journaling in the morning, reading in
the morning, exercising at the gym. Like
if I'm doing a set at the gym, I'll plop
down my phone at 0.5x and then I'll do
my set and then I'll finish and then
obviously turn off the camera. And I'll
also use 0.5x while walking. So if you
ever see a shot of me just walking to
school, walking to a building, and I
have the camera in my hand, it's very
visibly in my hand. You can see
everything that's going on around me.
it's a 0.5x shot because if you do a 1x
on your iPhone camera, then you're not
going to be able to really capture
what's going on around you and it's just
going to be a zoomedin shot of your
face. So, I really like the 0.5x when
I'm handheld and I'm walking. The second
type of shot is simply a 1x shot of my
laptop screen. And I'll actually use
this way more than you might initially
notice. Every time I talk about any
numbers on [ __ ] or any revenue numbers,
instead of pulling up a screen recording
or a screenshot on my iPhone, which
often looks tacky if you add it as a
sticker, I will take a video of my
laptop screen. So, literally put my
laptop screen in front of me, pull out
my iPhone camera, and record whatever is
going on on my laptop screen, even if it
could be represented with an iPhone
screenshot. And the reason why is
because it looks so much more cinematic
when it doesn't add this bulky overlay
and instead actually captures what it
looks like from my eyes point of view,
like my human eyes point of view. So
oftent times it'll be [ __ ] screenshots or
Discord screenshot or like a Google
image even. Sometimes if I want to pull
up a Google image to represent some sort
of graph, I won't pull it up on a
screenshot. I know it's like a little
bit more work, but that adds that
cinematic element. And the last shot
that I'll do is a time lapse. a
time-lapse of me eating, time-lapse of
me doing my morning routine, or a
time-lapse of me working on my laptop.
And oftentimes I'll do it at 0.5x.
Sometimes I'll do it at 1x if I'm know
for a fact I'm going to be staying at
the same location, but the 0.5x just
allows the wider angle where it captures
a lot more on the screen. It's a little
bit lower quality resolution obviously,
but it allows for me to move around. If
I'm doing some sort of work task and I
get up, I have to stretch, it'll
actually capture that because it's just
0.5x, it allows for more flexibility of
movement within the frame. Now, with all
these B-roll shots, with a time-lapse,
it's usually around like 10 to 30
minutes that I'll let it run. But for
every other shot, my 0.5x shots, I will
capture at least 30 seconds worth of
footage. Actually, for my laptop screen
videos, they'll be like 10 seconds long.
And for the videos of me walking when
I'm holding the camera at 0.5x, then
that will be 10 second long clips. But
if I do a video of me working, if I do a
video of me exercising or reading, I'll
do it for at least 30 seconds cuz I want
to capture enough footage just in case
my face looks weird during like a
10-second interval and I can use the
part where I don't look as stupid or if
I'm like picking my nose or something
stupid that ruins the shot can happen
within like a 5 to 10 second interval.
If you capture around like 30 seconds
plus, then you'll always kind of just
have this mental guarantee that the shot
will actually be good enough to be used.
So, I hope this helps. I will see you
guys in the day four module. Welcome
back to day four of the content academy.
Now, I know you might be thinking the
course has been kind of basic so far.
Let's actually get into the groove of
like getting results, you know, making
some money, getting our first freaking
viral viral video. And I want you guys
to understand why I'm taking a little
bit slow in the beginning. And it's
because I want to make sure you guys
have the foundations of content creation
that will carry through for the months
to proceed in your content creation
journey. And so we are going to be doing
some pretty pretty big important tasks
today. And the first one is going to be
laying out an exact story to brand your
entire life around online. And the
easiest easiest way that I found to do
that is simply to set a goal and then
brand your page around you trying to
accomplish that goal. And I'll touch
upon that in a second when we get onto
our laptop. The second thing we're going
to do is learning how to add B-roll in a
little bit more advanced way so we can
actually retention hack visually in the
beginning. The third thing we're going
to do is optimize our Tik Tok and
Instagram profiles to reflect the exact
brand image that we want to give off.
Whether you're trying to convert for
your business, whether you're just
trying to build a following or whether
you're trying to just express yourself
honestly online. It's going to
accomplish those three things with our
bio strategy. This is going to be our
best video that we've made so far. We're
simply just stacking wins on top of each
other. We're simply building upon all
the lessons that we learned in the past
3 days. And our videos are only going to
get better from here on out. So without
further ado, let's jump onto the
computer. Today's primary mission is to
build a brand around your life. And
today's tasks are very simple. We have
three tasks. The first one is going to
be establish the purpose and identity of
your life's brand. Second one is going
to be optimize your Tik Tok and
Instagram profiles and bios for your
life's brand. Third one is going to be
make our first life brand video. And by
life brand, I literally just mean
building this personal brand around your
life, specifically your life story as it
plays out and as it has played out. So
essentially present and past. And feel
free to look at any of these six
examples as well of people doing daily
vlogging content that have built brands
around their life using that daily
content based on this specific purpose
that they are on in life. So, my
example, obviously, you've probably
seen, wrote $200,000 a month in my
business. June, who is vlogging every
day until the end of this college
semester. Caleb, he is writing his first
film in 30 days, and he's documenting
the process for the next 30 days. Demo,
he is documenting every single day in
short form content his road to his first
bodybuilding show. Read e-commerce, he
documents his road to making a million
dollars by the end of 2024. And then
Jedcal, he documents his road to making
$100,000 in revenue with his startup.
And there's a bunch of other ones that
I've seen. That's just some examples of
how people have turned their lives into
brands. And today's task is basically to
establish that for yourself. But before
we set any ambitious goal or find the
ambitious goal that we're going to
essentially build our life brand around,
I want you to first ask yourself the
question of simply, how do you want to
help people with your brand and content?
What is the outcome that you want to
give other people from watching your
content? Oftentimes we get into content
creation because we have this initial
idea of we want to build a life creating
content because it's more fulfilling for
us. We want to build a remote scalable
income or we want to scale our business.
But I want you to take a step back from
that because this question is very
important for why people will actually
watch you and your page and keep coming
back to your page every single day. What
will bring people the reason to come
back to your page every single day? So I
answered, I want to show people that
achieving their crazy ambitious dreams
is not something that is outside of
themsel and inspire them to take action
towards these goals. It's okay if it
actually has nothing to do with
philosophy or their whole life. Maybe it
simply is like get people to eat
healthier or get people to be off their
phones more or get people to be kinder.
Any of these work. It's simply good to
ground yourself every single time you
wake up or every single time you feel
this massive resistance towards
concentration. It's like what am I even
doing with this? Is it really helping
anybody? you just come back to this.
This is why you're doing it. And it's
simply a reminder to yourself that you
can always come back to, which is simply
I want to show people that shooting
their crazy ambitious dreams is not
something that's outside of himself. And
me showing up is part of that purpose.
So even if the views aren't good, even
if nobody shows up to watch tomorrow,
it's okay because at least I tried in
this purpose. And that purpose doesn't
go away just because the numbers are
down. So now I want you to pick out a
goal or mission you have in life right
now and make it very specific and binary
in a sense of there will be a checkpoint
when you actually hit it and every
single day up till that point you
haven't hit it yet. So an example of a
non-specific goal that isn't binary with
a yes or no you've hit it yet or you
haven't hit it yet is like become a
better person become really good at
juggling. I have become good at this
skill or I have become a good juggler.
It's completely subjective. And the
reason why we want this for our content
is because people subscribe to very
specific goals that they can live
vicariously through. It's kind of just
the nature of content. They want to live
vicariously through your life. And
that's the kind of essence of a life
brand. They're watching vicariously
through your struggles and your journey.
And they're getting the value of being
inspired by you or learning how you're
going through and navigating these
challenges. If this is the goal and the
mission that they're going to be
subscribing to in your content, then it
has to be really easy to follow along to
and really easy to understand. So, when
you say trying to become better
basketball player, it's hard for people
to instantly tune into those because
that still has a lot of vagueness and a
lot of lack of clarity when you just
simply say become good at this. So,
that's the reason why I made the goal
grow my business to $100,000 a month in
revenue because there will be a day
where I said we have completed this.
Now, you might be wondering, "Oh, but I
don't want to stop content after I've
completed it." That's okay. You can
always create a new goal. Like, I could
always just say, "Okay, road to $150,000
a month in revenue." Or I could simply
change it to like growing a billion
dollar startup. I could easily have said
road to growing my business. But that is
so much more vague or road to becoming a
better entrepreneur. That is so vague
and that can be an underlying like
subheading, but you still need a very
clear, easy to follow along to
storyline. That's pretty much like my
hack to getting views and like the
massive growth that I've had on my
Instagram page in the past 5 months. The
only reason why I've been able to have
that massive growth is because people
can predictably follow this goal and
mission and they can understand it from
the instant I say it. So, set yourself a
very specific goal. And if you don't
have it already and you're kind of
wondering, I think the series content
would be good, but I don't know what my
purpose is in life. I don't know what my
mission is in life, so I just want to
keep making a little bit more random
content. It's okay to switch up on this
goal. You could simply say road to
$10,000 a month as a student. Then you
realize you actually don't want to make
$10,000 a month and you care more about
your studies and you actually want to
get a 4.0 GPA. Then you're like, okay,
I'm actually going to discontinue
because I didn't feel personally touched
by that goal. You can always switch in
the future. Like there is nobody telling
you you have to create this type of
content. I could always switch my my
series tomorrow if I wanted to. I enjoy
this series. Don't view it as this
extremely extremely narrow limiting
thing. Simply see it as like a way for
people to understand what journey you
are on really quickly on the internet.
It's more so essentially a marketing
tool, a very surface level marketing
tool for people to very quickly tune in
and understand the context of your life
without needing to go through an entire
explanation. I kind of enjoy these
things and like I'm kind of trying to
get better at this. Pick a goal and
attach that mission towards your brand
and that'll make for a very very easy
way to grow. Once you have that goal or
mission, I said grow my business to
$100,000 a month in revenue. We can move
on to the third question which is tell a
personal story related to this goal and
why it connects to this goal and make it
four to five sentences. This is going to
be the meat of today's video. and I
answered, "In the past like 2 years,
I've always wanted to make lifestyle
content and share all the lessons that I
learned in my life with as many people
as possible. I think that's the reason
why I create content in general, but I
realized content creation is not as
simple as having a helpful message and
instantly reaching a million people with
that message." I realized if you want
people to listen to your videos, you
actually have to do something that makes
people want to listen. This doesn't
really have to do much with $100,000 a
month. This is just personal story to
me. It's like, why did I embark on this
goal? your personal story of like why
you chose this goal could simply be I'm
taking a course right now on personal
branding and Mino told me to choose a
goal so I guess I'm choosing this and
I'm kind of scared about this goal but I
don't even know if I'm going to continue
it in a month but here we go. The story
could literally be anything. Don't put
this pressure to have it like be this
grandiose lifealtering thing. Even this
like the $100,000 a month really isn't
that important to me. The personal story
could be anything and it really just
gives a picture into why you think what
you think. And that's really essential
to building this personal brand around
you because it's one thing to simply
state what you do in a day. And it's
much more impactful when people can
understand the why behind those actions
because then they can really get to know
you as a person through the screen and
build that kind of parasocial
relationship that is kind of necessary
for audience building on the internet.
Now the last question I want you guys to
answer is so why are you pursuing this
goal then? Why does it matter to you?
now. And it's going to be five to six
sentences. So, I am pursuing this goal
of $100,000 a month in revenue because
in complete transparency, I simply want
to inspire other people to chase their
crazy, ambitious dreams. In fact, I
really don't care about having a lot of
money. In fact, I'm pretty satisfied
with $10,000 a month. The money number
of $100,000 a month simply stands out to
me as crazy ambitious to the point that
it seems impossibly beyond me. And if me
showing all the stress, self-doubt, and
my own suckiness as a human being helps
somebody get started in taking steps
towards their ambitious dreams, I feel
like I've already succeeded. And once
you have done with that, you can simply
insert it into this video portion
script. Once that is done, I'll show you
guys my example here. Today is day 109
of road to $100,000 a month. Now, why
$100,000 a month? Well, for the past two
years, I've always wanted to make
lifestyle content and share. I won't
read the rest of that. And then I say,
I'm pursuing this goal because in
complete transparency, and then I delve
into the answer from question number
three. And then my conclusion, I simply
added follow to stay tuned on the
journey. And I'll see you guys tomorrow.
So, I always end my videos with this.
I'll see you guys tomorrow. Peace. And
this time, I just added follow to stay
tuned in the journey. You can choose any
of these. You don't have to say I'll see
you guys tomorrow. You don't have to say
follow stay tuned for the journey. In
fact, you don't have to say either of
these. You could just be like, I feel
like I've already succeeded. End the
video there. But it's always nice to
have just like a very positive call to
action, positive reinforcement at the
end of every single video. Keeps people
hooked in order to come back. So these
kind of positive messages, even if it's
as simple as like, I'll see you guys
tomorrow, it's like a friend greeting
you goodbye. It's a very positive note
that feels good. And adding some kind of
element of positivity towards the end,
always give somebody a very slight
subconscious incentive to come back to
your videos. Now, once you are done with
that, before we even film our video, I
want to just talk about optimizing our
Tik Tok and Instagram profiles for your
life brand. So, we're going to move over
to my phone and I'll show you guys
Instagram first. Right now, I'm just
going to run very quickly through how to
optimize your bio. And it's a very
simple template that pretty much every
single Instagram, especially like
business owner, personal brand, uses,
which is if we hit edit profile, I'll
show you guys. In the bio, I simply have
my location and I put like my heritage
recently of like Korean. Just adding
that to the first line. This isn't
essential, okay? But I will note it does
help you give off slightly more of a
personable vibe. When people can
understand that you are a real person
who has a location in life, has a
heritage. You can even put like your age
if you want to. It helps people see you
as a real human being. Now, this second
line is just a simple life motto tagline
that represents you as a person. Not the
series and the goal that you're on, but
simply a quick introduction to you as a
person. I think at one point I really
had like my Tik Tok there, right? So,
anything that really just quickly
represents you. It could even be what
you do for a living or what college you
go to if you're a student at college.
Like all of these are very easy
identifiers for people to at a very
quick glance understand at least a piece
of you or something that encapsulates a
good amount of you in one sentence.
Lastly, at the bottom, I have my
documenting every single day till I hit
$100,000 a month. I shortened it.
documenting every day till 100k a month
because you want your bios to be
generally short. Putting your goal here
is very big because if you're going to
make this storyline content about your
life, you'd want your bio to reflect
that just to reinforce, oh yeah, this
person is still on this journey. This is
what I'm going to follow him for. And
lastly, if you want and you have a
business that you are scaling already,
then I have this little arrow here. And
then sometimes I also do start your
personal brand. On that note, I'm
actually going to keep that there
because that is a call to action to the
link in my bio, which is content premier
academy right there. And if you want to
add a website, simply hit edit profile
again and then you can find the link
section for your profile picture. I
highly highly recommend a clear head
shot of your face that is like about
shoulder height simply because if it's
just a vague picture of you on a balcony
or something. Yes, it might look nice as
a picture, but you have to realize that
if you see the bottom left of the screen
like it is tiny, they're not going to be
able to discern that little bottle that
you have in your hand, the little watch
that you have on your arm or the
background even that you are at. What
they are going to be able to discern is
a extreme close-up of your face like
this. And that's how they'll easily
recognize you. And this profile picture
is the subconscious image that they have
of you and your brand. So you want to
make it very clear identifier of you.
And then for your name, I just simply
put like my name. This is what pops up
at the top of your bio. And then for
your username, do not put a number at
the end of your name. I know I have an
MP4, but that represents the file of a
video, but do not put a number at the
end of the name. It is the easiest way
to seem unprofessional, especially if
you're a business owner, to hurt your
conversion rates because you'll seem
just like a casual user of the app
rather than somebody who has their own
professional brand. And now, if you take
a look at Tik Tok, we just have the same
exact thing. If we just hit edit
profile, you'll see my username is
sigma_amino.
I could change it to mino.mpp4, but eh,
I'm too lazy and I've kept it for a
while. If you've seen my bio, it is
literally the same. Since Tik Tok bios
are shorter, I don't put my location or
my country flag. I simply put the
tagline that represents me and then my
documenting. You know what? Actually, I
have to change this. Documenting every
day till 100k a month. There we go. Mind
you, on Tik Tok specifically, you can
only add this website after you've hit
a,000 followers, I believe. So, if you
don't have that, I would highly
recommend just linking your Instagram,
especially if you have a business to
sell because then nobody's going to be
able to really convert over to your
business unless they have a way to get
to your website or they have a way to DM
you and funneling them over to Instagram
is the easiest way to do that. Also, you
have a YouTube there's a YouTube link
right there as well. So now that we're
done with that, let's go over to Google
Docs and we can just start with our
video and
copy the entire thing and then going
over to Cap Cut right there.
Teleprompter
and then press the edit button and
delete it from before. And then paste
our new script and apply. Move it to 3
minutes. Once again, always uh cutting
out that first clip because the audio
always gets messed up. the first take on
Cow Cut's app for some reason. Maybe
that's just my phone. I don't know. Try
it out yourself. But now a big thing,
too. We're just going to test to see
where the lighting is good.
Okay, this lighting seems to be better
when I am right next to my window. So,
I'm going to go right nice and close to
my window. And since this video is very
short, we're just going to jump right
into it. I've already explained all the
guides on, you know, filming
meditations, making sure you feel really
comfortable and in talking
conversational flow with good posture,
deep breaths, and we're just going to
jump right into it.
Today is day 109 of the road to $100,000
a month. Now, why $100,000 a month?
Well, for the past 2 years, I've always
wanted to make lifestyle content and
share all the lessons that I learned in
my life with as many people as possible.
And I think that's the reason why I
create content in general. But I realize
content creation is not as simple as
having a helpful message and instantly
reaching a million people with that
message. I realize if you want people to
listen to your videos, you have to do
something that makes people want to
listen.
So I'm pursuing this goal of $100,000 a
month because in complete transparency,
I simply want to inspire other people to
chase their crazy, ambitious dreams. In
fact, I don't really care about having a
lot of money. I'm pretty satisfied with
$10,000 a month, but the number money of
I say but the number money but the money
number I think it's moving a little bit
too fast. So, I'm going to slow down the
speed to like 12 or 13 cuz I think it
was on like 14 or 15 before. But the
money number, okay,
but the money number of $100,000 a month
simply stands out to me as crazy
ambitious to the point that it seems
impossibly behind me. And if me showing
all the stress, self-doubt, and my own
suckiness as a human being helps someone
else get started in taking their own
steps towards their ambitious dreams, I
feel like I've already succeeded. So
follow
Yeah. So follow to stay tuned.
So follow to stay tuned on the journey
and I'll see you guys tomorrow. Peace.
And there we go. We can just press the
check. Today is day 100. And edit right
after.
>> Today's day 100. And we are now in the
editor. We're going to fast forward
because I've shown you guys all my
editing tricks on cutting out all the
dead space. Now that we've fully edited
up and chopped up our clips, we're going
to do a very special overlay trick here,
which is basically hyper cutting the
B-roll in the first two to 3 seconds, or
basically just like the first sentence.
So, in order to do that, we're simply
going to grab a piece of B-roll that we
want to add to the beginning. Since the
first sentence is today's day 109 road
$100,000 a month, I'm going to choose
this clip right here. It's it's almost
too fast for the viewers to process and
then it makes it very very stimulating.
First, we're going to find that like
action clip. I like this part right here
where I'm kind of moving the pen to my
hand into my mouse. So, I'm just going
to split it there. Delete the first
portion and then turn the volume down to
zero.
Now, we're doing a very important thing
here
at around the You can even zoom in on
the timeline with two fingers, but
literally just at that like 0.5 second
mark, right in the split point between
the first second and the 0 second, we're
just going to split it there. And then
we are going to find another part of the
clip where I'm slightly
like in a different position
essentially. And then drag it all the
way back to the beginning. And you're
going to see this very cool effect where
it's a slight stutter in the frame. So
it looks without obviously needing too
many different clips. So it looks like
this. Today is day 109.
And we're going to split right here.
Right when I end the term day 109. Split
right there. Delete. And we're going to
add a new overlay. So you can see these
overlay clips literally are 0.8 seconds
and 0.5 seconds long. And generally
speaking, keep them like under 1 second
long. That's how you make them cut so
fast that people cannot react. And you
only have to do this for like the first,
you know, 3 4 seconds of the clip. Or I
would say I'm doing it basically for
like the first 4 seconds because past
that point, you hook them. But this is
just one of those tactics to like really
essentially blast the viewer with visual
stimulus at the beginning. I'm not
saying to make it obstructive with a
bunch of stickers or text on the screen,
but simply fastm moving visuals. So,
we're going to switch it to a new clip
of me in a time lapse. We're going to
add that
and then we're going to move it
>> day 109. If we want to make the time
lapse even faster, just so it hits even
harder in this like first hyper
stimulating portion, what I'm going to
do is adjust the speed by pressing the
clip, hitting speed. You can do this
with any clip, by the way, not just
time-lapses. But then we're going to
turn the speed up. Let's say I like just
see what that looks like.
And then we're going to split it right
around like 0.5 second clip. Once again,
>> right when I say two, we're going to add
a new overlay. And this time we're going
to do a rock climbing clip. So I want to
find a rock climbing clip where it's
kind of zoomed in. I like this one. It's
very isolated of just me. Going to use
that clip. Load it up.
Obviously, the clip starts with me like
putting the camera down. So what we're
going to do is first turn the volume
down to zero. We're going to find the
point right where I'm like on the wall.
So, right about there. We're going to
split it, delete.
[Music]
And then right here, we're going to do
that same trick that we did with the
first clip where we select a new portion
of the clip. I actually like the part
where I'm falling. So, I'm going to use
this part right here. Split, delete the
middle portion, and then move it over.
And you'll see this very cool cutting
effect where it's still the same clip,
but it's action happening. It's very
intriguing. So then we split right
there. Delete the excess. And then we'll
just move it over there. And as you can
see now, if you watch over those first
uh 4 seconds, it's not even 4 seconds,
like first 3 seconds.
>> Today is day 109 of the road to $100,000
a month. Now,
>> it's engaging, but it's not spammy and
it's not over the top, too. Now, we can
move on. And at this point, we'll do our
typical of like one B-roll clip every 3
to 5 seconds. So, a new overlay we can
add here. And at this point, we've kind
of used a lot of the B-roll, but we can
essentially just recycle the existing
B-roll. So, we can go back to this clip
right here of me watching my computer
screen. At this point, it's just rinsing
and repeating the same B-roll process of
muting the clips, changing them every 3
to 5 seconds, switching over to adding
new overlay of a different one. This
one's just my face. Same process. And
then back to the time-lapse video. And
then after that talking portion, and
then we're going to add a rock climbing
clip. Now, because this is a rock
climbing clip and I feel like rock
climbing does have an inherent narrative
visually, uh, I am allowing myself to
just use this same clip for the rest of
the video. However, you'll notice I'll
split and cut out the moments where I am
stalling. However, I'll still cut out
the 3se secondond part of the clip where
the clip gets static just because I
don't want the B-roll to ever get
static. Then just add auto add captions.
At this point, we're just doing our
checklist of moving it up 3/4s, changing
the font to classic,
selecting that, and moving up a little
bit more so it's like 30% up from the
screen. Then we're just going to cut out
the beginning portion just to make it
one line each. Fixing any typos as
usual. Then once that is done, we're
going to go into our music file device
and then find the one we want. Kux thr.
We're going to cut out the beginning
portion, move it up to the beginning,
and then we're going to change the
volume down to like 60 for the music
clip. And then we're also going to
change our talking head portion to 200%
and loudness adjustment as usual. Press
to check. And there we go. And the last
thing we're going to do is just make
sure at the end we cut off so the black
part doesn't drag on because of the
music. And then that is it. Let's just
change our export settings to 4K 30 and
export. And with that, congratulations
on finishing day four of the
ContentPreneur Academy. Genuinely, good
job. It is hard to stay this consistent.
Tomorrow, we're going to be covering a
very important lesson of consistency and
how to stay consistent, especially on
your busy day. So, it's going to be much
simpler module, but I think it's
important nonetheless. So, I will see
you guys there. This next pro tip is so
important for editing. You're going to
notice I do it here as I'm talking in
this intro clip, but it's quick clip
cutting, and it's going to make your
pacing feel so much so much better in
your videos. I promise this is probably
the biggest biggest hack that you're
going to get in editing like ever. More
important than making fancy captions.
It's more important than getting OP
sound effects, OP visual effects. None
of that matters if you can't do this
simple simple thing of clip cutting. So,
I'm going to show you exactly how to do
that on my phone. Let's just jump right
into it. All right. So, here's what fine
clip cutting looks like in practice. And
it really just looks like doing the same
thing over and over. And I'll show you
what I mean by that in a second. So,
let's just watch the clip that has a
little bit of excess in it. And you
might not even notice it at first. the
final move out when her son graduates
from a prestigious college. Except I was
actually dropping out. The space might
actually look really small when zoomed
out. This is what your timeline might
look like. It's like this is the tiniest
bit of space. It's not that much, but
you'll really notice the impact of it
when you zoom in on the timeline with
two fingers. Just pinch outward and
you'll notice how much space there
actually is. This is where I actually
like to play in the timeline in about
this zoomed in where you can see the 20
frame, the 15th frame, 10 frame, five
frame. And since this is a 30 frames per
second, you can see exactly when it's a
five frames, the dot represents five
frames, 10 frames, 15 frames, 20 frames,
25 frames, and then that's 1 second has
passed. So now you can really see how
much dead space there actually is, and
we can cut it all out. the final move
out when her son graduates from a
prestigious college. I like to keep my
thumb right above the pause and play
button out when her son graduates from a
prestigious college. I can pause the
clip right there. Tap the clip and then
scrub that white end all the way down
there. And just as an extra measure,
I'll just do a little bit more oftent
times just because I know I probably
paused it a little bit too late. And
it'll look like this. Now, prestigious
college except. And there we go. Now,
the beginning of the next clip will
probably have that.
So, the audio probably started here. I'm
just going to scrub it here. Do a little
bit more
except.
And I think this one too. We can still
scrub a little bit more. And you really
have to watch and just listen to it. You
want to do it to the point where right
as you end the last letter of your word
just college except
and I think this one we could add a
little bit more like literally like two
frames more college except
>> perfect like this
>> from a prestigious college except I was
actually dropping out and this part too
I can do the same thing where I paused
it there and then I'll probably cut it a
little bit further into like herely
dropping out. It was winter break when
she finally conceded to letting me drop
out after right here too. There's too
much of a dead space. And I really, this
is so important. When you cut it out in
all these points, it makes your pacing
10 times 10 times quicker. So, make sure
you do this. Letting me drop out right
here. Once again, we've move it down.
Cut it a little bit more. Letting me
drop out after maybe 20. Like, boom.
Doesn't that sound so much so much
cleaner? And you'll notice over the span
of an entire video, you'll probably only
cut out maybe like 3 4 seconds tops from
the actual video length, but the feeling
will feel so much so much better paced
that it'll make the world of a
difference.
>> Welcome back to day five of the Content
Prer Academy. Today we're going to be
making a unscripted video. The benefits
of an unscripted video is that you can
portray much more of your authentic
energy. And maybe you guys have felt
this while doing these scripted videos
so far in the past 4 days is that it
feels a little bit forced and it feels
like a little bit noticeable that you're
reading off the script and that's okay.
I think it's really good to practice
these kind of unscripted videos. It's
going to be a little bit uncomfortable,
but that's okay because we're still
going to have a little bit of structure
that we're planning out. You'll see that
as we move on to the computer. But that
being said, I'm very excited for this.
We're also going to learn a lot about
hook scripting, which is very exciting.
That being said, I will see you guys on
the computer. Let's go. We're going to
be talking about the minimum viable vlog
system on our busy days. How we can
still create as compelling content as
possible. And this is more so just my
guide on how to make unscripted videos.
Unscripted videos do have an advantage
over scripted videos. Often times when
we script our videos, it can like give
off the energy that we are reading off a
script or it can just feel unnatural and
we're not able to get into a
conversational flow because think about
when we sound the most flowing. It's
when we aren't reading off a script. is
when we're talking to somebody and we
feel really comfortable around them,
that's the energy that we want to give
off in our content, right? And that's
like peak camera presence or camera flow
state. So, it's really good to practice
these kind of unscripted videos, too.
And the benefit is that they also take
way less time to prepare. So, I have two
examples here. Feel free to watch them.
These are both unscripted. I still have
a mental model that I want to walk you
guys through of how you can make a
coherent point because if you just turn
on the camera and start yapping, odds
are maybe the first 5 seconds won't be
interesting or hooking and the video
won't actually have a coherent point. So
like why would anybody watch it? You
know what I mean? So how can we make a
compelling idea without needing to
really write it down on paper? It's
basically an internal process of asking
myself these two questions. The first
one is what events happened today? And
this is a really easy question to answer
and it's a really good way to just jog
your memory. So, what happened today?
Right, I just listed out three things. I
ate lunch with my parents. I am
currently back home in New Jersey, away
from college for the weekend, and I
worked on my business planning out
systems for the rest of my course on a
piece of paper that night. That that's
it. Obviously, there aren't any video
ideas just from these listed events.
Like, I'm not just going to say, "Hey
guys, today I ate lunch with my
parents." Nobody cares about the events
in your life. It's best to partner them
with an actual lesson that you learned,
too, which makes you a real person,
which makes the video way more relatable
and compelling. So, we're going to be
asking Ourel a second question, which
is, what did I learn today?
Specifically, from the experiences that
happened today. So, I have three
experiences that I wrote down. Let's
extrapolate lessons from what happened
in our day. What did you learn or what
did you even think about or realize,
even if it's the smallest smallest thing
that you don't think is that
interesting, trust your intuition, trust
your realizations. Normally, I kind of
just jog them through in my head, close
my eyes for a second, think about the
event, and then think about what I
learned from that event. So, for the
first event, eating lunch with my
parents, what did I learn or what did I
realize? While eating lunch with my
parents today, I realized how much I've
grown. I'm less scared of my parents
disapproval. I used to bug me a [ __ ]
ton. I used to religiously believe
whatever they thought about me as true.
You're not working hard enough. You have
to be doing more. I don't think I could
ever feel like enough in front of them.
Now, I feel more peace with myself
around them. I think as I learned more
about myself, I realized a lot of the
limiting identities I feel like I
adopted were actually not true. This
realization lasted in my head for like
maybe like a minute during the entire
conversation, but it was the most
compelling. It's also the most
compelling to my younger self. So, I
really like this frame of like what
interesting lessons did I learn today or
what is really interesting that I felt
today that my younger self would have
gotten a lot of value from hearing and
you guys can read the rest of that. But
how can you actually spin that into a
compelling hook? And the thing is, the
video structure for my unfiltered videos
or my unscripted videos still has a
decent structure where I still will put
a lot of thought into how I will word
the hook because I don't want to just
start off saying a really boring thing
like, "Today I ate lunch with my
parents." That's a really boring hook.
Like, think about that in a vacuum,
right? You're a random stranger on the
for you page or explore page on these
social media apps and you hear somebody
say, "Today I ate lunch with my
parents." I don't give a [ __ ] that you
ate lunch with your parents. I am
currently back home in New Jersey away
from college for the weekend. Imagine I
just heard that on the for you page.
What would I think? I don't give a [ __ ]
about your life. I'm not going to care
about you being back home in New Jersey.
I don't even like New Jersey. What the
hell even is New Jersey? Never been
there before and I'm away from college
for the weekend. Okay. And the third
one, I worked on my business. Okay. So
did I. Shut up, bro. Nobody asked. Think
about this from a really harsh
perspective. Nobody asked. And and
that's okay, right? Because we're going
to spin it in a way that people will
actually be interested. And the first
variation of a hook is simply taking
your lesson learned and trying to make
it a little bit more unique to your
younger self. A lot of the life lessons
that we take away in life are very
cliche. Today I learned I need to work
harder. Yes, that might have felt really
meaningful to you, but at the end of the
day, that sounds really cliche when you
say it out of your mouth. Today I
learned that I need to work harder.
Today I learned that I need to lock in
in order to reach my goals. I've heard
that a million times. And just because
it's meaningful to you doesn't mean it's
necessarily worded in the best way
possible. So a lot of times we will tell
ourselves these very cliche mantras in
our head or we'll have these very cliche
lessons that we learn in our head. They
won't be worded in a really interesting
way when they go through our head. So
let's take these really boring
statements to ourself and let's make
them a little bit more unique or
contradictory. So the cliche messages,
it's okay to feel out of place in
certain environments. That sounds like
it's pretty compelling, but in reality
that's super cliche. Like I've heard
this a million times. What's a better
way to word it? Well, let's simply be a
little bit more specific. certain
environments and often times we'll have
this tendency to want to appeal to a lot
of people. It's like how can I make a
viral video viral video equals a million
people and my concept of a million
people is that I have to appeal to this
person in India who's 18 years old and I
have to appeal to this 34 year old
business owner and I also have to appeal
to this 21-year-old college student in
America. So, how can I spin a message
and make it universal to everybody? That
is the worst worst way to go about hook
creation. And this is one of the most
important lessons in hook creation and
actually making really compelling hooks
is you actually want to make it really
really specific. And that might be
counterintuitive because your concept of
viral videos might be that virality
equals appealing to everybody, but it's
actually the opposite. You have to
understand that these social media
platforms just have so many users and
they are flooded with so much content.
So, the art of making a hook that
actually captures somebody attention is
penetrating the noise that they've seen
for the past, say, hour of scrolling.
Somebody's been scrolling for an hour
and they've seen literally over like a
100 videos. The last thing you want is
for your video to sound the same to
something that somebody else has already
seen. Cuz the instant that we see
something that is not unique, we think
this is boring and the dopamine levels
do not shoot up. But if it's really
unique to the viewers that it is
specifically tailored to, which there
are a lot of, I want you to note, just
because you think, "Oh, there's not
enough college students who are 21 and
going through career crisis to actually
relate to this video." Yes, there are.
There's at least several million on this
app because the apps literally have a
billion users. Whatever you think is
it's too specific, nobody's going to
understand it. That is the farthest from
true. And if you watch any of my videos,
you realize that they are so so specific
to the point that there's a reason why
you're here. It's because the videos
must have spoken in such a such a unique
way to you. It's because I simply made
my videos for one person. When I think
of my hooks, I don't think about how can
I appeal to the masses. I think about
how can I make this really hit deeply to
one person. And if it hits deeply to one
person, trust me, it's going to hit
deeply to many people. Instead of saying
out of place in certain environments,
it's okay to feel out of place in
college. And this immediately knocks out
every high schooler, every college
graduate, and that's okay. I want that
to happen because if that doesn't
happen, then everybody's just going to
have like a five out of 10 level of
dopamine when they hear this sentence
and they're just going to think, I've
seen this a million times. Why would I
listen to this guy when I can listen to
David Gogggins saying it's okay to feel
out of place? Maybe Michael Jordan or
Kobe Bryant or David Gogggins, right?
These highest top 0.1%
level performers, they can say something
broad that appeals to the masses. But
you, the key for you is simply getting
anybody's attention, right? And if you
can get anybody's attention, that's how
you can get your first 10,000 followers
or 100,000 true fans. The point is to
hit with depth. But this is still kind
of broad because you might think, okay,
college students, there's a lot of
college students. I'm going to appeal to
college students. Any college student,
no, not every college student is
realistically an ideal candidate for my
audience. No. An even better, even more
hyper specific way of wording it is just
because you feel demotivated in college
doesn't mean you're a lazy bum. So it's
not the high performers in college. It's
the college students who feel
demotivated, they feel a little ashamed
about it because they feel like a lazy
bum and they want to do something about
it. So this is so so specific and in
every college campus, how many people
are going to relate to this? I don't
know like 30% of college students only
like one in three people that you know
or maybe one in five or one in 10 people
that you know will actually relate to
the hook that you say and that's the
point. Your videos are to the internet
where there are millions and millions of
people who resonate deeply with you but
you'll just never see them in person. So
it's this game of like convincing
yourself there are actually so many so
many people out there like me. I just I
can't conceptualize that in my brain cuz
I haven't seen that yet. And the
internet is simply how you reach these
people. So therefore, be extremely
extremely specific. I cannot stress this
enough. This is so important. Now, let's
do it for our third message, which is I
realize I've been doing entrepreneurship
wrong. I thought it was this build
whatever you want kind of thing, but in
reality, you have to focus on the ideal
customer and their needs. So, what's a
really cliche way of saying this message
to try and appeal and pander to the
masses without actually polarizing
anybody? Well, it's saying sometimes you
got to do the work you don't want to do.
Okay, sure. I mean, that literally
applies to pretty much every single
human being in the world, but that is
the most cliche thing I think I've ever
heard. And if I heard that, I would just
be like, "Shut up. You sound like my
mom." So, how can you resonate way more
deeply with your target viewer, which in
this case, I just use my younger self.
Sometimes in business, you have to do
the work you don't want to do. Even
better way wording this is business is
not just about building whatever you
want to build. You have to obsess over
the customer before you consider your
selfish goals. They have these selfish
goals of like hitting 10K a month,
right? Right? I could even even be more
specific and say like selfish goals of
making like making 10K a month and using
these specific examples like people eat
up numbers because they're so specific.
See when I say the word 10K a month then
people are like oh my god I have that
goal literally written on my wall and
it's not going to be everybody but it's
going to be a good amount of people. A
lot of times I work with business owners
will be like no I don't want to just
attract the customers who are like at 1K
a month trying to make 10K a month. I
want to attract the people who are
making 10K a month trying to get to 20K
a month. You have to realize that when
you try to pander to everybody on the
internet, you will never reach anybody
with depth. Now, the second way that you
can create a hook is simply by talking
about the event. Now, this is often
times a decent way to start your videos,
but a lot of times the events in our
life, like I said from before, are kind
of boring when we describe them out. For
example, I ate lunch with my parents
today. It's an impersonal, emotionless
description and doesn't really highlight
any new realizations or events. So, the
best way to describe events
realistically is to actually view them
as like reflections of novel
discoveries. After 20 years of my life,
I finally feel like I'm getting over my
fear of my parents' judgment. It mostly
highlights what you're discovering for
the first time and highlights the
emotion. That being said, if the events
are boring, often times just gloss over
them as quick as possible so you can get
to your interesting message. Next, if we
just gloss over that, we have to tell in
the rest of the video the story of what
actually happened and what you learned.
So, try to use the word you and we
whenever possible when you tell the
story. Often times, we'll go on in these
rambling sessions about today I did blah
blah blah, then I did blah blah blah.
Like, today I got lunch with my parents.
Then I worked on my business and I'm
actually back home in New Jersey away
from college for a weekend and I was
planning out systems in my business and
that was a day in the life of an
entrepreneur. Imagine you were talking
to somebody who said that. What do you
think your reaction would be? My
reaction when somebody just rambles
about me me me me me me me me me me me
me me me me me me me me me me me me me
me me me me me is I never ask you to
just give you me your life story. Why
are you telling me this? What do I gain
out of hearing you be so self-obsessed
and narcissistic in your own story?
Nobody will necessarily assume you're
like a narcissistic piece of [ __ ]
because content creation is like this
accepted norm. But at the end of the
day, how can you make it more
interesting? It's simply by involving
the viewer and actually giving them
something to chew on themselves. So if
you just simply use the word you or we
and you retell that story then you could
maybe say I ate lunch with my parents
and you know that feeling when your
parents tell you just this one thing and
it really ticks you off for some reason.
It almost like triggers some parental
trauma. It's like telling the story but
telling in a way it's like do you know
when this happens or you know that
feeling when you do blah blah blah and
it's simply inviting the person to like
yes thank you for thank you for asking
me. Thank you for asking me. It gives
the viewer space to feel like actually
present in the conversation in the video
and that is so huge. So if you just say
I I I I I I I
like talking to somebody who literally
has zero social cues and zero social
awareness in real life. That is the
feeling that you want to avoid in your
content because then there is no
quotequote value ad. At the end of the
day it's just human psychology to want
to watch things that provide value to us
that make us feel hurt because we are
obsessed with ourselves. That being
said, how can you actually incorporate
the word you or we? Well, pretend you're
telling this story to a younger self or
a friend and assume they can relate to
the certain point. So, remember when I
said, you know, that feeling when you're
you're talking to your parents and
something that they say really ticks you
off? You might have this assumption in
your head that passes through that says,
"Nobody would relate to that. Nobody
would relate to what I'm saying. I don't
want to use the word you because what if
they don't relate to it? Then I'm going
to sound weird." Once again, this goes
back to the specificity being the key to
getting views. You have to just
understand the truth that there are so
many people on the internet on these
social media platforms. Just assume that
people will relate to it because they
will and that is the biggest biggest
hack. So do not sound broad and pander
your story. Just try to be more
conscious of using the word you or we.
It also just makes you a more compelling
person to talk to because you don't
sound as narcissistic and selfobsessed
when you start inviting the viewer or
inviting the listener to the
conversation by using the word you or
we. So, I'm not going to script it out.
I simply have the hook that I'm going to
use which I can take from one of these.
After 20 years of my life, I finally
feel like I'm getting over my fear of my
parents judgment. So, taking one of
these and then let's move on to the
phone.
For the first time in my 20 years of
existence, I finally feel like I'm
getting over my parents' judgment of me.
I was eating par I was eating lunch with
my parents yesterday and I realized that
I definitely feel a lot less scared of
what they're thinking about me and their
disapproval of me. Not criticism, their
advice.
So, I want to spend the end of this
video to be like a a message to my
younger self. How can I make this
actually practical? Cuz I've just
rambled on a lot about myself. I want to
end the video on a positive note that
really lets the viewer in by once again
focusing on the you statement. So, I'm
going to say a piece of advice. And this
sounds counterintuitive, but I think
simply spending more time away from them
helped.
Like I think
I think I really need to build my self
understanding to a point where I could
actually
feel like an independent person from my
parents before I could actually develop
a relationship with them that wouldn't
[ __ ] me.
In this process, I feel like I'm also
getting closer to my parents, which is
really cool. But it took, ironically,
space away from them.
So yeah, I'll see you guys tomorrow.
Peace. Let's just hop into Cap Cut and
we'll just start editing right away. I'm
not going to show you guys the entire
editing process because I've walked you
guys through pretty much everything you
need to know about the editing process.
But I want to show you guys this one big
thing. Usually you might think, okay,
let's start cutting and splitting and
deleting. But the biggest biggest hack
that I realized for these unscripted
videos is actually this button called
transcriptbased editing. And I believe
you might have to have Cap Cut Premium
for like eight bucks a month. It is so
worth it. It is a game changer. And I'll
just show you why. So, basically, when
you hit transcriptbased editing, it
allows you to edit the entire video and
cut out portions of the video based on
the script. And every time I trip over
my words, I can simply highlight it and
delete that clip. Here's another one.
1.6 seconds to I finally feel like just
delete that whole thing. Here's another
example of when I messed up. Delete. And
sometimes I'll just say a stupid point
and I'll just delete the entire
paragraph cuz it doesn't make sense. I
think you guys get the point. So, like
every time I say that twice, so I just
delete the first so every time. And I'll
just repeat this for the rest of the
video. So you see there's a lot of dead
space where they say the second marks.
Like this one for example, 6.1 seconds.
Just can delete that one. Overall, this
transcriptbased editing portion can cut
down like a 30 minute clip cutting
session to 5 minutes and I can have the
entire video ready. Bear in mind the
software isn't perfect, so you're still
going to have to do some fine trimming,
but overall it's good for raw cuts. My
parents judgment of me. And now simply
you can find those fine trimming moments
where there still are like 0.5 seconds
of dead space and trim them. And just
continue this process for the rest of
the video. You'll notice the total time
duration of the video starts at like 1
minute 23 and by the end of this clean
trim. It goes down to like 1 minute and
10 seconds total video length. And once
that's done, we can simply add B-roll
and then add our auto captions as usual.
First, we're going to start off with the
usual B-roll. Turn the B-roll volume
down to zero. Cut the ending. And I did
something unique with the B-roll. I
added a key frame at the beginning and
end. and I zoomed in the ending portion
key frame which produces this
interesting zoom effect on the B-roll.
Just a subtle little trick I applied for
this B-roll just to make that B-roll
clip a little bit more intriguing at the
beginning. And yeah, I just continued
adding B-roll throughout the video. In
total, we had about nine different
B-roll clips. After that, we went to the
talking head portion clip. We pressed
one of them, pressed volume, and
increased it to 200 and loudness
adjustment. For this video, we chose a
slow Korean song for background music.
Turn the volume down to 60 for it just
so it doesn't overpower the talking head
portion. And then we press text, auto
captions, and generate. Then we did our
usual process of downsizing the captions
and moving them up to about 30% height
in the screen. Going to styles, taking
out the black border. For font, we
actually chose a new font, fantasy,
fitting the almost indie movie vibe we
wanted for this video. Then we're just
going to go into edit captions, change
any spelling errors, and then cleanly
splitting all the caption lines into
just one line at a time. And with that,
congratulations on finishing day five as
we just export and upload our clip onto
Instagram reels on this left side of the
screen. Just congratulate yourself once
again on finishing another day. I think
this might be one of the hardest videos
yet because it's unscripted. Hopefully
you guys take away a lot of the lessons
from the hook structuring. And with
that, I'll see you guys tomorrow for day
six. Welcome back to day four of the
content prneur academy. This one's going
to be a bit longer of a module because
this one we're really going to be
optimizing for virality. So strap in. I
think this module is probably going to
take you around 90 to 120 minutes to
complete. And it's a bit of an older
module, but trust me, the principles
still apply in 2024 for both Instagram
reels and Tik Tok. So, I will see you
guys inside the module. Brainstorming
for video ideas can be a long, grueling
process. Trust me, I've been there. I've
made over 500 videos on TikTok, and so
many times I found myself stuck
scrolling through the for you page for
hours or staring at my blank piece of
paper without coming up with a single
idea. After going through this brutal
creative block countless times, I
eventually came up with a systematic and
repeatable way to brainstorm video
ideas. Now, the first step in
brainstorming that you need to do before
you can even film, before you can even
script a video is you need to pick a
niche and a format. Now, a niche is
pretty simple. It's a category of
interest. Here are as many niches that I
can think of right off the top of my
head. Now, just pick one, at most three
that you're going to make your videos
on. Now, you hear a lot about picking a
niche. Picking a niche is important, but
picking a video format is, in my
opinion, so much more important and has
helped me so much more in my creative
process. Now, sticking to one video
format is good on Tik Tok for three
different reasons. One is it's better
for the algorithm and it'll make your
videos get more views. The second reason
is because it incentivizes people to
follow you so much more because they
know what to expect from your future
posts. And the third reason is that it
makes your brainstorming process so much
quicker and so much easier. I really
want to stress this last part because
saving time when it comes to
brainstorming videos is so important
when it comes to consistently uploading
on Tik Tok because you need to
consistently upload to grow and when
you're trying to balance on top of your
already probably very busy life.
Consistent uploads on Tik Tok. You need
to become efficient at it. Now, if you
don't know how to pick your video format
or your niche, I got you covered.
Personally, I was there two months ago
before I started my self-development
page, and I felt lost and had no
direction on what to make my videos on.
Now, I know my niche and my video format
so clearly. I make informative how-to
videos on self-development. Now, if you
can't pinpoint your niche and your
format right away, just like that, you
need to do this exercise. I want you to
write down on a piece of paper or a
document three niches and three video
formats. Now, picking a niche, it's
pretty simple. Just write down things
that you want to make videos on. If you
have a purpose, like marketing your
business, then you already know what
your niche will be. It's the niche of
your business. If you're a local
restaurant, then your niche is going to
be food. If you're a clothing brand,
then your niche is going to be fashion.
Writing down three niches that you might
want to make videos in is frankly pretty
simple. However, you're probably
scratching your head and thinking, "How
am I going to think of three video
formats?" So, to give some context and
examples, here are some of the video
formats that I can think of right off
the top of my head. dance videos, thirst
traps, tutorial videos, vlogs,
storytelling videos, music synced video
edits. If you're really struggling, just
scroll through your for you page and
look at the first three videos that come
up and try to write down for each one
what video format exactly each video is
in. Personally, I like to make videos in
the niche and format that I enjoy
watching, which is why I make
informative self-help videos because
that's personally what I watch. Once you
found your niche and your video format,
you can finally move on to brainstorming
and scripting ideas because now you have
in a sense a template for your videos.
Once you've identified your format, your
niche, it's time to start brainstorming
in bulk. So, what I want you guys to do
now is get out a blank piece of paper
and a pen. And at the top of this blank
piece of paper, write down the format
and niche of your video that you've
identified for yourself. Now, once
you're set up, we're going to do an
exercise I call creativity on demand,
which entails timing yourself for 10
minutes and coming up with 10 ideas.
Now, I know you're probably thinking,
"How am I going to come up with 10 good
video ideas in 10 minutes?" And to that,
I say, you're not supposed to have
perfect ideas. The point is to stretch
your creativity muscle to its absolute
limit and produce five, maybe even one
or two good ideas and maybe a few
mediocre ideas that you can tweak to
make good ideas. And I really like this
practice because it forces you to get
out of that perfectionist way of
thinking and really push your creativity
to its limits. And 10 seconds from now,
you're going to see just how many bad
ideas I can come up with.
Okay. So, I just got done with my 10
ideas. and see on this page.
And I'm going to be honest, only about
five of them are actually fully formed,
which is okay. But let me just walk you
guys through my thinking process as I
brainstormed. For the first around 4
minutes of the brainstorming period, I
listed a bunch of concepts related to my
niche that I might want to make videos
on. So, since my niche is
self-development, I listed things like
journaling, purpose, happiness, ego,
mindset, uh, identity, values, reading,
and you can apply this to whatever niche
you want to make videos for. For
example, if it's cooking, you know, you
can list a bunch of different maybe
cultures that you want to make foods
for, or if you're a fashion page, you
can write down a bunch of the different
fashion trends that you want to make or
different pop culture inspirations that
you might want to base outfits on. I'm
not a fashion person, so I'm not exactly
sure what concepts would go into that,
but whatever broad concept comes to mind
when you think of your niche, just write
them down at the beginning to give
yourself a little bit of direction. And
after around 4 minutes of listing just
concepts, I eventually moved on to this
portion, which is actually writing down
10 slightly more solidified ideas. And
it's okay for one of your video ideas to
suck or a lot of your video ideas to
suck, like in my case. The point, like I
said before, is to one, practice, and
two, maybe get a few ideas that are
actually solid. So, let me just look
through and circle some of the ideas
that I might make in a future video. The
first one, this is my hook with the skit
being about somebody who doesn't feel
confident around other confident people.
And then I followed up with an
explanation portion, which ties into my
informative/howto
type of video format. Another one,
tricks to be more happy. And I only had
one trick, which was keeping an internal
locus of control. Now, I might add one
or two more tricks that I can think of
later on. Another one, number six,
simple smoothie recipe for people who
hate the taste of protein powder plus
water or protein powder plus milk. I'm
thinking I might make this as my next
video because I think this idea is
actually pretty solid and I can work
with it and maybe add a bit to it and
it'll be a solid video. So, as you can
see, barely half of these ideas were
actually solidified ideas that I'm
probably going to use. Half of these I
might even scrap entirely, but that's
okay. The most important part of this
exercise is that I accomplished my goal
of coming up with at least one idea that
I can use as a base. So, for everyone
watching, feel free to try this on your
own. Time yourself for 10, maybe even 15
minutes if 10 minutes is too much of a
pressure. And force yourself, really
force yourself to come up with 10 ideas,
no matter how bad they might be. You
might be stuck at five good ideas, then
force out five bad ones in the last
minute. And once you think you have a
solid video idea, we can move on to the
next step, which is scripting. Now that
you have a base video idea to work with
and script with, let's talk about how to
structure your videos. So, I strongly
believe there are two things necessary
for any Tik Tok videos to go viral.
First is a strong hook that captivates
the viewer's attention. And second, the
video needs to provide enough value for
the viewer to stay until the end. And
when I say providing value, I use that
pretty loosely because on Tik Tok, this
providing value can come in the form of
anything from cheap entertainment to
learning something new. Now, starting
off with the hook, the number one thing
that you need to do in the hook is make
the context of the video clear. Most
people think the hook has to be
interesting and eye-catching, but the
number one pitfall that I see in any
video's hook is that it just isn't
clear. And the moment that anything
becomes unclear in a Tik Tok video and
anything becomes hard to understand, the
viewer will scroll. Now, if your content
doesn't involve you speaking, so you
can't verbally explain the context of
the video. A very common method that is
tried and true on Tik Tok is just
explaining the context of the video in
some sort of text caption. And I'll
cover exactly how to do that and all the
dos and don'ts of adding text to your
videos in our editing module about
adding text. Now, aside from being
clear, your hook also needs to be quick.
So, omit any unnecessary detail like,
"Hey guys, welcome back to my page or
like, "Hi, my name is blah blah blah."
Like, you don't need that kind of
information in the video. Since your
videos are always aiming at a new
audience in the for you page, the
audience is probably never going to be
interested in those little personal
details that you include at the
beginning of the video. I'm not saying
don't put any of your personality in the
video. Just don't slow it down with
boring facts. And this need for the hook
to be quick and to the point is
universal through all video formats on
Tik Tok videos and even in all other
short form video platforms like
Instagram reels and YouTube shorts. They
all need that same universal qualities
of the hook that are clarity and
concision regardless of video format.
All videos need a strong hook. Now in
terms of providing value in your video
because the term providing value is so
flexible. There isn't a clear formula
for providing value like there is for
structuring a hook in a Tik Tok video.
But there is a certain principle that
you should always keep in mind when you
think about providing value to your
viewer and that is putting yourself in
the shoes of this random viewer and
really questioning in your video why
exactly would this person be interested
in watching the video? Is there
something specifically interesting that
will peique the viewer's curiosity? Is
it entertaining? Is it funny? Etc. And
this ties back to the hook that you need
to make it abundantly clear what value
your video will be providing. A lot of
times I'll see videos from my friends or
one of my students and they'll be trying
to copy some video's format or follow
along some trend, but there isn't really
a clear reason for a random viewer to
watch that video. So, it's really
important to ask yourself what unique
value is your video providing. And if
you really dig deep, every video can
have some sort of unique value. You just
need to find it and identify it. For
example, you're making a day in the life
vlog about college, but you don't make
it abundantly clear that the vlog is
about college. You can't just assume
that people will know it's about
college. And you also have to assume
that when a random viewer sees your
video, they're going to assume your
life, your day in the life is
uninteresting. And they're probably
going to swipe unless they have a clear
reason that applies to them. So in this
case, for a college day in the life
vlog, you can assume that there are
people interested in a day in the life
vlog of a college student, but you have
to assume that they're not going to be
interested in you yet. Now, you can be
an interesting person and add your
personality to the vlog and that can
provide entertainment value. But from
the very beginning, if it isn't clear
what value that the viewer will be
getting from the video, most likely they
will scroll. Honestly, the college day
in the life trope is pretty overused and
most likely a random viewer isn't going
to be really interested in a college day
in the life because they've probably
seen a ton of them already and they
don't want to see another normal college
whatever. Maybe the first five college
day in the life vlogs ever were
interesting because there was no market
for that before. Now, there's tons of
day in the life vlogs of college
students, and this applies to most
niches, right? There's tons of fashion
videos now. There's tons of cooking
videos. There's tons of sports videos.
So, for the example of a college day in
the life vlog, it's good to add an even
more specific value that will be
interesting for a potential viewer. For
example, instead of just a regular
college day in the life, it could be a
productive college day in the life of a
lazy student. So, then the value
becomes, oh, how is this lazy college
student finding a way to become
productive? That's a fairly unique
trope. Obviously, I can't tell you what
exactly is a unique trope, but for
whatever your niche is, just try to
think about what are the most overused
tropes and how can I spin them even
slightly to make them new and novel and
provide that sort of new value to a
potential viewer. To sum up this
principle of providing value, you need
to assume that the viewer by default
will be less interested in you and your
video and you need to go above and
beyond to provide some new and novel
value to the viewer in order to keep
them watching for the rest of the video.
So, a practical step would be just study
the videos in your niche and just think
of any way to make it new and change it
up slightly. Trust me, on Tik Tok, there
are hundreds of repetitive videos and
anything novel on the app will have such
a good chance of getting views. That's
why trends work so well because there's
that good mix of familiarity and
understanding the context immediately
because it's a trend and also having
that new and novel aspect so it's not
repeating a video that's already exists.
I know I packed a lot of conceptual
ideas into this module, but once you've
taken that base idea, you've spun it
into something slightly more novel and
interesting to provide new value to
viewers, then you can move on to our
scripting process. What you do need in
any Tik Tok video script in order to go
viral is two things: concision and
speed. So, the first step I want you to
do is make a rough draft of your initial
script for your video. Personally, I
make informational videos on TikTok. So,
here's the structural template I
personally use. for anyone interested in
making informational videos. I start off
with a 1- secondond hook. Here's how to
fall asleep quicker. Then I immediately
follow that up with a solution to that
proposed problem so viewers instantly
know the context and the value that they
will be getting from this video. Stop
using your phone an hour before bed. Now
that I've clearly established the
context and the value that the video
will be providing to the viewer in the
first 3 seconds in the hook, I follow
that up with a common objection that a
viewer might be thinking in order to
establish relatability in my video.
because I believe relatability helps so
much in making a video do well because
it makes the viewer so much more
personally connected to the video and
thus makes them way more engaged. Now, I
know you don't want to hear this
information cuz your parents told you.
And lastly, now that I've hopefully
hooked my viewers attention, I will
follow that up with the actual meat and
information of my video. And this
portion will take up the majority of my
video's duration. Probably around 60 to
70% of my video is the actualformational
portion. Here's the actual science
behind why using your phone before bed
kills your ability to fall asleep. Your
brain is evolutionarily wired to see
bright blue light and feel awake because
that's the color of the literal sky. So
when your brain sees the blue light of
your computer screen or your phone
screen, it's been proven that it blocks
the natural production of melatonin in
your brain. So stop popping melatonin
gummies and just get off your phone.
Okay, now that I have my personal
template set up, let's finish that first
draft.
Perfect. Now, this draft is very rough
and I still need to proofread it. So,
the way I like to proofread my drafts is
read them out loud because then I can
get a sense of how the actual video will
sound and flow. So, let's just read it
out loud. Here's how to stop struggling
to control yourself. Actually, that
sounds pretty bad, honestly. Hold on.
Okay, so I just changed it from here's
how to stop struggling to control
yourself to here's how to have more
self-control. I think that just flows
smoother and it's quicker. And of
course, concision and speed are very
important in this script because in Tik
Tok, especially with the hook, you are
playing in a game of milliseconds. Okay,
solution, meditate. There's not really a
way I can tweak that because the answer
itself is just one word. It's meditate.
So now the objection that I wrote was,
why would I want to meditate? I can't
just wish my addictions away. It's not
that easy. Honestly, I like the way that
flows. I think I'm going to keep that.
And now I start my information section
by first countering that objection by
saying, "I'm not telling you to vibe
your addictions away." I like the way
that flows, too. I think it's pretty
clear. Okay, moving on. We go through
the same subconscious thought patterns
every day without realizing. H I might
move every day to the beginning. Just a
little tweak. I think that just sounds
better. Okay. I'm not telling you to
vibe your addictions away. Every day we
go through the same subconscious thought
patterns without realizing, "Oh, I saw a
cookie. Now I have to eat it because I
can't stop thinking about it now. Hm.
Can I make that any shorter? Oh, I say
now twice. That's why. Okay. Oh, I saw a
cookie. Now I have to eat it because I
can't stop thinking about it. So, just
to explain this scripting portion a
little bit more, I used two pretty
relatable, I would say, examples of how
a lack of self-control can make
somebody's life worse. So, the first
example is, "Oh, I saw a cookie. Now I
have to eat it because I can't stop
thinking about it." The second one is,
"Oh, someone just insulted me. Now I
have to feel insecure for the next three
days because there's no way I can get
that off my H.
Okay. Oh, someone just insulted me. Now
I have to feel insecure for the next 3
days because there's no way I can get
that off my mind. Okay. I like the way
that sounds. I'm emphasizing the that I
think it helps a lot to emphasize
certain words. Okay. Now for the final
sentence. Well, actually there is a way
to get off your mind. It's called
meditation and you have to practice it.
Is that just me or does that sound a
little cheesy? Okay, hold on. Maybe not
actually.
Maybe I'll say, well, yes, there is a
way to get off your mind. Maybe it is
too broad. I might change it to those
intrusive thoughts. I don't like I don't
I don't like the way I say it's called
meditation. That sounds pretty cheesy.
Have to really think about this one. So,
let me just erase this whole part.
You've just never practiced it. There we
go. Now, that's a natural sounding
transition into introducing meditation
into this information portion. When you
meditate, you practice fending off
intrusive
thoughts, focus,
and keep still. Okay, I think I'm done
proof reading now. Let's just run
through the entire script to see how it
all flows together. Now, here's how to
have more self-control. Meditate. Now, I
know you're probably thinking, "Why
would I want to meditate? I can't just
wish my addictions away. It's not that
easy. I'm not telling you to vibe your
addictions away. Every day, we go
through the same subconscious thought
patterns without realizing. Oh, I saw a
cookie. Now I have to eat it because I
can't stop thinking about it. Oh,
someone just insulted me. Now I have to
feel insecure for the next 3 days
because there's no way I can get that
off my mind. Well, yes, there is a way
to get those intrusive thoughts off your
mind. You just never practiced it. When
you meditate, you practice fending off
intrusive thoughts in order to focus and
keep still. H I feel like I haven't tied
it back to the hook yet in this
conclusion. So, let me just add that
real quick. Learning to control your
impulses starts with learning how to
control your thoughts. Now, from the
top, here's how to have more
self-control. Meditate. Now, I know
you're probably thinking, "Why would I
want to meditate? I can't just wish my
addictions away. It's not that easy. I'm
not telling you to vibe your addictions
away. Every day, we go through the same
subconscious thought patterns without
realizing, "Oh, I saw a cookie. Now I
have to eat it because I can't stop
thinking about it. Oh, someone just
insulted me. Now I have to feel insecure
for the next 3 days because there's no
way I can get that off my mind. Well,
yes, there is a way to get those
intrusive thoughts off your mind. You've
just never practiced it. When you
meditate, you practice fending off
intrusive thoughts in order to focus and
keep still. Learning to control your
impulses starts with learning how to
control your thoughts. Boom. I like
that. Okay, we've got it down. After
probably around two rounds of revisions,
we've got our finished script. Okay, I
know that was quite rough and all over
the place, but I really wanted to give a
transparent view of how I actually
script. And I really wanted to highlight
just how many revisions I make in order
to make it even a slightest bit more
clear, even the slightest bit faster
because in your script, especially
towards the beginning, those
milliseconds really matter. You really
can't underestimate how short people's
attention spans are when they're looking
through Tik Tok videos. So yeah,
scripting can be quite drawn out, but I
think it's so crucial in getting your
video to do well. Now that you have your
script for your Tik Tok video, let's
move on to actually filming it. Now,
this is where most people come into huge
roadblocks and they have the most
questions. How should I frame my video?
How should I light my video? What camera
angle should I use? Where should I put
the text? You know, all these questions
about visuals. And visually, you only
need to know these two principles in
order for your video to go viral. But
you need to know them well because they
can be so nuanced. And the two
principles that you need to optimize for
are clarity and speed. I know I've
already touched on those two principles
in scripting, but that's just how
important they are. Now, I know you're
probably thinking, "How does this
actually apply to all the micro details
of filming like lighting, framing,
cutting, timing?" And the answer to all
those questions is really just what
brings the most clarity and what makes
the video the fastest. So, starting off
with how to light your videos. Light
your videos in the way that produces the
most contrast and simplicity possible.
Visual satisfaction is so important to
keeping viewers engaged on TikTok. So,
say you light your video like this.
Hey guys, what's up? As you can see,
this is not visually appealing at all to
watch. And on an app like Tik Tok where
people's attention spans are so short,
any lapse in lighting or visual clutter
will be a reason for the viewer to
instantly scroll. Just follow this rule
of thumb. The higher the contrast, and
the simpler, the better. Now, moving on
to framing and camera angles. Frame your
subjects in the video so nothing is hard
to see and nothing is visually complex
or cluttered. So many times I see people
having these slight errors in their
framing where the subject is just too
high up or too far down. And those
slight visual inconveniences, I swear,
make the world of the difference to the
viewer. Like I said, people want visual
satisfaction. And anything that gets in
the way of that on the Tik Tok app is a
reason to scroll. Another rule of thumb
is don't put anything of importance in
the areas of the frame that are taken up
by buttons or the caption. A lot of
times I'll see people putting text too
high up where the for you and following
buttons are, or maybe they put text too
low where the caption is, and that's
such a small detail, but that makes the
biggest difference because viewers don't
want to struggle to read or understand
your video. So don't put your face too
far to the right where the buttons are,
and don't put your face or part of the
image where the caption is. Now, moving
on to pacing. Pacing is so heavily
overlooked on TikTok, and you do not
want to make mistakes in your pacing. So
often I see videos that just move way
too slow. And slow uninteresting videos
are the death of engagement and the
death of views. When I say a video it's
too slow, I mean there might be even
just a half second of dead air on the
video. And I know that sounds crazy.
Even just a half second, even a few
milliseconds of nothing going on in the
video, they make the world of a
difference. Hey guys, today we're going
to be going over my review of this
camera.
So, as I said, we're going over the
review of this camera. As a general rule
of thumb, you need something to be
happening on your screen every at least
3 seconds. And if the video stalls even
for 1 second, even half a second, try to
find a way to cut that out in your
editing.
>> Camera review. Starting off with the
microphone, it is quite bulky, but it
does have good sound quality. So, I'll
give it an 8 out of
>> For every part of the filming and
editing process, always question
yourself, are there any boring points in
the video that the video stalls or
doesn't get clear and makes it slightly
unsatisfying for the viewer. Try to find
a way to fix that. So, yeah, in terms of
visuals, those are the two factors you
need to know. And once you feel like
you've master them, then we can start
filming. Now that you know the guiding
principles of clarity and speed to
direct your filming, we can apply these
principles into tangible results in our
filming process. So, based on your video
format, you should have a general idea
of what you're filming and what your
shots should kind of look like. For
example, if you make skip videos, you're
going to have like person one and person
two or three in separate individual
shots. If you make vlog videos or
informational videos like I do, a very
common theme is to have voice over and
then B-roll on top of the voice over.
So, for my personal filming process,
which I will be showing you guys in this
module, I will have those two distinct
portions of my filming. the voiceovers
and the B-roll shots. Now, of course,
even if you make informational videos or
vlogs, you don't need to be as intricate
in the filming process as I do with the
B-roll shots and the separate voice
over. I simply like filming the voice
over and the B-roll separately so I can
cut out even milliseconds of time where
I literally just breathe in the voice
over like, "Hey guys, what's up?" I also
like to time my B-roll clips to match
the parts in the voice over where I'm
talking. So, I'll time my B-roll shots
with every new sentence of my voiceover.
Now, like I said, this is not mandatory
whatsoever. I simply do this to increase
my quality and engagement rate and of
course optimize for clarity and speed. I
would say even if you're making talking
head videos where you're just constantly
talking to the camera with no B-roll, no
shots overlaid on top of your voice, the
factors of clarity and speed do apply.
And I would say if possible, still try
to cut out parts where you're talking
where there is a little bit of dead
space where nothing's going on. Maybe
you're breathing, maybe you're pausing
to think. So, for that reason, I would
recommend to everybody to film outside
the Tik Tok app on your phone's native
camera because I would say editing is
where you can really optimize for
clarity and speed. And Tik Tok's inapp
editor is just not really welldeveloped.
It's kind of laggy. It's kind of buggy.
So, filming and editing outside the Tik
Tok app and then uploading back into the
Tik Tok app is, in my opinion, the best
way to do it. And don't worry if you've
never edited outside the Tik Tok app
before or even inside the Tik Tok app.
It's pretty simple and you can learn it
very quickly. It's very intuitive and
the only things you'll need to do is be
able to cut and trim and add captions,
which trust me, they take like 30
minutes to learn. I personally use the
app InShot to edit. It's free with ads,
but apps like Cap Cut or anything else
do the same. In this course, I'll be
showing you guys how to edit on InShot.
And even though the UIs on InShot and
like Cap Cut are pretty much the same,
if you've never really used a third
party editor or you're not exactly
comfortable with a certain editing
software, I would say just download
InShot to follow along. when I go
through the editing module. Now that
we've covered what software to use,
let's start filming. Okay, so now here I
have the script I wrote and revised from
the scripting module. And I actually
just rewrote it for clarity sake in this
module. Normally I just read off the
messy revise rough draft. And in the
bottom, I also wrote a list of the
B-roll shots I use in chronological
order. Okay, so I'm going to start off
by reading my voice over. And I'm
literally just going to record on my
camera roll like this.
Here's how to have more self-control. So
I just finished recording my voice over.
It took like 1 minute. And I think this
is a perfect time to showcase just how
many tries I take in my voice over. So
yeah, even though I only recorded one
video, you can see I actually say some
of the lines multiple times just because
they're not clear enough or I don't say
them fast enough. So here, I'll just
play it out loud. Here's how to have
more self-control. Well, yeah, there is
a way to get those intrusive thoughts
off your mind. Well, yeah, there is a
way to get those Well, yeah, there is a
way to get those intrusive thoughts off
your mind. you've just never practiced
it when you
>> So yeah, there's the uh optimizing for
clarity and speed right there in action.
Obviously when I edit through again, I'm
going to cut those parts out and audio
editing is actually pretty easy on
InShot. So I'll show you guys how to do
that in the next module, but now let's
move on to actually filming the B-roll
shots. Now, a lot of times I film my
B-roll shots on my Canon M50 camera, but
I really don't want to promote the idea
that you need high quality equipment for
videos to go viral. So in terms of this,
I'm using my $20 tripod that I bought on
Amazon and my smartphone. I also use
this ring light I got for like $30 on
Amazon. If you just search up like 12in
ring light, they're like all the same
kind of. But I'm not going to be using
this for this video either because like
I said, you do not need this high
quality equipment in order for videos to
do well. So, here's a quick montage of
me filming my B-roll shots.
Heat. Heat.
[Applause]
[Music]
Okay, we just got done with the last of
our clips in the B-roll and now we have
everything checked off. So, I hope that
montage of clips was at least a little
insightful to showing my filming
process. Like I said, it's not that
complex. The whole process took about
maybe like 30 minutes. And yeah, now
that I have my voice over and my B-roll
complete, we can now move on to our next
step in the process, which is cutting up
the clips in our third party editor. For
this walkthrough, I'll be using InShot.
And I'll be going over how to navigate
InShot UI in order to do these things
like cutting the clips and syncing the
video clips to the audio. Okay, so the
first step before we even get into the
actual editing process is downloading
the app InShot or if you have your own
editing software, then just downloading
that onto your phone or your computer,
wherever you edit from. So now let's get
into step one, which is opening InShot.
You want to click video all the way on
the left and then new. It opens up your
menu of your camera roll. It might have
asked for permission in order to use
your camera roll. Just say allow. Now
you want to select all the clips that
you want to compile into your video. So,
I'm just going to select all these
clips.
And
there you go. That should be good.
However, I have 4 minutes of footage
when in reality, I only want to use 30
seconds of it. That leads us to step
two, which is doing a rough trim of all
the clips that you have. So, you can see
none of this clutter is actually part of
my B-roll until I actually look at the
uh phone screen. That's when the clip
actually starts. What we're going to do
is do a rough trim of all the parts we
don't need. So there you go. We probably
just cut out like 30 seconds of footage.
And now our total video time is much
better. So we're going to do that with
every single clip. And there we go.
Using only the pre-cut icon and the
delete button that I used once, we were
able to trim our video down from around
4 minutes and 30 seconds to now a minute
44, which is still too long for my voice
over. But we got rid of all the
unnecessary fluff. And we'll do a more
fine trimming when we actually get to
our fifth step, which is syncing up the
video with the voice over audio. But
now, let's move on to step three, which
is adding the audio. So now, in order to
add music, we're going to go all the way
to the beginning just so we don't
accidentally add the music clip all the
way to the end. And what you want to do
is scroll all the way to the left on the
uh tools, and you want to click music
right there. And now it should open up
this little menu here, which is kind of
your audio editing menu. And right now
we only have one audio file, which is
the bass audio for all my clips. What I
actually like doing as well is I want to
mute all these clips because the only
audio I want is my voice over and then a
little bit of background music that I
add. So what I'm going to do is just
click on one of these clips. It doesn't
matter which clip you click on, but at
the bottom where the actual video file
is, what you want to do is just tap on
it and it opens up the volume menu for
all these clips. So, what I'm going to
do is I'm just gonna
>> go to each one
>> is a way to get
>> press each one
>> learning
>> and then just decrease the volume for
each one down to zero.
There we go. So, now we're going to add
one extra audio clip. And the way to do
that is you want to click all the way on
the left of these tools. It's a note
icon with a plus labeled music. So, you
want to add that. This one on the right
is a live voice over. So, say you want
to voice over your video and you haven't
done it yet, but you want to do it over
the clips you already have. What you can
do is you can press this button and
it'll start recording. 3 2 1 and you can
talk blah blah blah blah blah. And
once you click the stop button, it
should add that. And you can probably
hear it here.
>> And you can talk blah blah blah blah
blah. And yeah, and it adds it as a
audio clip. So, we're going to delete
that using the delete button. What we're
going to do is click the plus with the
music and we're going to extract from
video because the voice over I did was
on an actual video file. So yeah, we're
going to click extract from video. And
now we're going to look through our
videos. And there we go. The one with
the black screen should be the audio.
Here's how to have more self-control.
>> Yep. So that is our audio file. We're
just going to click the check. And there
you go. Now it should be added in.
However, if we actually look at the
audio file by just playing it.
>> Here's how to have more self-control.
Meditate. Now, I know you're probably
Now, I know you're probably thinking, I
have a bit of bloating, some unnecessary
parts in the audio as well. So, that
moves us on to step four, which is
trimming the audio file. Now, this is
where it gets a little complicated
because this is where we start trying to
fine-tune our video and using more
precise trimming tools. So, first we're
going to just do a rough trimming of all
the parts we don't need. And the way I
actually like to do this is instead of
using this edit,
>> here's how to have more self-control,
>> which is kind of like the pre-cut
function for videos, but instead this is
for audio. I don't want to use that
because it just opens up the entire
audio clip. What I'm going to do instead
is I'm simply going to use this button,
split. And what it does, it just splits
the audio clip in two. Here, I'll show
you how to do it right here. Split. And
now you have two separate audio clips.
This is good for being super precise
with where exactly you want to trim your
video. Now, to be even more precise,
what we can do is we can use two fingers
to zoom in to this timeline. And we can
go as far as literally dealing with
milliseconds. And this is where I
actually like to operate because I
really do believe in optimizing for
milliseconds in order to get your video
just the slightest bit faster and better
because these 1% improvements really do
make the world of a difference in terms
of getting views. So, we're going to
start off with just a rough trim. So,
we're not going to need to fine-tune it
and zoom in for now. And you can see
this part right here. I don't see
anything. So, I'm just going to cut that
out. And now, since the beginning of the
audio is displaced, I'm just going to
press and hold to get a hold of it. And
then, we're going to move it all the way
back to the beginning. There we go. Now,
it's aligned with the beginning of the
clip again.
>> Here's how to have more self-control.
Meditate. Now, I know you're probably
>> So, I see here I have a take that I
didn't even use. So, I'm just going to
split and then delete.
Now, we're going to move this clip back
here.
Listen to it.
>> Meditate. Now, I know you're probably
thinking, "Meditating? What do you
want?"
>> I promise you, these optimizations will
make a difference. Even the slightest
ones where you just trim off even a
millisecond or two off the ends of your
audio clip. You really don't want to
keep viewers waiting for like half
second because it just makes them a
little more annoyed when they watch the
video. Now that we have successfully
trimmed our audio, let's just listen to
it through one more time.
>> Here's how to have more self-control.
Meditate. Now, I know you're probably
thinking, "Meditating? What do you want
me to wish my addictions away?" It's not
that easy.
>> So, finally, we can move on to our last
step, which is syncing up the video
clips with the audio that we have.
Personally, when I wrote my script, I
already planned out which clips would go
with which sentences in my voice over.
So, I'm just going to pull out that
script that I've had before, and I'm
just going to follow it. I think I put
these in in reverse chronological order
to be honest. Okay, so what I'm going to
do is I'm just going to move everything
into the spots that they were intended.
This clip was second, the other one was
first. So our clips are now generally in
the right chronological order. So
starting off with the first clip, what I
like to do is a little fun fact. I loop
my videos. So this is actually the last
clip and I made it at the same time as
my first clip, if that makes sense. So,
I'm going to move this clip to the end
just to reorder it. Now, we can really
start our process. Here's how to have
more self-control. Meditate. Now, I know
you're probably Here's how to have more
self-control.
So, yeah, we can see I say meditate
right here. So, I'm going to trim the
clip all the way down to where my cursor
is. Right there. And now it should
switch immediately to a clip of me
meditating.
>> Here's how to have more self-control.
Meditate. You see how I cut the clips
exactly to that location? When I say
now, I know you're probably thinking I
cut to another clip. What I'm going to
do is I'm just going to trim out a
random portion of this and I'm going to
delete every other part of that
meditating clip. So, now it should look
like this.
>> Meditate. Now, I know you're probably
thinking,
>> there we go.
Cut out a little bit more.
>> More self-control. Meditate. Now, I know
you're probably thinking, meditate.
>> So, now we have to sync up. I lip-sync
the words meditating.
What do you want me to just wish my
addictions away? It's not that easy.
This should sync up or close to it.
>> Meditate. Now, I know you're probably
thinking, meditating, what do you want
me to wish my addictions away? It's not
that easy. I'm not telling you.
>> Okay. Now, here's a little dilemma. I
say it's not it's not that easy,
but I lip-sync it. And it's a lot
delayed. So, what I actually do here in
these kind of dilemmas is I split the
clip in the middle.
>> Meditating.
like right around here where it gets a
little too slow cuz this portion of the
clip is too slow when I want it to be a
little faster so it can sync up with the
voice over cuz I speak fast in the voice
over but the clip doesn't move very
fast. So what I can do is I can split
the clip where it starts getting slow
and what I do is I click this speed icon
which kind of looks like a speedometer
on a car and it says speed. I click that
and I increase the speed of this clip.
So, I'm going to increase to 1.5 and see
how it looks.
>> What do you want me to wish my
addictions away? It's not that easy. I'm
not telling you addictions away. It's
not that easy.
>> There we go. So, now it sinks up exactly
at 1.5. Perfect. Add a little bit more
to the end.
>> It's not that easy. I'm not telling you
to vibe your addictions away. Every day
we go.
>> Okay. So, I want to release my index
fingers off my temple right when I say
vibe like that. So,
>> I'm not telling you to vibe.
>> See, I'm not telling you to vibe your
addictions away. Every day we go
through.
>> Okay, perfect. So, now every day we go
through the same subconscious thought
patterns. Now, this part is actually I
think it moves a little too slow. We'll
see
>> thought patterns without realizing. Oh,
someone just insulted me now.
>> Okay. So, I'm going to cut this part
towards the beginning. And I think I'm
going to speed this one up, too, because
it moves a little slow. The audio clip
has to end around here. go through the
same subconscious thought patterns
without realizing. Oh,
>> yeah. Oh, okay.
>> patterns without realizing. Oh,
>> wait. Every day we go through the same
subconscious thought patterns without
realizing. Oh, someone just in.
>> There we go.
>> Realizing. Oh, someone.
>> There we go. Write the O. I want to
switch the clips. And that's how it
turned out. So, that's good. Now, oh,
control your impulses starts with
learning to control your thoughts.
Here's how to have more self-control.
>> Okay, perfect. Uh, I think this clip at
the end is a little too long. So, we're
just going to speed it up a little bit
just cuz the audio ends a little early.
Speed up to like Z 1.3 maybe.
And then we're going to speed this up to
like 1.3 as well. There we go.
>> Learning to control your impulses starts
with learning to control your thoughts.
>> Okay, perfect. So, yeah, there we go.
Now that we have synced up everything,
I'm just going to go in full screen and
watch over the entire video again and
see how it lines up. Here's how to have
more self-control. Meditate. Now, I know
you're probably thinking, "Meditating?
What do you want me to wish my
addictions away? It's not that easy. I'm
not telling you to vibe your addictions
away. Every day we go through the same
subconscious thought patterns without
realizing." Oh, someone just insulted
me. Now I have to feel insecure and
upset for the next 3 days because
there's no way I can get that off my
mind. Well, yeah, there is a way to get
those intrusive thoughts off your mind.
You've just never practiced it. When you
meditate, you practice fending off
intrusive thoughts in order to focus and
keep still. Learning to control your
impulses starts with learning to control
your thoughts. So now you can notice how
it was kind of satisfying that every
time I annunciated a new sentence, it
would switch to a new clip. And this is
very intentional just to keep the viewer
a little more satisfied visually. And
adding that little bit of visual
satisfaction really does make that big
difference. Like I said, now you're
probably wondering, why are subtitles
really important? Do I really need to
put them in my video? And to that I say
they are so important in making your
video go viral. Captions are good for
two things. One, they give an element on
the screen that constantly changes every
few seconds that a viewer can look at.
And two, they just make it so much
easier to follow along. Even though
viewers aren't staring at the subtitles
for the entire video, just
subconsciously they're seeing it. And
when they see the subtitles, they
process the words so much easier and
they process what's going on in your
video so much easier as well. Remember,
clarity and making sure your viewer
knows exactly what's going on in your
video is essential to going viral. So,
all mistakes come down to the captions
either being too long or too hard to
read. So, starting off with caption
length, I like to make my captions at
most like four words long. And I always
make sure the captions only take up one
line on my screen, not even two. And the
reason why is because if it takes up too
much real estate on your screen, it just
adds so much visual clutter and it kind
of gets in the way of whatever you're
trying to show in your actual video
portion. You don't want viewers feeling
like they have to read some paragraph,
some English paper on your screen.
People come on TikTok to relax and just
shut off their brain. They don't want to
be thinking super deeply when they're
watching a video. Quick, short, easy to
read captions are the way to go. In
terms of being too difficult to read, a
big mistake is that when people make
captions outside of the Tik Tok app,
they always use some really difficult to
read font or the colors of the subtitle
text don't actually contrast well with
the background and they're kind of hard
to read and distinguish from the video.
Luckily, a lot of these problems will be
solved in the Tik Tok app itself because
we're going to be using the
autogenerated Tik Tok captions and
they're basically already set to the
settings that we want. But just a quick
note, just in case any of you guys want
to make captions outside of the Tik Tok
app, I would give a few pointers on what
not to do. One, try to use a font that
looks very similar to Tik Tok's default
font. The Tik Tok default font is called
Proxima Nova Semold, but there are tons
of fonts that look very similar to that,
so you don't have to worry too much.
When I used to add captions manually on
InShot, I would use the font that looks
the most similar. It was called like
system or Helvetica new, something like
that. And the reason why it's good to
use text that looks similar to Tik Tok's
default fonts for text is that people
like things that are visually familiar,
especially on Tik Tok. If your video
seems too foreign to the app, for
example, if it uses really complex
fonts, it might seem too alien to the
viewers and people don't want to
struggle with the unknown. That sense of
visual familiarity is why so many trends
go viral. And that's why most Tik Toks
kind of look the same. And if you're
trying to reinvent the wheel on Tik Tok,
it's actually shooting yourself in the
foot. So, you really want to just, as
weird as it sounds, make your videos
look very familiar and similar to all
the other videos on the for you page.
And that's why you should use fonts that
look similar to the Tik Tok default
font. Now, where should you be putting
the actual subtitle text in your video?
Where on the screen? Is it all the way
up, all the way down, all the way at the
bottom? Does it even matter? And to
that, I say yes, it does. Caption
placement actually is very important.
And here's why. You want your caption to
be as easy to read as possible. And one
big mistake that I see a lot of creators
doing is that they'll make captions and
have them covered by either the buttons
on the side, the for you and following
buttons at the top or the hashtag and
caption at the bottom. So, quick rule of
thumb, I already mentioned this in a
previous module, but do not put any text
in this red area. My best recommendation
is either put them right smack in the
middle or about 1/4 25% up between the
middle and the bottom of the screen.
About halfway between that point. And
the reason why is because that middle
area/bottom area is where people's eyes
just naturally gravitate towards and
that's where they expect the
captions/subtitles to be. So it would
kind of weird them out if the captions
and subtitles were all the way at the
top because that's where people usually
put text titles of their video. You know
text titles that describe their video,
not the actual subtitles themselves. And
if you put it too low, that's where the
caption is. So you don't want to be
putting it anywhere below like the
bottom 25% of the screen. Make sure also
the text is cropped small enough so it's
not touching that right hand side of the
screen where the buttons are. If you
cover all that, then you should be good.
And I make my subtitles right in the
middle, but I'm just going to shift them
slightly to the left just in case the
longer parts touch the right hand side.
Move it slightly more to the right.
Okay, perfect. The subtitles are now in
the right place with the right font with
the right timing. Now we can move on to
adding music to our video. And with
that, congratulations on finishing day
six. Seriously, congratulations. I know
this one was a bit longer of a module,
but genuinely congratulations. Pat
yourself on the back. All right, today's
day seven. Congratulations on making it
through the entire journey together. We
have been on a crazy journey. I really
hope that you took action on all of the
modules that I've released to you guys
today. And if you made it this far, it's
clear that you're actually super serious
about building your personal brand. But
my one gripe with courses is that it's
really easy to consume and feel like
you're passively absorbing knowledge
without actually applying and actually
learning 90% of the valuable information
that you'll get by simply applying and
taking action. So, let's recap
everything we've learned in the last 6
days and then I have a special offer for
you and what I highly recommend you do
to scale to your 10,000 true fans and
actually to make your first dollar
online with content creation. So, first
you learn how to post your first video
and use the basics of Capka, the basics
of scripting. Second, you learn how to
create videos that resonate with your
younger self so you can build that
audience of thousand true fans that
resonate with you and your story. Three,
you learn the mindset it takes to
actually become a creator. And four, you
learn how to build a brand around your
life. And five, you actually learn how
to make educational videos in a viral
way. and my way of saying thank you for
taking action because it is genuinely my
mission to make content creation
education as accessible as possible. I
wish somebody was out there teaching how
to turn my creative passion into an
actual career and that's what I seek to
do with Content Academy with all of my
videos is to make content creation a
sustainable career path for anybody out
there. I've been told by multiple
consultants that the information and the
community that I provide within Content
Academy should be worth over $4,000. And
it's true because we've gotten results
like Henry, for example, who joined and
in 60 days went from not having even
posted a single video as a 17-year-old
high schooler to reaching 10,000
followers and making his first couple
thousand online thanks to UGC. And And
Andrew, who after being in the community
for a little bit over a month, joined
one of the UGC program opportunities
that we have partnerships with, he
applied and in his first month with that
opportunity where he was making UGC
videos for another brand, he made over
$10,000. Now, once again though,
information like this is nothing without
actual implementation. And it's okay if
you only applied like one or two of the
modules in this entire 3-hour course.
That's actually very normal. So, my best
and final piece of advice after this
week of locking in together is to
immerse yourself in a community of other
people who are action takers, who
actually care about content creation,
who care about the goals that you have,
and will help you improve. Reviewing
your content, answering your questions
on live weekly calls. That's exactly why
we built Content Academy. We do
accountability games in our community.
Our most recent one is literally giving
away $4,500
to the person who lasts the longest,
posting daily. We have four live Q&A
calls that we run every single week in
our Discord server with experienced
creators. We even throw events every
quarter to make sure that you can
actually meet other creators and develop
genuine friendships. And of course,
lastly, we have over 9 hours of course
modules on top of everything that I'm
giving to you today. So, just go to the
second link in the description to get
started with Content Academy and I hope
to see you inside. I hope to see you
crushing your creator goals and turning
this passion that you have right now
into a career, bro. Let's [ __ ] go,
dude. Genuinely. Thank you guys so much
for watching. Make sure to like and
subscribe as well because I'm dropping
way more sauce in the future.