Here is how to use AI to make your reals
and Tik Toks impossible to skip. Now, in
the past two years, I've posted over 500
times. I actually started posting daily
while I was in college while
simultaneously starting an online
business. All to say, I was really,
really busy. But the centerpiece of all
of this growth came from simply posting
daily on Instagram and Tik Tok. Now, I'm
going to explain to you what worked in
order to actually make this growth
possible using AI and what didn't work
when I was actually trying to use AI to
grow my personal brand and to make
content that actually went viral. So,
first off with what worked, I like to
call it AI augmented content. Fancy
speak for basically just saying AI
assisted viral hook creation. I actually
use this method to make videos like
this. I got 800,000 views, 200,000,
700K, 2.5 mil, 3.2 mil. But what didn't
work was this concept I like to simply
call like one button automation. And
you'll see a lot of these videos online
from people promising you that they have
this secret automation, this crazy
complex automation that somehow
basically allows you to press one button
and with a chain of like this nadn or
make.com automation, you'll end up
getting a million views. Like basically
this concept that they'll sell you on
because it's so attractive to think that
you can just press one button and then
it'll make you a viral video, right?
where it'll scrape the internet, script
a video using AI, use some AI agent to
make some AI video with AI bureau, AI AI
captions that'll get you a million
views. Except the one problem is that
all this is actually possible. You can
automate a lot of the content creation
process, except it's actually not going
to get views. It's probably end going to
end up getting some shitty 300 views,
which makes you feel productive, but in
reality, it's not going to help you
build an actual following, and it's not
going to help you get better views. And
more most importantly, it's not going to
help you actually build your business
either or build your online income with
content creation. Okay, so let me tell
you why this doesn't work real quick
just so you really understand how the
entirety of actually like making AI to
make your content will actually work and
how to not go about it. Okay. So, in
order to understand how to use AI
effectively to make viral hooks and
viral videos that will actually blow up
your personal brand, you have to
understand why from a psychological
perspective content actually even goes
viral to begin with on Instagram and Tik
Tok. Okay? And it's very very simple.
The content that actually goes viral on
these platforms is content that gets
high watch time. In order for a video to
get high watch time at the very very
basic first principles level, humans
just inherently need to watch things
that give them authentic value. You are
not going to watch this video unless I'm
consistently giving you actual
information that's going to help you,
right? And I have if I haven't proven to
you that I can actually help you. AI
often times just cannot do this. You
cannot automate authentic value. And the
reason why is because AI is just trained
off of what data it's already
accessible. And let's say if you ask GPT
to script an entire video for you,
inevitably it's just going to spew out
slop because it's only utilizing the
data that it's trained off of. And it's
just not going to produce quality
content that's actually real, that
represents your lived experience, your
true story, your authentic personality.
All of these things are what we actually
watch content for. Because when's the
last time you actually watch something
that you could tell was some uncreative
slop, right? You might see AI video on
your feed popping up, but inevitably
it's prompted by an actual human being.
And the reason why you're probably even
watching that AI produced content is
because it feels original and it feels
like a very unique use case of the AI
technology. inevitably a human needs to
actually come up with this authentic
value. So what can you actually use AI
then for in your content? Because if you
can't automate the entire process,
what's the use of AI? To that I say
automate the part that is actually easy
and possible to automate. And the part
that's super automatable in my opinion
is simply hooks. It's the first 3 to 5
seconds of your videos on Instagram and
Tik Tok. I think that's the part that
can be the most automated, right?
Because a lot of times the hooks that
work on Tik Tok and Instagram are simply
rehashed versions of what already worked
online. So you can essentially use AI to
speed up this process and to augment it
to give you a lot more creative ideas
more quickly and then help you come up
with the ideas that are actually like
the most proven for virality and then
help you do it in seconds rather than
taking like a ton of time. So yes, the
one button automation doesn't work, but
when you use AI to help you create viral
content by assisting you and augmenting
this process, that's when you can
actually consistently come up with viral
content, save you like a good 30 minutes
to an hour every single time you make
your video, which helps you actually
create consistently, which then helps
you grow your personal brand. So this is
what helped me grow my following and
also consistently pump out content. It's
this AI augmented content strategy. And
very specifically, it's a custom tool
that I built and that I'm going to give
you by the end of this video access for
completely free. And it's something I
like to call Hooker AI. And it's a
Discord bot that I put inside my Discord
server. And it helps you speed up the
process, but it doesn't do it fully for
you. And even amongst the people and
community members that I see who
actually use Hooker AI, the ones who
actually succeed are the ones who do two
things properly. One is they still have
their element of human input when
they're actually making the videos. So
instead of just simply okay AI do the
entire work for me and I'm just going to
screw off and I'm just going to like you
know pick my nose and two they actually
have a semblance of understanding what
content actually goes viral. So I'm
going to teach you how to utilize this
tool and then how to gain a sense of
both. Okay, so first off what is Hooker
AI? How does this work? It's a
three-step Discord bot. All you have to
do is in the Discord bot type/hook and
then paste your full video script. So,
you do need to have a full video script
written out. And then it's going to give
you five viral hooks based on proven
templates and using the best model
possible, which is Claude for Sonnet.
There's no other model that's best at
actually doing natural human writing.
Okay. So, it's a custom bot that's
trained off of hundreds of handpooked
hooks that I've personally scraped off
of Tik Tok across multiple different
niches. not just like my own niche which
is content growth and personal
development but also other hooks in
other niches like personal uh like
personal finance, vlogging, lifestyle,
makeup, beauty, uh fitness, all these
different niches. I've basically trained
this AI to know exactly what hooks are
like going viral across all these
different niches and then pick you the
best one that best fits your script. So,
the key is also that you need to have an
actual script that you're feeding into
this AI, right?
And then it's going to help you pick out
the details from that script that are
the most applicable to this video. And
then it's going to just simply rank them
in order of least to most viral. And as
proof that this actually worked, one of
our uh Content Academy paid members,
Richard, used Hooker AI and got his
first viral video, right? This was
literally like his first video ever that
got even over I think like 10K views. It
got 30K views, right? and he used the
Hooker bot and now it's actually on like
900,000 views and I believe like
Richard's actually grown like a couple
thousand followers from this video alone
that Hooker helped package and write the
hook for. Okay, so how it works like I
told you it's Clawude for Sonnet. It's
trained on hundreds of viral hooks and
it needs a full script to write quote
unquote authentic hooks. Because if you
don't feed it like an actual script of
your life story, of your actual talking
points, of what you're actually going to
cover in your video, then how is it
going to write a hook that like
authentically represents your story and
package your video in a way that
actually makes sense, right? Because if
I if I just tell like if I tell AI to
write me a hook for a video about let's
say like cars, it can it it'll try to
pick apart all these different avenues
of making a car hook, but at the end of
the day, it's going to be very broad.
It's going to be very vague, and human
beings don't like watching content
that's vague and broad anyways. So, you
need to like feed in an actual script
and it's going to help you package that
script to essentially maximize the
amount of views because the difference
between a bad hook and a really good
hook on a video on Instagram and Tik Tok
can literally be like 10x the views.
Because if 80% of your viewers fall off
in the first 3 seconds of your video,
the algorithms will see that and be
like, "Well, this video is not that
good." But if like let's say only 50% of
the viewers fall off in the first 3
seconds of that video, then the
algorithms will be like, "Okay, people
are clearly really interested in this
video." And that's what AI will help you
do. is going to help you package it.
Okay. Now, before AI, right, basically
what you'd probably have to do if you're
not using AI and you're not using Hook
or AI is to write like 10 versions of
your hook. If you actually want to go
like viral, you need to sit down and
rehash different versions of the hook
that you think might do well. And this
can be a very tedious process where
you're just writing the hook and then
writing another variation of it and then
writing another variation of it, right?
cuz I usually recommend writing like
five to 10 variations of your hook in
order to actually maximize the potential
of it going viral because often times
the first time we write a hook it's
always going to be like not as good as
the final product, right? And then you
have to pick the best one. So this
process alone can take like 30 minutes.
It can be very tedious and it has a
lower chance of going viral if you
aren't actually writing multiple
versions of the hook. Okay? Okay, so it
can make your content creation process
literally take an extra 30, maybe even
60 minutes if you don't understand this
process of hooks yet and what hooks
actually go viral. Okay, but after AI,
you can simply let AI write 10 versions
of the hook, train on the most viral
hooks already. So you don't have to go
onto Tik Tok, onto Instagram, keep
scrolling until you find hooks that
actually match your script. You can just
let AI do that process for you and speed
it up. And then all you have to do is
pick the best one. Okay, pick the one
then that actually is most concise, most
accurately describes what your video is
going to be about and then triggers the
most emotion, right? It's essentially
just like trying to do this intuitive
process of what's going to be the most
interesting. And that's what AI can help
you augment and speed up. And that's why
Hooker AI has been so effective for me,
right, in my videos that I showed you
that I actually used it on and for other
creators who are just starting out,
right? It helped them understand
packaging a lot quicker and then it
helped them also create hooks that go
more viral more quickly. Okay, so in
order to actually get access to this,
all you have to do is click the first
link in the description and you can
access it in our free Discord server,
right? And then free members get up to
three prompts every single day of like
this is not cheap. Like it's literally
cloud for it's also like one of the most
expensive writing models, right? and
it's trained on hundreds of viral hooks.
And um yeah, all you have to do is go to
that first link in the description and
access it in our free Discord server.
Now, I do want to give you an like a
quick warning. Like I said before, just
because you understand how to use AI to
actually make your hooks viral doesn't
mean you can just suddenly snap your
fingers and go viral. Obviously, and I
think you understand this, too. So, if
you actually are interested in building
an actual audience, I highly recommend
also learning the basics of making
quality content that retains attention.
So, I actually have this 7-day full
course completely free on YouTube as
well on how to start your personal brand
by simply copying these six videos that
I've made and you can see like the
videos themselves got like 200k views,
400k views, 70k views, right? Videos
that have built the core of my personal
brand and I giving away these six
modules on how I script, film, and edit
these completely for free. That's going
to be in the second link in the
description uh of this video. And yeah,
that being said, right, just to
summarize what we covered today, uh you
can use Hooker AI to actually make your
videos go viral by guaranteeing that
you're actually going to come up with a
hook that maximizes the viral potential
of your video, right? We covered what
doesn't work, which is this kind of one
button lazy automations that sells you
on this dream that you can just press
one button, you can go viral. And we
broke down exactly why that doesn't work
and why that's a complete misconception.
and you're pretty much being sold on a
lie if you're actually being convinced
that this works. I'm sorry. Right? And
then we covered what else you need
outside of just AI to actually go viral.
So hopefully this was very helpful.
Right? Honestly, I was just really
pissed off when I see a lot of these AI
creators talk about how you can like
automate your content process. And
honestly, it's a bunch of slop. It's
honestly just made so it can hook your
attention and get you to click, right?
But it doesn't actually freaking work
because I've tried it. I've grown over
three accounts on TikTok to over 100,000
followers. So, please trust me when I
say like I actually know what does well
on these platforms and it it's not this
like automated slop because it has no
actual respect for like human psychology
and the actual viewer who's watching
this video, right? In order to make
viral videos actually do well on Tik Tok
and Instagram, you have to understand
this communication that's going on right
now between me and you as a viewer.
Okay, so hopefully this was helpful. I'm
like so so passionate about like
actually helping creators maximize their
potential. If you are interested in that
mission, you want to keep learning, I
highly recommend you check out the other
videos on my page. That being said,
thank you guys for watching. I'll catch
you guys in the next video.