Last month, our business did 101K. This
is basically the traffic breakdown that
we had. The only social media sources
that even were able to like become
buyers to begin with were from my reals
and from my YouTube. I'm pretty sure
last month I probably did around 6
million views. And then on YouTube,
whatever you add up these three is, we
probably did around 50k views. Last
month, we turned 6 million views on
reals and 50k views on Instagram into
100k. I really want to break down the
system that we did that. I honestly
think this system is not that optimized,
but I want to break down the system
anyways. Even if you guys are a beginner
to online business, the way a funnel
works for all of you guys beginners.
Basically, there's three steps. The
words that I'm going to use today are
traffic, nurture, and product awareness.
And then lastly, there's the uh the
sale, which is like the last step, and
that's when somebody buys. Most people
when they think of internet marketing
and like making money online, they
usually think of these two. Oh, I need
to get a lot of views and I need to get
a lot of sales. it it's like very
rudimentary understanding of it. Oh, as
long as I get a lot of views, I can get
lots of money and sales. And the truth
is just like very far from that. And I
know this because I had an account on
TikTok with over a 900,000 followers.
And yes, it's a completely different
audience from what I was selling. But
when I first tried to launch like a
course to them, bro, I got two sales. I
made like 500 bucks from 900,000
followers on average a million views a
video. So, I got a ton of traffic and
zero sales. So, when I say like these
steps matter, this is why certain
creators can get way less views than
others and still make way more sales.
And that's what I'm very proud of in
this system. And I want to shout out to
my team as well, my my sales team and
Justin back in operations because they
made this system possible. Okay, so I
didn't do this alone. I do want to
highlight for people who want to reach
like 100k months. Yes, you can try to do
it alone. It's just like significantly
harder to do that way and I honestly
just think it's less fun. Here are the
two steps that nobody ever really talks
about online unless you are an advanced
like funnel person. But I'm going to
explain it to you guys anyways for those
you guys are advanced and who want to
learn like what the [ __ ] even is a
funnel. Okay, step two after you get
traffic, after you get views is you need
a nurture sequence. This is when people
say like give free value. The reason why
they say give free value is because
nobody's going to see your face and then
be like, you know what, today's a really
great day to pay this guy money. Like
no. Okay, even if they see the product
up front, like they need to somewhat
become aware. And this process, mind
you, it can happen pretty quickly.
Somebody can go from not knowing who you
are, seeing your face for the first
time, and buying from you in like a day.
That happens. That actually happens like
very often. It doesn't matter how long
it usually takes, but you need them
regardless. You You see those people who
like make [ __ ] ton of money from their
personal brands by selling something,
it's usually because they have nurture.
Like so big names like TJR, Santa Cruz
medicinals, rescales, Iman Godzi,
Horoszi, they all have these kind of
systems in place to break down our
nurture sequence. Basically, the the
goal of nurture is to give value through
your content. And the reason why is
because you want to build trust. You
can't just like dance your dance with
the pants online and then suddenly like
show wake up with like a million
dollars. like you you they need to be
able to trust that you actually know
you're talking about so they can
associate the trust that they have to
you and the value that you've provided
them to the products that you can sell
as well. So the nurture sequences that
we have, one of them is this free class
that I'm doing right now. Okay? And the
way that I've structured these free
classes, this is like getting kind of
really super meta because you are
literally like you are in the funnel.
Like you are the method right now, bro.
Low key. Okay? Even if you're watching
this on YouTube, like you are part of
the method. And I know that sounds like
really [ __ ] meta and weird and like
silly, but I want to explain actually
like the the thought behind it. For any
of you guys who have like resistance
towards actually like becoming online
marketers or online business people,
it's like wait that sounds like really
weird and like I don't like like selling
like I'll explain why that's probably
some product of like a limiting belief
in your mindset because that's a
limiting belief I had to conquer. I used
to hate the idea of selling online and I
realized it was a peopleleasing tendency
because when you actually have something
worth selling, you do want to promote
it. So, this is one of those things.
It's a free class where I give value.
Now, I'm not going to be like like at
the end of this, you're going to be
subtly manipulated into buying. Like, I
I do want to note that everybody has the
option to just like never progress from
one step to the other. So, somebody
who's watching the free class or
somebody who's watching the YouTube
video can just be like, actually, I just
want to stay here. I just want to stay
within the YouTube viewership. So, 46K
of these people, maybe only like 200 of
them even considered. let me actually
like think about going the next step
into his funnel. Other than that, they
mostly just stay here and that's okay.
Okay, that's fine. That's not like a big
deal. But you still need these sequences
in place regardless. Next step after
they see like one of my pieces of
content is sometimes they'll see my
Instagram story or they'll comment like
yeah on one of my videos or comment
viewer or comment class and then they
will be directed towards either my free
class or they will be directed towards
this one page. Okay. Now, what this one
website page is is called a landing
page. And your goal as a internet
marketer is basically to just to direct
as much traffic as possible towards that
one thing that sort of transitions your
viewer from a just a viewer to an actual
buyer. And the difference between a
viewer and a buyer, right? I'm going to
draw two people here. Let's say like a
viewer in red and then we have like
buyer in green. Like what actually
separates like A from B, the viewer
versus the buyer? Realistically, it's
that one middle step and it's called
like product awareness. And the way that
you build product awareness is through a
a few things. You can do it in a free
class or you can do it in a website or
you can do it in a video sales letter.
That's realistically like the three ways
you should do it. There's like no other
ways that you should make your viewers
aware of your product. You could even do
it in your YouTube video. Like some
people make YouTube videos that
introduce and make your viewers product
aware. I don't think you should make
your viewers product aware in your
reals. I don't think that actually works
that well. You could talk about how much
of a product that you're selling, but
realistically you're just going to sound
salesy. For those of you guys who
actually do make like Instagram reels,
you you don't want to just like stay in
Instagram reels and just try to sell
always through your Instagram reels.
Like I I think that's like you need at
least one middle step and that's usually
a website or a landing page. Okay, so
I'll show you guys my website and
landing page. It's basically if you look
in the description of this YouTube
video, you can find it too. It's
basically this and it's a very simple
video. These are the four stages you
will go through starting. It walks
through some free value as well because
you need some transitionary step. You
can't just be like, "Hey, here's what
happens when you buy content academy."
Like that. That sounds really abrupt.
You want to frame it like free value as
well and then only introduce the product
as an extension to the free value. You
need this transitionary step in the
middle to introduce them and take them
from free value into an actual like
offer aare or product aare person. And
at this point, that doesn't mean they're
a buyer. that just means they're like
capable of buying and then they can book
a a call with one of our onboarding
specialists uh to join content academy.
So you guys can do this too, right? And
basically all this website is supposed
to do is introduce you to the idea of
the offer and the product and
potentially book the customer into a
call. And that's the whole goal of a
marketing funnel is to basically take
them from the viewer into a buyer. So,
there's maybe going to be like 100x the
amount of viewers or a,000x the amount
of viewers or 10,000x the amount of
viewers that you have versus buyers.
That's just natural because not
everybody wants to be a buyer of your
thing, okay? Like eventually maybe they
will be, but at the end of the day, like
that's not what people go on social
media to do. Like people don't go on
social media with wallets in their hand
or card in their hand. They're just like
scrolling to get free stuff and to get
entertainment and to like learn
something. Maybe that's why they go on
social media. So the goal of the nurture
is to just make them aware and plant the
seed in their mind. That's what a lot of
advertising is. Just planting the seed
in somebody's mind that like, oh, this
thing exists. So when I do have a
painoint, I might buy it. Like think
about Coca-Cola. You see their ads and
their billboards all the time. Like
they're not telling you, hey, purchase a
Coca-Cola right now, fat [ __ ]
Like no, they're not telling you to do
that. They're just saying like, "Hey, a
Coca-Cola is nice and if you ever need a
refreshing thing, like they're there."
And that that's the goal. The goal is
just to make them aware. And then
lastly, you need an actual sale
mechanism. After you have made them
product aware, you need a sales
mechanism. And the sale mechanism for us
is a call. That's pretty much the only
way that we sell. Now, we've closed a
couple people over the DMs, but even
now, like we're optimizing a lot for
calls. And this is like the classic
classic way of selling things, which is
a sales call or a discovery call. And
that's where people actually go from
like, oh, I'm interested in this thing
to like, oh, I'm actually going to buy
it. This is a this is quite advanced and
I understand like the there's a lot of a
lot of moving parts. But I want to make
something very very clear, which is that
I am not a big fan of on your website
directly selling something simply
because it's incredibly unlikely. Like
the likelihood that somebody's going to
buy something directly from a website,
especially if it's above like $100,
skyrockets down. It plummets downward.
And the reason why is because like when
somebody watches a piece of content,
it's a lot harder for them to just be
like, "Oh, this piece of content was
good." to like, "Let me purchase."
There's a lot more steps. There's like
one more step that needs to come in. And
that's what closing is. That's what
selling is. Okay? And the the goal of
sales, the goal of like selling and
closing is just to help somebody get
over the edge. A good example of this,
uh, a really good analogy of sales is
not like, don't think of Jordan
Belelffort, right, and Wolf of Wall
Street. Think of like a server at a
restaurant. They're simply helping the
person make a decision. So, if you are
ever like finding yourself trying to do
sales, always remember like your goal is
not necessarily, yo, I'm going to hard
sell them and I'm going to make sure the
buyer [ __ ] buys or does. Like, don't
think of it that way. That's probably
going to put you in a hell of scarce
mindset. What you probably want to do is
just think about it like you're a server
and you're helping them make a decision
where you're just like, maybe I want
this or maybe I don't want it. help me
make a decision. And then the server
kind of comes to it and and they're
like, "Oh," or the waiter and they're
like, like the pasta is like pretty
good, but I recommend for your
situation, you sound like you want to
like optimize for protein intake. Let's
get you a steak today. And you're like,
I bet. Thank you, bro. You know, so like
that that's kind of what like the call
is. Having a human there helps make the
decision a lot easier. Okay. Okay. And a
lot of times too, like especially with
purchase something online, like we can
have a lot of resistance and a lot of
questions, which is very natural. And
that's why a website probably can't
answer those questions and develop that
trust and rapport, but a actual
one-to-one call with a human being can.
And that's the whole goal of directing
people from your your page to a call.
Now, I do want to note, you could
actually just scrap all of this [ __ ] I
know that sounds kind of crazy. You
could just theoretically put a link in
your bio that says like book a call. And
I've seen people do this. So I do want
to simplify this concept to you. Instead
of thinking about it like holy [ __ ] how
do I start, bro? How do I make all of
this? Like think about it like what if
you just told people to book a call from
your Instagram page and then they booked
a call. That's level one. And that's
fine. That's actually fine. That's fine.
I don't want you to need to think about
this in this complex way. The only
reason why I have that complex mechanism
is because we're driving a ton of views.
And also because I've been running this
business now for over a year. So like we
have a bunch of things in place because
we want to be able to like optimize it.
Something I really want to note is slow
motion is better than no motion. And if
you want to get started with an online
business, don't think about it like you
need to build all 11 steps. You just
need to build one, which is the ability
to sell something. The way you can
either do that is yes, you can sell
through a VSSL like I've done that too
like literally just through a landing
page. You just have your website and
then it directly has the purchase link.
That happens. You don't need that
either. You can just do like a directly
to a call and that'll teach you about
the psychology of sales where you're
going to talk you're going to hop on a
call with somebody and then they're
going to be like like let's say you're
selling a you know sell say you're
selling something like really specific
like a software an AI agent that helps
business owners. You're like oh shoot I
want to hop on a call and talk to this
business owner. You're going to help
it's that's going to help you understand
what does a buyer go through? what does
like this business owner actually want
in their life as opposed to guessing and
just throwing spaghetti onto a website
and hoping that the writing on the wall
works? You can talk to them. You can ask
them a lot of questions. The goal of a
sales call is to ask a ton of questions
and learn about the person. So, you can
actually deliver like a product that
actually helps them specifically. That's
the whole benefit of having that call
there. And yeah, like if you do want to
book a call and learn about Content
Academy, which is our like program to
learn content creation, and then start
making that into like an income for you,
you can book a call in that first link
in the description down below. But
anyways, I know there's like probably a
lot of questions here, and there's two
main questions that I want to answer.
This next part is directed specifically
for the people who are kind of on the
fence of like, uh, like I don't really
know about selling something online.
First question is like, bro, isn't this
kind of scammy and manipulative? Isn't
selling like this this entire like
manipulative process of like taking them
from a viewer to the dollar in your
pocket kind of manipulative and scammy?
And I had that limiting belief too when
I like let's take like 10 steps
backwards when I was first starting
online business. I had this limiting
belief of like bro I don't want to be
one of those scammers online basically
scams people to make money from them. I
saw all these people online, right, who
made a shitload of money, but I was
like, damn, bro. I I don't want to be
perceived as like a guru. And I think
that's a very common common thing that I
hear. To quell any objections, I do want
to say learning business has absolutely
[ __ ] changed my life. With our
business, I've been able to throw events
in person for up to like 60 70 people.
60 70 people. I've been able to meet
such brilliant people like some of the
most cracked people I would never would
have met as a bummy like high school
college student. Most importantly, I
think it's learned it's taught me a lot
about selfmastery and leadership. All of
these tangible skills and I think that's
like the beauty of building your own
online business even if you're not going
to take it to the moon is it's going to
teach you so much. That's what benefit
it's provided me. But if you're on the
fence because you like have this
aversion to selling, you don't want to
seem scammy. It's only a scam if you
sell a shitty scammy product that
doesn't work and you don't care to fix
it. Because the thing is a lot of times
when we first launch a product online,
it's going to be like mid. It's like
literally going to be kind of mid and
you're going to be like, "Damn, like
this ain't no 10 out of 10." Like, bro,
I ain't selling Google and Amazon out
here. I'm not selling like an iPhone.
I'm selling like a Samsung. I'm selling
a an OPPO phone, whatever [ __ ]
Android like shitty phones there are.
Like I'm selling a BlackBerry in 2025
when there's already iPhones out there.
And I do want to say like one, it's
going to teach you a lot more just to
like learn these skills anyways. So
don't view it as like you have to be
perfect on day one. That's not how
anything in life works. And two, you
only become a scammer if you make
something shitty and you don't care
about fixing it. And if you even have
this concern, that means you your head
is on the right place. That means that
you have what it takes to actually build
a beautiful product. And it just takes
time. But don't let that fear and
imposter syndrome stop you from trying
to build something that actually helps
people and making that an actual income.
That's what a business is. And I want
you to understand that like this is one
of the like most beautiful things that
and most beautiful blessings that I've
ever had in my life is to embark on this
journey of trying to become a business
owner. There's a lot of imposttor
syndrome that you're going to face.
There's a lot of holy [ __ ] am I a bad
person? Am I just a money grabber? And
you only become that way if you actually
don't put in the work to like become
better at it. 1% better every single day
just like any skill in life like the gym
like content creation like social media
and if you check our wins channel too in
our discord where you can see like all
the people who are winning every single
day and I do want to note as cool and as
like OP as content academy as a product
seems today it was not that case when we
first started it like it was a kind of
meh product like our churn was 40% which
basically means 40% of people didn't
like our product so much that they left
after 1 month okay now it's at 8% so we
we've worked a lot on making the product
better Now, obviously, we get literally
wins every single day. It's only a scam
if it doesn't work. Okay? And I do want
to emphasize like put in the work to
improve because it's hard. It's not easy
to build a like a really good product,
but it's really rewarding over the long
term because I don't think there's any
more rewarding of a feeling when I know
I can do something that helps a lot of
people that I get inherent fulfillment
from doing because I like building
things, which I'm going to assume a lot
of you watching are. you you find
inherent joy from building things,
making content, making videos and also I
I guarantee you're going to feel that
same fulfillment from building a system
that continuously helps people and you
get paid for it and you can make it
scale even more and you can even build
careers for other people inside a
business. I know it's hard but it's
beautiful and I think that's what like
the essence of being a creator and a
creative is is to like make things that
help people and then like do it at
larger scales. I know like there's
obviously like shitty business people
out there but like you don't have to be
one of them. I I want at least content
academy to be an example that you can do
it like the right way. That's one of
like the missions that I have
personally. Content academy is like I
want to build like an actual good
product. I I like I want us to be like a
pillar in the space of like information
and coaching and uh communities that's
like, oh [ __ ] they're actually good.
Like you can actually build like really
cool [ __ ] and then maybe other
entrepreneurs can see that and be like,
you know what, [ __ ] it. Like I want to
do something like that and I want to
make something that helps people. I
think that's what being a creator is.
And I think the same with being an
entrepreneur. Okay. Second one is I
don't want to be labeled as a course
seller. So I hear this one often, right?
And like I I will I will not lie like
being a course seller specifically. It's
like one type of business. You can apply
marketing funnels to like every single
other one. But it's just because like
like content academy is like 50% a
course. So a lot of people can see that
and be like man are you a core seller
bro? Man you [ __ ] scammer bro. And to
that I say the method that I'm kind of
teaching you today is what I like to
call the ninja funnel. And the
ninjafunnel I'm not talking about
Fortnite. Ninjael basically means like
you can basically present yourself as a
guy who just gives out free stuff on the
front of your marketing which is just
like your your social media. On social
media you can present yourself as a
person who just gives out free stuff.
And then only if if they become product
aware and they become interested which
happens later down the funnel to most
viewers on social media. They're not
going to perceive you as somebody who's
directly selling something because your
website's not going to directly sell
something because there's no link to pay
on the website. There's no link to pay
on your like Instagram story. The only
link to pay happens once they hop on
like a call and that helps you like
evade this perception of like bro is
just making content to sell stuff. I'm
not going to lie, it is a mere
perception game, right? It's like it's
kind of just an optics thing where like
people see that you're selling something
and they just like inherently have less
trust. That's just normal. And I think
it's because like a lot of people on the
internet sell like kind of garbage
products and it's like normal. That's
like part of the game design, right? is
like this human psychology of if you
present yourself as a seller, people are
just going to be less averse to trusting
you. So the ninja funnel, which I've
kind of walked through with you guys
here, instead of labeling yourself
outright, hey, I'm selling the course,
I'm selling the course, I'm selling the
course, just give out free stuff on the
front end. And that's what makes a this
a little bit more complex is because
everything in this section is free.
Everything in the nurture sequence is
free. And that's the whole goal. And
that's what can make it so your your
social media can still continue to grow.
Your following and your trust can still
continue to grow. Your YouTube audience
can still continue to grow. Your
reputation will continue to grow. And
you can still have buyers because it's
still behind the scenes. And it's that's
what the beauty of like a Ninja is. A
Ninja is a funnel that that hides in
plain sight. And still it's like you
guys are still here watching. It's
because I'm giving free value. Like in
no way do I feel even weird about this.
at no point and I'm like
my [ __ ] Like no, it's just like
free. It's it's like actually free. And
I think that's like the the best version
of like a ninja funnel is like actually
free value. So to like to non- buyers,
which is like 80% of the people who
watch your stuff anyways, they are just
going to see you giving out free stuff
and they're not going to feel weird
about it. Just like pretty much like
every good business out there. Let's
think of any good like service that you
guys use that you guys like actually
enjoy using like YouTube. We are
literally on YouTube and Discord right
now. 90s something% of people who use
both YouTube and Discord are never going
to pay for their like free premium
subscription. Do does that make us like
feel ew and icked out by YouTube and
Discord? No. We're just like, "Yo,
thanks YouTube. Thanks Discord for
giving out free stuff because they're
not looking to scare away the people who
could potentially eventually become
buyers. They're just letting them in
anyways into the ecosystem." And then
eventually they could like behind the
scenes maybe once you like get tired as
[ __ ] of like YouTube ads and you're like
fine I'll buy YouTube premium or once
you actually need to like launch a
really cool Discord server then you can
be like fine I'll buy Discord Nitro but
you're not thinking about that
consciously as you use the platforms
because it's just free. So that's the
whole goal of a Ninjael and I actually
think like the the best companies in the
world use Ninjaels like YouTube right?
Uh what what are some other like
platforms like Instagram even right
Instagram like they have metaverified
right which costs like 15 to like 200
bucks a month but like 90% of user base
is never going to see that YouTube is a
great example okay where it's premium
right clash of clients clash royale okay
there we go good good brain rod examples
here but yeah only pitch your product to
the most invested people and the beauty
is that if they want to there's this big
thing of optionality where if you want
the thing then you can buy it but you
don't have to and if a buyer and
reviewer feels like they're being forced
while watching you to buy your thing,
it's just going to feel really weird all
around. The next logical question that I
want to answer for you guys is how do
you start? Okay, how do I actually start
this online business journey? Because
it's like sounds really interesting in
theory, but how do I go from like
current version of me? I'm just like
watching. I'm just like what like what
is going on here, man? Like you know,
like I'm kind of like picking my nose.
I'm not saying you guys are, but maybe
one of you guys or one or two of you
guys are just kind of like watching
picking your nose being me like what
like how do I start? I'm here talking
about 100k a month coaching business,
but a good two years ago, I like pretty
much never sold anything online before.
Like four years ago, I was like dead
ass, like a bummy like college student
who just like didn't really know what I
was going to do with my life. A lot can
change very quickly. I have broken down
my own journey into six stages to a 100k
a month coaching business. Now, I've
condensed this down to six stages, but
like you got to understand this stage
one might also take you like a good like
year or two. Skill portion is part one
to building a coaching business.
Basically, you don't need a skill if you
have a different style of business, but
if you want to do a coaching business,
you need a skill that you can coach
other people. The step one that I had to
go through was like I had to build a
skill. And that took me like a good like
2 years of learning Tik Tok. I had to
learn how to go viral. So, like I
literally ran up these accounts on Tik
Tok before I even considered like ever
selling like an actual like coaching
program to teach how to do content
creation because I ran up all of these
accounts. I made like a a couple
thousand dollars doing brand deals for
for businesses and that's how I like
learned the skill of content creation.
That's why I teach content creation
because I spent a lot of time learning
it. So number one is like build a skill
and I know that's like really weird like
bro aren't we here for business and
social media advice like yeah part of
running a business and part of being on
social media is like you know low-key
being like a developed human being. Wa
shocker like yes build skills learn to
be articulate uh learn to do things.
Some of these things can be like go do
like sales, like go knock doors, right?
If you want to learn sales as a skill,
go knock doors. If you want to learn
content creation, post a 100 videos. If
you want to become a fitness coach, go
lift weights 100 days in a row. Like
learn a skill. And like it doesn't have
to be a really complex skill. Like I
would say that's number one. But once
you have a somewhat developed skill and
you can consider yourself a decent level
of like expertise in that skill. The
best coaching business is like the least
amount of friction you'll have is when
you're an actual expert. But let's say
you're like pretty expert already. Then
next step is to develop your content
skill set. And you can do this in tandem
with like building your skill set as
well. You really want to build the skill
of content creation because I don't
think this like coaching business model
really works unless you can actually
like make content and do it well. The
the main goal that I have for you is
build your content level one. Like that
your content skill set level one. If you
can do that, that's going to make this
entire thing possible. That's going to
make all sorts of businesses possible
when you just learn the basics of
content creation. And I see that as just
getting your first thousand followers.
thousand organic just means like you got
your view you got your followers from
like videos that you posted not like
bought you bought them or something like
I'm talking about like your first
thousand true fans your real followers
and the way that you can actually do
this is by building up your basic
content strategy and your basic content
skills. So the basic content skills that
I highly suggest you learn if you want
to get into this online business thing
and this like online marketing thing is
to learn editing. It's to learn
scripting. It's to learn hooks. And
that's when you can actually learn the
basic content strategy. And an example
of a basic content strategy that I was
giving one of my clients. If you're
teaching sales, a basic content strategy
can be like showing videos of you taking
sales calls. Uh sales call tips and then
showcasing lifestyle videos. That's like
a very basic content strategy. But the
main thing is you need to learn editing,
right? You need to master scripting. You
need to master hooks. And that sounds
really stupid. Like wait, what? Bro,
what? I'm not going to edit, bro. I'm
trying to be a business owner, bro.
That's low leverage, bro. Shut the [ __ ]
up. Shut shut the [ __ ] up, bro. You you
like you have zero understanding of
marketing. like learn learn how to edit
at least like to a basic degree and then
we can talk about more advanced [ __ ] cuz
I I don't know I I meet a lot of
business owners and they're kind of like
yo how do I do this and it's like Mitch
you skipped two three and four and
you're trying to get to five and six
like shut up. So learn like the basics
of content creation that's that's one of
the most useful skills you can have in
today's day and age. Whether you want to
start an online business or you
literally just want to like build your
skill content creation because you can
literally get there's certain
opportunities out there that you can
literally just get paid to make videos
for other businesses and you get paid
like a a shitload of money just to like
learn the skill of content creation.
It's it's so OP. Okay. And that's what
Content Academy does. We like teach that
before you actually look to even build
your offer or aka your product/
business. In online business terms, we
just call it an offer because it's an
offer that you make to your viewers to
buy something from you. You want to
master like level one, two, and three of
content creation, which I think is
getting your first thousand followers.
And in order to get your first thousand
followers, you need to understand the
basics of content content strategy, you
need to learn the basics of editing,
learn the basics of scripting, and learn
the basics of hooks. And if you want to
speedrun that, I'm going to tell you
exactly how to do that in a bit. But
after you have mastered the basics of
content creation, which will take you
probably a good like uh you can probably
do it around 90 days. I I would say like
the most like realistic timeline for
people who've like done it quickly is
around 90 days of like mastering content
creation to uh hit their first like
th000 to 10,000 followers takes around
90 days of like effort and I see that in
our content academy members okay in our
like paid program and once you even do
that then you can start thinking about
like offer like okay now what do I offer
these people I've got a thousand people
watching me what do I sell them what do
I give them and that's when you can
start thinking about your offer and I'll
explain exactly how to how to come up
with your first ever offer/online
business in a second I am expling
explaining a lot right now, but the main
gist is like build a skill. Build your
skill of content creation. That's like
your level one marketing. And then you
can think about offer and product. It's
weird because usually you think like,
wait, let me build the iPhone first
before I go out and market it. It's
actually kind of the opposite. Like you
want to learn how to market something.
So then when you have a product to
actually distribute, that's when you can
actually start to like make money from
it. It's it's a lot harder when you
don't have people already watching you.
Next, you want to get to content level
four. And the reason why I say content
level four is 10,000 10,000 organic
followers in order to actually like run
a successful business. I think you need
to have enough of an understanding where
you can essentially make your content
systemized. And this is where like the
concept of like running a business kind
of through your content exists. You need
to be able to systemize it where you
have a repeatable format that you can
actually do with your videos and you
also have a niche. And usually by 10k
organic followers, you'll have a very
clear understanding of that. and then
you'll have a very clear understanding
of how to replicate your content without
too much effort. But if you're trying to
learn the business side for the first
time and you're trying to learn the
content side for the first time, it's
going to be really hard. Honestly, it's
just going to be really hard. Like learn
one first. And I highly recommend like
always learn the content thing first
because it's going to make it your life
10 times easier to actually learn the
offer side because now you have people
to market to. Would you rather try and
build like a really cool product but
then have nobody to like share it and
get feedback from or would you rather
have a classroom full of people, a
lecture hall full of people and then get
feedback? Like I'd rather get the
lecture hall of people to get feedback
from rather than like, oh, I have this
thing. Anybody want it? Crickets. So
that's what makes it easier to build an
online business. And then once you have
your content in a decent level where
you've like systemized it and now you
can start making ideas a lot quicker. So
instead of spending 3 hours learning the
basics of a video, you can do it in like
30 minutes every single day. That's the
point that I've gotten to and that's how
I was able to grow my business to 100K a
month and simultaneously uh consistently
grow my page from 50K to 400,000
followers on Instagram in the past like
21 months. So like January 2024, I was
at 50k Instagram followers. This was
like while I was in college, while I was
starting this online business, and now
it's like we've also grown on Instagram,
too. You can do both, but you need to
have like a decent level of like these
systems understanding of content. I'm
just throwing out buzzwords. Basically,
you need to be like good enough at it.
You need to understand it so you can
like kind of do it with your eyes
closed. Do it with half your brain. Like
think about the amount of effort that it
takes to like learn Cap Cut. Like try
imagine you're trying to learn offers
right now. You're trying to like learn
all this complex business stuff, but
then you're like you have to post a
video and now you're just like you have
Cap Cut open. It's this like complex
[ __ ] editing platform. There's like a
video here, like a [ __ ] button here,
like 10 bajillion buttons here, 10 blah
blah blah blah. you're just like, "Oh, I
hate this." And then you give up. Like,
if if that's you, it's probably because
you're trying to like bite off way more
than you can chew. You're not doing it
in a in an orderly fashion. Like, learn
the skill set first. Okay? Then you can
systemize your content. And it's kind of
this you can play this game of like
continuously running your content and
your business simultaneously. And it's
just becomes this loop that you have to
continuously run and it's a flywheel.
And you can pay people to help you run
this thing. That's where hiring comes
in. But it's this continuous thing of
marketing and then building your
product, marketing, building your
product. And it's over and over and over
and over. And the longer that you can
run it, the like the better the business
that you build. And yes, doing a daily
content challenge is probably one of the
best ways to build your skill set of
content creation because it's really
hard to build this skill set if you're
not doing it every single day. It's like
trying to get good at the gym and trying
to like get into like a decent level of
fitness, but then you go to the gym like
once every week and you're like, h like
next time you show to the gym, you're
like I forgot what even the workout was.
How do I do this? Versus if you're going
every single day, even for like 30
minutes, you're like, right, okay, today
I'm just going to do this and I'm going
to be in and out and I know exactly that
I'm feeling like I'm making progress and
I'm making it a habit like deep down in
like the the habit center of my brain
neurologically, which is I I think like
the basil ganglia. So don't treat
content as like a once a week thing
because you're never going to build the
habit of it and then your brain's never
going to get into like a creative habit.
And the best creators have a creative
habit of thinking creatively every
single day. Okay. And then lastly, once
you have been running this flywheel,
which is known as a business for a while
now on repeat in circles and circles and
circles and circles, then you can start
introducing these which are also other
circles. Like you have to understand
like YouTube is its own circle and now
you have like two circles running
simultaneously and that's why it's like
kind of hard. Like a lot of people are
like, "Yo, so I'm going to like
systemize my Instagram and then I'm
going to systemize my YouTube. I'm just
going to run it up at the same time and
I'm also going to have Twitter and I'm
also going to have LinkedIn." And it's
like, "Brother, you you haven't even
mastered one platform. You're like
trying. You think you're doing like this
masterful like spinning multiple wheels
at the same time. When in reality,
you're just doing this. Like you're
you're like, "Oh, I'm I'm going to spin
the wheel a little bit. Okay, now I'm
going to move it over here. I'm just
going to turn it like a little bit like
like 15°. Oh, wait. Let's try that." And
I turn this like 10°. Oh, okay. LinkedIn
LinkedIn today. LinkedIn today. Oh,
boom. And it's like nothing actually
runs because you're like not actually
doing anything with full effort. And
you're not going to succeed in any
platform if you're not like putting like
100% of your effort into learning it. So
that's why learn this first. And my
highest recommendation is learn Tik Tok
and Instagram first. If you learn Tik
Tok and Instagram first, it's going to
teach you the basics of retention. It's
going to teach you the basics of
filming. It's going to teach you the
basics of editing software. It's going
to make it so you get a a very quick
feedback loop. And Instagram and Tik
Tok's algorithms will literally tell you
if your video was good or bad within
like a day. YouTube is going to take
like a month. And your videos are going
to take like 10 times longer cuz they're
long. So I would recommend start on Tik
Tok and start on YouTube if you actually
want to or start on Instagram if you
actually want to learn content creation
and like a lot of people will genuinely
I'll see them as complete beginners and
within 90 days of joining content
academy I'll see them like getting their
first like million view video or getting
their first like several hundredk view
video and then hitting their first like
1k 5k followers. Okay? So focus on the
skill of content creation guys. If you
actually want to like go from literally
like zero skill picking your nose to
actually like building this complex
thing focus on skill content creation
first. worry about starting your online
business after you have mastered the
traffic side, aka the uh content
creation side and you've acquired a
skill. So, to get from level one to
level four in content creation, I
recommend joining the content academy. I
genuinely think we have like the best
resources to learn content creation from
scratch. And if you want to learn offer
creation, you're a little bit more
advanced in this journey, you want to
learn the ropes of basic online
business, read this book by Alex Rozzi.
It's not that long. It's like 200 pages.
Uh maybe not even 200. It might be like
100 pages. and they have like picture
books and stuff, so like it's like hella
easy. Like you can read that [ __ ] like
being like hella low attention span like
me. It took me like a week to read this
cuz I like I was like a pretty terrible
reader. But if you're not at that level
of offer creation yet and you need to
learn content creation and get from
level zero to level one to level two to
level three to level four, you learn the
basics of scripting, filming, and
editing, I highly recommend content
academy because in content academy,
we've like the whole mission that we
have is to to create the complete
community to make content creation a
predictable career path for anyone. And
to prove it to you, these are literally
people who have sent a win into our wins
channel in our Discord server in the
past 24 hours. You can see this was sent
yesterday at 9:00 p.m. So after 10 days
of posting one to two times a day, Seb,
he was literally a lost 15year-old, like
not really knowing what he should do. It
was a little personal, but you know, I I
really appreciate him having the honesty
here. Like after getting coaching from
all of our coaches, from me, our content
coach Prosper, who has 400k or 390K
followers, and then Sam, he went and got
his first video to hit, I think, 50K
views. It was his first video that ever
popped off, right? After 10 days of
posting one to two times a day and
reinforcing that skill set. After that,
you can get to people like Keel, right,
who got his first 500k view video in the
fashion niche and he got a good amount
of followers from it. And then after you
start building up that skill set of
content creation, right? This is at the
point where you're probably around level
three. Then you can start making money
from Instagram. And it doesn't have to
be from your own business. It can be
from like things like UGC, from
essentially just going to a business and
being like, "What if I come inside your
business and help you make a video or
two every single uh week or every single
day?" And that's where you can make your
first dollar from content creation. That
requires you to have a skill set because
what kind of business is going to pay
you if you make a video and it looks
like it was made by a 2-year-old. Okay?
So, like, learn the skill of content
creation first. That's that's the whole
goal of what we do in Content Academy.
We're training you and then you can get
your first dollar from Instagram from
getting paid by a brand, right? Or
getting your even your first client.
This is malt. I know he's in the chat
right now, but shout out Malt, bro. He
closed a new client from his content,
right? And shout out one of our coaches,
Gabe, who teaches monetization, because
he told him to do a specific type of
format, which didn't go viral, but the
video alone booked him two calls and got
him a client. So, you can start making
your first dollar from content creation.
And then there's just people who are
absolute like monsters in our community
who like I remember when Rajan was under
10,000 followers back in like October of
last year, bro. He's at 400,000
followers now. Okay, he's about to pass
me, bro. I got to lock in on my own
content, man. Damn. But yeah, like
there's absolute monsters in our
community who went though and started
off in this very first stage of just
learning to post your first video, then
learning to post your first seven video,
and then getting your first 50k view
video, your first 500k view video, then
getting your first like 500,000
followers. Like, damn, I probably
skipped a few steps of learning, but
that's what we do in Content Academy.
And these were all just wins in our
community in the past 24 hours. So, if
you are interested in getting this
training to become a goated content
creator, make money from brand deals,
make money by getting paid by other
brands through UGC and eventually
parlaying that skill set to become a
business owner or scale your own
business. It really just starts at
contentacademy.io/start
and you can apply. We'll only take your
call if you are actually qualified to be
a member. Uh, and there's a few
qualifications which you will find in
this page. So, in the link in the
description in this YouTube video,
you'll see the first link is a link to
uh apply and book a call. And then you
can just book a call with our onboarding
specialist to join the best creator
community in the world. And that's how
you're going to speedrun your skill set
of learning content creation from
scratch. And then after you do that,
then you can learn offer creation. And
then you become this like super cool
business owner that that gets to make
like spinning spinning wheel
presentations and pretend like he knows
things when in reality all he's done is
make a really simple funnel. And then
you get to make really cool diagrams and
share them on YouTube. and then pretend
like you have Aura. But hopefully this
was uh not too confusing for you guys.
Thank you guys so much for tuning in. Uh
if you want to learn more about how to
get started with content creation, you
can book a call down below and the
website should look like this. First
link in the description right down
there.