Quite sadly and with regret, the
undergraduate dean's office is
withdrawing you from the Carol School of
Management at Boston College. So, I got
this letter in May 28th of 2024.
Actually, I I wasn't the first one to
see it. My mom was the first one. And
being a Korean mom who for the past 20
months was arguing with me to not leave
college. It was pretty [ __ ]
embarrassing. A little backstory. A year
before I got this letter, I was entering
my sophomore year of college, right
after taking a gap year to make this
like social media content creation thing
try to work. It didn't really work,
hence why I was going back to college.
But right before I entered, I told my
mom one thing. At the end of the year,
no matter what, I will drop out of
college. And at the time, she was kind
of like, like whatever, fine. You're
back in college. Like, you know, go go
study. And I think a lot of fellow
Asians carry this kind of guilt and
burden. you feel like the reason why you
work very hard is so you can make your
parents proud. But the way that
manifested for me in high school and
college is that I always felt this
pressure to get like straight A's, but I
could never actually lock in and focus
on school. So there was always this push
and pull between wanting to study more
and [ __ ] I need to lock in, dude. Why
am I so bad at this school thing, bro?
I'm actually going to get straight A's
and then never actually doing it. always
resorting back to these terrible habits
of staying up late till like 3:00 a.m.
playing League of Legends all night,
like gooning every single night, low
key, watching YouTube. But today, I
wanted to actually tell you guys the
story of how I transformed myself to
actually lock in on the goals that I
truly knew were aligned with me, which
was social media content creation. And
then how I went from in just a single
year going from making less than like
500 bucks a month from social media to
just like eight months later turning
that into a 10K a month consistent
business. And then 8 months after that
after I'd actually left college, I
turned that into a 100K a month social
media business. So let's go back
September 2023. I entered college with
this very happy golucky mindset.
Honestly, I was very optimistic because
I literally just told my parents I'm
about to drop out of college by the end
of this year. This going to be my last
year. And one of the biggest things that
I did really early on in that first
semester is I actually didn't sign up
for any business classes despite being a
business major in my second year, which
means you have to do a bunch of these
like business prerequisites, finance and
accounting 101. I said, "Fuck all of
that." And I took acting classes fully
knowing that this would not meet my
credit minimum. And I think it's one of
the best decisions that I ever made
because for once in my life, I actually
went to class excited. I took acting and
I took this relationship class called
interpersonal relations and I committed
also to this one thing which was to
actually become consistent as a
lifestyle creator in college. Up until
this point, I did post on social media.
I was posting on TikTok for the past 2
years, but I was bouncing between these
comedy videos that I used to make that
made me like close to no money and then
these self-improvement videos that also
didn't really make me much money either.
So, I wanted two things out of this
year. I wanted to actually figure out
how to actually monetize my personal
brand on social media. I went in with
around 20,000 Instagram followers. I had
literally made $0 from Instagram up
until that point. But I knew going in if
there's one thing I want to get out of
this last year of college, it's that I
want to document this is me going
through my last year of college. So I
kind of viewed a lot of this last year
of college as just fodder for making a
[ __ ] ton of cool videos. And I actually
think this is like one of these weirdly
untapped methods. Making videos about
college genuinely led to me building a
business. It also led to me literally
getting paid from Tik Tok's creativity
program directly, probably around
$10,000 throughout that school year
because I would make videos of me
studying one hour for my exams last
minute. And there were about three of
these what I'll call pivot points
throughout this last year of college
that genuinely I think changed my life.
And that first pivot point was doing
this accountability challenge with my
friend Prosper called Project 50 where
we had to do these five non-negotiable
things every single day. We had to text
a picture of ourselves waking up out of
bed at 8 a.m. Do 1 hour of an
undistracted morning routine. We had to
do a new skill for an hour every single
day. We had to do an hour of exercise
every single day. And then we had to
follow some sort of strictish diet. So I
had to cut out all added sugar during
those 50 days of this accountability
challenge. And I started this around
October of 2023. And I just started
documenting that in videos every single
day. Project 50 day one. I posted that
onto my Instagram. And that's like my
pro tip number one is that if you
actually want to make this content
creation thing work, just start
documenting random [ __ ] online. Even if
you want to get into online business, I
think starting to just build your
personal brand on Instagram as a young
person. I think it's very very possible
is one of the most valuable things that
you can do while you're in college,
while you're just trying to figure out
what you want to do with your life. If
you have no clue, bro, post on social
media. You're going to get opportunities
thrown at you. And I think like it's one
of the best ways to build optionality as
a young person where instead of clawing
for opportunities and constantly being
at the mercy of other people, you're
building your own optionality and you're
building your own luck. You're
increasing your surface area of luck
every time you put something out onto
social media. And yes, you're facing
like this low social aura moment of like
trying to be an influencer, but that's
not the [ __ ] point. The point is not
to like, you know, be narcissistic and
be this like influencer. Oh my gosh,
guys, look at me. No, it's to put out
stuff that genuinely might help one
person out there on the internet and
then in return eventually it'll reach
somebody who actually has an opportunity
for you. You talk about being unemployed
online or you talk about working a job
online. I've literally seen people get
jobs because they documented that
process online. So that was pivot point
number one. Staying accountable to
living some sort of healthy lifestyle
while I was in college. And I think
that's one of the reasons why I have
literally zero regrets from that last
year of college is because I actually
spent it with like such an optimal
balance of being locked in while also
having fun. Like I probably smoked weed,
I'm not going to lie, like 20 times
throughout that last year of college. I
hit the gym very consistently and then
instead of tryh harding in classes, I
made videos about studying for them and
cramming for them. And that series of
videos, which it was about four videos
about like studying 1 hour for a midterm
or a final, they got me around 30
million views across Tik Tok and
Instagram, and they made me like $10,000
from Tik Tok's creativity program. I
also think if you do see a path for
yourself, a career path that isn't
traditional, you don't have to complete
all four years of college. I would have
graduated in May of 2025. And in those
four years, I had already hit 100K a
month with a social media business. I
think I hit like 300,000 followers on
Instagram, over a million followers
across all my accounts on TikTok. And if
I just waited until college was over, I
frankly know a lot of people who like
did that. And now there's this feeling
of being behind and too late because
everybody who actually is serious about
chasing their goals, serious about
becoming a content creator, serious
about social media, they were dialed in
on that [ __ ] early on. They started that
[ __ ] while they were in freshman year,
sophomore year of college. And by the
time they actually left, because they
were actually focused on making it work,
actually focused on making it a career
while they were in college. By the time
they left college, they already made it
career. So now it's either you're 21
years old. Now that I'm finally done
with college, I can finally start
chasing my dreams or you've already made
your dream somewhat successful or you
have insane amounts of momentum towards
it. And I I just don't want you to have
that harrowing realization at the end of
the four years that like, damn, I wish I
just simply started a little bit sooner
on these dreams because nothing
fundamentally changes about you being
able to chase your goals once you leave
college. If anything, there's more
pressure because now you have to think
about financially supporting yourself.
You have to think about financially
supporting a future with a potential
family or even your parents are getting
older. So now if you actually even have
thoughts of like, oh [ __ ] I I might
need to like retire my parents or take
care of my parents. But if you didn't
start off on your goals a year or two in
advance from leaving college, think
about how much pressure now and burden
that you're weighing onto your
shoulders. If you have the opportunity
and you're like less than 21 years old,
pause and you have these big dreams. Do
not wait. Let's talk about pivot point
number two, which happened in January
1st of 2024 when I publicly embarrassed
myself telling everybody online that I
was going to make 100K a month and post
every single day until I hit that. And
that started this content series of
posting daily onto Instagram.
>> Okay, Google, stop.
>> Today is day one of trying to make
$100,000 a month. Currently, we are at
$0 a month. It's obvious [ __ ] 30
updated first. We just got done taking a
crap and a shower.
>> So, this was an absolutely like shitty
video. And I want to highlight here if
you are serious about social media, your
videos don't have to be good. In fact,
me, I'm just yapping. This video has
been on for like 23 minutes now. The
most important thing is that you're
showing up consistently and doing
volume. So I I want to show here with
this series that like it didn't really
go viral and that the goal of a series
on social media is not to go viral. It's
actually to keep yourself accountable to
showing up on social media so you can
build the skill set and improve. And
then as a consequence of actually
showing up authentically and
consistently. You're going to build an
audience of people who actually resonate
with the life that you are seeking to
live the goals that you are chasing and
the values you are living under. And in
that first month of January, bro, I
think I made around like $600 or $700
67. That was like pretty embarrassing.
It's like me going online, sharing these
goals publicly and posting every single
day documenting this journey when the
journey felt like it was making zero
progress. Bro, it was hella
embarrassing. I felt like I lost so much
social aura during that. But there's one
huge thing that I think I learned. And I
think I genuinely learned how to
overcome this social anxiety of like I
would post a video and then I would walk
to class and then see people who clearly
saw my videos. So, a lot of times people
might have seen like one or two of my
videos where I'm pouring my heart out,
telling my biggest insecurities, what
I'm struggling with and then I walk to
class and then somebody says, "Hey man,
I saw your video yesterday." It's like,
bro, but I think it taught me a lot
about being genuinely secure in myself
and understanding that no matter what I
put online, it's okay. A lot of these
anxieties that we have about what people
are going to judge us for and dislike us
for, maybe they're frankly true. Maybe
if you post videos talking about your
genuine self, you might be perceived as
cringe and judged by like some friends
and peers that you have. That's that's
actually very normal, but it's not going
to hurt you in an actual tangible way.
And if anything, you're going to grow so
much stronger and so much thicker skin.
And I think there's a beautiful feeling
of simply being authentic to yourself
and just putting out your life as it is,
putting out yourself with all of your
flaws and then realizing that it's
actually okay to do so. But in February
2nd of 2024, I made this random video
saying, "Is it possible to start a
business in one day?" and make our first
$1,000 off of it. That's the business
that I started that now in the past 16
months has made $800,000. That's
genuinely become my passion, my purpose
in life. Not with this deep thought, but
simply with this spontaneity of I'm
posting every single day. I need
something to post about. Let me just
make this video about making a business
in one day. And it worked. In fact, in
that first day, I made 400 bucks from
it. But within that month of February,
it just took off because I was
documenting it every day. So, this is
like a small lesson for any of you
builders out there who are building cool
[ __ ] Post about it every single day and
opportunities and customers and interest
will just flow your way because posting
videos like this onto the internet is
free. It's freaking free, bro. All you
have to pay is this like pain of
actually making a video, putting it
together in Caput, which will probably
take like 3 hours. If you want help with
that, by the way, I released a 3hour
full course on how to actually start
content creation. You can check it out
in the first link in the description. I
started posting every single day in
January 1st of 2024. In in February 1st
of 2024, I started this random business
in one day. It actually kind of flopped,
honestly, in my opinion on day one
because my goal was to make 1K from that
business in one day. I made 400 bucks.
But then in 15 days, because I was
posting about it every single day, the
business actually hit 10K. I made
$10,000 from that new business in 15
days. All of the business came from me
just documenting it on Instagram in
daily videos. 80% of my website traffic
came from Instagram and then 20% from
Tik Tok. I didn't pay for ads. I didn't
pay for like any other exposure. Because
a lot of times too, marketing, I
genuinely think through your personal
brand is not about like this tactical,
oh, what are the features of the
product. A lot of it is just people
resonating with you as a person and you
and your values and your life. And then
as a result, they'll buy into the
mission that you have of your business.
And that's exactly what happened in 15
days of me just documenting
authentically. It wasn't this thoughtout
process of, "Ooh, I'm going to do this
marketing ploy every single day to to
grow this business." No, it was
genuinely just me like with zero thought
putting videos out there onto the
internet and as a result the algorithm
literally finding the people who
actually resonated with what I stood
for. And I kept that up until the
fateful month of May 2024. Now, last
pivot point. This is a really
interesting one, but it was actually
getting this letter. And what was
interesting about this pivot point was I
actually filmed this with my mom and I
posted this video online. I'm going to
show it to you guys.
>> The undergraduate dean's office is
withdrawing me from the Carol School of
Management. I secretly skipped my
college classes behind my parents back.
>> So, I posted this video in I think June
of 2024 after I saw this letter. What
was crazy about this was I think it was
like the first time I genuinely got like
low-key hate on the internet in like the
comment sections. It's very very
controversial, but it taught me a very
important lesson in social media. Hate
is not that deep and people will not
understand the extent of your actual
life. So don't do everything in your
power to just please random strangers on
the internet that you're afraid are
going to judge you for the [ __ ] that you
post on the internet. Bro, they don't
know who you actually are. So why are
you letting their thoughts and their
judgments dictate how you're going to
actually live your life? Especially if
you want to do this. Like if you are
still watching at this point, you
actually want to do this social media
thing. It's because my story resonates
with you. Follow that intuition and
don't look back. If there's one lesson I
want you to take away from this entire
long Japanese story that I'm telling you
right now, dreams are not made by just
confining yourself to whatever social
norms are comfortable to stay within
your your dreams and your most authentic
version of your life. Your best version
of your life. Your best version of
yourself is not going to be built by
just watching on the sidelines and
judging other people's actions because
they look cringe while they're actually
chasing their dreams. It's possible to
chase your dreams. It's possible to make
the most out of college. It's possible
to actually pursue an unconventional
path in college and still actually live
like a happy, decent college experience
and for your life to not fall apart by
chasing these dreams. I grew up watching
a lot of these like YouTubers talk about
how they dropped out and chased their
dreams. And I always thought that was
some stupid pipe dream for the lucky
people. It's really weird when you
experience it yourself and you realize
anything is [ __ ] possible. And
everything that you used to put on this
pedestal behind this screen, cuz you're
watching me literally on a screen right
now. Everything you used to pit to luck
whenever you saw these kind of creators
and influencers talk about chasing your
dreams. And it's not some corny [ __ ]
where the person talking to you across
the screen is just some lucky byproduct
of survivorship bias where now they can
tell you all these motivational quotes
when in reality they got luck. And the
reason why I can tell you it's not luck
is because I literally have a community
of over 500 people pursuing the same
exact dream on social media. Literally
yesterday, I saw a video, a 15-year-old
who went from 100 to 10,000 followers in
just 10 days in this program.
>> I was a socially anxious 15-year-old
that went from 100 to 10,000 followers
in just 10 days. And I genuinely
wouldn't be able to do it without Mino's
Content Academy. Ever since 8 years old
making Lego stop motion with my mom's
iPad, I've always loved sharing stories
that can impact and inspire other
people. Yet, there's always this fear of
failing, of embarrassing myself, and not
knowing what to do. For years, this fear
stopped me from actually posting stuff
online. Before I joined the Conor
Academy, I was feeling so stuck even
before I took the first step. For
months, I felt miserable because I knew
I didn't have the courage to do what I
knew I wanted to do. That was until
>> Bro, just [ __ ] talk to the content,
man. Just stop being a [ __ ]
>> Yeah. Yeah. By far my favorite thing in
the Conent Academy isn't the 15-hour
comprehensive course modules literally
teaching you everything about content
creation. Nor is it the free AI
literally giving you personalized viral
hooks. I'm taking a [ __ ] It's the
people. The coaches there were always
passionate to help. Sam showed me the
ropes of talking in front of a camera
like this. Justin was always there when
I needed help. Prosper literally taught
me everything I needed to know about
starting a series. And Mino was able to
show me the beauty of inspiring people
with what I create. Meanwhile, members
like Erin, Sean, Richard, and Fane
believed in me even before I believed in
myself. Everyone is rooting for you, and
I'm rooting for you, too. I'm still in
the beginning of figuring things out,
but I'm so glad you're following along
for a journey. Peace. Join Content
Academy, man. Like, come on. I even
bought the hoodie. Like, come on. And if
you want to learn more about what that's
all about, you can just check the second
link in the description to check out
what Content Academy is all about and
how we can actually serve your wildest
creator dreams and actually help them
become true by imbuing you with the
skill set of social media and content
creation and how you can use that
towards your own mission, your own
goals, your own business, your own
personal brand. So, that being said,
thank you guys for listening to me yap
about my story. Please like and
subscribe because I'm going to be
posting more of these kind of videos and
I'll catch you on the next one. Peace.