This is Richard. And 90 days ago, when
he joined my Discord community, he had
just quit his job and wanted to go allin
on content creation full-time, but he
had zero experience. But after 90 days
of grinding in our community, posting
daily, he went from no followers and
basically no videos posted to in just 90
days hitting 10,000 followers on two
accounts. And he's on track to make
$10,000 this month from UGC content. So
today we sat down with him and he broke
down exactly how he speedrun his
Instagram growth during a time where
most people say that content and UGC are
too saturated. How many months ago did
you start content creation?
>> Three. Yeah, 3 months ago.
>> I joined I joined your community
actually like a week into me creating
content and like I never How many videos
my life?
>> Um I'm like 100 videos straight now. 100
days straight of posting I think.
>> Yeah. That's awesome.
>> So, within 3 months and 100 days
straight of posting, you went from
pretty much like zero experience and
you've grown now two accounts to over
10,000 followers. One of which you've
grown to 30,000 followers in what is it
like 2 weeks or 3 weeks?
>> Well, I I started less than a month ago,
but all the growth happened in two
weeks.
>> Holy [ __ ] So 50 to 30,000 followers
within two weeks.
>> Two weeks. Yeah. And it's still And the
thing is like you know like when the
growth is like isn't tapering off like
every time I refresh the app it's like
100 at the top. And so I know I'm like
oh it's not going to be at 30K for a
while. Like even today it's already
grown like 2K.
>> Oh my gosh. Yeah. Wait. If I refresh too
right now. Yeah. Oh my gosh. I see the
view numbers going up.
>> Yeah. It's crazy. It's crazy.
Dude, that's awesome. And how much have
you made from UGC so far?
>> Um, I think in total I've probably made
like six grand so far, but my first
month of doing it was in August. And
like I wasn't putting in like any effort
really. So I think I made like a,000
that month, probably just doing like I
don't know, maybe like 3 to four hours a
week. And then last month I did, you
know, I quit my full-time job to to do
this. and probably spending like
anywhere between like 10 to 12 hours a
day for 3 weeks straight and I made 5
grand. Um, and then this month I'm on
the way to making at least 10 grand.
Like I don't know yet cuz like again
like the views haven't clicked yet. So
um I'll have a number at the end of the
month and I'll like I actually make a
video about how much I make at the end
of this month like through my personal
brand.
>> Dude, that's that's freaking crazy
hearing though that you put in like 10
to 12 hours. really shows like I don't
know many UGC creators who have put that
level of dedication and I I think it
shows why like you've been able to stand
out so quickly.
>> Yeah. I think um the reason why I say 10
12 hours is cuz I was working for three
startups and also you like doing my
personal brand and also I've I've been
trying to help um this other guy like
this like really older dude like
starting social media um and like
pitching to consumer companies. So, I'm
not actually spending like 12 hours a
day making these UGC videos. I think out
of a day, it's probably like maybe five
or six for like spread across three
different startups. But this month, I'm
taking a much different approach. And
I'm just going to focus on this one
account now since it's it's so hot right
now.
>> That makes sense. So, you were doing
three different UGC accounts last month,
>> right?
>> And posting, I guess, like once a day on
each. Yeah, I was doing um once a day
for one startup, about twice a day for
another, and then for Whisper uh Whisper
Flow, I was doing anywhere between like
three to six videos a day for them.
>> I see.
>> Yeah. Oh, so I guess real quick to take
a step back, I've noticed a lot of
people are starting to hear a lot about
UGC online and I I think there's now a
lot of stories like yours where it's
like, yo, I went from pretty much zero
experience to within like 90 days
hitting like a 5k month with UGC and
probably like scaling even up to like a
10k month probably by the end of this
month. Um, but how did you even get
started in finding out about this
opportunity and like even learning about
like how to essentially make money from
content like this?
Yeah, honestly like I think the first
time I learned about UGC was when I
joined content academy and I saw like
the the paid opportunities channel and
actually I think it was Andrew like I
think my first week Andrew um who worked
for Cluey was saying like I hit a 10K
month and I was just seeing like damn
like you can make 10 grand off of
content in a month and then I went to
his account and looked at I was like he
was just like [ __ ] posting memes and
like also like some talking heads too
but I was just thinking like dang this
like a really good opportunity. So, I
ended up joining um a startup I think
like my second month of making content.
Um and then honestly like growing my
personal brand was the biggest hack to
unlocking a lot of UGC opportunities cuz
when people see you're doing talking
heads every day and like you know
hitting like good views on certain
videos in the formats that they want,
they just like already know like oh he's
a creator like he knows how to make
videos. Um, and so I had a lot of
inbounds. Like at one point I had like
maybe like 10 to 15 companies like
startups saying like, "Oh, like come
join my startup. We'll pay you to do
UGC." So I had to be like really
selective about which ones I picked. Um,
because like I really think like UGC
comes down to pitching a product that
like you truly believe would like help
you or like someone else. Um, and so I
was like selective about joining
companies that I felt like aligned with
like what I wanted to do.
interesting. I I feel like you have a
lot of like very specific sauce on how
to like go about finding which company
like how to actually stand out with like
a specific company. I guess like real
quick for anybody who wants to
essentially get started like right now,
but they're like very lost. I've gotten
a lot of people ask me and I'm sure like
a lot of people have asked you like,
"Bro, like where do I like what do I
do?" Like um what would you give as like
uh just like yo, like I haven't posted
any videos,
>> Richard like help me, bro. like what do
I do? I want to start making money with
this. Like
>> I think honestly like you should create
an Instagram and a Tik Tok that is just
like a portfolio. Like it's not you're
not meant to it's not meant to grow.
It's not meant to go viral. It's just
supposed to be out there so that when
you pitch to brands and companies they
will already see like oh he's already
uploaded like five to 10 videos. And
then if you don't know what kind of
videos to make um just go to like really
famous UGC creator like you know
Allegarns um Clue Mags you can even copy
me if you want. Uh but just like you
know take a video right that like has
gotten millions of views and just
recreate it. Um maybe add like your own
personality into it and then have five
to 10 of those. I promise like at a
certain point people will just start
reaching out to you if you're posting
consistently enough. But even if you
aren't, like I know like every single
startup is like fiending for creators.
As long as you have some some sort of
group, as in like literally five to 10
videos up, I think most startups would
take you in as like a creator.
>> Wow. Five to 10 videos. I guess to even
double down on that question, like
>> yo, like I'm scared to to make those
first five to 10 videos. Like where how
did you get over that hump of even
starting?
um or just like making content in
general. I I guess
>> yeah,
>> I um yeah, I think that's a good
question. I think like honestly you just
have to have a really good reason for
why you're posting content. Like I see
this a lot. I think a lot of people
create content. They think like, oh, I'm
going to go viral and like I want to get
views and whatever. But I don't think
they like their their why behind why
they're creating content is very clear.
Like for me, um I wasn't very happy with
my job and like I kind of saw creating
content as an outlet at the time. And
then at one point I was just like wait I
lowkey enjoy making content more than my
actual job and I know that there's
opportunities here. So my why behind
creating content and doing UGC was it's
like a means um for me to pivot to
something else more meaningful in my
career. But also like I feel like
another big reason why I really liked
these startup UGC deals and retainer
deals is because um if you want to be
good at it, you have to like obtain a
viral sense. So, I feel like the past
month of me working these like really
long hours and making like a [ __ ] ton of
videos every day has really honed in my
viral sense where I can look at videos
now and I can instantly tell you why
like this will perform well, this won't
perform well and also like understand
what videos I can steal for my own
content and whatnot.
>> I see. I I I guess quick question there
like when you say you had like a really
strong why
or I guess could you describe your
situation when you were first starting
content?
>> Yeah, 100%. Um so I've never created
content uh before like like I think was
it June of this year? June like at the
end of June was the first time I ever
created video and like post on the
internet. Um, and like the month before
that, I became friends with one of my
friend's dad who was doing e-commerce
and he's selling these like uh coasters
and golf bag tags and I was just trying
to help him market because he's like
really old and doesn't understand social
media. Um, at a certain point like we
had like you know done his website and
like reoptimize everything. I realized
that like the only way to get him more
traffic at that point was either to run
ads or to get into marketing like by
just creating short form. And so I was
like well running ads costs a lot of
money. so I can just make videos. So I
started growing a personal brand because
I was like um the fastest way to like
know what to do is just by like
experimenting and trying and learning.
Um and so through that I was able to I
guess I guess that's my why. It's like I
wanted to learn how to make good content
so I could help market but then it also
expanded to more other reasons down the
road for me.
>> I see. Were you in like marketing before
content? No, I've literally never done
marketing before in my life. I was um
you know, I studied computer science at
Berkeley for the past four years and
then I was a software engineer for a
year um before like I decided to just
get into it. I don't know like it's it's
really random. I would like I don't
really have a good reason for why it
happened, but it just happened one day
and then I've kind of gone down this
road now.
>> Was there a reason why you want to get
out of like software engineering
specifically?
>> Yeah, 100%. I think um like going to
college, I didn't have a very clear
reason behind like what major I picked.
So, I just kind of picked one that I
knew would probably pay dividends in the
future. And like, you know, I graduated
and I was making six figures working a
software engineering job in New York
City. Um
>> but like like a a few months in, I just
realized like, you know, I don't really
enjoy this job. And then I thought, oh,
maybe like if I get like a higher
company or like more prestige or like a
better pay, like it'll work out. Um, but
honestly, the more I thought about it,
the more I just realized like I just
don't think I was made to be a software
engineer. Like it doesn't really play to
my strengths. I'm a very like I feel
like I'm a pretty social person. I like
u a lot of other things besides coding.
In fact, like I I would get like really
nervous having to code a lot of stuff
cuz I just realized like it didn't I
didn't have this drive to want to be the
best at it. And so I just kind of
realized like, oh, I need to I need to
do something else that like I really
that will actually consume me and will
actually make me motivated to try every
single day.
M what would you say your goals are now
after having like 3 months under your
belt starting to make pretty much like a
full-time income now from content?
>> Yeah. Um that's a good question. I think
I don't know. It's I feel like making
money is somehow somewhat like not the
priority for me right now. Like I think
I'm really prioritizing like learning.
Um and part of that is through you know
like growing my personal brand. other
part of it is, you know, learning how to
make good UGC content. And then the
third aspect, like this is like the one
I'm most excited to work on is uh
marketing for this guy that um you know,
like kind of motivated me to start
creating content in the first place cuz
I moved to Austin cuz that's where he
lived because I wanted to work with him
and like um helped scale his e-commerce
business cuz I just I just thought it
was really cool and I realized like you
can really do anything you want as long
as you're just like making some money.
So once I hit um I guess like for people
who are watching this and don't know, I'
I've set a goal to hit $20,000 a month
through making UGC by the end of this
year. Uh and once I've hit that goal, I
think I'm probably going to scale back
the amount of time I spend on trying to
make money through UGC and spend more
time like trying to scale his brand and
like figuring out how I can kind of do
that cuz like I it just sounds really
interesting to me and I think like it
it's another really great way for me to
learn. Um, and eventually down the road,
like the reason I'm doing all this is
because I think I think marketing is
really important and especially like the
content creation business is going to
double in the next five years. So, I
think like learning the skill now will
probably serve me pretty well if I ever
want to start a company or uh whatnot.
But also, I've started to realize like
there's even more opportunities since I
started creating content. Like um I've
been offered a CMO position for a
startup that paid six figures in like my
second month of creating content. Um,
and then now like, you know, after, you
know, doing really well with this UGC
company, I'm pretty sure like I could
get a lot of growth positions at
different startups if I wanted to. Uh,
so I think the doors are kind of open
for me to do a lot of different things
now. And I'm honestly not really even
sure where my life will be a year from
now, but um, at least for like the
foreseeable future, I will just be
trying to scale this guy's e-commerce
business.
>> Dude, that's awesome, bro. it it's like
you're suffering from success at how
many opportunities have opened up.
>> Yeah, that's that's one way to put it.
Yeah,
>> that's great. Did any part of you
imagine this was going to happen like as
quickly as it did or like like I guess
as explosively as it did?
>> Honestly, not really. And the reason I
say that is cuz when I started creating
content, I actually like um wrote on a
sheet of paper like by January 1st,
2026, my goals are to have I think it's
5,000 followers was number one. And
number two is to make $3,000 a month
from content. And like going from that
in January, like I hit that goal last
month already. Like I've already
exceeded those goals. And so now like I
don't know it's I I don't think I I
definitely did not think I was going to
be this successful but I also did not
think like I was going to be a failure
doing this. But it was hard to predict
like I guess it's hard it's always hard
to predict like when are you going to
become successful or when you're going
to like blow up overnight.
That's true. I I feel like the most
important thing that you did right is
that you were just showing up daily and
like just putting in the reps
consistently. And I feel like over time
it's like it might happen 30 days in, it
could happen like 180 days in, but like
you put in the daily work anyways.
Yeah, definitely. I think the like the
the first two weeks when I moved to
Austin, like after quitting my job and
you know like no money was coming in um
every day I would wake up with like a
lot of anxiety thinking like like you
know did I make the right choice
quitting my job to do content? um am I
like even able to do this for like 10
hours a day non-stop even if I didn't
see progress and for like the first two
weeks it was like mental warfare every
day cuz it was like I didn't really want
to make videos and I was scared to make
videos
>> um but I was still like showing up and
doing the work um just because I knew
like you know if you want cuz I was
anxious about you know making money and
knowing this would work out and I'm like
well the only way it is is if you like
do the work every single day. So even
though there wasn't progress for you
know two to three weeks I showed up and
then you know it's all about like taking
advantage of the opportunities and
chances you're given and I feel grateful
to say like I got an opportunity like
week three or four of me doing this and
I was able to capitalize on it. Um but
you know the first two weeks were just
like it's it was like genuinely hell
like every single morning I woke up and
it was just like I don't know if I can
do this and keep going.
>> Dang. How did you deal with that anxiety
and pressure early on?
>> My sister lives out here, so I think,
you know, I was able to see her like
every other day. Um, and that was good
to some degree cuz it's like having
family. Um, but I think the other aspect
of it is
it's honestly just having stuff that can
help you relieve the stress and then
also just like believing in your
ultimate vision. Um, and so like, you
know, my vision was just you're going to
make $20,000 a month. Like I would
hammer in my head every morning wake up
like you're going to make $20,000 a
month. I even like have a sign on like
my door. So when I wake up in the
morning, it's the first thing I see.
It's like you're going to make 20 grand
a month by the end of this year. And
then um I'm a big advocate of like the
gym. So like I feel like just like
working out for an hour every day takes
off the stress. And then it's really
just like having this belief that it'll
work out even when you're like not
seeing anything. And like it's what you
said like showing up even when like it's
hard, showing up even when you're tired.
Um and over time you get these small
wins that kind of stack into something
more monumental.
M I remember a lot of your earlier
personal brand videos were about like
how working like with your parents like
when you were younger at the restaurant
like really built a lot of discipline
like do do you think that helped a lot
in content discipline as well?
>> Yeah, definitely. I think I'm just in
general like kind of an obsessive person
where if I find something that like I
really do care about, I will spend all
of my like time just thinking about it.
Um, and I think like that it it's kind
of related to that work ethic of um,
growing up. So like when I was a kid, my
parents owned a restaurant. I would I
started helping at the restaurant like 8
years old all the way up through high
school. Um, you know, so like as like a
10-year-old working like 12 hour shift
and like senior friends outside playing.
It's like, oh, this sucks. I hate this.
So I had like a lot of motivation as a
kid to just try really hard in school so
I could get out of that situation. But I
think it's also translated to other
aspects of my life now where if I see
something like if I see a goal that's
worth chasing, I'm willing to like put
in a lot of time and effort to get
there.
[Music]
>> That's awesome, dude. Like does any part
of you want to start like a company? Cuz
I feel like the skill sets now that
you've built of like you have the CS
background and now you're building the
growth and marketing part like
>> Yeah, it's a good question. I actually
um this might be a controversial take,
but I really hate startups. Like I hate
like the the whole like people around
them where they're like, "Oh yeah, I'm a
founder and like I'm doing this and
that." And I think part of it just stems
from my like I don't really enjoy coding
very much or like CS in general. And so
I really hate like especially in
college, I hate it when people like,
"Oh, he's a CS major." Like it it really
annoyed me. So I don't really have like
a desire to be like a startup founder, I
think. But I think I do have a desire
someday to like own a company and like
do something more entrepreneurial. Um I
think like you know seeing my parents
own a small business at a you know like
they started that when they were in
their 20s. It's kind of like made me
realize like oh like I could do the same
thing too. It doesn't need to be a
restaurant but I could be something
else.
>> Yeah, dude. Genuinely like it if you've
already built this much of a skill set
of growing startups like it's Yeah. like
you have that option now too. I feel
like it's it's like a options like the
only one. But yeah, like I would also I
don't know how much you've talked to
Gabe about this um in the academy like
but he kind of had a similar sit like
story where a year ago when he joined
the academy like he basically just like
started building this the skill set of
content posting daily and he was trying
a bunch of different things with like
the digital product space like selling
like ebooks like trying faceless pages
and then eventually he turned it into
like what he has now which is marketing
agency and he was able to like scale
that marketing agency to up to like dude
his peak month it was like high likeund
something like
>> [ __ ]
>> yeah and I feel like he could probably
give a lot of insight on like you know
like next steps to parlay that skill set
into like the highest leverage possible
opportunity.
>> Yeah, definitely. Honestly, it's I know
I should think about this a lot more,
but um like this is really only like my
first or second month doing content
full-time, so I haven't really put a lot
of thought and effort into it cuz you
know even three weeks ago I was like
thinking about like how am I going to
pay the bills? Um so it's I'm grateful
now like you know to be able to sit here
and say like yeah I have a lot of
options going forward. Um but yeah, I
think definitely need to think about it
and like talk to other people to get
advice on where to go going from here.
Yeah, I it's like at the end of the day
like you're you're doing all the right
moves and you're like you're like
crushing it. So, I'm sure you're going
to find like you know what aligns with
you the most as well. Like it's it's
it's awesome to see like whenever I see
people go from like okay like I'm
starting out this like posting daily
thing like and they actually dog through
it and then suddenly it just and then it
goes from like bro like I like I'm like
just starting out like I I don't know
like kind of unsure about this and then
boom like all the options are just
coming to you and you're like right like
>> I I don't know if you remember this but
like um at the first meetup like in New
York
Uh, I don't know if you remember this,
but I came up to you and I asked you for
advice. Like at that point, I was like I
think like 15 days into posting and I
was like, "Oh, Mino, like what do I do?"
Like I I feel like I I don't really know
uh my niche and whatnot. You're like,
"Oh, like it's all good. Just make sure
like you, you know, show keep showing
consistently and whatnot." And I think
like going from that point where I was
like so lost and confused to now like
having said like I've successfully grown
two accounts to over 10K is like it's
kind of insane, you know, like how fast
your life can really change in like span
of like a couple months.
>> Dude, that's that's fire. I I love how
the advice was so stupid. It was like,
"Yeah, man. Just post daily."
>> Yeah. No, but I was like asking you
like, oh, like what um format or niche
should I go into because like I feel
like I don't have a very clear reason
behind it right now. And you were just
saying, well, I I wish I wrote this
down, but it was like you're basically
saying like, oh, like I switched knees
so many times and you know, my format
changed a lot, but like what's important
is that like you just keep showing up
and like you know, you like keep working
at it every single day, which you know,
it sounds like sounds like you were like
pushing me like don't bother me, but
genuinely like that is the best advice.
Like if you just keep showing up and
like keep working at it, like I feel
like eventually you will figure it out.
Yeah, it's it's interesting because I
feel like here's my take on that. I feel
like a lot of times I've like tried to
overintellectualize it because it's
really fun to think about like yeah
let's like let's theory craft here like
so what do you do on a dayto-day like
you know let's like really get this like
really in-depth content strategy and I
feel like a lot of times it's actually
like it creates like this like
perfectionist like over like over input
and I've received that too a lot of
times where it's like hey man you should
do this you should do you should do this
and then suddenly I like I get more lost
rather than just like well at the end of
the day it's like just post bro like
that's like the number one But then you
think about wait but like brand like
what about branding like what like what
about the you know I want to like build
the
>> the audience and the niche and like and
it's just like and then suddenly you're
you're two weeks without posting and
you're like all right like I've just
lost all my momentum now internally and
then it turns into this like internal
slump. That's what happened to me
before. So, I try to just make sure I
don't like over like over inellectualize
it to people to the point where it's
like ah like
>> Yeah. Yeah, definitely.
>> Dude, that's that's awesome. What do you
think is one piece of advice that like
most people trying to get into UDC and
content are doing wrong?
>> Um,
that's a really good question. I think
I'll answer from the UGC side because I
feel like content is like a lot harder
to judge, but I think from UGC side,
I've even seen this with people within
like my current startup, but I think a
lot of people like so the strategy for
people who aren't aware of like how you
make viral UGC videos is you just have
to scroll on Tik Tok until you find like
million view videos and then you steal
the hook and steal the idea and like you
spin it into your own startup. And so I
think a lot of people they kind of skip
that step and they just go straight into
like making video based on idea that
they think is good. And you know
sometimes you know it'll work out but
like 99% of the time it'll fail. Um, and
then the other thing I've seen a lot is
people will steal my content and they
will never like repurpose it to
themselves and the video will just
absolutely flop because like they don't
understand fundamentally that like I saw
a different idea and I like repurposed
it into like what my vision of like a
good video was. And I feel like if you
want to get into UGC and become like
really good at it, you need to like
start thinking for yourself like why did
this video do well and like how can I
fit my personality or like my um acting
or my input into here so that it's a
twist off of that idea and not a direct
copy because copies don't work well.
Like you need to innovate on top of an
idea.
What did that distinction look like for
you between like you found the inspo
video and then you added your own
personal choice? How did you go about
that?
>> Yeah, that's actually a good question.
So, the video that went viral for me um
and it wasn't even that viral. I think
has like 150,000 views on Tik Tok right
now is um the original inspiration was
this uh this another UGC account where
this girl was like, "Oh, I caught my
merry professor on hinge and attached
the screenshot onto this rewrite." Um
and it had 6 million views. So I saw
that and I was like, "Okay, wait. This
is, you know, 6 million view video. That
means like there's the idea is there,
right?" But she just did it like in like
pasted a text on the screen and put some
music overlay over it and filmed some
B-roll. So there was no talking
involved. It was only text. So I was
like, "Okay, so this idea works. What if
I just flipped it to a talking head and
added like my own like twist to it?" So,
literally what I did was I just took the
exact same hook, like text hook that she
had, said it out loud like but like with
like an inquisitive face and then showed
um the document that I created like of a
different guy and then you know that was
it. Uh literally 12 seconds like I I
made it that day and it wasn't even a
video that was like yeah this is going
to go mega viral and like start a series
and whatnot. I was just at that point I
was just making videos to see like which
ideas were going to stick.
a day later, 100k views. And then from
there, I was like, "Okay, well, now we
know like this this series works, so I
just need to write out a plot line." And
so every day, I would write out like a
small plot line and add on to it. Um,
and I think like when I make my videos,
they're I don't really know like what my
style is, but I think like to some
extent I've really built up a
storytelling skill set. Like I feel like
um like creators who I've met have
always told me like, "Oh, like your
storytelling is really good." And like
they that's like that's always the first
question they ask me. It's like how did
you print views with a storytelling
format? So I was like I'm going to lean
into my strengths here and do like a
storytelling video with a lot of B-roll
like a lot of really quick B-roll and
then um accounts actually that I've like
studied from like UGC accounts
specifically is this guy named Side
Quest with Jason. I don't know if you
you've seen his videos. He he works for
Turbo. Um but he has this series where
it's like is it possible to get rejected
from a college with a 100% Yeah.
>> So
>> I've seen him before.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So I was looking at his
account and I was like studying his
content thinking like why did this
million view video like get you know
like why did it go so viral and he does
a really good job of like clip stitching
B-roll together along with talking head
and then you know I noticed that he he
would do like really quick text as well.
So, I literally mimicked that exact
style. Um, but like shot it from like my
perspective and like how I make content.
Um, but the format is like almost
identical. Like if you compare videos
side by side, it's like you can kind of
see like where I get inspiration from.
And then yeah, it's just it's kind of
popped off since there. Um,
yeah, I guess that's how that's how I
got my videos to go go viral.
Do you have any specific hacks for
researching and then for like hooks or
or any part of the video creation
process that you haven't really seen
people talk about?
I think honestly I think all the
information is kind of out there and
this this sounds like the worst advice
ever, but it's really just like you just
got to go out there and do it and then
like find what works for you because
like um at the beginning when I was
creating these videos, what they wanted
me to double down on was like
entertaining videos and funny memes. And
so if you go back to my UGC account,
like the first 30 videos or so are all
just memes and like entertaining videos.
Um, and like if you know your niche and
you know your format, finding
inspiration hooks are actually really
easy because all you need to do is find
million view videos that have that are
within your niche and like you think
relate to your product. So for me like
um I still do this every day where like
for an hour in the morning I will go on
Tik Tok and I will just scroll and
scroll until I find um a million view
video that's within my niche and format
which is like memes for me and then I'll
save them to a collection and then at
the end of the hour I'll look back on
the collection and think like how can I
spin this into my startup idea like how
like how can I like plug my startup
here? Um, and so I think that's really
the only advice I can give to how you
can create viral videos like ideiation
wise, but it's it sounds like really bad
advice, but it's it's genuinely you just
have to put in like an unbelievable
amount of volume because like what works
for me is not going to work for someone
else.
>> Yeah. I I feel like the the interesting
part about UGC
is I feel like it's a lot of the menial
research part like the research
component is what I'm hearing.
Interesting.
Um, do you have any hacks for like maybe
the way that you scroll or like curate
your for you page or like if you utilize
the search engines at all or is it just
like scrolling until you see it?
>> Um, for the meme format like I've gotten
it down so my for you page only outputs
study memes now and I'm just like so
selective like when I go through and
scroll like you have to be so
disciplined when you're just scrolling.
I'm sure like this has happened to you
>> where like you'll see these memes and
you're like, "Wow, these are actually so
funny." And you'll stalk the guy's
account and you're like, "Oh, wait. No,
I have to go back to scrolling memes
again."
>> Um, so I think just
>> yeah, just like a lot of disappointment
you're scrolling and understanding like
you're researching right now. You're not
like having fun. And then something I've
been trying out recently um and this
isn't really proven yet, but like I'll
write down like an idea. So like we're
trying to double down on more conversion
videos now. And so I've been trying to
figure out like what are like hooks that
I could start using for conversion video
because that's more talking head. So
another thing I've been doing right now
is just like if I have like an idea. So
like let's say um like the other day I
was thinking like something along the
lines of like a girl best friend like
how can we craft a hook around that?
I'll I'll search it up and then I'll
look at the the top performing videos in
that category and see like what hooks
are they using? Why did that perform
video perform well? What not. Um, but
honestly it's like if you can research
really well, creating videos is creating
videos is kind of the easy part. Like
researching a viral idea and like
formatting it to your startup is the
harder part.
>> Do you have any tips then to for
essentially CTAs and adding in the
startup component for UGC videos?
>> Yeah, CTA. Um,
oh that's a that's a tough question. I
feel like I'm like every day I'm still
like pondering this too.
I don't know. It's like
sometimes I've I feel like I've done it
so subtly that people don't even realize
that like I'm plugging my startup. Um,
but another thing I've been seeing a lot
of is engagement baiting where you have
like your friends comment like, "Oh,
what is that tool you're using?" And
then you just respond like, "Oh, it's
it's called Whisper Flow." Um, so that's
one way I've seen like people bring more
attention, but otherwise like yeah, I
don't know. I haven't really had a like
a I would say I've gone very viral on
top funnel and I'm trying to figure out
how I can go viral on bottom funnel cuz
I think that's really like the harder
the harder type of UTC to do.
Well, the thing is though, it's like I I
feel like it's a you you've danced the
line really well without making it feel
so much like an ad to the point where
it's like, oh, like I don't like it
kills retention, you know? Like that's
the harder part that you've solved is
that you've gotten like talking head
like with retention. Like my I've almost
thought like, huh,
how have you almost like not forgotten
to put the plug in there, you know? or
like
>> well what was your thought when you when
you saw my video like the one that you
comment on like this is a great UGC
example like what were you thinking when
you watched it?
>> I did not expect it to be UGC. So at
first I was like well this happened to
Richard. What the [ __ ] Like I'm watch
I'm I'm locked in like what what the and
then I see whisper flow. I was like, "Oh
no,
I just got caught."
And I was like, "This is [ __ ]
genius." Like, I fully did not I I was
so caught off guard by that. But that's
like I as in like I wouldn't even picked
up the Whisper Flow plug if not for the
fact that like I'm super conscious of
when I see like a product demo, you
know? So I was like I was shocked
because usually the product demos are
also very obvious though. It's like I
made a website called blah blah
blah.com. It's like okay like all right
scroll like I I'll study it but I won't
like feel like this is good. This is
good. Like I was so locked into the
video. I was like I was so retained bro.
>> Yeah. No I think for Okay. For that
series um for me I was like there's like
three different touch points I could
use. One was like text messages, one was
emails, and the other was like asking
questions at chat GBT. And I feel like
these are like everyday tasks that are
really easy. And like I was switching up
the shots a lot. Like if you if you
watch on the videos, I don't think I
repeat the same shot or angle um ever or
like if I do it's maybe like once. So
for me, like switching to the product
demo feels very natural because I've
already switched up the shot so many
times that when you see the product
demo, you're like, "Oh, this is some of
the shot that he's using.
Oh,
interesting. I I see it now. Yeah, the
shots are really well done. Like they're
constantly like high and then close up
and then like the side angle.
>> Yeah, definitely. Yeah, cuz I think I
think um you know these are all like the
micro hacks that like this is not the
reason why it goes viral, but like when
you have a good idea and like you can
execute the micro hacks, that's what
takes it from like let's say 100K to
like a million views.
>> Yeah,
I I feel like these are these do all the
fundamentals really well on top of being
a really good idea. Like the lighting is
really good, too.
>> Yeah. I know the the lighting is super
like I'm so conscious when I'm filming
these videos of what lighting I'm using.
Um like cuz like you know it's the color
theory like certain colors convey
certain meanings and whatnot. Um and
yeah it's like again like I don't want
the takeaway from this video to be like
you need to use good lighting in
multiple shot like shot types. Like
that's not what made this video go
viral. What made the video go viral is
that it's a really good idea and you I
knew how to execute the hook well and
then everything after that is kind of
like the cherry on top that makes it go
mega viral.
>> Yeah, it's I do think it's like creators
should definitely at least practice the
basics. So it's like practicing the same
shot in like basketball like a hundred
times. like it's not necessarily going
to like let's say like make you win a
game, but like when you need to pull it
out, you already have it in your in your
arsenal of moves that you can just
instantly like oh like B-roll like
you're like okay this is a storytime
video I need to represent I need a
really hooking hook like visual hook to
represent how my professor just texted
me.
And then you've already
exactly what the shot looks like that
would like really feel captivating. And
it's like the
>> like looking at the phone while like
doing the facial expression. It's like
okay.
>> And then all the like little Lego pieces
added together makes it a really
compelling video al together too.
>> Yeah. I like I also want to credit like
um there was like the phase in the
beginning when I was building my
personal brand. I think I made like 18
videos in a row, the exact same format.
I think like we talk about I'd start
super close to my face. I put the camera
down and it just transitioned to like a
[ __ ] ton of B-roll. And I think like
that two to three week span where I was
only making those videos has really
honed it in for me so that like when I
got to this I was like, "Oh, like pull
it out the bag. Like we we're ready to
go. like we already know exactly how to
do it and it doesn't take you like four
hours cuz you know when I first started
making those videos genuinely every
night it would take me like 3 to four
hours to make one of them but now it's
like it's kind of like second nature
because I put in so many reps in the
past.
>> Yeah, that that's such a great lesson
too that I I think a lot of people miss
about content is like oh like I it's not
working right now. This is useless. like
I'm I've wasted my effort here spending
5 hours making a video that didn't like
blow up. Why why shouldn't I just spend
30 minutes making a [ __ ] and just
like you know? Yeah. But you stack it's
it's all stacked learning and like I
remember Prosper was telling me this
when we were in person once when he was
starting content too like this was
before boyfriend maxing before he even
started making polish stuff. He was like
he watched me spend 12 straight hours on
a video. I was like he was literally
like saw me with the tism. I was like
bro I see the vision bro trust bro. Like
it was we were mid-con conversation. I
was like wait wait wait wait. And then
he saw me spend an hour on one B-roll
shot and he was like, "You're allowed to
do that." Like he almost felt like it
was like wrong, you know? It's like you
need permission to spend that much
effort on a video and then like once you
see like, "Oh, it's normal to spend a
good amount of effort on content because
it's like taking a risk. You know, you
spend a lot of time and it's okay even
if it doesn't work out cuz you like you
understand that it's okay." And I think
that's so important because a lot of
people are just like, well, like how do
I minmax this, you know, how do I get
maximum views for minimum effort? And I
like, yeah, that's kind of sometimes a
good like mindset so you're like more
efficient. But when you're learning a
new skill, I think it's just like do
whatever possible to to make the best
quality video and eventually you'll be
rewarded for it, but you won't see how
how it'll pan out at the beginning.
>> Yeah, I think the the prime example of
that is actually on my account. If you
scroll back to the the very beginning, I
had two videos back to back that was
like how to ri up like my professor on
LinkedIn and I I think I spent like two
hours each on each of those videos just
for them to get like 2k views. Um but
like that's like a prime example of what
you said where it's like I tried it in
the beginning and I realized like oh
this is like I can make a video like
this and it's I actually enjoyed making
it and watching it afterwards but it
didn't go viral per se. So then when the
professor series started, I was like,
"Oh, okay." Like, you know, it's the
same exact thing. You just got to remake
it in a different way now.
>> Is it is it possible to go on a date
with my professor? Is it
>> that? Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Like I think it's a good video, but it
it doesn't have viral potential, you
know? And that's like, you know, that's
like this this part that sucks. Like
sometimes you will make a video and
you'll think it's like the best video in
the world, but like it won't go viral.
like that's you just kind of would be
okay with that. I think you said it once
too in like your coaching calls where it
was like um you know at the end of the
day like we make videos for fun and it's
not because like you know like not every
video will go viral and I think for me
like when you said I was like yeah he's
so right like you know you have to make
videos with like no expectations because
like not every video is going to go
viral.
>> Yeah. And it's going to feel like a gut
punch every single day if you're like if
it hurts that much every time it flops
because it's like let's say an average
hit rate especially if you're starting
out is like one out of 30. Like you're
going to take 29 like punches to the gut
and if you can't learn to like take it
with grace then
>> like nobody's going to sit through 29
days of like feeling like [ __ ] Like
we're going to we're going to stop on
like day 16 and be like ah like this
sucks. Like it didn't work. But it's
like,
>> yeah,
>> I think that's such a good point. It's
part of it
>> 100%.
>> So, I guess last question here, and this
is a subtle plug, uh, and you you can
answer this like however you want, but
how how has the content academy helped
you like and how have you like best
utilized content academy like when
>> starting out?
>> Honestly, I feel like nowadays I don't
use content academy as much as I I used
to. Um, and it's honestly because my
first two months I was really active in
content academy. Like I went to like
basically every coaching calls. I was
doing the content reviews. I was pretty
active in the chat and like you know cuz
I was only really growing my personal
brand. Um, but I think after a certain
point I learned what format worked best
for me and I learned what video types I
like to do. And I think what content
academy does really well is really it
teaches you like from a first principles
perspective like why videos do well and
why videos do bad and then also taking
you from like not knowing how to make a
video to making your very first video
and then just that feedback loop like
going to these coaching calls. I
remember the first couple times I went I
just get my videos torn to shreds and I
would just be like be so sad after the
call being like I thought that was such
a good video like like what like they
hated it. Um, but that's kind of part of
the process. It's like you need someone
to tell you like, "Yeah, your stuff
sucks and here's how to improve it." Um,
cuz like that's that is the best advice.
Like that's the advice that you need to
hear in the beginning. Um, and kind of
just going through that that cycle we
were just talking about where it's like
you can go like your first 30 videos. I
remember like I tell this story all the
time. My first 28 videos, 27 videos
didn't even break 2K views. Like it was
like a couple hundred, maybe a thousand
sometimes. the 28th video. And I
remember like when I created the video,
I was thinking like, I really like this
video. I think it's going to be a good
one. I really hope it does well. It's
it's at like 1 million views now. Um,
but like there was a point there was
genuinely a point in the when I was
creating the first 27 videos where I
thought like maybe I'm not cut out for
this. Like maybe this isn't for me. Um,
but like every day I'd like like I'd
wake up the next morning like no, I'm
going to try one more time. I'm going to
try one more time. And then I'd say like
once you taste the success once um you
realize like low key it's like more even
more pressure after that because then
you're like now I have to recreate this
like I have to like do as well again.
But it like finally validates like all
the hard work you did. And I think yeah
content academy I I I tell this to
people all the time. You know I think
Content Academy was probably like one of
the best thousand investments I made in
my life. like it it did single-handedly
like change the course of my life and
what I thought was possible um just
because I started making content and
like you know it I think it does a
really good job of creating a community
that like holds each other accountable
and I've met a lot of really cool people
through it and you know I look forward
to being part of the community in the
future and like coming to I don't know
when the next inerson events are but
like I look forward to like coming out
to those as well. Yeah, next one it's
going to be in uh December in New York
again. So if you're back in the area,
pull up.
>> Fire. Yeah, I'll definitely I'll
probably fly out because I've been
telling my friends I got to go visit
them. So make it two birds of one stone.
>> Dude, that's awesome. I I really hear I
really appreciate hearing that, dude. I
think like that's the whole goal is like
get everybody to that first point of
like proof cuz once you get proof on
your own you don't need to necessarily
like hear it constantly that it's
possible like it's possible from other
people see that it's possible from other
people cuz now you have your own data
set but until then I think that's the
power of like a community is like
>> it's it doesn't feel real until like you
see it yourself so you kind of need to
see real examples of other people and I
think that's what you're doing Now it's
like so many like Andrew to you when you
saw holy [ __ ] this dude went from like
first month 10k like what what like
$10,000 the first month of UGC like
>> that doesn't sound real until you see
like no this guy Andrew a college
student went and did that
>> and then now like you're probably that
example to a lot of people in the
community where like wait what like
Richard just grew it from 50 followers
to 20,000 in 10 days like
>> huh and And now there's so many people
who are probably like, "Okay, like bet.
If he can do it, bro, I can, dude." And
I think that's the like that's the epic
feedback loop that happens when like
everyone else there is like so dialed
into.
>> Yeah, definitely. I also really like um
like actually shout out shout out to
Henry when I was first starting like he
used to give me so much feedback and he
had like I think he was like 20k
followers at that point. I was just
thinking like, wow, like that's kind of
crazy. Like there's people who are like
experienced like giving me feedback and
and whatnot. And like I've been doing a
bad job of this, but like every once in
a while I'll go into the content reviews
channel and I'll just like dissect
videos for like half an hour straight.
And like I think like there is like
there are a lot of people I think who
like try to give back to the community
which I think is like it's you know
that's a really good thing that the
community is active and every time I
come back like um you know I've gotten a
lot of people actually like DM me like
asking like oh can can we talk like I've
seen your videos do well and like I feel
like I'm starting to establish like I
guess the social proof now uh where like
people actually like want to hear my
thoughts and like what I have to say
about content.
>> Dude, that's awesome, bro. I I genuinely
hope like uh I I hope you know that
you're you're probably like right now
inspiring so many people to like go
after it and like keep going, dude.
>> Yeah, I really I really hope so. Um
yeah, thank you so much for that.
>> Yeah, dude. I'm excited for this to go
up on uh on YouTube and in the academy
as well. Like dude, there's like good
sauce here. I I think especially the
research component for a lot of people
doing UGC. It's like I I think it's
really I've seen it firsthand like a lot
of people view UDC with like a ah like
I'm just going to like copy the format
like you know like oh like it doesn't
work like ah you know the account's dead
like I need to warm up my account more.
>> Like I hear that all the time. It's like
oh my account's not warm enough. I'm
like no dude you just got to make more
videos. Like what are you doing?
>> My account's not warming up dude that's
so funny bro. Like I never heard about
this until UGC and I think what makes it
like a a valid excuse now is that
because people are making multiple
accounts but like
>> this was never a thing in personal
branding. Like yeah like it might take a
little bit but like that's not the
reason why the videos aren't dead for a
month straight. Like
>> yeah 100%.
>> Dude, that that's awesome. Like I guess
my final question here is to to somebody
who's like looking to start they're
they're like man like if I guess if you
talk to your former self when he was on
the cusp of of of starting or or
whenever it was most difficult honestly
and you had one piece of advice what
would you give him?
>> That's really hard. I actually um I
really recently saw this clip of Daniel
Mint actually your friend um and it's
like what's the one secret sauce to
going viral every time and he's like oh
there's no secret sauce and actually
like it's really hard and difficult but
if it was easy then everyone would be
doing it and I feel like that is what
you need to keep reminding yourself like
if you're if you keep flopping your
videos keep flopping and it's hard um
that's part of the process. And I
actually think it's like a disservice if
you if you go viral on your second or
third video because now you've like just
kind of thought like, oh, it's so easy.
Like I've already gained like 20,000
30,000 views. But like I think people
who are like able to stomach like 30,
40, 50, 60 videos straight of flops and
then get successful end up being a lot
more um like prominent, successful over
time because they understand that pain.
And so I guess the best advice I'd give
to my former self is like if it gets
hard just know that like um you know
it's it's supposed to be it's supposed
to be this way. And also like everybody
around you probably has quit at this
point. So every day that you keep going
forward is like you're beating out the
competition by like one more day. And so
like the longer you can go and the
longer you can stomach this failure the
more successful you'll actually be.
>> Quote from the great Daniel Vin. Bro,
>> I like that a lot.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. No, I I I think that's
like honestly the best piece of advice
you ever need when you're creating
content. It's like it's genuinely it's
just how long can you sustain failure
for um before like you give up cuz
content is like it's kind of like life.
Like it's infinite game. As long as you
keep trying like you can win with
content.
>> Yeah. Wow. It's And it I I know there's
going to be somebody out there being
like, man, like ah like bro like oh
brother
But it's true, dude. It's And how many
how many examples are there where you
see like like I saw this with Daniel, I
saw this with Prosper. I saw this with
myself. It's like it was always around
like 60 to 90 days of like actually
putting in effort. I think that's the
distinction too. A lot of people hear me
say, "Yo, 90 days is usually when it
takes to like really start seeing like
exponential growth in content, but
they'll like won't actually try. They'll
just be like waiting, okay, around 90
days of me just putting in five out of
10 effort every single day.
>> Oh, where where is it? It's it's
>> it's like it has to feel painful almost
because that's what makes it rare.
That's what makes success rare to
genuinely put your full 100% creative
effort and love into a video and then
see the algorithm [ __ ] slap it in the
face and be like, "Yo, this was not
good."
>> Yeah, dude. That was like the first
month of me creating content just felt
like that. It's like I would pour I'd
come home from like a workday like 9 to5
and I think from like 6:00 p.m. until
like 11:00, right? Like 4 to 5 hours
straight like scripting, ideulating,
filming the video, filming the B-roll,
editing, and all of that. And then I put
it out there like 400 views. And I'm
just like, "Oh my god." Like, "Am I
going to do this again tomorrow? Like am
I going to wake up and like put up
another stinker?" Um, but yeah, it's
like I feel like everybody everyone
who's ever made content and like has
become really successful has gone
through that phase. Like I'm so
confident. Like no one's ever like
picked up the camera and instantly like
became like million million view videos
every single day. Like I refuse to
believe that that's true.
>> Yeah. And and I actually noticed too
people who don't do that usually
struggle to pivot. And usually like the
first sign of like okay like this
content strategy I was doing earlier on
isn't working anymore. A lot of times
I'll notice like like people falling off
like after they've gotten really quick
early success too. I don't know may
maybe I'm just like hating or something
but like it's like I I feel like
pivoting also kind of exposes that where
the people who understand that actual
grilling process of starting again like
will be able to pivot better too. And I
think that's what makes like you or
somebody like Daniel like like I I have
so much faith that like whatever avenue
you take this it'll work because it's
not just a factor of like oh you got
lucky or anything like it it it was a
matter of like the character that you
built and how that like built you the
discipline to actually stick through any
kind of long period of drought.
>> Yeah, 100%.
Yeah, that is really the defining
factor. I feel like it's like just
pushing through when there's no success
and when there's no promise of success
even.
>> That's awesome, bro. I I think that's a
great way to like finish the the pod,
dude. I I really appreciate your time.