This is an in-depth tutorial on how I
grew in 128 days, 100,000 followers on
Instagram and went from making $0 from
Instagram and down bad to 10K a month
for 3 months straight all through
Instagram. Literally just through the
followers that I had built and I also
actually happened to get a girlfriend on
May 10th. That's just like an
interesting coincidence. But to prove
that it was not luck, I continued this
growth for the past I think like year
and a half since that point. Now we're
at 400k followers on Instagram and I've
also grown three Tik Tok accounts to
over 100,000 followers across three
different niches. So the principles I'm
going to teach you in this video are the
basics of audios audience building that
also help you build the fundamentals of
an actual longlasting personal brand and
also a longlasting income from social
media. If I were to just pull up like
this year the business that I talked
about, right, that I had started during
this period up until uh October 14th of
this year. So, in 10 months, we've done
around $500,000 from that business as
well. So, in January 2nd, 2024, I did
three main things to grow over the next
128 days. And I know it's going to sound
really simple, but you you just have to
hear me out. I posted at 3:00 a.m. I
posted at 3 p.m. But the main thing that
you need to do for the first 30 days is
just get used to daily posting. So, a
lot of people approach content from this
perspective of how do I make sure that I
get the highest quality and oh [ __ ]
bro. I posing for 7 days, but none of my
videos hit above like 10,000 views. Bro,
I'm flopping. Like, this is not worth
it. and you get super in your head, but
you have to realize that in the first 30
days of posting, not only are you simply
getting accustomed to the muscle of just
posting, but you also have no idea what
actually works and resonates with your
own unique life. And often times from
the people that I personally work with
and coach on this social media stuff, I
notice that it takes them around 30 days
to even find that because you might be
thinking, dude, I'm going to become a
fitness creator. But then you realize
later on that people actually really
like watching your 9-to-f5 content. And
you're not going to know that until you
literally have just market feedback of
posting for 30 days in a row. Also,
during this period of 30 days, you're
going to learn like hooks. How do you
get 50% of viewers who see your face for
the first 5 seconds to actually enjoy
watching you? And that comes from just
practicing and learning. And yes,
obviously learning these things matter.
But every single time I have ever tried
to convince somebody, wait, wait, wait,
change this word for the hook. But 90%
of the time, even if I give people like
the most 10 out of 10 hook that's going
to actually hook people in, they give up
posting after seven freaking days. So if
you are watching this video doubting
what I'm seeing about posting daily, but
you have never gone longer than a week
of daily posting. It's the equivalent of
somebody who's fat as [ __ ] who sits on
his couch all day. He's like telling his
friend, "No, man. I need to take a rest
day because uh JPG told me that it's
like optimal to take a rest day and I
need to like get, you know, like a
myionuclear
blah blah. Like, dude, in the past 30
days, you've gone to the gym once. What
are you talking about rest days for
after your first day? Like, shut up,
bro. You have to realize that 90% of the
battle of creating content is getting
over your own head and getting over
yourself. I've literally probably seen
half of my friends, right? And this is
no shade, but half of my friends have
come to me, yo, like, how do I get
started with this content thing? you
know, I'm not really sure how to go
about it. And within 3 days, within 3
days, they haven't even posted more than
one video. It's difficult. And there's a
massive psychology game behind like
actually being able to even convince
yourself to show up to do any new habit
for 30 days. But you have to understand
this is not some technical thing. It is
a purely war against your own psyche and
get over all of these doubts. Because if
you want to get to the point where you
can literally be even just making online
income, like side income, I'm talking
like 5 to 10k a month from content, you
have to learn how to make this a daily
habit while it's cringe, while people
are still judging you, while you still
feel the discomfort. But in step two, I
do think one of the easiest way to get
out of your own head about making
content is just to actually find a way
to monetize it. And I know this like
sounds like a really silly answer. It's
like, oh, like, how do I monetize it?
But the reason why I actually think you
should be looking to make money from
your content in day 30 to 60, even if
you've only ever gotten like videos
around like 1 2,000 views, you can
actually start monetizing. And there's
two ways you can monetize. There's one
that I've actually highlighted here, and
there's another one, which is starting
your own coaching business. I believe
this is like the only two ways you can
realistically monetize your following in
your first 30 to 60 days. other forms of
monetization like doing brand deals,
being like an actual big influencer that
takes a lot longer to build, but you can
do these two methods of monetizing
within the first 30 to 60 days. Now,
before I get into it, I just want to
explain why that's actually like really
crucial. The reason why it's important,
though, is because at this point, you're
probably going to feel really crazy.
You're probably going to feel really
insane that you're trying this content
thing and your friends are telling you,
"Hey, man, keep up this good influencer
work, bro. I see you trying to be an
influencer, man. Like, keep going, but
like, you know, make sure to focus on
your studies and [ __ ] bro." you're
going to feel really crazy. And the
thing that monetizing helps you do is
recognize that it's actually correlated
with the real world. When you are doing
this internet posting thing and you're
trying to do this whole content
influencer thing, part of you is
actually have these very logical doubts
of like, wait, this is actually kind of
a waste of time. Well, the best thing
that you can do to motivate yourself to
keep going is literally essentially like
turn into a job and make money from it
and start actually trying to make money
from it because once you get that first
hit of making your first $1,000 from
content, that's when it's real. That's
when you can parlay that into your first
$2,000 a month, $5,000 a month, $10,000
month, and I've seen it with my own eyes
because I run a community of over 600
creators, people going from literally
zero experience to making 5 to 10k a
month with content creation, right? I've
seen it firsthand that one of the most
exciting and gamechanging things is when
they they literally post into our
Discord wins channel, right? Like that
they made their first dollar online. And
I I'll literally show you, right? These
are people who don't even have that
crazy of a following, but have been
posting for like their first like 30ish
days. First month with UGC, made 1.1K.
Another person got paid 450 bucks off of
one UGC video last week. 1K off his
first month doing two UDC opportunities.
And UDC stands for user generated
content. It's basically making content
for a brand. So, this is opportunity
number one. And this is probably the
easiest, lowest barrier to entry that
you can realistically start with zero
followers and also like zero experience.
And the reason why is because you're
creating content for brands, not on your
account, but on their account or you're
going to make a new account for the
brand. And basically what you're going
to do is you're going to build a very
basic skill set of content creation. So
I highly recommend you at least have
like one or two videos posted before
because that's going to make it 10 times
easier for these brands to actually want
to hire you. Or you could just join our
exclusive community. We have like
opportunities in like an opportunities
channel that we send. We're literally
people who are just starting out because
these brands really trust our program
and our training that we give them. You
can just get hired immediately. But if
you want to join, you can just like go
to the first link in the description to
our exclusive community. But yeah,
basically to start UDC, you don't need
experience, but you do need to simply be
consistent though because these brands
will pay you around $500 a month even as
a complete beginner, but it's so you can
post daily, right? So, the average that
you can get paid when you're starting
out is around like $10 to $30 per video
that you post onto a brand account. But
the benefit of that is that it forces
you to be consistent if you want to like
scale to even like 500 bucks a month. It
doesn't take that long of a time. Like
I'm talking like spend like an hour a
day on these UGC videos, but it also
makes content real. And once again, the
main thing is that you don't want to
feel crazy doing that. $2,000 a month
that can pay for your rent. That makes
this [ __ ] worth it, bro. And that makes
content real. And yes, you might have
these big dreams of building a larger
audience and turning content into
eventually your full-time income. And
that's that will come with time. Right
now, you need to make this stuff feel
real. So, you get out of your own head
and these identities around content of
it being fickle and stupid. And
everybody around you is going to tell
you it's cringe and useless because they
don't understand the context of how much
people actually make from social media
out there. But once you actually start
making real money for me, that's when
you can even like tell your friends,
your your parents at the very least
like, "Yeah, I'm wasting my time with
this like content hobby thing, but I'm
making money, bro. So, like, shut up."
And the second one is coaching. Now, I'm
not going to go super in-depth with this
because I I have another video on my
channel on how I actually scaled my
coaching business, but basically, you
want to charge people around 500 bucks a
month for like your first onetoone
client. and then just post a story daily
to your own audience saying that you're
looking for a one-to-one client in one
of the niches of health, wealth, or
relationships. That's where most
coaching businesses lie. For example,
dating coaching for relationships, uh
content coaching for making money.
That's what I do. And then for health,
it's fitness coaching. Very simple.
Weight loss coaching, bodybuilding
coaching, muscle building coaching, etc.
Okay? And you can literally just work
with people onetoone. It's just a little
bit harder because you do need like at
least, you know, maybe a couple hundred
people that have seen your face online
from these videos for one of them to pay
you like 500 bucks a month, right? So,
regardless of which one you choose, it's
just about starting to make money from
it in the first 30 to 60 days so you can
make it feel real, so you don't feel as
crazy. And it goes back to this
motivation thing of like like the gym is
a very socially accepted thing, but it
would be a lot more harrowing and
isolating if you were the only person
you knew who worked out, right? If you
were trying to get into fitness, but you
knew nobody else who was into fitness.
That's like 20 times harder. That's like
50 times harder to actually become
consistent at the gym because you feel
crazy and you you feel like absurd and
you feel judged. And I know exactly what
that's like. I'm I'm an Asian-American
and like growing up like but nobody
around me was doing this stuff, right?
So, another thing I do recommend is join
like an online community. That's why I
run my own community. So, I help people
feel less alone on this journey and then
you can reach the point until you reach
the point of escape velocity where you
learn content, you build your following.
It's around 10K followers and you can
just start monetizing like full-time.
Okay. But step three, and this one's a
really interesting one that I've never
seen anybody talk about, is to set a
goal outside of content. It's literally
to turn content into a side hobby.
Because what I've noticed from a lot of
people is that when you put like an
overly high sense of importance onto
content creation and growing your
following, it can really mess with you
and it can really mess with your
motivation where suddenly your ego is
attached to this thing where it's like,
okay, I like I've met a lot of people
who are like, I'm going to make content
creation my full-time thing and I'm like
really going to go ham at it. Kind of
like the gym. It's usually like these
like people who are like pretty built,
you know, like a little bit more macho,
right? And that kind of like macho
mentality of I'm just going to brute
force my way with a lot of with like I'm
going to spend 8 hours a day on this
content stuff every single day. Well,
realistically, a video only takes you
like one to at most like 4 hours a day.
At most 4 hours, if you're putting the
most cinematic highlevel editing and
scripting level of effort, it's going to
take like at most 4 hours. But for me,
like on an average day, it takes me like
1 to two hours. So, what do you do with
the rest of the 14 hours of your day?
Well, actually invest into things like
your health, into a hobby that you
genuinely enjoy outside of it. And one
of the things that I did during my own
daily posting series is just like I made
sure to go to the gym every single day
and I was at like one of the best shapes
of my life. And that gave me the
confidence to then be like, "Okay, well,
I'm not making content about nothing. I
have something else going for me." And I
also was really focused on documenting
the journey of building this business.
That's what the content series about was
I literally made a content series called
Road to $100,000 a month. You can see
here it was in my bio filming every day
till $100,000 a month. And that gave me
also consistent inspiration for my
content. So like the main thing is if
you set a goal outside of content, it's
going to one help you feel less crazy.
Like you want to feel detached from
this. So content feels effortless and
you start to approach content from like
a state of play rather than from this
state of stress and work and you have to
show up and do it. And yes, I understand
once money is tied to it and you start
making money from it, you can't help but
start to feel that way. But if you have
something else you're working on outside
of content, maybe it's a job, maybe it's
school, but you actually care about
these things, too, where you're at least
like entertaining yourself doing them
every single day. It gives you stuff to
make content about as well. It's
literally content inspiration. Some of
my best videos are me taking an hour,
like studying for an hour to take a test
and that's gotten like 5 million views
and on Tik Tok it got like 10 million
views, right? And it's literally just so
I had something to make content about.
But it also helps you kind of detach and
recognize that, okay, no matter how bad
my videos flopped today, at the very
least, like I have a life outside of
this stuff. But imagine if you're like a
a video game player, but all you did was
play League of Legends for 12 hours a
day and then you just had like an insane
losing streak and you like demoted like
three ranks in one day, bro, you would
probably like be borderline suicidal if
that happened to you. Same with like if
you've been posting daily for seven days
in a row and all you do and think about
in a daily basis is content and your
views and then you flop for like a week
or two straight and nothing hits, bro.
You probably suicidal, bro. like, okay,
not really. But that's the level of
importance that your brain will probably
like and the level level of ego that
your brain will probably attach to
content when you're so serious about
making this a goal because you're
watching this video about how I grew
100,000 followers without being lucky.
It's like you care about this. You you
clearly do. But I want you to actually
take a step back. If you are at the
point of first 30 days of posting,
you've already started posting and you
recognize now that you can actually
start monetizing this too. I want you to
actually take a step back and detach and
not take this thing so seriously. And I
know that's really counterintuitive, but
the moment that you actually detach from
this and take it a little bit less
seriously is the moment that you're
actually going to like enjoy it more and
the moment that you're going to show up
more creatively. And this also goes down
to the psychology of creativity. Uh I've
read like multiple books on this. I
highly recommend too like pick up a book
if you really got nothing else to do. Uh
I got like three book recommendations.
One is the the war of art by Steven
Presfield. Two is The Creative Act by
Rick Rubin. And three is Atomic Habits
by James Clear. Any of these books will
give you constant inspiration. You'll
feel like you're learning and improving
as a person rather than just in this
magical internet world of influencer
follower growth clout, right? Because I
do think that can be actually kind of
soul draining when all you care about is
your follower count and a single number
defines your existence. you want to
detach your ego entirely from your brand
and from your content and start to
actually have other things in your life
that genuinely are passionate about and
that it's going to that's going to help
you be more compelling as a person
online. Like for example, I'm out here
traveling in Bali in Indonesia. And it's
given me so much more content inspoke
than when I've been just stuck in my
apartment in New York thinking I'm going
to lock in on my content. And I just
feel zero creative inspiration. And then
I kind of feel like a loser cuz I'm like
trying to be like a content creator and
make content all the time, but then I
realize it only takes me like 1 hour as
long as I have a good idea, but I don't
have any good ideas cuz I'm stuck inside
all day. So, I've been like spending a
lot of time just like at the gym and
like really focused on my gym goals for
the past week. And I've like like my
content is actually performing better
right now on Instagram, right, than one
was when I was literally back at home
and I was like, "Okay, let me let me
like try to make some like really
compelling like yapp videos, 30k views,
right?" Which is low for me. And then
when I actually got to Bali, it's like,
"Okay, well, I'm actually locking in on
just like, you know, living life." 1.6
million views, 200k views, 90K views.
This one's at like 88K. If I refresh it,
um 90K views. Yeah, there we go. It's
like growing pretty fast. So, what my my
point with showing all these numbers is
that oftent times when you just go out
and like do cool [ __ ] that gives you
some of the best content to film, right?
So, to recap this video, you got step
one, daily posting. And I know like 90%
of the viewers that watch this video,
95% of the people who are still watching
this video are probably here in daily
posting. And I guarantee like also
congratulations for making it through.
My retention graphs are not that crazy.
So I'm pretty sure only like 20% of the
people are still watching at this point.
And if you are in that 20% genuinely
good good job cuz it takes a lot to like
you know hear somebody tell you advice
that's like kind of uncomfortable. you
have to post daily, which is an
incredibly uncomfortable thing, and
still watch it and still consume that
advice because I know for a fact once I
said, "Oh, there's no like I'm not going
to tell you like one small tiny hack,
right? Despite me literally having data
on like hundreds of people that I have
personally worked with who have hit
10,000 followers. And despite knowing
that data, I guarantee people still will
hear that, let it go through one ear and
out the other because most people when
they like face discomfort, they will
just like fold. And and that's why
content is hard and that's why not a lot
of people succeed with it. It's because
it's incredibly uncomfortable. And
that's exactly why it's low-key kind of
easy. Like you don't have to get lucky.
You just have to like face your fear and
actually be one of the few people who
can actually like put yourself out there
consistently and then slowly learn
strategically how you can turn that into
an income and how you can also start
strategizing with your hooks and with
your scripting and with your shots. Yes,
that does matter. Like I'm not going to
pretend like that doesn't matter. Okay,
but most importantly, it's like you're
you're going to be in the fastest
feedback loop of improvement if you're
posting daily as well. And also, you're
going to like get into the creative
habit where your ideas are going to flow
much more consistently if you're posting
daily and then eventually detach from
that [ __ ] And I know that sounds way
easier said than done if you're actually
at the point of consistency. It's
probably one of the most addicting
things to check your views. One of the
habits that I would recommend is do not
check your views. Do not open social
media until it is time to post your next
video. I know a lot of people like to
think that scrolling on Tik Tok and
Instagram is going to help help inspire
you to make your next video, but 90% of
the time that's not actually true. If
you actually want to like make good
video ideas, scroll intentionally, set a
timer on your phone, have a notes app
next to you, and write down all the
hooks that you see that you like and you
want to implement. Write them down on a
piece of paper or on a Google doc. I do
that very regularly. If I were to
literally show you like right now,
like I have um I literally have like a
I have a list of hooks actually. Um and
I'll leave it in the first link in the
description. Usually I charge people for
this, but yeah, this is like one of the
most useful assets. It's like 255 viral
hooks that I've personally scraped that
have like gone viral for other creators
that I've watched. I literally just like
I go to this doc every day. If you don't
have anything to post, if I literally go
into the stock every single day, I think
about what my niche is. So, my niche is
self-improvement. It's being Asian. Gen
genuinely, that's like kind of my niche,
like being Asian-American and building a
business and being okay. Let me uh let
me look through uh let's see, three
steps for becoming uh three steps for
becoming an entrepreneur
when you're as a young Asian-American.
That's not the best hook. Three steps
for becoming a legit entrepreneur in
your 20s. Three steps for becoming a
legit entrepreneur in your teen in your
teens or three steps for becoming a
legitimate entrepreneur uh in college.
Boom. Those are like three hooks. Feel
free to steal them, right? And those are
videos that I would like genuinely make,
right? But yeah, all in all, I really
hope this was helpful. And if you do
feel like you do want a community of
people who are genuinely like consistent
with daily posting, I'll pull up our
Discord server here. People are posting
in there daily like saying good morning.
We got coaching calls every single week
from experts like Sam for example. He's
got like 200,000 followers on Instagram
um who are going to teach you exactly
how to make your content better, but
most importantly support you in this
journey of making content cuz it's
freaking scary, man. And when you see
people winning all the time, right,
hitting these massive views, but also
hitting smaller wins, like hitting their
first like 100,000, okay, 100,000 uh
views on Tik Tok, for example, or even
just posting their first eight videos
and getting like 2,000 views. Like this
is one of our newest members, Sam, and
he's literally just like celebrating
getting 2,000 views. And you got to
realize that's amazing. That is amazing
that he's even posted for like more than
seven days in a row. You see this here?
He's really he's he's been consistently
grinding the content. There you go.
Second art auction videos. Oh, and he's
already made 200 bucks from his latest
piece. Like boom. Right. Like right
there. People who are turning content
into their income, making it like an
actual part of their life and posting
consistently. Okay. If you want all of
that and people sharing advice, the
first link in the description will help
you join Content Academy. It's a paid
community. I will make that very clear.
It is an investment to join, but if
you're interested in also learning UDC,
getting placed with one of our partner
opportunities as a creator, right? Cuz
we have tons of brands who reach out to
us who want to work with our creators,
uh, then go to that first link in the
description and I would love to have you
inside our community. We're very
welcome. We throw out inerson events too
to make sure like everybody like gets
together. That's actually like why I'm
here in Bali. It's uh I'm at this villa
now because we just finished a retreat.
But dude, this is literally all from
content. And I know I'm kind of rambling
here, but like, bro, this is what
content has gotten me. That's a pool.
It's like the exposure is really
overdoing it. But yeah, like this is
possible from content creation. The
reason why I make these videos is to
show you what's possible and to just
like help inspire at least maybe one or
two more people out there to start
content and to change your life because
I see it firsthand in our insider
community, people changing their lives
every single day. I genuinely believe
content is one of the most incredible
professions that people can have in the
21st century because you get to build an
income doing something creative using
the highest height of creative
consciousness as a human being which I
believe is one of the most fun ways to
spend your time as a human being and you
get to impact hella lives bro like you
can put out a video and it could change
somebody's life bro one person's life
like maybe one of you is watching right
now but I guarantee like if you're
watching at this point you're probably
feeling hella inspired to actually go
make a video. So, go make that video,
bro, and go inspire somebody else.