In the past 2 years, I have absolutely
cracked the Instagram and Tik Tok
algorithm. I've grown my Instagram
account over 400,000 followers in the
past 2 years. And I now have three Tik
Tok accounts with above 100,000
followers. And today I want to show you
something I made called the viral
content playbook that amalgamates all of
the lessons that I have learned
throughout the past 4 years of creating
content across Tik Tok and Instagram.
And then I've broken it down to
specifically a checklist of what exactly
to do when you script, film, and edit
your videos so you can replicate
virality. 255 viral hooks ready to use
immediately. So, I'm more so just going
to cover exactly how to utilize this.
I've scraped all of the most viral
videos from those niches and I've
compiled it into one cheat sheet with
255 viral hooks. I also have a list of
the most viral songs that I have used
that I have not seen too many other
creators use or when I've used them,
then I've seen other creators copy and
then they've gone viral as well. And
then I also have two AI writing
assistants that I'm giving away for
free. One trained on Claude specifically
to help you write hooks and then the
other one trained on Chatbt for broader
use to help you ideulate and brainstorm
and script your videos. So that being
said, this is the viral content
playbook. So the first part is the viral
content checklist. Now in order for you
to make viral videos, this is something
that nobody else talks about with
content. It's actually a game of just
copy. And that's why I've created this
copy paste template because I've gotten
so good at copying other creators. So,
first thing you want to do is choose
your niche and format when it comes to
your videos. So, for example, a niche
can be something like tech, gaming, it
can be makeup, it could be fitness, etc.
But you need to choose one. Disregard
the [ __ ] that you've heard about
becoming the niche. Frankly, in my
opinion, every creator actually has a
niche in which people are actually going
to follow you for, especially when
you're first starting out. Because when
you're first starting out, people don't
know who you are, and they need to
actually be able to know that they can
get value directly from you. And the
best way to convey value is by having a
specific shared topic or interest that
you share with your audience member.
Makes it 10 times easier to make
content. There are four types of content
that I've seen work specifically on
Instagram. Tik Tok largely leans heavier
towards talking head. I'm not going to
lie. More vlog and cinematic style
content does a little bit worse. But I
want you to choose one of the four. And
keyword choose one. I know a lot of
people like to have this creative
freedom of choosing different formats.
But if you're actually in the business
of actually getting videos that get a
million plus views and you want to do
that as fast as possible so you can grow
your accounts and actually start growing
a career as a creator. That is my
intention with the viral content
playbook. I want you to choose just one
format because once you choose just one
format, you're going to know exactly
what direction to take your content.
It's going to be 10 times easier to
brainstorm video ideas and then learn
upon implementation and iteration. The
algorithm is going to teach you if your
video sucks. You want to use that data
and collect as much data as possible.
And the best way to do that and improve
as quickly as possible is by choosing
just one niche in one format. The next
thing I want you to do, I actually want
to take your niche and search keywords
on Tik Tok regarding your niche. So
let's say for example, I'm actually
going to open Tik Tok here. And let's
say my niche is fitness. I actually want
you to search up the word fitness on Tik
Tok, right? And then find videos within
your format. So let's say I'm trying to
do talking head videos. So I'm going to
skip this one. I'm going to skip this
one. This is the first video that I'm
actually going to even like consider
looking at and studying. Viral content
is all a game of simply copying and
studying what's working right now. So, I
want you to find videos with only above
50,000 likes. That is what I would
consider a viral video because that's
anywhere between 500,000 to a million
views.
>> No other fitness trainer on this app is
going to tell you this.
>> And now, what I want you to do after you
find is write down the hooks word for
word that you see. So, let's see here.
No other fitness trainer on this app is
going to tell you this. is going to tell
you this because it's not going to make
them any money. Now, what I want you to
do, right, and for the sake of time, I'm
not going to go through writing down
three different hooks. I'm just going to
do one, is I want you to write down like
one specific thing that you notice that
the creator did. So, it's like, why did
they use this sentence is a very good
frame that I like to ask myself. No
other fitness trainer on this app is
going to tell you this because it's not
going to make them any money. The secret
fitness influencers do not want you to
know this. And then what I want you to
do is simply write your hook using the
same framework that you see in this
hook. So let's say for example my niche
is still fitness. No other fitness
influencer on this app is going to tell
you this ruin their ability to get
sponsors. Right? I'm just going to
change it up a little bit. And that's
what you're going to notice about most
viral videos is that they're probably
really basic advice that they're just
packaged with a really interesting,
maybe a little bit controversial but
unique hook. So the best thing you can
do is just simply write down other
creators hooks and then and just write
your own spin on them. So another thing
that I like to do is oftent times I'll
study people in adjacent niches. So
let's say I'm not a fitness creator and
I am literally in like the business
space. No other make money online guru
on this app is is going to let's say
share you this because it's going to
ruin their ability to make money. And
it's a and it's literally just me
breaking down like for example a
step-by-step checklist on what makes
videos go viral. It could be me talking
about this viral video checklist. And I
can start off with the hook. No other
make money online guru on this app is
going to share you this because it's
going to ruin their ability to make
money. That's a way that you can copy
the hook. And then from there, you can
obviously script your video. Script the
rest of your video. And if you want any
more pointers on that, there's two
methods. One is to literally write down
their entire script and then write down
the structure that they're using. So a
lot of times with like talking head
videos, they're oftentimes going to be
like lists and just make your three
bullet point list as your script.
Obviously, don't copy their meat of the
video. Copy their structure and copy
their hook. Yes. But don't copy their
actual information in the video. One,
because I think that's like crossing the
line. I think that's like borderline
plagiarism. But even if I don't think
you can actually take away somebody's
like genuine information from a video
and it will like do equally as well for
you just because you're probably going
to be a watered down version of their
information. And like I am in the
business of making the most viral videos
possible, which usually requires some
sort of ingenuity from me and some
unique information from me. That's
what's going to get people from watching
the hook the first 3 seconds and then
realizing, oh, this is a load of
horseshit and I'm going to stop watching
to like, oh, this is actually really,
really valuable. So, something I do with
my YouTube titles is I literally just go
to the top creators in my niche and just
copy their YouTube titles. But I'm not
going to copy their full video because
if I copy their full video, you're just
going to be like, why are you watching
me right now? I'm going to go watch the
other guy. So, that's my little gripe on
scripting, but that's how I would
recommend going about it. And this is
the process that I want you to repeat
for all of your videos. If you can do
this, I guarantee you'll probably get
your first viral video at least above a
100,000 views, if not above a million
views, within the next like 60 days of
doing this consistently every single
day. Moving on. Filming. First thing is
I need you to have good lighting, man. I
I I don't know why it's so common for
people to like disregard having good
lighting. But you notice here how like
the background is kind of dim. I I do
have the window facing behind me, but I
have this literal like lamp that is
facing my face. It's It's like 12 in
away from my face here, allowing me to
get directly lit. So, my face can
actually show up vibrantly and contrast
from the background. Notice how well
contrasted I am from the background. But
if I just simply remove the lighting
now, suddenly the lighting is absolute
[ __ ] I'm not contrasted. I'm literally
the same color. I'm blue just like my
background. But if I add this little
color here, now it makes me completely
pop out. So, the first thing I want you
to do is get a desk light or a ring
light. And in the checklist, I literally
have my recommended ring light purchase
written down there. there. And then the
second one I want you to do is a vocal
energy warm-up. This is something I
literally did right before I started
filming. I'm not going to lie because I
was actually crying cuz I was doing like
a deep journaling session. Had like a
long conversation with my girlfriend
yesterday. That's personal information I
won't share. But [laughter] I was crying
earlier today and I was like, damn, bro.
I still got to make this video cuz I'm
kind of in a rut right now cuz I was
kind of sad. So I was like, [ __ ] I I
need to make a video. Here's how I did
it. And I actually I'm showing up with
camera energy right now. Like you
wouldn't have guessed that I was
literally crying like 30 minutes ago.
This is one of the things I learned in
acting class while I was in college. I
set as 30 second timer and I'll
literally just press play and then I'll
just force myself to laugh. [laughter]
Maybe shake out the nerves a little bit.
I'm not going to do that for the rest of
it cuz it's probably going to make you
uncomfortable. But the point is to make
yourself feel a little bit
uncomfortable. If that looks really
cringy and awkward, good. That means
you're probably stepping out of your
comfort zone a little bit. And if you
can do that, your nervous system is
quite literally going to calm down
because you probably have a lot of
nerves when you talk in front of the
camera. It's very normal. We're
literally biologically programmed not to
find this normal. We're talking to a
metal box. We're supposed to talk to
human beings. So, another thing I want
you to do is like pretend you actually
have a person that you're talking to
that is the camera. Cuz the easier they
can do that, the more comfortable you'll
feel because you're all everyone is
inherently used to talking to people.
That's really the frame that I have in
my mind. And I did a little vocal energy
warm-up to get myself out of a little
sad bummy state. And here we are. We're
filming, bro. Okay. Next one is editing.
And I recommend getting Cap Cut Pro.
It's like eight bucks a month. Highly,
highly recommend it. It might have
increased their price honestly, but it's
one of the most worth purchases. So,
here's what I want you to do inside Cap
Cut. I want you to use the Tik Tok font
auto captions. I want to repeat this one
more time. Use the Tik Tok font auto
captions. It literally looks like this.
Click Tik Tok classic font. It says
classic in the Cap Cut app. The reason
why is because Tik Tok and Instagram are
both a game of simply mimicry. Mimicking
what's already doing well on the
platform. So, you can inject yourself
into the stream of the for you page
consciousness. And the way they can do
that is just by making your content
visually look very similar and
reminiscent of the other viral creators.
So if every other viral creator on Tik
Tok is using their classic font, then
use it too. Don't try to be creative and
use your own font cuz that's just going
to literally make your videos stick out
like a sore thumb. And unless you are
literally like Michael Jordan of content
creation with your first few videos just
being super duper epic, viral and OP and
super valuable and super interesting and
your talking is like super charismatic.
Unless you are literally like that, you
need to follow the norms of the platform
or else you are going to stick out like
a sore thumb. Because not only is your
video probably going to be kind of mid
because you're new, that's perfectly
fine, but your visuals are going to look
also like really out of whack because
you're not using the same font that
everybody else is. So I want you to use
Tik Tok's font if you're using any other
editing software. Literally download the
font file. It's a TTF file. I have the
Google Drive link literally here for
anybody to download. And then I want you
to do secondly cut out all dead space in
your video. That includes anytime you
literally pause and take a breath in a
60second take off. You don't have any
time or a 60second Instagram reel. You
don't have any time for people to wait
for you to think, to wait for you to
even breathe. I'm not even kidding. If
you were able to do that and cut out
every space in your video between your
sentences that you pause for longer than
2 seconds, 0.2 seconds. I want you to
literally see on your cap cut timeline
that there's like 0.2 seconds of dead
space. Cut that [ __ ] out. Cut it out.
Delete it. And watch it over over and
over again. Did I miss any dead space?
Did I miss any dead space? Watch your
video over at least three times and just
check for dead space. I guarantee that's
going to already double your views. The
next one I want you to do is choose a
background song from our music list. And
I have that literally here. My main
thesis behind music is one, it largely
works a lot better on Instagram res. Tik
Tok, I've found generally prefers either
close to zero audio or if there is
instrumental music in the background,
it's very slight and it's very, very
faint. Because I think Tik Tok, what it
rewards is a feeling of authenticity and
like you're an actual human being on
FaceTime with the person watching.
Meanwhile, on Instagram, I think it's a
little bit more process. it's a little
bit more produced. So, the viewers
generally seem to prefer more produced,
more well-edited content. So, within
that is using instrumental songs. But
what songs do you use? The main thing
that I want to tell you is make sure you
one match the vibe and emotion of your
song. And that's why I have these vibes
and emotions under each song. The second
thing is I don't want you to use any
songs with lyrics in it. The moment that
you put lyrics from a song into your
video and your voice is literally
fighting against the singer's voice or
the rapper's [music] voice for the
viewers's attention, what is that going
to do to a viewer? They're going to be
like, "Bro, this is this is the most
difficult video to ever watch. I'm going
to watch this." That's why on TikTok,
too, a lot of times people just don't
use music cuz it just makes the video
harder to watch. And you might think
you're making this all like really nice,
well-made video when in reality you're
probably just making the viewing
experience really difficult and adding a
lot of friction and making it annoying.
And the last thing you want to do is
create friction and annoy your viewer.
Cuz if you do that, your viewer
scrolling. Tik Tok and Instagram,
they're a game of retention. How long
you can keep your viewer retained so
they can not only watch the entirety of
the video and signal to Instagram and
Tik Tok's algorithm that the video is
good and worth watching and worth
pushing out to other people, but then
also so they can actually engage,
comment, like, share. They're not going
to do that if they leave 3 seconds in
because your video is annoying to watch.
So, another thing I want you to do when
you see your background audio inside Cap
Cuts editor, I want you to press that
like press the audio file and then I
want you to turn down the audio to
around 20%. The music audio should be
around 20% and your speaking audio
should be like 100 or even 200%. Most
music files are just generally pretty
loud. Like they've maxed out the decibel
level ups. And then lastly, I really
want to harp on this audio thing because
audio quality is really important. If I
had a bunch of background noise, little
cars moving around in the background, a
bunch of car honking sounds, you
probably wouldn't want to watch the rest
of this video right now. Like, the fact
that my audio is fine is something that
you haven't even noticed. And that's the
point. If audio sticks out like a sore
thumb, people will notice and they'll
scroll. So, one of the best things I
recommend you do is get a Dnoising app.
This is a free app called D Noiseis FX
that I use oftent times on my iPhone.
But, if you want a more premium quality
like AI, it it's pretty much the best in
the game right now. something called
Adobe Podcast and you do have to pay for
it. It's one of the best audio
enhancers. I'll literally show you. This
is the original audio.
>> This is an in-depth tutorial on how I
grew in 128.
>> It's very loud. You can kind of hear
there's background noise.
>> I went from making the zero.
>> And then if I do the enhanced audio from
Instagram and down bad to 10K a month
for 3 months straight.
>> Bro, this audio is pitch perfect. Okay,
I'm probably going to use that on my own
audio even though there's literally no
background noise in this like hotel room
right now. Okay, so that is the viral
video checklist and if you want to get
access to it, it is in the first link in
the description. Now, moving on. This is
the viral hooks list. So, if you want to
save time from doing this hook research
process, which I still highly recommend
you do. This is a game of trying to
actually hone your viral sense. That's
why I made this process for you. But if
you genuinely don't have time, you don't
want to think, I want you to use this
list. It's just 255 viral hooks. They're
very basic and they're they're very
applicable to everybody, but they still
have like the nuance of being hookie,
having a little bit controversial twist
to it. They're they're proven viral
hooks that have been used across
different niches. And I've tried them
myself. I recommend just referencing
this list every time you have creative
block. Cuz every time I have creative
block, I'm literally like, "Okay, I'm
going to choose a hook right now." And I
like point to the screen. I'm like,
"Okay, this hook right here." All right.
So, if you're young and you like blank,
let me tell you a little secret. This is
coming from somebody who also problem
like 3 years ago. So be like, yo, if you
are young and you are addicted to
vaping. I'll tell you, let me tell you a
little secret. This is coming from
somebody who also vaped. I would like go
through uh a new vape a week like 3
years ago. And now I have not vaped for
the past 2 years of my life. Here's how
I quit. So like that's an example. I've
actually never vaped before. That's not
like a hook that I would actually use,
but that's an example of a hook that I
would probably recommend using. If
you're a vape addiction creator, go use
that. Okay. Now, lastly, lastly, two AI
writing assistants that I have made
specifically to help you write better
hooks and write better scripts. It's one
thing to have this playbook that you're
probably going to read and then you're
going to forget 5 minutes from now. I'm
sorry, that's just the nature of human
attention span. It's another thing to
have this literally downloaded into your
chatbt into your discord and you can
just reference this at any point that
you feel stuck. So, first tool is called
the hooker AI and I'll just show you.
It's in our Discord server. And even
though cloud obviously has its like API
cost, any user who just joins our
Discord server for free will get three
free uses every single day. And then
premium members of our community content
academy, which is a community of like
600 plus people who are dedicated to
creating content and growing and
monetizing their personal brands from
scratch all the way to doing things like
getting 150K plus views, passing 2K
subscribers, etc. A lot of people are
starting for beginners. So if you are
interested in that, you can apply in the
second link in the description to our
exclusive community content academy. But
anyways, if you are just looking to use
this tool for free, that's fine. This is
how Hooker AI works. So if you just do
slash hook, you can now just paste in
your script. So if I were to just pick
out a script from one of my notes app,
right? So I'm just going to copy paste
this script right here and go to the
Discord server. Now what I'm going to do
is I'm just going to copy and paste this
script slash paste and then I'm just
going to prompt it. Now, what you do
need is a finished script and then
Claude alongside 255 viral hooks is
going to cook up some viral hooks for
you. And these are literally ranked
based on virality. And I've told it
specifically to try and go as viral as
possible. So, they're sometimes a little
bit out of pocket, sometimes a little
bit controversial, but I think it's a
great way to also jog some like
brainstorming for viral hooks. So,
that's Hooker AI. Tool number two is
something I just called contentbot. You
can basically combine chat GBT5 with my
best script templates for educational
videos, for storytelling videos, for
list videos and the 255 viral hooks all
combined into one knowledge base that
Chachi BT5 10 reference. So all you have
to do is literally click this button and
then it'll add it to your ChachiBT and
you have to make sure to use ChachiBT5.
So I believe if I do auto and then let's
just say I do do this uh base prompt.
Give me five hooks for a viewer
struggling to make money online as
college student. Here's exactly how I
made my first 500 bucks online as broke
college student. No fancy laptop, no
startup money. Now, GBT, I will say, is
slightly worse at writing hooks just
because it just sounds naturally less
human. I don't know what it is. Claude,
in my opinion, is like significantly
better. That's why I have hooker AI. But
I think using these two in tandem, like
something you can do on chat, literally
just talk to it. Be like, "Yo, I'm
making a video right now about my viral
video checklist. Give me the most viral
possible first three sentences of a
video."
>> Absolutely. Let's make those first three
sentences totally pop. Yo, if you want
to go from zero to viral real quick, you
need this checklist.
>> I think it's great. And I've had a lot
of people literally tell me that they
like use it every single day, a lot of
my clients. So, that being said, if you
check the first link in the description,
you can get this viral content playbook
literally for free. This is stuff that
I've genuinely some of these resources
I've genuinely charged people hundreds
of dollars for. And the reason why I am
doing this is because I I've realized
when it comes to like coaching and it
comes to helping people actually get
results with content creation, which is
what I do. I run a community. I run a
coaching program helping creators go
viral, build their audiences, and spread
their message and their purpose online,
and then eventually monetize it. Whether
it's through selling their own digital
products, whether it's getting hired and
doing UGC or brand deals, the best way
to actually help people succeed is by
giving them an interactive community
where they can ask me questions, where
they can ask each other questions
alongside a community of people who are
super active. Like literally in our
co-working cafe these days, people are
literally there every single day
chatting with each other, helping each
other out with their scripting. And we
even have a content reviews channel
where people are actively sending in
their videos and giving each other
feedback on the content. We host little
mini games as well where we give away
prizes for people who are consistent.
But the main thing I want to say is that
if you are interested in actually
speeding your growth as a creator, the
biggest thing that I can recommend is
joining a community of like-minded
people where there's experts who are
hopping on calls. We do four coaching
calls every single week with creators
who all have above 100,000 followers.
We're going to review your content,
answer any questions, and I genuinely
believe like none of this information is
going to like guarantee your success.
But I think what gives people the
highest likelihood of succeeding is
being surrounded in a community of
people who actually push each other,
keep each other accountable, and help
each other. So, if you are interested in
that, the second link in the description
is a link to apply and join Content
Academy. Mind you, it is a paid program.
It's a paid community, but I can
confidently say it's the best paid
content community and program on the
earth for helping you go viral and learn
content creation. That being said, get
your viral content playbook in the first
link in the description. Thank you guys
so much for watching and if you aren't
already, subscribe because I'm going to
keep dropping banger sauce here. And
stay tuned in my next video. I think I'm
going to be talking about monetizing and
how to monetize your content. So stay
tuned for that. Night. Peace.