So, in this video, I want to walk you
guys through exactly how I went from
50,000 to 450,000 followers on my
personal brand while being just an
average college student, balancing
college and also building my business at
the same time. And my first tip for you
is that more effort and cleaner content
doesn't get you more views. I think I
see a lot of people talking about
aesthetic Instagram hacks and how to
have like the most perfect profile. That
is not the problem. Your problem is that
you need to get more views. you don't
know how to go viral and everybody
thinks it's just luck and they want to
avoid this touchy topic of I don't I
don't want to tell people to to that
they have to go viral. You do you do
have to go viral if you want to grow and
this fancy accounting strategy is not
going to get you there. You just need
better ideas. And when you study the
best creators who actually do this
full-time, you're going to realize it's
not about how aesthetic their profile
is. If you look at my profile, it's
literally super discombobulated, too.
You just need better ideas. You need
better ideas for your videos. How do you
do that? You need to make stuff simply
that people care about and need. I think
a lot of people approach content
ideation from, oh, what am I doing
today? What's going on in my life right
now? How can I just like document that?
There's this idea that you just need to
document your life and that you can just
become the niche and talk about whatever
you want. That's not true. Honestly,
they're just feelood lies to make you
feel better about having [ __ ] content.
But I am here to tell you the absolute
truth because there is a vast difference
between a thousand view idea and a
million view idea. And it's a very
subtle difference. One is very
self-obsessed. It's very self-centric.
the ideation process that most people
do. It's me, me, me, me, me, me. What do
I care about? What do I think will be
easy and interesting to make? No, that's
not how viral content is made. You make
viral content by thinking about what
does the viewer want to know? What does
the viewer want to learn? What questions
does the viewer have in mind within your
niche? You got to ask yourself then, who
is your ideal viewer persona? Who is
this actual person? And I have a notice
I have a picture of my younger self
[clears throat] here because my video
ideas are just an embodiment of what I
wish I knew when I was younger. And then
I frame these video ideas around how
they would help my younger self get
through certain problems. And I call
this process viewer centric ideiation.
So there's two variations of a very
similar idea. Let's say you are a
college creator. One way of going about
ideas is come with me to take my exam or
come with me to do XYZ. And the problem
with that is that it doesn't make the
viewer feel like they're actually going
to get any value from your video. So
what you actually need to do then is
reframe your hook bottom up and think
about just from the viewer's perspective
what would make them most likely to be
interested and think in these extremes.
this concept. Is it possible to ace an
exam? Studying just 1 hour is literally
a very similar variation to this concept
except it's opening the possibility for
a viewer to actually get value because
I'm answering a question. But when there
is nothing for a viewer to be curious
about and there's no need or problem
being subtly solved by your video, then
why would a viewer watch until the end?
In fact, why would they watch past your
first sentence? Come with me to take my
exam. Why would I watch a stranger take
an exam? Why would I watch a stranger do
anything if I'm not going to get value
out of it? And you have to get out of
this mindset of what's comfortable for
me to film and think just in the
perspective of how do I provide the most
value possible to this person. So the
first thing I want you to do is get very
clear on your ideal viewer persona and
have a literal doc walking you through
everything that I have done to
understand my ideal viewer persona.
Because it's one thing to just say, "Oh,
it's my younger self." It's another
thing to actually list out all the
problems and desires that my younger
self actually had. This is my ideal
viewer persona. You can see how detailed
it is. It's not just, oh, I want to grow
a business. Oh, I want to like get more
in shape. Oh, I want to command more
respect from people cuz I was lowkey
like bullied a little bit in high
school. No, it's very specific. 10K a
month lead flow from Instagram alone.
This is what I wanted desperately when I
was younger. I want to have a cash
flowing lead source on autopilot. Just a
couple hours spent on tweets and videos
per day. And the better that you can
understand this actual version of
yourself or it's an actual just friend
of yours. Maybe it's a client if you run
some sort of business like a coaching
business or a consulting business. It's
your client but you have to write down
everything down to a tea down to the
numbers. And the better that you can
understand how much they respond to
certain concepts like 10K a month,
right? Is that what they care about or
do they care about 10K a month working
as little time as possible? And that's
how you can start crafting these things
like hooks in a way where your viewer
will actually respond to it. And once
you can do that, then your retention
will skyrocket past your first 3
seconds. Your skip rate on your reels
and your Tik Toks will plummet downwards
because your content is actually for
once delivering the value that you know
somebody out there, even if it's just
one person actually needs, not centered
around, oh, what do I find interesting?
I personally think that's quite
narcissistic, right? And it's very
selfish. And if you think that you
deserve views just because you're
documenting your random stuff throughout
your day with zero thought about how
it's actually helping anybody out there,
no [ __ ] Your personal brand is not
worth watching. Who is it even serving?
Why would somebody follow you? You have
to think of your personal brand almost
like a business that has to continuously
provide value because people are paying
with their time and attention. And
especially in such a competitive market
as social media when everyone else is so
dialed in, especially the bigger
creators. And when you're on the for you
page or the explore page on Tik Tok or
Instagram, your videos are being
directly compared right next to Mr.
Beast. And then right below it is
probably like another creator who's
getting a million likes on their post.
So how are you supposed to compete if
you are just carelessly, aimlessly
making videos that have zero direction
and zero value directly being provided
and zero clarity on the value that
you're actually trying to bribe. So if
you want, I literally have my ideal
viewer persona tool for free in the
first link in the description. So you
can go check that out and make your own
ideal viewer persona. So your first
action step is to make your ideal viewer
persona. I don't care if you aren't in
like a educational niche. It still
matters because if you're making vlogs,
you still have to cater to how do I
frame my vlog and my day in a way where
people will actually care. And that's
the subtle difference between let's say
a creator who gets a,000 views on their
day in the life versus my 5 to9 after my
investment banking 9 to5. There's a
subtle difference in the framing and
packaging of that hook, but it makes the
world of a difference because that
specificity is what attracts your
audience and your ideal audience that
actually resonates and relates to you.
Targeting very specific wording that
resonate with my impatient younger self.
Now, the next biggest tip is to simply
go do interesting [ __ ] And this is
something I don't see enough people
talking about too because I I think
content advice is often so heavily
sugarcoated online that if you can just
simply document your life and do it with
abundance, you're going to attract your
ideal audience. Shut up, bro. That's not
true. Look at what content actually made
the biggest YouTubers blow up and you're
going to realize that they weren't just
documenting their life. They not only
had compelling ideas, but they actually
went out and did something difficult.
That's the key because if you can do
something difficult that not many other
people would do and execute on, that's
how you build yourself a moat in your
personal brand. A very easy example and
not many people actually I think
remember this, but Mr. Beast when he
first blew up on YouTube 8 years ago
when he was first getting his first
million view video, it was actually him
saying a word like 100,000 times. He
even made a video I think counting to
100,000. And those videos were like 10
hours plus long. Nobody else on YouTube
had ever done something like this. So of
course Mr. priest who was not some
handsome jacked guy. He wasn't rich at
the time whatsoever. He didn't have any
inherent like celebrity status or a
massive amount of money to start. All he
did was do something that most people
wouldn't even dare to do, which is just
sit in front of a camera for 10 hours
and do something pretty uncomfortable.
The same goes with Ryan Tran's Penny
series. This is his biggest series that
he's ever done. One of the biggest
storytelling YouTubers on YouTube. One
of the most renowned storytelling
YouTubers. He's not just good at
storytelling and scripting. As easy and
nice as it sounds to just be able to
just sit in your room and just type away
at your laptop and suddenly appear with
a million views tomorrow, that's not
actually true. You have to go out and do
something. That's what being a creator
is. And that's what makes you worth
watching as a person, as a viewer. You
wouldn't watch me if I didn't tell you
that I literally building this following
online. And if I hadn't done that, then
why would you be here watching me talk
about content strategy? You wouldn't.
And the same goes with your own content.
Go do interesting [ __ ] I'm saying this
because I actually did this, too. So,
this was me before I actually learned
how to do interesting [ __ ] in my
content. This was literally back toback
videos and this was my first ever 1
million view lifestyle video where I was
actually documenting being a college
creator cuz I was really trying to
figure out back in 2023 when I first got
back to college. I was like, yo, how do
I actually become a lifestyle creator
where people know, like, and trust me?
For me, that's what everybody wants with
their personal brand. You can actually
scale a business. You can actually have
a loyal audience. So, I was doing all
these random ideas like a weighted
blanket review. Now, mind you, I was
still kind of interested in weighted
blankets. But notice how the demand is
absolutely tiny. Nobody wants to know
about a weighted blanket review. Why?
Because it's convenient for me. It's not
out of the way for me to get a weighted
blanket. I already have it and all I did
was review it. Now, the video that I
made right after that that went
absolutely bonkers viral. My first
million view video doing any sort of
college content was me talking about
this was the literal hook. Have you ever
wondered if you can overdose on
caffeine? Well, me too. today took 800
millig of caffeine and it was the worst
day of my life. And I actually took 800
millig of caffeine within the span of 5
minutes and I literally puked that day.
Now, am I saying you need to like go out
of the way and actually harm your body?
No. I actually went like I actually
wound up getting on the news for this on
Business Insider. Okay? And that's not
to say that means anything really
substantial. Like that didn't impact me,
my personal brand or my business. I just
thought that was cool that like I was in
a news article. Okay? But what I'm
trying to say is that cool ideas often
require you to go out of the box and do
something that you probably wouldn't
normally do. You find an idea that
people actually have demand over that
resonates with your ideal of your
persona and then you actually put some
skin in the game. That's what being a
creator is. That's what being an
influencer is. It's leading by example
and doing something that probably makes
you a little bit uncomfortable. So you
look at the most motivational
influencers, they're probably
motivational because they've done
something actually impressive. David
Gogggins runs like 12 miles every
morning. No [ __ ] He's one of the most
motivational influencers out there cuz
he does something that nobody else is
willing to do. Now, I'm not saying you
have to do that. Find what resonates
with you. For me, it's overdosing on
caffeine.
You don't have to harm yourself. And
this was the other viral series that I
was telling you about. Is it possible to
ace an exam studying just 1 hour? That
content series got 12 million views in
the best iteration of it. Then got 8
million views on another time. And then
another time I did it got like 5 million
views. So, you don't have to go out and
harm yourself, but execute on
interesting ideas. Now, this is
something that like not many people
would actually do, like actually
studying for just 1 hour. Like, I
literally went to the library. I lined
up the clock just so it would say 12,
12:00 p.m. and just so I could show the
clock going up until 1:00 p.m. and then
stopping and then leaving. I actually
did that in an exam. Okay? So, you don't
have to harm yourself physically, but I
do think you doing something that
actually pushes you to some level of
discomfort will make you an interesting
creator to watch. Especially right,
especially if you're just a normal
person right now, cuz a lot of people
will come to me, especially cuz I work
with creators in my private community
and I coach them on how to build their
own personal brands. They'll tell me,
"Yo, I don't have the credibility to
actually build a personal brand yet. I
don't want to like I want to become
eventually like an industry leader, but
I don't have the experience yet to go
and do that. Okay, yes, you can document
your life. But that being said, if
you're documenting your life, do
something interesting. Don't just stay
within your comfort zone." And this is a
harsh truth. And the reality of being a
creator is that it is a competitive
market, which means that if you aren't
going out and doing something that
actually pushes you to do something that
most people aren't doing, then of course
you're just going to look like every
other clone who likes to stay
comfortable. But you will realize,
you'll very soon realize that you just
simply doing anything slightly
uncomfortable. Maybe just going out and
like complimenting 10 strangers today,
fighting my social anxiety by
complimenting 10 strangers today. That's
probably a video idea that if you
execute well and edit well could
probably get at least 100,000 views. You
wouldn't watch somebody who doesn't do
interesting [ __ ] So why are you trying
to just stay within your comfort zone
and not do anything interesting? Okay,
that's what being a lifestyle creator
is. And if you want to build a a uh
personal brand around your life and you
and your story, go make a story around
your life. And the viral series that I
got actually got me from 50,000 to now
like $400,000 followers is a series
called Road to $100,000 a month where I
was literally a broke college student
and I was like can I grow a business
from 0 to $100,000 a month and then I
literally just I told myself I'm going
to post every single day just showcasing
whatever I'm doing until I hit that
until I'm not going to stop until I hit
that. A year later I actually did grow
my business from 0 to $100,000 uh
dollars a month, right? But that that
series had never been done before of
somebody saying, "Yo, I'm going to
document every single day until I hit
this goal, this crazy goal, especially
as just like a broke college student."
Okay, so that's what I that's what I
challenge you to do. If you actually
want to build a personal brand that has
longevity and actually stands out, think
about an interesting idea based on your
idea of your persona and then do
something that makes you slightly
uncomfortable. Because posting every
single day as a college student made me
deeply uncomfortable. I was so worried
right before I started that daily
posting challenge of what are people
going to think about me? What are my
college friends? What are these like
college acquaintances I kind of say hi
to but like don't really know. They're
probably going to judge me because I'm
talking about all my insecurities and me
trying to do this unconventional
business thing, online business thing,
and neglecting my college classes and
kind of being a student bum, right?
They're probably going to judge me for
doing all these things. And that's the
point. That's exactly what I realized
differentiated me because no other
college student was willing to document
their process of building a business
while they were actually doing it
because you lose so much aura being like
a like wannabe entrepreneur who makes
$10 a month, $1,000 a month. It looks
freaking lame and that's the point. And
I realized like if I can just eat that
[ __ ] I will probably build a a very
valuable personal brand of people who
actually know, like, and trust me. Now,
lastly, let's actually talk about how to
save time and how I was able to balance
being a student and also being a creator
and running up my online business,
right? Because that concoction of really
interesting things of me actually living
my life and having new unique
experiences and stories to tell
alongside making like daily content
helped me build my personal brand in the
last 2 years to 400,000 followers as a
22-year-old now. Right? So, the first
thing I want you to do is go to that
first link in the description and get my
cheat sheet for today's video, which is
also going to walk you through my
minimum viable video editing format.
Okay? But the the main thing I want you
to learn from this is that you need to
stop doing low ROI content tasks. So,
specifically, I see a lot of people
talking about things like, oh, what VFX
should you add into the edits of your
video? Which might overwhelm you to
think, oh, I need to learn all this
complex editing. You don't. You can edit
on Cap Cut. I have only ever edited my
videos on my phone. On my iPhone, that's
where I edit every single one of my
short form videos that get millions of
views on my iPhone in Cap Cut. Okay, so
you don't need fancy VFX. Okay, you
don't need some aesthetic background.
Once again, were these videos filmed in
an aesthetic background like this
million view video or was it filmed
literally in my bedroom with just a blue
LED light in the background? Was this
filmed with an aesthetic background or
did I literally just go to my college
campus and film a video? You have to
stop being in this frame of like, "Oh, I
need this extra thing. I need a more
expensive camera in order to go viral."
You don't. It's usually some form of
cope. And I hear this very often, like,
"Oh, I just need a more expensive
camera. Maybe I need to hire an editor."
When in reality, the bottleneck is you
and your skill set and your
understanding of what actually goes
viral. But the good thing is that's
actually learnable. So today I want to
walk you through at least what doesn't
have any impact really towards your
virality. Okay. So when I stripped down
all of a video to its just primary
components so I was able to post daily
while in college while balancing my
business. I realized that I needed to
scrap a lot of this perfectionist
mindset that I have. And this is what
came to be the minimum viable video
format which allowed me to still grow
100,000 followers in the span of around
4 months while I was in my last semester
of college. while starting my online
business and growing it from zero to 10K
a month. Okay, so the first thing is to
think of a main idea. We just talked
about that, but based on your ideal
viewers, desires, interests, and daily
pains. Now, pains I really want to
highlight because a lot of times videos
and Tik Toks and reals exist to solve
problems. And the best way to capture
somebody's attention in a very quick
manner is to highlight a relatable pain
that you share with that person. So, if
I told you that I had a cure to having
300 view jail or 500 view jail every
time you wake up and you see your video
flopped, you'd probably listen more so
if I just said, "Oh, here's how I make
my videos. Here's how I edit my videos."
That's a lot less appealing of a
packaging because it doesn't like lean
into a relatable pain that you probably
feel. So, the more visceral and
relatable of a pain that you can
actually describe in your first sentence
or the more visceral of a desire that
you can actually describe in your first
sentence, the more likely the video is
actually going to do well. The second is
to make sure to write your hook in a way
that actually uh follows a framework of
viral proven hooks. So, I actually have
a list of viral hooks and if I go to the
uh this document, I'll actually show you
linked in this document. I also have a
list of 255 viral hooks that you can
literally steal, right? And I literally
just want you to, if you're stuck at any
point on the packaging of your video,
just go to this document and just pick
one hook. Here's how to actually uh
build a business. Here's how to actually
grow a following online without getting
lucky. Use the use these three methods,
for example, or use a minimum viable
video format. So, that's an example of
me just stealing a hook right there from
this list of hooks. Okay? Okay, I do
this all the time whenever I feel stuck.
So I don't have to think for 30 minutes
on what hook I should use. You just pick
one and run with it and then try to make
it as specific and relatable as
possible. Okay, next one is to script.
And actually, if you don't have time to
script your full video, I actually want
to challenge you to just try doing three
bullet points. And if you can get used
to just simply yapping on top of just
bullet points, it's going to one help
you actually become a much more
articulate speaker. Like I am now able
to riff this entire video pretty much
without a script. Like this is the this
is the level of script that I have. This
is not a script. It's just a bunch of
pictures, right? I'm able to actually
riff off the ideas of this because I
have so much experience just going
unscripted on my videos. And if I
actually do need a script, I just write
down my hook. I write down whatever
story I want to cover. And then I write
down whatever takeaway that I have in
the video. So, for example, if I'm
talking about like me documenting my
journey of how I went from 0 to 100K a
month as a college student, then that
would probably be my hook. Like, this is
the story of how I went from 0 to 100K a
month as a college student. My personal
story would probably be something
regarding like me talking to my mom
about dropping out and having this
argument with her. And then the takeaway
would be that uh you need to take action
regardless of like whatever people are
telling you. Okay, this is like a very
simple example. I'm just thinking off
the top of my head, but my point being
that you usually want to start with a
hook obviously to capture your viewers's
attention. Then one of the best ways to
actually make a story flow is to cover
your personal story first. Don't go and
just start spitting advice the first
thing that you do in your video. That's
a very easy way to turn off your ideal
viewer because you haven't proven to
your viewer yet that you know what
you're talking about and that you can
actually resonate and help them. So
instead of giving them advice outright
at the beginning of the video, I usually
opt to give any advice that I have
towards the end. Okay? And that's kind
of the framework I'm following for this
YouTube video, too. This is like the
actual hard tangible advice on content
strategy. But you wouldn't believe me if
I didn't shower through a bunch of proof
throughout the video in the form of me
telling many stories about my experience
growing my audience. The same goes with
your videos. If you don't sell your
viewer on why you are actually the one
person to listen to and like why your
story actually can help them, then your
advice means nothing to them and they're
going to take it with a grain of salt.
They're going to instantly scroll and
get turned off if anything if you try to
give them unsolicited advice. Like
imagine some random person on the
street, cuz that's what you are to a
random viewer, comes up to you and they
tell you, "Here's why perfectionism is
killing your gains." Bro, I'm going to
be like, "Bro, what the [ __ ] are you
talking about? You're a stranger. Why
are you telling me this? like, "Stop
giving me unsolicited advice." Like, ew.
You know, and I'm probably going to be
like I'm I'm literally going to have my
guard up and be like, "What the hell is
wrong with you? Like, who is this weirdo
telling me like how I need to live my
life?" The same goes with your video. If
you haven't proved if you haven't proven
with a story that you can actually
resonate with your viewer, then they're
not going to have any buying towards
your advice. And as a result, they're
not going to take away actually any any
of the real value that you probably want
to provide to your viewer. And they're
probably also just going to like dislike
you because they're they're not going to
trust you. And trust is obviously very
low on social media just because you are
a stranger at the end of the day. Okay?
And for you to actually become known to
a person, you need to tell your story
first and give them proof. Okay? Now,
next, filming. I literally just film on
my iPhone camera. I will prop up my
phone um literally like this, right? And
then I will just start speaking to the
camera. Literally just like this. Just
like this. like I'm on a FaceTime call
and sometimes I try to be a little bit
more animated and then I don't stop the
video until it is fully finished
recording because like it allows you to
sell into a flow state while you're
filming where you actually can imagine a
real conversation with a human being
rather than just cutting off every
sentence during your script. It allows
you to actually settle into a flow and
sort of just using your natural
vocabulary because it's very hard to
actually talk to a camera. That's one of
the like most difficult things of
becoming a creator is getting used to
this. So if you can try and immerse
yourself and become present and grounded
while you are speaking to the camera by
just not like stopping the camera at any
point and just allowing yourself to be
seen by this metal box and be here with
the camera, you're going to realize, oh,
I can actually be myself. Nothing's
going to happen if I stumble over a
word. I can just [clears throat]
I can just keep talking. Okay? and
nothing's going to happen. But a lot of
times we have this anxiety of needing to
be perfect. And as a result, it's going
to make it 10 times harder to even just
get into a flow while we're speaking. So
then our video just ends up sounding
choppy because we're we we're so clearly
saying each line at a time trying to
deliver it in a very specific way and
then we watch over all the lines strung
together and it just looks really weird.
You don't want to you really want to
avoid that effect by just letting
yourself ramble the entire script. If
you mess up, that's fine. Don't hit cut.
Okay? That's also just going to save you
a little bit of time in the filming
process as well, okay? Cuz if you're
start stopping, start stopping. You're
just going to waste a ton of time. And I
I've spent literally 2 hours filming my
videos before, just the talking head for
like a 60-second reel. I've also spent
literally 3 minutes filming the the
talking portion of a reel. And usually
when I spend less time filming, I
actually do better. The video actually
does better. And I think it's because of
a spontaneous, genuine energy that I can
bring to the camera when I'm just simply
present with the person. And that's what
people are seeking at the end of the day
when they are following a person or a
personal brand is they're seeking
authentic connection with a human being.
So bring that to the camera. And the
best way to do that is not just by like
ditching a script. Like you can still
script because that helps provide you
the structure, right? But just don't hit
stop. It's one of the biggest tips that
I have. Okay. And the last one, editing.
These are just quickfire tips. If you
want more tips, I have a like more
in-depth video linked below on how you
can actually like learn how to edit like
like a pro. But these are the four
biggest tips. First one is to do this
thing called transcript based editing in
Caput. And that cuts your footage down
without needing to watch the whole
thing. You can just watch look at the
transcript and you can see every time
there's a big pause in your speech and
then Cap Cut allows you to just cut that
out.
>> Okay. The next one I want you to do is
trim out any dead space. Any points in
your video that there is more than a 0.3
second pause in between your speech.
Okay. Now, third is to rewatch your
video and determine the emotion. This is
a little bit more difficult and nuance,
but I want you to ask yourself, what
emotion am I trying to evoke in my
viewer during my video? Is it
[clears throat] intense? Is it sad? Is
it nostalgic? Is it hope? Is it corore?
Is it inspirational? Ask yourself that
and then find a song and only the
instrumental because you don't want
lyrics in your song competing with your
voice that actually matches that
emotion. And then lastly, add B-roll.
B-roll, by the way, is when just another
footage is layered on top of your
talking footage. So, right now, me
talking to the screen right now is
A-roll. And I guess you can consider the
screen share that I'm showing B-roll cuz
I'm showing it on top. It's the B the
secondary uh footage, right? Add B-roll
only to clarify your sentences or words,
not just for for visual stimulation.
This is actually a key thing, but a big
thing that you want to optimize for in
your videos is understanding and clarity
rather than just mere stimulus and
dopamine. A lot of people think that you
just need to dopamine fry your viewers
with your editing. Just quick cuts, lots
of noise, sound effects, and everything
like that. But in reality, a lot of
people just like watching slightly
calmer videos where they just actually
feel like they're watching a real human
being. So, your editing should feel
intentional only to help a viewer
understand what you're saying, not like
just so you can like dopamine fry your
viewer. Okay, so those are my three
biggest tips when it comes to actually
building your personal brand. And that's
how I was able to grow so fast. Once
again, to reiterate, the the main lesson
I want to tell you guys today is that
it's not about like what strategy that
you're employing and what aesthetic
strategy you're employing. Notice how I
didn't give you an actual posting
strategy. I told you the raw principles.
What actually gathers attention on
social media? What retains people's
attention? That is what social media is.
It's the game of viewer psychology. Are
you making things that viewers actually
want to watch? And then are you actually
making your videos in a way that keeps
them retained and actually delivers the
value and the promise that you said in
your first 3 seconds. Okay? And if you
can do that, you're actually going to
gain an audience of people who like you
and trust you and want to continuously
watch your work. Okay? And I also want
to make the key differentiation here.
It's not about your page. It's not about
like the broad aesthetic. It's about
your videos. Every single video that you
put out is a unique chance to go viral
and build your audience. And you need to
treat it like that with that level of
care that if you aren't putting that
level of effort and you don't have that
level of intentionality with your video,
don't expect it to go viral. Don't treat
it like this game of pure luck.
Understand that yes, you need to put in
a ton of reps, but you don't need to
just get lucky one day. You can really
try to put yourself in the shoes of the
viewer who's watching your videos and
then ask yourself, would I personally
want to watch this video if I were them?
And nine times out of 10, if the video
didn't do well, the answer is probably
no for some reason. Whether it's the
editing, the scripting, the hook, maybe
it's the way the video was filmed. Maybe
it's just the energy that you gave off
on camera. Genuinely, that can happen
sometimes, and that's okay. So, that's
why my last piece of advice to you, my
bonus piece of advice is just to post
daily and find a group that keeps you
accountable. Find people that will
actually keep you accountable to your
goals because content is a very lonely
process. And that's why I actually have
a private community. We have four
coaching calls every single week where I
can actually hop on calls with you live
amongst the other group members of this
community and answer your questions,
give you feedback on your content,
right? And there are people who are
winning every single day because they
are in such a supportive community. June
does just hit 400 followers, right?
Aaron hit 5K on YouTube. Gabriel hitting
5K followers on IG. One of our members,
Richard, who joined around like 60 to 90
days ago, just got a payment of $16,000
for doing UGC for a company called
Whisper Flow, and he generated 20
million views for them. He was a
beginner when he started content, and he
joined our content academy. So, if
you're interested in surrounding
yourself with a group of people who are
absolutely dialed in and getting
coaching from me alongside three other
experts of content creation every single
week, I highly recommend checking out
that third link in the description,
right, to join Content Academy. Thank
you guys so much for watching. Make sure
to subscribe. I'll catch you guys in the
next one.