Is it possible? Is it possible? Is it
possible? Is it possible? Is it possible
to ace a [music] midterm after studying
for just one hour?
>> I've posted a series of 10 videos to
Instagram with the exact same hook.
Those 10 videos alone have cumulatively
gotten 24 million views. But not just
that, they've gained me [music] 94,000
followers on Instagram. They've also
cumulatively gotten like over 30 million
views on Tik Tok. So, in this video, I'm
going to teach you the exact four steps
that I use to find this viral format so
you can find your own viral format that
you can repeatedly go viral with.
Because at the end of the day on
Instagram and on Tik Tok, about 80% of
your followers are going to come from
like 20% of your videos. And this is the
viral series that was for me. It's 10
videos that I posted onto Instagram that
got me 94,000 [music]
followers. And I'm also going to walk
you through exactly what I personally do
in my own viral videos. So you can
actually study like what I did to go
viral because I've taught many many
people as well to go viral by following
these fundamentals. And we're going to
cover exactly that in this video.
[music] Zero gatekeeping. All right.
First step in how to find your viral
format. And this is something that I
don't see any creators talking about for
some reason. Any of these content gurus,
it's to study creators outside of your
niche. Everybody says, "Oh, find the
creators who are popping in your niche."
I actually think that's kind of meh
advice. The reason why I think it's mid
advice is because if you're trying to
copy just people within your niche,
you're probably not going to innovate.
It's like in the business niche when
everybody's trying to copy Daniel Dalen
when in reality Daniel Dalen was
probably taking inspo from like Casey
Neistat or it's when everybody was
trying to copy like Alex Ramoszi in the
business niche and everybody was trying
to do Hormosi style of editing when
Hormozi style of editing was frankly
[ __ ] It's really bad. But then
everybody for some reason like monkeys
were just copying the way he was doing
content and it does not work. One of the
most goated piece of advice that I got
to study creators not in my niche. So I
am in the business and college niche or
at least I was and then I dropped out of
college. But when I was finding this
format I purposely studied this creator
Ryan Trhan, an entertainment, travel and
[music] food creator who's also very
goated at content in general and
storytelling. And I studied his videos.
I would watch them on repeat and I would
literally put out a pen and paper and
write down the exact why did he put that
shot there? Why did he put that piece of
B-roll there? Why did he put that text
caption there? Why did he zoom in there?
And then I wrote down all of his most
viral hooks. And then eventually it
joged my ideas to find [music] the is it
possible hook. Like feel free to steal
the is it possible hook. Honestly, I've
seen people literally copy the video
word for word and that's fine and they
have gotten a million plus views. Okay.
But if you want to find your own viral
format for longevity sake, I do
recommend you do this process of
understanding and training your viral
sense by studying creators outside of
your niche that are consistently pulling
a million plus views. And if you can do
that and then apply it to a niche that
they are not in, that's how you can
absolutely dominate. And I'll put this
into perspective. Imagine if you are
trying to dominate, let's say, the
smartphone market, right? which is
already obviously very saturated with
companies like Apple and then also you
got like the Androids and whatnot,
right? But let's say you're trying to
dominate the smartphone niche. Well,
you're probably not going to try and go
into like the US market where
everybody's already obviously knows of
Apple. So, you're just going to look
like an Apple clone. But what if you
were literally to go to like the random
streets of like a rural third world
country that has never seen iPhones
before? I'm not going to name specific
countries because [laughter] I don't
want to get I don't want to profile the
stereotype and then be called a racist
because people are going to be like,
"Yo, that country actually does have
iPhones." Okay, you you get my [ __ ]
point. Do not try to compete in the US
where everybody knows Apple. Instead,
what if you just created an iPhone,
right? You call it the Zone, and then
you dropped it in like a random country
that nobody's even ever heard of iPhones
before. You would print. And the same
goes with your content niche. Okay, this
is kind of a butchered analogy, but the
same goes with your content niche. If
you're trying to dominate a niche, don't
study like other creators in your niche
who are absolutely printing already. If
anything, go into other markets and then
figure out what they are doing and
dominating and then pull out pull
literally their scripts, pull their
hooks and pull their [music] concepts
and then throw them into your own niche.
Before I get into the viral script
fundamentals, something I want you to
understand [music] is that there is no
silver bullet to virality that just is
finding a viral format. Viring a viral
format is good, but I've seen a lot of
creators with really decent ideas and
really decent concepts that are super
novel, but they just don't know how to
script and their videos are inherently
like poorly made. The next two parts of
this are less about finding your viral
format and more so the fundamentals of
how to actually maximize once you find
that viral format through scripting and
editing. And if you are averaging less
than 10,000 views on your videos, please
listen the hell up. This this definitely
applies to you. I came here for the
viral sauce. So like I need to find a
viral format and the viral format is
going to save all my problems and I'm
going to get a million views tomorrow.
Like man like this is why you are stuck
man because you don't want to understand
scripting. So let's dive into it. How
does viral scripting actually work?
Okay, so the first step in your hook,
your hook needs to solve these [music]
two things. If you want to go viral, the
first thing you need to solve for in
your hook is specificity. Because
[music] inside your hook, if you're not
being specific, then a viewer is just
simply not going to be able to
understand. It's hard for a viewer to
actually have buyin into your video if
your video isn't [music] specific. And
what I mean by specific is using very
specific names, places, time frames, and
numbers. And if you can use very
specific time frames and numbers, that
can instantly 10x the viral potential of
your hook. So notice here in the viral
hooks that I have used, Ace Exam in 1
hour or make $1,000 in one day. And
you'll notice this with like the most
famous Mr. Beast titles as well. Notice
how they all have a very specific number
in them, like $1 yacht versus $1 million
yacht. The same can apply for short form
content. If you think that the most
viral YouTube creators are using very
specific numbers in their titles because
they trigger some deep psychological
association that viewers have with
numbers, why don't you apply that to
your own short film hooks? Why are you
saying, "Is it possible to ace an exam
after studying for a little bit of
time?" Just say, "Ace an exam in 1
hour." or choose a very specific time
frame. That's how important the number
is that I've literally revolved my video
idea around the number rather than vice
versa. Rather than trying to do, okay,
I'm studying and I need to cram it in
one day and I have like this vague
amount of time. How do I make a video
around that? No, it's like, well,
viewers are probably going to find it
most interesting if it's a very short
and specific amount of time. I've seen
people do, is it possible to ace my
final after studying for 12 hours? and
they'll still get like I think like
500,000 views on the video, too. So,
I've seen it work with like 12 hours. It
doesn't really matter what the time
frame is. I've also seen creators do
hooks like 593 days ago, I built this
Airbnb in the [music] woods in Virginia.
Okay, I've butchered that hook, but like
there are creators who very specifically
use time frames and a very specific
number. 500 days ago, 600 days ago. The
more that you can use these specific
numbers, the more that your viewer is
going to better visualize whatever
you're talking about in their brain. And
the better that a viewer can visualize
whatever story that you are telling and
the quicker that they can have this
mental association that instantly makes
them visualize something as you speak,
the more quickly they will be retained
on your video. And the more likely that
they're actually going to stay, boosts
your watch time, and as [music] a
result, your views go up. Now, this is
the more nuanced part of creating
[music] content, and it's the actual
body of your script. Now, this looks
pretty hefty, but basically with the
body of your script, you want to utilize
speed and specifically ruthlessly cut
out any unnecessary detail in your
script. I'll show you a very specific
example because this is actually
incredibly incredibly important. And you
can ruthlessly cut out details in your
editing process, too. A lot of times, if
I have a 60-second video, in my editing
process, after I've done my first rough
draft, it'll be like 2 minutes long. And
the goal for me is to cut out any detail
that slows down the video. And there's
details that stagnate the video and
there's details that are just completely
irrelevant. So, I want you to ruthlessly
be able to identify what are unnecessary
details that don't relate back to your
hook, right? Which involves these
specific uh numbers and time frames and
names and then a relatable painoint
[music] which is basically just a result
that somebody relates to. So, ACE exam
is obviously pretty relatable. It's a
lot of people are going through exams
and then starting a business is a lot
more relatable than scaling a business.
For example, I've literally like battle
tested this. Whenever I talk about
scaling my business, it'll probably get
like 100k views max. If I talk about
starting a business, it has the
potential to hit a million views. This
literally means a 10x in the like the
total total addressable market of my
video just because it's more relatable
because the actual percentage of people
who are in scaling mode of a business is
literally like 10x in population, right?
Versus the people who've never made a
single dollar online. Of course, there's
going to be a much higher population of
people who want to start but never have
started. Okay? It's just the nature of
[music] human beings in the body of your
script. Now, in order to make sure your
viewer doesn't get bored, you really
want to develop this skill of ruthlessly
cutting out unnecessary details. Even
though my studying video was about
studying, the studying in the video
itself only lasted on screen about
[music] 20 seconds out of the 62 video.
So, the question I want you to ask
yourself when you are revising your
script or even while you are scripting
and you're like halfway done, you're
like, "Okay, this is kind of getting
wordy. Should [music] I like make my
should I redo my video? Should I redo
the entire script?" No, just I want you
to continuously ask yourself, does this
sentence relate directly to the hook?
So, let's say my hook is ace an exam in
1 hour. I want to continuously ask
myself in this script, does it relate
directly to the hook? So, let's take a
look at this script here. This little
tidbit of a script. I finished studying,
then met with my friend for lunch. We
met and ate lunch. We ate tuna tacos at
the dining hall. We talked about what we
thought about the exam. [music] Do you
think you're going to do well? Lol. No.
I studied 1 hour. Eventually, we made a
bet. Whoever scores lower has to buy a
[music] meal. Now, it was time for the
exam. So, obviously, if you have like if
you're not directly color blind, you
you'll notice that this is directly made
in red because it's obviously
irrelevant. I met with my friend for
lunch. We met and ate lunch. Now, one of
these sentences alone isn't going to
make or break your retention. But
combining literally what? Three
irrelevant sentences. One, two, three,
[music] four irrelevant sentences. It's
going to slow down your video so much.
And this happens so often. And
especially in a 60-second short form
video, you don't have the luxury of
dillydallying on screen talking about
things that just aren't directly related
to your hook. So, I finished studying.
that is directly related because it's a
necessary detail [music] to knowing what
is happening in this video, right? But
if I ever say it again, I finished
studying, man, finishing studying feels
so good and now that I'm finished
studying, I'm going to take a break.
Like you don't have to repeat yourself
three times. Just say it once and get it
done with. Okay? And that's the
difficult part is like you might think,
"Wow, like I really want to show how
tired I was after I was finished
studying." when in reality, a viewer, if
you really really empathize and put
yourself in their shoes, probably is
just thinking, "Oh, I'm just curious to
see what the result they got on the exam
is." They're not thinking about your
video that deeply. Okay? So, I want you
to remove any biases that you have with
your own script when you are actually
scripting and revising and editing your
videos. And I want you to ask yourself,
is this actually necessary? Can I get
away with cutting it out? And rule of
thumb is if you can actually get away
with cutting it out and it still makes
sense and the video actually still makes
sense, cut it out. And I guarantee it'll
make your video feel so much faster
paced. So if it's not directly injecting
either a necessary detail or an actual
dopamine hit to your viewer, right?
Keyword dopamine hit. If it's actually
so entertaining that you have to leave
it in. If it's so funny, sure, leave it
in. But have a little bit of empathy for
your viewer and understand if this is
boring or kind of irrelevant or I just
like the detail, it's probably going to
hurt your retention. So that's why I
literally chose to cut out all of these
parts. And even this conversation, now
this is where it probably is
interesting, [music] right? For those of
you guys who have actually scripted a
video before, you might think, "Oh, but
this part's kind of interesting. A
conversation about studying. Isn't that
related to the exam? Obviously freaking
tuna tacos at the dining hall is
completely irrelevant. Obviously, cut
that out. Do you think you're going to
do well?" No. No. No. I studied 1 hour.
That's actually one of those game time
decisions where you have to think, is
this redundant? And I think it is
because let's say in this sentence,
right? I studied 1 hour. No [ __ ] The
viewer already knows that because you
said it once and then you reinforce it
with the clips of you studying. Why are
you saying it again three times [music]
now? You don't need to say it again.
Just cut it out. Okay. And do you think
you're going to do well? This part
[music] you could leave in. Okay. So,
this is one of those orange areas where
you could leave it in. it's not going to
be the biggest deal in the world because
it somewhat gives some context. But if
you just stack a bunch of these
irrelevant points like okay now you're
talking to your friend about you know
how you studied for 1 hour and then you
talk to your other friend about how oh
like what how long did you study? Oh how
long did you study? We get it bro. We
you're here to answer the question
though at the end of the day. Is it
possible to ace an exam after studying
for 1 hour? You're not answering that
question by said side tangenting and
talking to your friend about what they
think they're going to get on the exam
or how long they studied. These are side
tangents that are about like 60%
related. They're related just about this
part. They're not related to this and
they're not related to this acing and 1
hour. So, as a result, you have to make
the game time decision while you're
scripting to be able to cut out things
[music] that are completely redundant
and completely irrelevant. And this is
the nuance science of content writing
that nobody else will teach you somehow.
And I genuinely think it's it's because
it's kind of boring and and this kind of
stuff it'll likely pass through a lot of
people's ear and go out the other
because it's it's kind of hard and you
require some critical thinking and
requires you to actually look at your
script one more time before you actually
film it and ask yourself is this 100%
quality or [music] am I 70% there but
there's still like a good 30 seconds of
the script that I can cut out and I
guarantee if you don't think you can cut
out like 10 seconds from your video, you
can probably cut out 30. I I guarantee,
especially if it's not going viral yet,
eventually. This is just another one. It
it this is fluff eventually. A lot of
times I'll literally just cut out fluff
sent like fluff [music] words, right?
That saves an extra Maybe this is like
0.5 seconds [music] in the video. Is
this going to make or break your video
alone? No. 0.5 seconds of dead space or
of redundant words or fluff words.
They're not going to make or break your
script. But if you keep adding them up,
eventually 0.5 seconds like added up
multiple times turns into like 10
seconds. And 10 seconds in a 60-second
video is huge. At the end of the day,
views on social media are determined by
this thing called the retention graph.
And this is what people start at 100%.
Right? 100% of the viewers who are shown
the video are initially retained. And
the more that you can actually keep your
viewers retained like this on the graph,
you're more likely to go viral. So if
for example 50% of your videos are or
viewers are watching until the end or
even like 30 seconds in, that's an
incredible that's an insane retention
graph. In fact, if even 50% of the
people are still watching past the first
5 seconds on Instagram, that's actually
that's insane. That that's actually like
it's probably going to go viral. This
video itself, if I go back here, most of
these videos had around like a 40 49%
[music]
uh skip rate in the first 5 seconds.
Most of the time, people are still going
to scroll. That's just the nature of
social media. But if you can bump it up
even just a little bit by killing
redundant sentences by the end of the
video instead of maybe getting like 10%
retention by the end of the video like
you usually do. Maybe you've just bumped
it up 20%. [music] Because literally
look, even if your video is just a
little bit shorter, like it's already
beating your previous video's retention
by a decent percentage points [music]
because it's shorter. Let's say the
average viewer watch time is like 50
seconds on your video, which is absurd.
That's absurdly high, but let's just say
it is, right? that video is probably
getting like 20 [music] million views.
But let's say your average viewer watch
time is 50 seconds. If that is on a
2minute video, that's not that good,
right? That that's not impeccable. But
if it's 50 seconds, right? And and mind
you, this just like never happens, by
the way, but these are just arbitrary
numbers. Let's say 50 seconds on a
60-second video. Instagram sees that and
they're like, "Wow, the entire video is
[music] insanely wellm made and retains
people's attentions insanely well. I
need to push this out to all of our
viewers." And that's what they're going
to do. Lastly, in terms of scripting and
editing, I want to talk about viral
editing because scripting will get you
about 50% there, where you actually now
have a very compelling series of words
that you're saying to the camera that's
going to help your video do well. But
let's move on to editing itself. What
actually makes a video go viral in
editing? And there's two principles that
I pretty much see are universal in terms
of content. [music] The first one is
using auto captions. And my best
recommendation is to do two to three
words at a time. And I'll show an
example here of what that looks like on
screen. And my second recommendation for
my auto captions is to use this font,
Tik Tok sans, or if you're actually
finding it inside cap code or inside Tik
Tok, it's literally just called the
classic font. And the reason why I
always always tell people to use the
classic font is because Tik Tok and
Instagram viewers are so attuned to just
simply watching what is familiar.
Because once you are in this scrolling
mindset where you are in this consumer
mindset, you're you're scrolling through
your iPhone [music] and you're just
watching reals, you you're literally
there to continue consuming what is
already comfortable. You're literally in
a state of trying to feel comfortable.
That's what scrolling is. You're going
through this like kind of dopamine
emotional slot machine so you can
actually feel slightly comfortable and
probably escape your problems. That's
what people do when they are scrolling
social media. And the worst thing that
you want to do is use captions or use
like some sort of editing style that is
completely different from what people
have seen on the platform. Unless it is
literally unless you are literally like
Da Vinci of editing, do not try to beat
the norm. [music] Do not try to
distinguish yourself from the norm of
editing cuz I guarantee and I would
consider myself still in like the top 1%
of editors. And I still don't try to
break this norm because I understand how
strong the viewer biases are when it
comes to actually make like [music]
watching videos that are familiar and
watching fonts and text that are
visually familiar. And the second thing
I want you to do is cut out all dead
space. Now dead space in a video is any
time that you take a pause or [music] a
break in your words. And I'm talking if
the piece of dead space is literally
even just like 0.3 seconds. If it's over
0.3 seconds, [music] cut it out. And
you'll notice it in the timeline. You'll
notice when there's just a little break
between the words, it can literally last
as long as these breaks that I'm doing
right now. Cut those breaks out. It's
going to make your video feel so much
more snappy and choppy. And this is one
of those things that even like top
editors that I have worked with, like
people whose literal careers are in
editing, they still don't do this. So,
if you can do this as a creator, you're
already going to stand out from 90% of
videos that are made out there on the
internet just are slightly slower. And I
guarantee the most viral viral videos
will not take [music] breaks of dead
space. And the only times a creator will
actually have dead space is if they
literally have to breathe and they're
not doing any cuts in their videos,
which there are creators who make zero
cuts in their videos. But if you unless
you are the most charismatic,
entertaining, most entertaining speaker
and you are so talented at this gift,
you need to play this game of retention
and cut out the dead space. And I hate
when people and these like content hacks
and growth hacker people tell you be
yourself on camera when in reality being
yourself probably just entails being
inexperienced on camera. Do you have
theater experience? You have acting
experience, public speaking experience.
If not, you're probably not going to be
goated from the from the get-go. So, cut
out all dead space. And in your editing
process as well, hunt for these directly
irrelevant words and cut them out. cut
them out as if you are literally like a
head hunter that if you if you see any
irrelevant sentence even slightly, you
get disgusted and you have to eradicate
that [ __ ] Okay, that that's how
important these [music] two things are.
And I guarantee you just do these two
things and then you pair it with a viral
format and a decent idea, you will be
able to replicate virality. And this is
a skill set that takes time. Like I
said, I posted 10 of these videos and
yes, these are literally all 10 times
I've like used this format of the is it
possible hook. It's pretty much gone
viral every single time I've done this
style of content. That doesn't mean
that's the only videos I've ever posted.
And I specifically saved this is it
possible style of video for a challenge
video where I'm actually going out and
doing something. Like I'm not going to
say is it possible to get a hotel in
Soul, Korea and film three videos. Like
no [ __ ] it is. Of course it's possible.
Viewers not going to be curious about
that. I don't care about that idea. But
I only save it for ideas that I find
interesting. Like is it possible to
learn a back flip in 1 hour? Right?
That's my most recent iteration of this
video. Got a million views. Didn't get
that many follows though because it
didn't have any talking in it. That's a
completely other concept. Right? But
something I do want to highlight in
order to actually get to this point
where you can see this level of growth,
you need to post a ton of videos.
Because yes, that's 10 videos in a viral
series that got 94,000 follows and 24
million views. It took a ton of
consistency to get there. And I want to
highlight this by by literally showing
you my Instagram account. This is my
Instagram account sorted by the lowest
views, lowest viewed videos. [music] And
you can see there are so many videos
that have not gone viral. There are so
so so many videos that are nowhere near
as good as the is it possible series of
videos. And as I get to the top,
obviously you're going to see more of
the is it possible videos. But there are
so many videos. I it's literally an
endless endless scroll of videos. These
are all videos that I've pretty much
posted in the past 2 years. all of these
videos. I've posted around 400 videos in
the past uh 2 years. You can see there
just so many an endless scroll. And as I
get to the top, you can start seeing the
uh the is it possible series of videos.
This one, this one, this one, and this
one, right? But in order to get there,
right, this is literally 481 reels on my
account, right? So about 400 of them or
maybe like 430 to 440 of them were
posted in the last 2 years. So, I really
want to highlight that in order to get
to that skill level of being able to get
in 10 videos 94,000 followers, you need
to build up the skill set over so much
time cuz this is probably you here. This
is your uh skill level at making
content, which directly correlates with
your ability to go viral. Because
virality is not something that you just
unlock one day, you get lucky and then
you get like one lucky video hits a
million views, you get like 3,000
followers from that. Great. That's a
dopamine hit. And I know that's more
than most people have ever gotten in
their life. But just hear me out for a
second. Hear me out because if you are
actually in the business of making
content, something that you do, you will
do long-term as some form of a career,
okay? Whether it's brand deals, whether
it's building your own business, whether
it's doing like UGC, if this is
something that you are serious about,
please listen up. So, all the gooners
are gone now. Treat it like a skill set.
And skill sets are obviously built with
time and consistency. So, this is the uh
x-axis time. Now, most people never
reach the point of actually developing
the skill because this probably takes
like 3 years to get to my level of
skill. It will take you between 1 to 3
years. I've seen creators in my
community who've like learned from me
directly and then speed ran this [ __ ] in
about 1 year, right? And there's a
couple creators who have done this and
hit around like 300,000 plus followers
in the span of a year, right? There are
creators who learn this skill much
faster, but I guarantee you're not going
to learn it faster than a year. Okay? I
I promise you, you're not going to get
to like 300,000 followers faster than a
year. And I would say in order to even
make this a full-time income, you
realistically just need to hit like 50k
followers. The most important thing that
I want to highlight over 1 to 3 years is
consistency. I'm going to draw something
[music] in purple, which is your views.
Now, your views on your average views on
your videos is probably going to look
something like this right now. Looks
something like this, right? It's pretty
low. This is the difference if you were
to actually simply be consistent. And I
just realized this is a y-axis uh
variable. But let's say you're actually
starting to be consistent with your
videos. What you're going to notice is
that it's going to do this. It's going
to feel like you're plateauing, but
eventually once you start mastering the
things like making your videos concise,
actually following the viral editing
fundamentals, and then you recognize
with humility that your videos are
probably shite if they're getting less
than 10,000 views, and then slowly
building up the skill set. Eventually
over time your peaks and valleys will
become higher and higher and eventually
this will be your views graph. But this
is you if you actually stayed consistent
consistent posting and I'm talking daily
every single day. And that's the hard
part of building the skill set of
content. It's not having talent. It's
not getting lucky. It's just staying
consistent for like literally posting
consistently daily or even at least
weekly. Following some weekly cadence
for longer than like 2 weeks. I promise
you, if you can do this, you will
actually build the skill set of content
creation. But most people who want to go
viral, they want to become influencers,
they're missing one of two things.
They're either posting somewhat
consistently, but they're posting slop
where they're not actually pushing
themselves to learn viral scripting
fundamentals. They're not actually
studying outside creators [music] and
asking themselves, "What is the
difference between their content and my
content?" And they're not actually
trying to make their videos 1% better
every time they edit them. And I know
this. I've seen this because I run a
creator community of of paid members in
our Discord server who literally pay to
learn content creation and I see the
ones who improve over time and I see the
ones who literally don't. And it's a
factor of consistency, specifically
consistently posting and constantly
improving your videos 1% better every
single time. And that is the difficult
part of content creation. All of this
doesn't matter if you can't even be
consistent. If you're watching this and
you are actually serious about your
content growth, I want you to like
answer me this, right? Feel free to
comment. If you're here until this point
in the video, that means you actually
care. Let me know in the comment section
if you can actually promise me that
you're going to post consistently for
the next at least 7 days. 7 days. Give
it 7 days. And if that is so, I actually
made a 7-day guide to starting content
creation. And I'm going to link that
video in the first link in the
description. But it's basically this
video. It's a full course on how to
start your personal brand and it's
literally a six video guide. It's 3
hours long. It's going to take you the
next 7 days. If you are serious about
content creation, feel free to go watch
that next video linked in the
description. That being said, [music]
subscribe for more content like this and
let's actually blow up our creator
careers and make this a full-time thing.
[music] I be.