3 years ago, I formulated this protocol
called the ideal viewer persona, and it
helped me grow my personal brand on Tik
Tok from zero to 100,000 followers in 30
days. Now, [music] this ideal viewer
persona protocol is the process of
choosing the one person that your videos
are for and then [music] making all of
your scripts and editing decisions
around that singular viewer. This is how
I was able to create video scripts in
those 30 days that [music] were simple
but got 500,000 views plus every single
time. And so in this video, I'm going to
walk you guys through exactly how to
write your hooks and scripts of your
videos that speak to your ideal viewer
persona's soul so you can go viral as
well, but more importantly, [music]
build an audience for your personal
brand that likes you, trusts you, and
buys [music] anything that you sell. So
this is how to find your ideal viewer
persona. Your ideal viewer persona,
ideally somebody that you know. So Cle
is my friend. Cle is my best friend from
college. He was my like freshman year
roommate. Having a person that you know,
like a friend that you know, helps you
like actually imagine you're talking to
them and then write down exactly what
they want. This was a time when my
friend was actually starting content and
he was asking me like how to develop an
audience and do it in a genuine way.
Like key word here, I'm going to
highlight the stuff that really made the
difference. And then he wants to support
financial freedom and online income.
Those were important to him and that's
slightly different for a lot of people
because specific things for certain
people are broadly relatable for
everyone. But if you're specific to
nobody, then you're going to like be
non-relatable to everybody. Then also
there's a bunch of objections. I don't
have anything to sell. I am busy. I'm
busy grinding. I'm busy socializing. I'm
busy self-improving. Like I'm going to
the gym. I already have too much on my
plate. I already understand hooks. I'm
too lazy to edit my captions. These are
not things that he told me, but I was
just like assuming it. And now I'm going
to show you guys the actual beginning
part of my video and you're going to see
how much of it was tailored specifically
to solve his problems. I'm going to
actually go to the video now.
How I grew 200k followers in a year
working 90 minutes a day. This is the I
don't have time objection. And we're
solving it in the working 90 minutes a
day because a busy college student is
not going to be able to work more than
like 90 minutes a day, right? Or maybe
they could, but it's like easier pill to
swallow that way. Let's see the next
one. Do it in a genuine way. Go viral
authentically. That's the best
performing thumbnail. People have come
up to me like, "Yo, you're the go viral
authentically guy on YouTube, right?" I
was like, "Sure, I guess." And then in
the actual hook of the video, right?
Because the title and thumbnail of a
YouTube video is realistically basically
your hook of a Tik Tok or real. I was
really focused on making sure the viewer
feels heard on these things. I don't
have anything to sell yet. I want to
create financial freedom. So, a lot of
it was around money. So, notice what I
did here. Once I posted 259 videos,
started an online business, start an
online business, B-roll shows money,
made $260,000
from said online business. So, we've
we've answered that problem and desire
and objection within the first 6
seconds. We've addressed this. We've
addressed this. We've kind of addressed
this because I said, "I started an
online business. Uh, I am busy grinding,
socializing, self-improving because of
college." Dropped out of college and so
I was in college. So, that kind of
addresses this one. And then, I already
understand hooks. I'm too lazy to edit
my captions. Now, for those of you who
think you understand, folks, and you're
ready to scroll off or get to the next
part of the section. I I just had a
feeling that when people would watch the
video, they would assume that they knew
what what I'm talking about already. How
many of you guys here in the chat like
watched a video that's how to do hooks?
Use this viral hook. Oh, steal steal
this viral hook. This is a challenge
hook. This is a visual hook. Blah blah
blah blah. Like, there's so many things
about steal the hook. There's not much
about understand the hook. And that's
what I'm trying to do here as well with
the idea of your persona is like an
ideal viewer persona framework is a way
of also solving and creating hooks. It's
a way of also solving and creating
scripting. Now for those of you who
think you understand hooks and you're
ready to the idea of your persona even
informs my editing process. It informs
which parts to really emphasize based on
what I believe they're thinking. And
this is why if you choose an idea of
your persona you know and that you've
like actually conversed with is so much
easier because then now you like can do
all of these more complex empathetic
mental gymnastics cuz you're like yes of
course they're going to think about this
all to really address this objection. So
I think like I really like the
objections framework because
realistically like all of you guys here
who are making content to like help
people out you guys have a lot of these
advice and talking points that you
really want to help them with which is
great. That's why we are here to create
content because we have a message that
we clearly want to share. Now, the game,
the creative game is how to sell
somebody on actually wanting to watch
you, give them that advice because the
actual advice that works with content is
really unsexy. If I'm going to tell them
exactly how they should be editing their
videos, they damn well sure need a
reason to actually trust me and believe
that I know the information that's going
to help them and I know what it's like
to like be them. So, in order to do
that, it's just a ton of building
relatability and breaking down their
objections. Another part too, it's like
if you're making talking head
educational content, it's very closely
tied to sales principles because you are
selling somebody on giving you their
attention. In order for somebody to sit
through even 90 seconds or 60 seconds of
their time base level that you're
starting with at the beginning of the
video is like 0% trust. You're you're
here and now as you build you handle
their objections. You predict what
they're saying. You give them actual
like unique value. Their trust meter to
watch the next part of the video kind of
goes like here and then here and they
here. So later on in the video, you can
kind of be more loosey goosey, like joke
around and stuff, but towards the hook,
I'm like super like militant with my
cuts, with my scripting. If every word
is not like hitting to the viewer, that
incorporates some level of persuasion
and some level of like relatability and
understanding, then it's probably losing
retention. So an action step for you
guys then for those of you guys who do
want to like script using this ideal
viewer persona framework, before your
next video, write down a person and then
write down any objections that they
would have towards your method. So let's
say you have a solution in mind of like
whose question I asked earlier? Malt,
right? Malte, you want to sell people on
like the entrepreneur mentorship, which
I'm going to guess is like creating
content and starting a business. Who are
they? Are they like a young person? What
objections does a young person have? And
then it's easier if you know the exact
young person. And realistically, what's
top of mind for young people is
incredibly different from what's top of
mind to like somebody who's in college
versus postrad. Literally a difference
of like four years. That makes a massive
difference. Like that's night and day.
So when people also say my IVP, my ICP
is 18 to 24, you got to realize an 18
and 24 year old, as a person who's in
between 18 to 24, like I can like see
how like desires have like rapidly
shifted every year. In fact, every like
3 months, the desire shifts, bro,
depending on if it's final season or not
final season for a college student, the
desire rapidly shifts. Sometimes the
best content that I make comes right off
the bat of a coaching call or talking
onetoone with somebody because that's
when I know it's super fresh and top of
mind that I could close my eyes and
imagine conversing with them and that I
could imagine what they're saying back
to me or at least thinking back, you
know, like in the minute ways where like
I don't think my friend actually told me
this or I don't think people have
actually told me I already understand
hooks like shut up. But you can kind of
like sense these things. Let me know in
the chat if this made sense or you have
any questions. This is something I'm
like super passionate about because this
is low-key like the bread and butter of
like every like aspect of the decision-m
of the content that I create. Now,
Jordan asked, "So, basically to think of
convos you've had with friends where you
gave advice and use that to help." Yes.
For those of you guys who've used the
script template that I've uh given out,
I'm going to drop it in the chat
actually cuz this goes a little bit
deeper into the specific application of
it. This script template itself got me
from 0 to 100k followers on Tik Tok in a
single month. Like copy pasting this
this template. I've only ever done
freestyle talking head videos, but this
makes me want a fully scripted content.
So, this is another kind of correlated
question, which is, well, then should
you script your videos or should you
not? Scripting videos, I still think
allows you to think through this entire
thing. So, imagine you're conversing
with a friend and you're like debating
with them or you're like trying to
convince them of a thing. If you're just
trying to like freestyle in the moment,
you might sound more passionate and your
tonality might come out better and your
energy might be there, but then your
thoughts just might be combobulated.
Let's say my friend asked me for content
advice and then I'm sitting there and
I'm like, "Wait, wait. I persona wait
actually. Editing, editing, editing.
Wait, wait, wait, wait. No, consistency,
consistency." And then he's just sitting
there like, "What the [ __ ] is this guy
saying?" So scripting allows you to not
do that where you're just like, "Wait,
wait, wait. This thing. Oh, no, no, no.
This thing." Like these like ADHD jumps
where you're like back and forth, back
and forth. Now, that can be entertaining
on camera, but that's also just not that
helpful. So, like the most helpful
version of you is probably a version of
you that like writes out their thoughts.
But the more entertaining version is
probably the one that's yapping. So to
understand the mental models of scripts,
I would script out first. Now after
scripting probably like 100 plus videos,
I have this memorized. It's like a hook
proof explanation takeaway. Hook proof
explanation takeaway. And then I kind of
know what that means. But that's because
I wrote that down on paper a ton of
time. But like before I did that, if I
was trying to make these videos, like
when I said like 0 to 100k followers in
a month on TikTok, during that period, I
was scripting every single one of my
videos and I spent six hours on each
one. So like I just sped ran the process
of learning content in that month cuz it
was a new format that I was learning. I
just sped ran that because I was putting
so many hours into this and I was like
watching videos all the time about
content by the way too. So realistically
like my brain was thinking about content
for like 12 hours every day. The other
four hours are probably like gym or like
how to get better at talking to girls or
something. I don't know. Parallels
between sales and talking head videos.
Yes. Because all content is persuasion.
Content is like mass psychology, right?
And and I'm glad that we can have this
level of complexity in these calls
because if I was making like a Instagram
real or YouTube video about this, people
are like, "But what about posting
times?" [laughter] Or like what about
hashtag? Wait, how does that affect it?
It like doesn't. Could you even niche a
niche? Yes. So, like the nichest of
niches is your ideal viewer. Because
eventually you get to the point with
your niche where it's like, I want to
make self-development content. Well,
what kind of self-development content?
Well, I want to make a fitness video.
Well, now the video idea, what is a
fitness video? The idea for my fitness
video is going to be how I went from
like skinny fat to jacked in 3 months
using systems. Now, how do I script the
video? And then you go into this. And
eventually, you go from your niche to
then your video idea and then to your
video script. And by that point, you've
gone from a niche to like a person. And
that's like I think the best form of
content is like when you're talking to a
person. That's at least the form of
content I like watching. And that AI
cannot replace is your understanding of
another human being. AI can replace
delivery. It can replace like the part
of you that understands how to make
visuals, how to edit. It's not going to
replace the part of you that understands
who you're talking to behind the screen
and really knows them. I think the
people who win at this game of like
content persuasion are the ones who can
really make the person across the screen
feel heard. I have problem with
overexlaining everything. I write my
scripts include so much unnecessary
fluff. Well, in order to concise down
fluff, you got to ask yourself, would
this person want to watch this part of
the video? Would they care or would they
like kind of eye roll? Cuz another part
of it, too, right? And this is like
layer layer three of the scripting
process now, is you now know what they
want. You now know what they're going to
object to. Now, you have to address
their objections in a way that they'll
actually want to hear it. That's really
weird and difficult. Like, that's
actually weird. Now, it's kind of this
game of making sure you don't just say,
"Hey, you uh you you're busy grinding,
socializing, and self-improving." Like,
you sound like a doctor. Like, you're
busy grinding and socializing, so here's
how to fix that. Like, what? [laughter]
Like, that just sounds weird. Now, the
creative problem solving of scripting
now is like, how do you do it in a
creative way? That's where I think
creativity comes in. It's like that's
where the creativity comes in now where
you're like making them feel they don't
hate me while I'm persuading them
because it's really easy to hate a
salesperson. It's really easy to like
dislike a person who's on camera because
they're trying to get something out of
you. They're trying to persuade you.
Now, how do you kind of do it in a
likable way? How do you do it in a way
like that makes them maybe laugh? Like
my preferred method of persuasion is
often times humor cuz I think that's a
great rapport builder. Uh but there's
other ways of doing it. What kind of
personality are you? You know, this is
where your personality probably comes
into play and then it like harmonizes
well. What is your preferred mechanism
of talking to your viewer? For me, I'm
like a joking person. Like I I'm like
largely unserious and so that's like my
method of like persuasion. But if you're
a more stern personality, perhaps you're
a more like somber, reflective
personality, then you lean more into
that while addressing the objection. I
hope that was that was very helpful and
insightful towards the the scripting and
ideal viewer process. Awesome. All
right. Wait, that was an excerpt from
one of my coaching calls in our private
community, Content Academy, where we
teach you how to go viral directly,
where you can ask me questions alongside
three other coaches on weekly calls. So,
if you do want to get access to these
private calls where they're an hour long
where you can actually hop on a call and
talk to me and ask me questions on how
to grow your personal brand, feel free
to go to that first link down below and
click apply to join our community if you
do want to fast track your personal
brand growth. Other than that, I will
see you guys in the next valuepacked
YouTube video. Catch you guys in the
next one. Peace.