So, I made $26,000 in the span of two
hours. And that same night, I also
relapsed to porn. And I want to tell you
guys a story of how this happened. This
is a very raw and vulnerable story. So,
it was November 21st, 2024. And that was
the most amount of money I'd ever made
in a single day, $26,511.
[music]
It was during a 2-hour launch
presentation of a product that I had
been working on for the past 60 days.
And I didn't realize it at the time, but
I think that was also the day that
[music] I started to really hate working
on my business. Every day for the 60
days [music] leading up to that launch,
I woke up and immediately stared at that
date on my whiteboard, November 21st,
2024. [music] I pretty much forced my
brain to think about and care about
nothing else outside of that November
21st launch. I cared so much about that
launch, the launch presentation,
marketing the launch on my Instagram,
and then building out the actual course
modules for that launch that I basically
didn't work out for that entire month.
Every time I was facetiming my
girlfriend at night, my brain was
probably half thinking about what work I
needed to [music] do the next day to
even work on that launch. And then after
60 days of perfecting and grinding this
launch presentation, [music] building
out a 100 slide presentation on Canva,
getting 2,000 people to sign up to watch
this live presentation on November 21st,
[music] 2024 at 7:00 p.m. It was done.
And during that 2-hour launch
presentation, we made $26,511.
Holy [ __ ] Today [music] is November
21st, and we launched a new product,
Content Academy 2.0. Literally in the
span of like [music] 2 hours, I think we
made 24 grand. Uh, this is the most
amount of money I've ever made. [music]
And immediately after, I felt sad and
confused. So, in that feeling of
confusion, [music] I decided I should
probably celebrate. That's probably why
I'm feeling a little bit empty inside.
So, I went out to K Town, went [music]
to the nicest K barbecue restaurant. I
spent 150 bucks on some nice ass
Chadurbagi, got myself a soju to [music]
drink alone at the restaurant. That was
my first time ever drinking alone for
the first time ever. I I hate drinking
and for some reason I did it because I
thought that would make me feel [music]
better in the celebration. So then after
finishing this amazing dinner, frankly,
that I ate on my own. I stumbled back to
my apartment and then I just sat down on
my desk, stared at the $26,000 [music]
on my screen and I asked myself, now
what? I still felt like I owed myself a
crazy celebration after feeling like I
had sacrificed 60 days of my happiness
to [music] work for that one moment. But
I just sat there in my New York City
apartment for a good like 30 minutes,
half tipsy, alone and staring [music] at
that $26,000 on my screen, hoping that
looking at it for longer would make me
feel something. I chose not to call up
any of my friends [music] to celebrate
cuz I would just feel kind of out of
touch, like gloating and flexing. And
it's also weird because I was wise
enough to know that I should invest half
of the $26,000. is I should save about
25% to invest in business expenses
[music] and I should save about 25% for
taxes. So, I'd have no money left to
splurge [music] on stupid shiny objects
because I don't think I'm materialistic.
I didn't want to buy a nice watch or a
car with that money. But that also made
me feel kind of sad [music] because it
just felt like I'd spent the last 60
days of grinding of somewhat losing my
sense of self outside of work [music]
just to transfer money around into
saving accounts. And I started feeling
this [music] mix of all these confusing
emotions, still half tipsy, alone in my
dream [music] New York City apartment,
staring still at those $26,000 on my
MacBook screen. And I thought, "This
can't be it, right?" So, I started doing
anything I could. I started scrolling
Tik Toks on my phone. Maybe the [music]
cheap dopamine would finally make me
feel something. Then, about an hour into
me just hunting for something that would
make me feel [music] something in
celebration, I did the unthinkable. I
relapsed to porn that night. Something
that [music] I was very convinced that I
had cut out of my life. Something that
my girlfriend and I had established
months prior was basically cheating in
our relationship. And by 1:00 a.m. that
night, I found myself laying there
[music]
in my intentionally tiny twinsized bed
so I could focus more on work, feeling
ashamed, guilty, and empty. I turned a
$26,000 celebration [music]
into one of the worst nights of my life.
Now, I think many of you might hear this
story and think instantly, oh, it's of
course money was the root of all of this
evil and shame, which is fair. A part of
me started to despise making money and
even building businesses after that,
believing subconsciously that making
more money turned me into a more
wretched person. And after wrestling
with that internal dissonance for the
past year while still building my
business, that same business, I believe
that concept is wrong. I believe it's
oversimplified. And I don't hear enough
people talking about this because how
can any of us work hard if money the
primary incentive structure of [ __ ]
society is evil. Then we're all doomed
to live in this cognitive dissonance for
the rest of our working lives. And I
just didn't buy that personally because
after all maybe all the people who buy
Rolexes and shiny cars with their money,
they're the ones who idolize money and
get lost. But I don't do that stuff and
you watching probably relate to that
too. We save and invest our money. So we
couldn't possibly be idolizing the money
then, right? if we're not even going to
spend it on stupid [ __ ] But I think
what I've realized is that the
idolization of money is a lot more
subtle and nefarious than materialism
and degeneracy. I really like this quote
from King Solomon from Proverbs in the
Bible. Do not wear yourself out to get
rich. Have the wisdom to show restraint.
That's Proverbs 23:4, I believe. Now, I
think once you start making money,
you're faced with these two voices in
your head. The first one, which you know
is wrong, is the voice that tells you to
stay complacent and don't chase any form
of growth because it's evil. I think
that's like an ADIQ interpretation of
wisdom. It shuns hard work and pursuing
goals. But you're also faced with this
other voice inside your head, which you
also know to be wrong deep down, which
is the hyonic treadmill. This idea that
buying more expensive things is the key
to more happiness, which you know is a
falsity. But then is it even possible to
be happy while making a lot of money?
Like maybe the key is just to just like
absolve all desire for growth, sell it
all, get get rid of all of it. But a
couple months back, I read this quote
from Marcus Aurelius, one of the most
powerful Roman emperors ever. Even in a
palace, life can be led well. Even when
you have all of the things that life has
to offer you that will kind of distract
you and be all these shiny objects that
start to make you feel a little bit
empty and numb inside, you can still
live an incredibly happy and meaningful
and purposeful life. ironic, but I've
felt that brought me a lot of peace
inside because I think working hard for
a goal that is meaningful to you is
still one of the beauties of life. But
I've also come to realize with my own
two eyes, from my own lived experience,
not just from like wisdom in a book,
that getting the pot of gold at the end
in business is genuinely less happy than
the pursuit of the goal itself. And to
think back to like the happiest I felt
in high school when I was hard grinding
League of Legends, I still remember back
to the last day of the season. I was
hard grinding, ranked from 6:00 p.m. to
12:00 a.m. with full focus, memorizing
all of the builds, queuing up every 5
minutes, hopping on Discord calls with
all my teammates just so we could win
and just so I could rank up to plat 4
before the end of the season. But the
joy I got from actually seeing that
shiny platform icon in my League of
Legends profile lasted about like 10
minutes. And so I stopped really playing
ranked League of Legends after hitting
that milestone. I stopped caring. And I
think the reality of an incredibly
exciting pursuit followed by a somewhat
underwhelming realization of the gold at
the end of that pursuit is an
inevitability that will continue for the
rest of our lives as people who love
chasing goals. Now, that doesn't mean
chasing goals is evil and that it's
empty. It's one of the most exciting
things in life that brings me the most
joy. And I hated when people told me
that I am just getting lost in this
pursuit. But there's two methods that I
think I had to learn in the past year to
help me still stay in love with the work
of business without getting drained by
this constant up and down and feeling
underwhelmed. And the first one is to
invest a scary amount of money into
people who win when you win in business.
So, I'm currently chasing a 200k month
in my business. And there's nothing that
excites me more than the idea of
rewarding my head of operations, Justin,
with a fat bonus when we hit that goal
together. cuz he's been helping me build
this business, Content Academy, for the
past year. And there's nothing I want to
do more than to see him win in the
business, too. And to see him build like
a genuine career out of this. That
brings me so much more joy than seeing a
number in my own bank account go up. And
I think it's really reminding myself in
those moments where I feel scarce and
I'm like, wait, like maybe I'm not
paying myself enough like [ __ ] [ __ ]
[ __ ] Like my profit margins are low.
Does that make me like a stupid loser in
front of all the other cool entrepreneur
guys who take like 90% profit margins?
And I think to this frame of in my last
day alive, what would I feel the most
happiest doing? And I think I feel the
most joy and invigoration when I see
other people feeling just as much joy
with me because there's nothing worse of
a feeling than feeling on top of the
world and then just feeling [ __ ]
lonely as [ __ ] and feeling like there's
nobody else that you can smile with. and
just knowing that if you like tell
anybody of the wins and the joy that
you're experiencing, it's just going to
be met with maybe judgment and
misunderstanding, which I think is
natural when running your own business.
But having other people that genuinely
are incentiv I think is what makes
things exciting. It's what makes video
games and sports exciting when you're
playing on a team. Second is to go
really hard on my hobbies outside of
business. This is something I realized
very recently because the hard part
about actually having hobbies outside of
business is I actually think it's really
hard because business like any other
video game is incredibly addictive and
can make you glued to your screen for 12
hours a day just like any other video
game. Literally checking the numbers on
my screen of how many sales we got is
this dopamine hit that will keep me
glued to my bed. Every single morning
when I wake up, I feel this intense pull
of addiction to check my phone and check
the number of sales that we got and the
amount of money that we made overnight
to get that dopamine hit instantly
injected into my veins. But I know
instant gratification and living for
that shot of dopamine is not something
that brings me happiness long term. And
I know if I get too caught up in that,
then I'm just not going to want to work
out. I'm not going to want to do the
things that actually bring joy to my
soul deeply, like journaling,
meditating, reading, wisdom. So,
understand that you might love the work
and you might love working on your
business, but the path to a healthy life
is still probably the path of a little
bit more resistance. Like, I really
don't want to work out right now. I I
want to hop off after I film this video,
edit it, post it, and then go work on my
like email funnel right after this. But
I know I'm probably going to end the day
then and feel like [ __ ] and feel like
I've sacrificed my whole day to feel
nothing at the end of it if I haven't at
least worked out and actually put in
like 100% presence into working out
because that brings me joy today. And I
really want [clears throat] to emphasize
this because it's really [ __ ]
annoying to wake up and have to like
instead of check my phone and start
working to like go to my desk and
journal and remember my why. Like I
don't give a [ __ ] about that. I want to
see numbers go up on my screen, bro.
That's what gives me dopamine, bro. It's
literally like a video game. But don't
let that feeling of wanting to get the
dopamine of your business make you
believe that it somehow makes you like
more hardworking. It's just an addiction
just like any other addiction. And this
specific thing which I have to remind
myself every single day to be where my
feet are is something that's helped me
be more present with my girlfriend, with
my friends, and with my family. Because
I'm going to be honest, like maybe I
have like ADHD or something. I I like
choose not to believe that. Like it's
really hard for me to focus some days on
anything that isn't business. Especially
when I know like I get anxious when
there's a fire I have to put out in my
business. Like I know something's wrong
that I just have to fix like in my email
automations or I have to create this
piece of content that I know is like
really fresh in my head. But be where
your feet are and it's okay to grow a
little slower. A creative mind and a
healthy soul are most conducive to being
like the most creative founder, the most
effective leader and communicator. But
the point of being present is not to be
a better founder. It's actually just to
like be there with the people that you
love. And I think I also went through
these mental loops of, oh, I'm
meditating so I can be more creative
today so I can make a better video. All
of my decisions just went back to making
better stuff for my business. And it's
really cool to see this win-win
relationship between healthy habits and
business growth. But understand that
that doesn't mean everything is
literally for your business growth over
time. That's made me feel really
soulless. And then lastly, this is a
bonus tip. Don't beat yourself up for
not being perfect as an entrepreneur. I
see stories every single day of
entrepreneurs and creators whose
business makes 3x the money as me and
they work half the amount of time as me.
And there's no other profession where
people get criticized more for being
stupid, inefficient, and morally corrupt
than business owners. Sometimes when I
talk to old friends who don't really
know what I've been up to, they'll
sometimes look at me like I'm some lost
prodigal son, lost in the ways of
obsessing and idolizing money. But I
know the mission of my business. I know
the impact that I have and no one else
will know that for you either. I also
know the flaws I need to work on. But
shame is one of the least productive
emotions that you can live and work in.
If you are currently in a state of
feeling a little bit of this lostness,
maybe feeling a little bit of this guilt
and shame around being an entrepreneur.
I just want to say from the bottom of my
heart, it's genuinely okay. And I wish
somebody just told me this, but there is
a version of you that you will reach in
the future that genuinely has the level
of success that you can only dream of,
who has impact, who has love, who has
leveled up to the level of leader and
business owner that you want to reach.
But the path is always unclear when
you're in the weeds of it right now. So,
it's okay to not be there yet. That is
the beauty of this game of running a
business, of chasing any of your goals
really and leveling up. There's always
going to be days where comparison and
scarcity seeps in. stress gets to you,
you get consumed by the work again. It's
normal. I'm I'm literally speaking to my
[ __ ] self right now, man. But if you
ever feel lost and want a reminder, you
can feel free to come back to this video
cuz I think you probably deal with
enough stress and criticism and shame on
a day-to-day basis. So, I don't want
this video to feel like that whatsoever.
I just want you to know it's it's okay.
And hopefully hearing how much I've
[ __ ] up makes you maybe feel a little
bit less bad about maybe things that you
feel ashamed of as an entrepreneur. Cuz
it's weird. It's weird, bro. And I've
I've noticed like so much [ __ ] shame
in the past [laughter] year.
[snorts]
I don't know why I'm crying, but I guess
I'll leave this in the video. Um,
I just want you to know it's okay. It's
okay to be lost and doesn't make you a
bad person for trying your best. But
yeah, not my usual value videos, but I
hope this is helpful. Shame is a really
weird thing to deal with as an
entrepreneur. things figure themselves
out. And
there's like been days in the past year
where I felt like, damn, like I just
[ __ ] suck. Like I'm I'm like letting
everyone down. And [clears throat] I
know that's going to continue to happen.
It's okay. My YouTuber attention's
[ __ ] cooked right now for the one
person that's saying thank you. And uh
you [snorts] know, it's okay not to be
perfect right now. being in a position
of like this weird level of like
privilege but also responsibility. You
can feel this mixture of shame while
[snorts] also feeling this mixture of
pressure. And it's just confusing as
[ __ ] man. And I I think I'm [snorts]
reaching this point right now where I'm
realizing like I'm I'm starting to
figure out how to like feel okay with
myself and like get back to levels of
self-love that I was at more than a year
ago before I went down this weird
journey of like trying to start this
business. [snorts] But yeah, I'll catch
you guys in the next video.