You are not the niche. Stop trying to
become the niche. This is coming from
somebody who's grown three accounts in
three different niches. And now I also
grew an Instagram account. I guess it's
my fourth account. Now, to really
understand why becoming the niche is
terrible advice, you have to think about
content and social media from
microeconomics because at the end of the
day, there is a limited amount of
viewers and attention on social media, a
limited number of watch hours. In
biology, the literal definition of niche
or I believe how it's pronounced is
niche is the functional role that an
organism plays in their ecosystem,
especially what predators and what prey
and what resources they're after and
then who their competition is. Animals
over time in order to actually survive
and reproduce across multiple
generations. They had to find the corner
of the ecosystem that they could
actually thrive and survive in. And you
as a beginner creator must do the same.
Everybody telling you that you need to
become the niche and that you are the
niche, it's frankly survivorship bias.
They're usually either talented, they're
pretty, or they've been creating on
social media for so long that they've
niched down at the start and now because
they've actually built an audience and a
moat around themselves, they've kind of
like become lions in the jungle where a
lion can do what the [ __ ] he wants.
Doesn't have to really stress too hard
and find a very specific niche that he
can survive in. A lion can get resources
pretty easily. When you are starting
social media, you are not a [ __ ]
lion. So, stop taking advice from lions
in the space who are telling you that
you just need to feel good. And don't
choose a niche because that's too
restricting. You, a beginner creator
with less than 100,000 followers, are
like a pigeon in the nicest way
possible. I say this because I'm
literally like a pigeon too on YouTube
right now. You are hunting for worms.
You are not trying to compete with the
lions who've been creating content for
years, built a massive audience. You
need to choose the niche that you can
actually have more experience and a
competitive edge in. choosing your
niche, which is just whatever topic or
sector that you are creating content
about that's specific. It's not doing
your personal brand a disservice. It's
just basic microeconomics of supply and
demand. That doesn't mean don't tell
your life story. That doesn't mean don't
show your personality. That's not what
I'm saying. You should be telling your
life story. You should be sharing your
life experiences. You should be
expressing yourself authentically. But
know who your ideal viewer is. Know what
their wants are. Know what their fears
are. Know what their needs are. and know
what content your ideal viewer is
already watching. That's your niche.
Don't think of yourself as the niche.
Think of yourself as the competitive
advantage, your life story, your
personality as the competitive edge to
dominate a niche. Everybody who's
telling you to become the niche if you
like fitness and you like art. Talk
about both. They're telling you
literally to spread yourself thin and
try to compete in three different niches
simultaneously. No [ __ ] you're not
going to win because nobody in the art
niche is going to want to watch your
fitness content and nobody in the
fitness niche is going to want to watch
your art content. So, it makes your page
hard to follow along to and the value
proposition of your account really
confusing to strangers. That's you
confusing your stranger viewer who saw
you 2 days ago for 30 seconds on your
feed. You are not that important to your
strangers yet. If you're not providing
value to your stranger viewers, they are
going to leave you. They are not going
to give you this time of day. And that's
where a lot of these more experienced
creators who've been creating content on
one singular account get wrong. They're
now projecting the advice that they do
today, which is just enjoy the process
and not burn out. But that's because
they built an audience of over a million
followers. And they are trying now to
play the game of sustainability, not the
game of survival. When you are first
starting your personal brand, you want
to even get breath to survive and just
make your first $10,000 online. Try to
get your first brand deal. Try to get
your first UGC deal. Try to get your
first client or customer to your
business. Do not try to become the
niche. You're taking advice from people
who are comfortable. So, you're probably
wondering now, how do you actually
choose your niche then? And the simple
answer is if you genuinely want to reach
100,000 followers and make content your
full-time career, choose a niche of a
topic you're interested in, but the
viewers in that niche can perceive you
as more entertaining, more
inspirational, or more educational than
the rest of the creators in that niche.
So, for example, when I was first
starting out my Instagram, and I was
stuck literally at like 2,000 to 20,000
followers, I tried getting into the
lifestyle and vlogs niche. I wanted to
be a college creator. Like all of my
favorite college creators, like Elliot
Choy, Justin Han, I was like, damn, bro.
I just I want people to like me for me.
And my videos just were stuck, bro.
They'd get like 10k views. I wouldn't
reach a new audience. And that feeling
of being stuck hurts. That's why I want
to make this message to you. When I
actually niched down to the online
business niche, that's when my content
[ __ ] took off. This was in around
October, November of 2023, I realized I
should probably just make online
business content because that's what
that's what I nerd about. And since
November of 2023, now in the past 2
years, I went from around 25,000
followers to 460,000 followers on
Instagram. I built an audience that
knows, likes, and trusts me, but that's
because I niched down to the online
business niche. However, niching down is
not the same thing as winning and
dominating in your niche. I'd like to
think that I was one of the fastest
growing people in this niche in the past
2 years. So, how did I, a broke college
student who at the time literally made
$3,000 a month, dominate the online
business niche and grow so fast? I
didn't become the niche, but I did
inject parts of my personality that were
different for everybody else in the
space being in college and being Asian.
I really leaned into those angles as
hard as possible. So, I started a series
on Instagram where I would vlog my daily
college life and I would really make
clear that I'm in college. every single
hook. Road to $100,000 a month as a
college student. Road to $100,000 a
month before I drop out of college. And
then every time I was back home with my
parents, POV, you told your Korean mom
you're going to drop out. POV, you told
your Korean mom how much you made from
your online business. POV, you became a
disappointment to your Korean mom. I
spam these angles where I would relate
to a very specific ICP of a Korean
college student. So, you need to
understand your niche. You need to see
what the norms are in your niche. And
what I saw was people flexing all the
time in the online business niche. I
didn't see anybody just being real,
being funny, and I knew these
[ __ ] in the online bishop niche
are not as funny as me. And I knew they
were not as Korean as me. And I knew
they were not in college either. Another
similar example that I think did a
really good job is this creator named
Ken Jandre who at the beginning of this
year in 2025, he was around maybe like
20,000 followers and now he's at 500,000
followers in the Christianity niche. Ken
Jandre made vulnerable cinematic
storytelling content. That blend in the
Christianity niche hadn't really been
seen before where somebody was taking
these cinematic principles of creators
like OMG Adrian, Khloe, Shei, Mileen's
Mind, Film with Colleen, and injecting
it into the niche of Christianity while
also taking principles from creators
like Hamza opening up about problems
with lust and being vulnerable. Find a
niche that you can dominate in where
your personality and your life story
hasn't really been leaned into as much.
Like, I'm not going to lie, I hadn't
really seen that many Korean online
business people on the internet. So,
another thing too is feel free to take
inspiration from other niches, but know
your niche deep down. Which niche you
are trying to build a competitive edge
inside. Was I richer than anybody in the
niche? [ __ ] no. Was I smarter than
anybody in the niche? No. [ __ ] no, bro.
I am a [ __ ] entrepreneur. Honestly, I'm
not going to try to compete and outsmart
and out business advice Alexi. And if
you are trying to do the same thing,
understand that you're going to get
squashed. It's like you are a pigeon,
but then you don't have a beak and
you're trying to compete eating worms
out of a hole against all the pigeons
with beaks. You're going to get [ __ ]
You're going to lose. But then you might
just have this weird biological
adaptation where your claws are really
sharp. So then you can just, I don't
know, kill other pigeons while they're
eating their worms. Okay, if you have
weird things that make you eccentric and
different from people in your niche,
understand that that can be your
creative strategic advantage. My
background was in comedy and why I watch
hella brain rot content. So that
honestly became part of my strategic
advantage too is I tried to reference as
much brain rot and pop culture in my
videos as possible because I know for a
fact that experienced seasoned
entrepreneurs don't have the time to
actually be tapped in with pop culture
and I was young. I was 19 when I was
making this content so it was perfect
timing. So what makes you different?
This is not becoming the niche. You
still have a niche but lean into your
advantages that make you different and
[ __ ] dominate your niche. That is how
you grow lightning fast and actually
build a creator career. What gap in
viewership do you notice is underserved
and feels unheard in your niche? That is
your genetic adaptation that's going to
make you thrive and survive in your
niche and build a creator career.