I hate to break it to you, but not
everybody can be a successful content
creator. And this is coming from
somebody. I'm 22 and I just recently
crossed my first million dollars made
from social media. But in order to reach
that point, it's not just luck and it's
not just content strategy like every
guru will tell you. I believe there's
three very rare traits because not many
creators get to the point where they
actually can even make a full-time
income, let alone seven figures. So
trait number one that you need to have
to reach this top 1% level of success as
a content creator is an aggressive
competitive nature. hate it or love it,
you are competing with every single
other creator in your niche. As a
content creation advice creator, I am
competing with the likes of Callaway,
Junior, Patty Galloway, and I have to
ask myself ruthlessly, why am I worth
watching versus them? And you need to
ask yourself that same question. What is
your brain constantly thinking right now
as you're watching this video? Is this
person's information worth my time? You
have to ask yourself that same question
with your own content. And you might
think this only applies to content where
you're selling something, but that's not
true. I grew an account in the comedy
niche to 900,000 followers and I still
applied this aggressive mindset towards
my skits. I would watch every other
creator in the skit space. Right at the
time it was like Joe Roth, Jason Weeden,
Edward. So, and I would watch all of
these people's skits and I'd be like,
"What is one edge that I have that they
don't have?" Everybody has that one
thing in your life, that one part of
your story that makes you unique. Find
out what that is that no one else in the
space has or at least not many people in
the space have. and juice the hell out
of it. I am now competing in the online
business, making money online space.
I've grown 450,000 followers in the last
2 years. And the way I've been able to
do that in such a saturated niche is
because I thought really long and hard
about what makes me unique. I'm a lot
funnier than these [ __ ] like
Iman Godzi and like Alexi. They're
they're frankly pretty boring and way
too serious. So that's one strategic
advantage. The other one is that they're
not Korean. So I told myself, yo, I'm
going to be like the Korean Imani. I'm
going to be the Asian Immanazi. I'm
going to talk about K-pop. I'm talking
about having a Korean mom, growing up
with Asian tiger parents. And those are
the topics that I lean heavily into.
These are subjective advantages that
allow you to relate to other people, but
it all stems from thinking this
competitive nature of what makes you
different from other people. The
algorithms are pitting your video
against the other five videos in your
niche, and they're literally comparing
your video's watch time and engagement
and like rate and comment rate, right?
If you're a fitness creator, but your
video is getting put right next to like
a super jacked dude. If you're playing
that game of trying to be the most
jacked looking fitness influencer, you
have to understand that that video is
not going to perform well. I'm sorry.
You have to analyze what other creators
have an advantage in, what you have an
advantage in, and compete in that zone.
Now, the cool thing about this level of
competition is that in social media,
you're not competing for just one spot
at the throne. There are so many
subniches and micro influencers at this
point that there are new creators
popping off for the weirdest combination
of stuff. I saw this one fitness creator
popping off. His name is Iayuk Proof or
Luke Proof. He popped off not by making
fitness content whatsoever. In fact, he
doesn't have that crazy physique. He has
like a pretty average looking fitness
influencer physique. So, what did he do
to stand out as a fitness coach and
fitness influencer? He started playing
the saxophone and learning the saxophone
and learning how to paint the Mona Lisa
in one day. That is the type of crazy
out there ideas that helps you compete
and win. And that stems from always
thinking about what are my
disadvantages, what are my strengths.
Find any strategic advantage that you
can find in your life. Once you find
that one concept that hits, gets a
million or even 100k plus views, milk
the hell out of it. Character trait
number two, you have to kill your ego to
grow. Now, we've already talked about
how you can stand out and lean into the
strengths that make you different from
all the other creators in your niche.
And often times, you're going to have an
inkling of this. People seem to resonate
a lot with dropping out, but I don't
want to be perceived that way. I don't
want to be perceived as the guy who
dropped out. Ew, that's like Lora and
like, yo, I'm I'm going to get like no.
That's a thought process that might
happen. Now, a genius content angle
that's worked so well for so many
fitness creators is the whole morning
routine before my 9 to5. That's a way
that you can stand out in the niche. So,
maybe your road to success will not be
the traditional being a fitness
influencer and just being glazed for how
you look. Maybe the followers that are
out there that will [ __ ] with you are
going to be the ones who actually are
really obsessed with the fact that you
work a 9 to 5 and that they really
resonate with you being an accountant,
the boring job that you hate. Yeah,
you're going to have to lean into that
if you want a strategic advantage
because you don't have a better physique
than David Laid. You don't have a better
physique than Sebum. So, you can't win
in that department. So, you're gonna
have to compete in this department of
talking about your 9to-5. And I know you
probably don't want that. You don't want
to be perceived as this guy who works a
9 to5. And you don't like that part of
yourself because it's kind of boring.
But you have to understand that that's
what makes you unique and that's what's
going to make you relatable to so many
people in a similar life situation as
you. Because once you start talking
about the stuff that nobody else wants
to talk about because there's so much
shame involved there and there's so much
vulnerability involved there, that's how
you can build a tribe of people who
genuinely [ __ ] with you so hard. Really
random combination, but that's how you
build a tribe of people who really,
really love you for you. Now, back in
high school when I first started
creating content in 2020, I used to be a
kid who always made jokes and never took
himself seriously because I was afraid
to be perceived as somebody who tried
too hard. So, in 2023, when I pivoted my
content from comedic skits that never
took myself too seriously cuz I was
always playing a character to the
serious advice content where I was
speaking from the heart, man, that [ __ ]
was [ __ ] embarrassing. I had this
inkling, this theory that if I was just
vulnerable enough with all the struggles
that I was going through as a college
student trying to make it in this
content creation, personal development,
becoming a top 1% sigma male [ __ ] it
would be embarrassing, but it would
stand out. And I knew no Asian person
out there was doing that. So, I wanted
to fill in that gap in the market. It
was embarrassing to post daily talking
about my struggles of trying to start a
no fab streak. It was embarrassing to
talk about how I was obsessed with
reading these make money online books
despite making no money. And in order to
grow to a higher level of yourself as a
creator, as an entrepreneur, there's
going to be these pivot points where you
feel your old identity scratching and
clawing to keep you as the same identity
as you were always comfortable with. You
don't want to be perceived as the guy in
the group who tried to do that content
thing and failed. And this is your ego
talking because your ego simply serves
to keep life the same as it is right
now. That you maintain the safe
perception that everyone else around you
has of you. But that ego is also the one
that's keeping you broke as a creator.
And if you feel like you've stayed stuck
wanting to start content creation,
wanting to start maybe a business, or
maybe you just feel like you've
plateaued as a creator, I can guarantee
you there's probably a part of your ego
that is resisting growth. So ask
yourself, because I have to ask myself
literally every month, what part of me
is resisting change right now? What is
the one change that terrifies the [ __ ]
out of me? And what are the actions that
you can take to obliterate that fear?
That's the exact word that everybody
else who's watching this video who's not
going to make a million dollars is
shying away from that is your
competitive edge edge. Okay, trait
number three. This one's an interesting
one, but you need to gaslight yourself
into believing that you love creating
for creating and that you don't love
money. Now, don't get me wrong, I have
these huge lofty goals. I remember I
entered college being like, I want to
make $100,000 before the time I
graduate. And then right before I
dropped out, I wrote down, I want to
make $100,000 in a single month. I want
to retire myself and my girlfriend, the
entirety of my bloodline. I want to do
it before the age of 25 cuz I'm 22 right
now. Yo, I want to make a lot of money.
If you're a content creator and you want
to build a business out of that, you're
in the business of people liking you.
That's what a follower is. So why would
somebody follow your shallow ass if all
you think about every single day when
you're creating is how is this going to
get a million views? There is no soul
and purpose and mission behind your
content. And I know we are here because
my thumbnail and title literally talked
about money. But when you are creating,
you have to let go of that desire to
take from your audience. The creators
that succeed long-term genuinely at
least have convinced themselves that
they actually care and give a [ __ ] about
the person behind the camera. And I know
exactly what it feels like to want so
much from your content. I want to make
millions of dollars. I want to hit a
million a month one day, but I can't put
that before my desire to serve my viewer
in my videos. I can't put that before my
desire to just put out something that
genuinely helps one person reach their
goals. And as a business owner, I can't
put my own selfish desires before my
clients and my customers and my
students. I have to trust and I have to
have faith, somewhat blind faith, that
if I put out the most valuable video
that I pour my heart into, even if it
doesn't make a single dollar, I'm still
going to show up with that maximum
effort putting into this video the level
of care that I would even if I got paid
$0. Cuz low key, these videos don't
really do that well on YouTube. So, I
don't make that much money from them.
But, I still have to have that faith
that if I just keep showing up and keep
giving value and keep caring, that one
day money will come. And I believe that
comes from relinquishing this desire and
need for money to come predictably from
your content. Not saying you can't sell
in your content. In fact, if you go to
that first link in the description, you
can apply to join my coaching program,
Content Academy. But I still give a [ __ ]
ton of value. And I try to give as much
value as possible. Now, it's subtle.
That energy is subtle. When you feel
like a creator is taking from you, you
[ __ ] hate that [ __ ] because that is a
waste of your time. You need to bring
the energy of, yo, I don't even care if
this helps one person. I'm still going
to make it the best possible video I
can. I don't care if I don't get paid
for it. Or else you're going to lose.
You're going to lose to the other guy
who cares way more than you, who pours
in 8 hours of effort into planning the
perfectly crafted, incredibly wellshot
my 5 to9 after my 9 to5 video. And in
order to build a large enough audience
to actually support a business, to
support a full-time income as a content
creator, I believe the number one thing
you need is a mission to serve your
viewer. So, who is that viewer that you
are serving and what do you want to help
them do? What do you want to help them
achieve? Yo, that could just mean you
want to serve college students and make
them laugh. That genuinely could be your
mission statement, but do that to the
best of your ability because that's how
you make the best possible videos that
then stand out in the algorithm, make
you one ofone as a creator rather than
blending into every other [ __ ] slop
is a possible creator in the niche and
make you actually stand out. And this is
coming from somebody who's coached now
over 2,000 creators and not every one of
them succeeds. As much as I would love
to say my program makes every single one
of them succeed, there's a handful of
creators that do stand out, and it's the
ones who genuinely embody these three
traits with their content and
consistently show up every single day to