Everybody tells you to start posting
content in 2026. It's going to change
your life. But no one ever tells you how
to actually go from idea to viral post.
Well, in the past month, I posted 15
videos on this brand new Instagram
[music] account and I grew to 30,000
followers. And today, I want to show you
guys exactly how I made this most recent
video in the next 15 minutes. And I
literally screen recorded live
scripting, filming, and editing the
entire thing to teach you exactly how to
post your first video using my exact
five-step viral framework. And if you
stick to the very end of the video, I'll
also teach you exactly how I got paid
$4,900 just for posting those videos on
that brand new Instagram account, too.
So, so let's jump into it. All right, so
we have a blank Google doc open, and
we're just going to start with step one,
which is scrolling on Instagram reels to
find an inspiration video. So, I have
the reals tab open here, and I'm just
literally just going to scroll until I
find something that either I think is in
a similar format that I can recreate for
my account, which looks like this,
right? I've only have 15 videos posted
so far. We actually were able to grow
this account to 32K followers in these
first 15 videos because I was
specifically just following this formula
that I'm going to show you guys today.
It starts by just going to the real tab
once again and until you find something
that you can actually copy into your own
niche. So literally any of these topics
can work. But personally what I am
paying attention for is whether it's in
my niche which is in the side hustles or
vibe coding niche or it's in my format
which is either a talking ahead or like
challenge or vlog style video or it's
some sort of journey based content where
I'm documenting a journey or the
achievement of a goal. So I'm going to
go to the reals tab here. I became a
millionaire by the age of 23 and grew to
millions of followers online. This
video, right, it got a decent amount of
traction. So, that's my signal that it's
pretty much worth copying. But this
one's more of an authority
[clears throat] style video. I became a
millionaire. Whereas my page, I'm
documenting the journey of a beginner to
vibe coding. So, I'm probably not going
to do that. Let's keep going. This is my
own video on my main account. I'm just
going to skip that one. It's possible to
make 10K a month online before
graduating. This one does match the
format because it's in sidehustle/making
money online, which is my niche on this
account. But the only issue is that
doesn't have a lot of traction. So, I'm
sorry. I'm actually friends with this
guy, Thomas, but I'm going have to skip
your video cuz only has 700 likes. And
I'm looking for videos that at least
have 5,000 likes. That to me is the sign
of an outlier/viral video. And we
realistically only want to copy outliers
because if we want our video to become
an outlier and a viral video, we can
only be studying and copying outliers.
Okay, this one. Ooh, this one's actually
pretty good. 20,000 likes starting
content at zero. That very much fits my
niche because I'm starting vibe coding
at zero. So, let's see. Not a week ago
with zero followers. I haven't told any
of my friends. I haven't told any of my
family. Absolutely no one I know knows
I'm doing this. I'm
>> So, this actually this video is pretty
good. 20,000 likes. So, it checks the
view view benchmark. [music] It checks
our niche benchmark because it's in a
similar he's talking about he's starting
a personal brand and an Instagram page
which is similar enough I guess it's a
tangential niche to me talking about
vibe coding. So this one works. And
lastly the format is pretty much
spot-on. I'm talking about starting vibe
coding from zero and I'll show you guys
exactly what that looks like. Right?
This is me basically documenting like me
starting vibe coding not knowing how to
code. This guy's talking about basically
not knowing how to create content. So,
it's perfect. It's a perfect match.
Okay. So, I found this video. I'm just
going to copy the link here at the top.
I'm just going to paste it here. Now,
after I do this process manually, I
actually want to show you guys an app
that actually I made that can help you
do this entire process more automated,
more quickly, but I'm going to do it
manually so I can walk through the exact
thought process of how to make and copy
viral content. So, step two after we're
done scrolling is simply to transcribe
the video. So, that's exactly what I'm
going to do here. I'm going to copy this
video link and I'm just going to go and
transcribe it now. And what I mean by
transcribe is quite literally watch the
video over and over until I can just
write the entire script out. Okay, so
we're going to watch the video one more
time. I might have actually not copied
the right link now that I look at it,
but it's okay cuz I bookmarked it. So,
make sure you also save the inspiration
videos that you find. I might have just
actually lost the video. Did I just lose
the video? Oh my goodness. No way. I
just lost the video. was trying to be
myself.
>> Okay, I'm an actual idiot, so I like
lost the video. But there is a way to
find the videos that you liked but you
didn't save. And basically the way you
do that is you uh click the more and
your activity section and that's where
you can go find your liked videos. Uh so
that's like a low-key a hack because I'm
an actual idiot and I somehow didn't
copy the right link. If you want to copy
the link, you have to go here, save or
share, copy link. So I'm going to make
sure I actually save the link so I don't
lose it again. But let's actually just
start writing down the actual script.
And when I say write down the actual
script, it's a [music] very tedious
process of writing down exactly what
they said. So starting content
at zero is the title, right? So we're
going to actually put that at text hook,
right? It's basically the same as a
title. Starting content at zero. Right
now, we've pretty much transcribed the
entire video. Right? It's a tedious
process. Took me about 2 minutes. So go
ahead and scroll and find a inspo video
based on whatever format that you are
trying to replicate. Whether it's vlogs,
whether it's challenge videos, [music]
whether it's just talking head like this
one, right? Or maybe it's just a
transformation video, right? Etc. Find
something [music] in a similar format.
It doesn't have to be exactly in your
niche. And sometimes going outside your
niche is better. Find a video with 5,000
plus likes, which is the indicator
that's an actual outlier, and then go
transcribe it. Once you're done, just
unpause the video, come back here, and
let's move on to step two of the
transcription process. This is where the
actual magic happens. This is where the
hack actually occurs with copying
content because you're not just trying
to transcribe and then move a couple
words around. [music] What you're really
trying to do is build your mental model
of why things actually go viral. So now,
I want you to ask yourself a question
after every sentence that you have
written down that you've taken from the
creator. Right? So, this is a pretty
simple video. is only five sentences,
but I want you to ask yourself, or I
guess six sentences, I want you to ask
yourself, why did this creator put this
sentence and why did it go viral? Now,
regardless of whether this creator
actually knew that this one was going to
pop off or not, cuz it clearly freaking
popped off. 20K likes in 7 days on a
brand new account. I want you to ask
yourself,
why did this video do well? And what
about this sentence correlated with the
video doing well? So, I just started
this account a week ago with zero
followers. He's looking a little meek,
like grabbing his arm and [ __ ] Why did
that do well? Clearly, it's because it's
relatable, [music]
right? It's relatable. It shows somebody
somebody in a quote unquote vulnerable
state. Now, was he actually feeling like
vulnerable during this video? Man, I
don't know. Maybe he was low-key just
acting like he was shy and [ __ ] Like,
he looked hella shy, right? And I think
that resonated with a lot of people who
are trying to or wanting to start
content, but they're scared. And it's
like watching somebody else take that
leap of faith can be a big inspiration
for a lot of people. So when I apply
that to my own niche of vibe coding,
right? I feel this too. I feel a lot of
fear. I'm a complete noob and I'm really
bad and I want to resonate then with the
people who can relate to feeling new to
coding and specifically feeling new to
this dream. Right? So for him the dream
is becoming a content creator. So I can
even write down my own um interpretation
of the text hook which is you know
appeal
to newbies starting content
right I can then apply that to every
single one of these sentences [music]
right and you don't have to be super
in-depth just think from you as a
consumer like when you watch this video
as a regular viewer what makes you
interested in watching this person and
it's a very simple intuitive process
that you want to ask yourself It's like,
why didn't I scroll personally on this
video? Like, there's probably a reason
why you chose the video that you just
did during your scroll session. Why did
you watch it? And ask yourself, do a
little self cycle analysis, right? I
haven't told any of my friends. I
haven't told any of my family. Why was
that sentence so relatable to people?
It's probably because it's his like
secret thing, right? There's no right
answer, by the way. It's your own
subjective interpretation, but it's his
secret thing. And I haven't told any of
my family like like creator is being
vulnerable, right? And you're going to
show I'm going to show you exactly why
this analysis I know it's once again
very tedious, but I'm going to show you
exactly why it's correlated with you
being able to get your first viral
video. Okay? Now, absolutely no one
knows I'm doing this. This one's it
doubles down on the vulnerability. It's
like more vulnerability.
I'm starting this like it's kind of just
reiterating at this [music] point.
reiterating
how difficult of a journey this is,
right? So, it's it's like he knows that
people are relating with the fact that
he's starting from zero. So, instead of
just saying it once, he's saying it
again [music] and again and again,
making you really feel it as a viewer.
That's at least what I experienced when
I watch this video. It's like, wow, like
I feel this pain that he's going
through. Or maybe not pain, but he's
feeling this [music] difficulty and
hardship. So, that's exactly the type of
feeling that I want to encapsulate in my
own video when I go on to step three,
which is remixing. But [music] once
again, I'm just going to finish it off
for the rest of the script here. My own
analysis on why I think the video did
well and resonated with people.
Okay, so we finished our analysis. We
finished step two, which is
transcription, [music]
and then the second part, which is
analysis. Now, step three is where the
magic happens. Now, let's actually start
creating the video. So, the way we
create the video is simply by remixing
every single sentence. Specifically,
analyze the sentence structure. Pretend
we're basically in English class here
and you want to see what the exact
sentence structure is and then instead
of using his words of let's say content
literally just replace content with
right just going to exit out here
replace it with vibe coding and that's
it. Let's start step three by remixing
our own version of the video now and you
can see that's literally the formula to
creating a viral video text hook
starting vibe coding at zero and boom
like I'm already feeling it now. I'm
like, damn, people are going to relate
to that cuz they're like, yo, I can
start it, too. Like, yo, I'm lowkey
thinking of starting it, too. Like, I
want to start it, too. Okay, I'm I'm
being mad, sassy. Anyways, uh I just
started this account. I just started
maybe instead of I just [music] started
this app and it's not a week ago for me.
I started it 45 days ago. So, [music] um
I started I just started this I just
started vibe coding this app 40 maybe
not even this app. I just started vibe
coding 49 days ago. Um with zero
experience, right? Cuz [music] he said
zero followers. I said with zero
experience. Um
uh maybe not zero followers. Is there a
better way to say zero experience? Like
maybe zero zero understanding. Now I
think experience is [music] fine. I
haven't told told
any of my friends. Now, this is hard
because I I mean, I've told all my
friends that I vibe coded. And I'm not
going to lie about this. So, it's like
it's his secret thing. How can I build
that feeling of like vulnerability and
intimacy with the [music] viewer, right?
Because when he's saying, "I haven't
told my friends, but I'm going to tell
you guys." It feels very intimate, and I
want to recreate that feeling. I haven't
told any of my friends. Maybe I'll just
say I have been losing money
on this project on trying to [music]
make this app.
I've been losing money. It's a similar
feeling of like, yo, like I'm in a hell
of vulnerable state. Okay, [music]
anyways, next sentence. Absolutely no
one knows I'm doing this. Absolutely no
one no one I know knows I'm doing
this. Once again, people people know.
And this is not the pain point when
starting an app, right? The the the main
difficult thing when starting an app is
more so like
hm what what is the actual relatable
pain point? [music]
Instead of maybe absolutely no one knows
I'm doing this, I could say
I have absolutely no clue what any of
this code means. I I think that's a good
way to create that relatability once
again because it's like I'm trying to
relate to the people who don't know how
to code just like this person wants to
relate to the people who are starring
content, right? I have no absolutely no
clue what any of this coding stuff
means.
Coding stuff. I don't know why that just
sounds like hella Gen Z talk coding
[music] stuff. I don't know what any of
this coding [ __ ] means. Um code [ __ ]
not coding code [ __ ] Um, I'm literally
starting this. I'm literally vibe coding
this from zero all by myself. Yo, I
don't even need from zero low key. It
just makes the video longer. All by
myself. Um,
I just want to prove that in 2026, if
you just start,
if you just start, if you just try, like
I could even just take those sentences.
If you just try, if you just
send instead of post, send a prompt to
Claude.
Claude,
even if you don't know what you're doing
yet,
that there's a possibility that this
could all
work out.
Oh, and then maybe instead of workout, I
can inject [clears throat] a little bit
of specific stuff towards app building.
It's like this could all become a huge
app one day.
Huge app. Ooh, I like that. Um,
okay. And we're almost done scripting
here. Just going to add a couple more
sentences. So, if you're watching this
right now, if I'm on your feed,
honestly, I'm just going to say those
words once again, like take a sentence.
If you're watching this right now,
if I'm on your feed, just know you're
here with me at the at the
beginning of a crazy journey as I'm
building this
to become and then I'm going to put a
little see the last the point of this
last sentence kind of tell the viewer
that I'm starting a journey and that
they're new and they're early, right?
because that creates this FOMO of being
early where it's like, oh, I don't want
to miss out if I'm early. I want to
follow along at the very start. You
know, people want to be or people want
to feel like they found their own unique
niche, little interest. So, as I'm
building this to become the number one
like content creation tool on the app
store.
Number one content creation tool on the
app store.
Uh, and how does he finish off the
video? Actually, I you know what, man? I
don't even know. Honestly, I'll just say
like
I I'll I'll finish it off with some
random sentence that I make up. This is
the only original thought I've done so
far, which is like we've made $2,000
so far. See you guys
soon. Okay, there we go. And we've
finished step number three, which is
remixing. Aka, if you've just followed
along and you've done this entire
process, you have just scripted your
very first video that is potentially
super duper viral. Now, obviously, I
want to give a caveat here. It takes a
lot of time and practice of building up
this repetition of like asking yourself
why certain sentences are viral. And you
can notice I started referencing these
small things like psychology and [music]
what would trigger a viewer's
psychology. It might sound like I'm very
experienced at this and I frankly am.
I've posted over like 2,000 videos. But
even if you have just consumed a lot of
content before, you already have a
decent intuition because you know what
it looks like to watch an interesting
video and you know what it feels like to
watch a hella boring video cuz you just
stroll past it after like 2 seconds. So
use that part of your brain and trust
your intuition. And I guarantee this is
how people pick up content a lot quicker
is when they start trusting their
intuition and they realize that their
like hours and hours of doom scrolling
actually have contributed to you
becoming a goated creator. Like you have
been practicing being a content creator
just by watching videos for years
probably and you just don't know it yet
because you haven't applied that same
part of your brain that just like chills
and doom scrolls on the toilet. Apply
that same part of your brain of like you
know that kind of doom scroller brain of
like yo like man this sentence lowkey
hella boring and I'd probably scroll if
I heard my some dude talking about like
you know vine coding and then he like
talks about some complex coding [ __ ]
So, I want to use the word code [ __ ] to
be like hella relatable and [ __ ] you
know, hella hella Gen Z cuz I like I
like watching people who are Gen Z. Use
honestly the intuition of who you like
watching and I guarantee you're going to
build content that attracts an audience
that really [ __ ] with you and that's
very similar to you. That's kind of just
what ends up happening with social media
and personal branding anyways. Okay, so
now we have the entire script of this
video. Now, I'm just going to switch
over to my iPhone and start filming this
video. Right. And to start off with
that, I'm literally just going to copy
whatever framing this guy did. So, you
guys can see here, he's leaning over on
a table. I don't know if he's he's
holding the camera with one hand. I know
it's very subtle, but you can kind of
tell like the camera is shaking a little
bit. Maybe that actually adds a little
effect of being very vulnerable and shy.
You also This video probably ripped him
like 5k followers just off of this
video. So, it's pretty crazy like maybe
we can we can replicate this effect. So,
um you know, I'm going to do this with
my hand and I'm just going to hold the
camera um like like so like this, right?
You can see, right? This is literally
the angle except I'm going to use the
front camera here. Okay, I'm just going
to rip this angle here. Um maybe I
should put on a long sleeve shirt
because he seems a little bit more shy
if he has a long sleeve shirt on. I
don't know, honestly. I'm going to do
that real quick. Let me grab a long
sleeve.
Yeah, I'm telling you the these small
things sound really stupid and like
low-key autistic, but they do add up
because man, like this guy could be
low-key like the most confident like
charismatic guy, but you wouldn't know
that. He seems kind of shy on camera.
And I think that's kind of like the med
the appeal of this like low-key handsome
Asian man like acting hella shy and
[ __ ] Like, yo, why is he acting hella
shy and [ __ ] Like, so I don't know. I
I'm just like psychoanalyzing this guy,
but I'm gonna show the baldness a little
bit. I'mma like rub my shoulder a little
bit, you know? I'll do a little little
bit of this, a little bit of that. And
I'm just going to open up the um it
helps. You don't have to have like you
can do this entire process on your
phone. And I do it very often on my
phone, but it does make it easier if you
have your script open on your laptop and
then you're just filming on your phone.
So, I'm going to start doing that here.
You guys can see this is my process. So,
I'm just going to open up the camera app
here and let's just start. And one pro
tip that I want to give you guys right
before filming [music]
is uh obviously I'm probably going to
try and act a little bit shy by doing
like the same camera angle and motions
and [ __ ] but like I I want you to try
reading the script front to back as much
as possible. This is a pro tip. A lot of
people will read one sentence, pause,
read again, then say another sentence,
pause, say another sentence, pause, and
it makes the entire video feel
potentially choppy. [music] So a pro tip
is just try reading the entire script
front to back. Okay. So, let's let's
start by just doing that. I'm going to
read two sentences at a time. So, I'm
going to I just started vibe coding 49
days ago. It's your experience. I've
been losing [music] money on this on
trying to make this app. Wrote that
wrong.
I just started vibe coding 49 days ago
and I've been losing money on trying to
make this app.
I have absolutely no clue what any of
this code [ __ ] means.
>> [music]
>> I'll see you guys very soon for the next
update of this app. Peace.
And there we go. 2 minutes of filming
and we're done. We are done filming.
Okay, we are almost at the finish line.
If you've followed me up until this
point, pausing the video and trying this
live with me, I commend you that like
you are goated for doing that because
you are literally right there to almost
finishing your video. So, now it is time
to start editing on our phone with Cap
Cut. So, if you want to learn how to do
that, just go to the link in the
description, just buy my course. No, I'm
just kidding. We're going to hop into
editing here on Cap Cut. And I'm just
going to press the plus and toss in this
[music] video. Press add. Oh, wait. No,
that's a screen recording. That's not
the right one. It's this one. Two 2
minutes in. I'm just going to delete the
other footage by scrolling rightward on
the timeline, pressing that, and
pressing delete. Okay. And that's how
you delete footage. Also, delete this
cap cut watermark at the end. You just
never want that to be there. So, select
it by pressing it on the timeline, which
is that second lower half of the the um
the screen, and then just hit delete.
Okay. Next, what we're going to do is
watch through the entire video. Um, oh,
if you haven't already, this is a weird
thing that just happened because I
attached the screen recording, which is
the wrong aspect ratio. Scroll at the
bottom until you see this thing called
aspect ratio and just make sure [music]
it's set to 9 by6. It's a small hack,
but a lot of creators mess this up when
they're first starting. [music] And then
just make sure it's actually resized to
the right ones. And then let's just cut
out all the dead space. Now, you could
go through the hassle of watching the
entire thing, which won't take that
long, but an easy way to do this quicker
is just hit that transcript button right
there, and boom, it's going to basically
auto transcribe your videos clips. Crazy
thing is you can just literally cut your
video by looking at the text, not even
watching it through. Um, so it's going
to save us a little bit of time. I'm not
going to let AI do it for me just
because it might be inaccurate. And I'm
just going to select on the parts that
are
not necessary and I'm just going to
delete them by pressing the remove
button. Right. Um,
okay. And this I think this whole part
I'm just going to select it and delete.
I've been losing money on this app.
Okay. Delete that. I have absolutely no
clue. Um, I said it twice so I think the
last time I said it is [music] the best
take. Delete. Delete. Delete. And I'm
just going to delete all of these
sentences that are not part of my script
or at least that I know are not part of
my video because you know your your
video and your script the best. So, as
I'm doing this, feel free to start maybe
pausing and transcribing and then
editing and deleting your clips as well.
Okay, there we go. So, we've done the
rough cut. Now, what we're going to do
is just do the actual like more fine
cuts because the transcript based
editing sometimes can be a little bit
inaccurate. I just started vibe coding
49 days ago and I've been losing money
on trying to make this app.
And there we go. We've cut out all the
0.1.2
seconds of dead space. And now we're
just going to look back at the actual
edit of the app and or edit of the
video. I'm just going to notice a couple
things how he did his text. So if you
look closely here, you can see the
there's this white text captions at the
bottom and then of course he has his
text hook at the very top. If I just
refresh and watch it again, this is the
editing style that we're going to match
here. So I'm going to teach you guys
exactly how I'm going to copy this one
here. Now, editing is one of these more
minute skills, but I'm going to show you
guys how I add auto captions and add a
text hook and make sure that I also make
my uh font look the same as his. So,
luckily, I think this guy actually did
edit on Cap Cut, so it's very easy to
replicate. First step was we're just
going to go to text and auto captions
[music] and generate here. And he does
his auto captions pretty small towards
the bottom. I think that gives a little
bit more of this like authentic feel to
the content or feels more raw. So,
here's how we're going to do it. First,
we're going to go to style. Then, we're
going to go to styles again. And then
just press that like X there. And then,
boom. We've pretty much just replicated
his his uh his editing style, but I'm
going to I'm going to make sure it's a
lowercase. I I like that effect. I just
started I just started uh is it the same
placement? Yeah, it's pretty much the
same placement here. Vibe coding 49 days
ago, and I've been losing money on
trying to make this app. I have no clue
what any of this code [ __ ] means. I'm
literally just vibe coding by myself. I
just want to prove that in um I don't
like how it's in a separate line. So,
I'm just going to make these separate by
pressing return. I just want to prove
that in 2026 if you just start I'm going
to separate these into separate lines.
Go ahead and return here. If you just
start if you just try if you send one
prompt to chat GPT even if you don't
know what you're doing it there's a
possibility that what you're build
doing. I'm going to remove it. that's
not part of the script.
There's a possibility that what you're
building can turn into a massive app one
day. So, if you're uh these are
separate, so I'm going to press return
and then make sure that the green
caption box, I'm just going to press
them to realign them. Apple one day. So,
if you're watching this right now, if
you're seeing me on your feed, just know
that you're that you're watching
somebody.
Um
I'm going to hit return here. be
starting this journey with you as I try
to build this to become the number one
content creation tool on the app store.
And we've made $2,000 so far just from
posting these videos and vibe coding
this app. So, I'll see you guys very
soon. Now, cool thing is this guy
doesn't even have to add music. So, I'm
not even going to add music here. Like,
if the if the info video didn't add
music, like you don't need to add music,
you know? Don't don't need to overdo it.
Like honestly, if if the video editing
worked and you're new to video editing,
I would say actually don't force
yourself to try all these new effects,
animations, sound effects, especially if
the video that you're inspired by isn't
doing them, you know. So, one pro tip
though that I'm going to do is I'm
actually going to adjust the volume by
just hitting one of the clips, hitting
volume, pushing it up to like 300, and
then hitting loudness adjustment.
And boom. That should just make all of
the clips like 300 400ish volume. Um,
and then lastly, I'm just going to add a
text hook. So, hit text, [music] add
text, and then starting.
Um, should I say vibe coding or coding?
I'll say vibe coding. I think that's
more of a hot term right now.
Ving vibe coding at zero. Um,
there's a little bit less contrast and I
think he has it on screen for around
like 5 to 10 seconds. So, I'm just going
to leave it up on screen for like 8
seconds. App. I have no clue what any of
this code [ __ ] means. I'm literally just
vibe coding. Yeah, I can move the
captions up a little bit more. You don't
want it to be too far to the right
because then it's blocked by the like,
comment, share buttons. And then you
don't want to be too far to the bottom
cuz then it's going to be blocked by
like the the uh username and caption,
right? So, just avoid those those zones
on the bottom and the right side. Okay.
And you know, I think I should add a
little bit of shadow just cuz this one I
know it's a little bit different, but
it's a little bit hard to read the white
text on the white ceiling. So, I'm going
to hit style on the text. Hit styles
once again. Go to shadow, the black one.
And I don't want it to be too harsh of a
shadow. I don't want it to be too
noticeable. I'll do like 20% opacity and
maybe like 20% blur. That's like a small
hack there. I just started vibe coding
49 days ago and I've been losing need
that much of shadow. I'll do like 10%
shadow opacity actually.
Code ship means I'm literally just V.
And lastly, now he has two screenshots.
I don't know if you paid close attention
to the inspo video that I'm studying,
but he used a screenshot of a I think
picture of his follower account. So
instead of a follower account, I'm going
to screenshot a picture of my app on the
app store. So, Scout
Scout AI.
Okay.
Um, and I'm just going to install it,
too, just so I don't have like the whole
test flight thing here. I'm going to
screenshot it. I'm going to maybe crop
it a little bit and then hit that check
box. Um,
that little save to photos. And then
what we're going to do
Oh, and I've been losing money on And
then I'm just going to add an overlay.
Add overlay. go to photos and add this
into it. And I'm just going to do that.
>> Losing money on trying to make this app
I have and I'm only going to leave it on
screen.
>> I have no clue what any of this code
[ __ ] means. I'm literally means [music]
and now I'm just going to add one
overlay of a video. And I'm going to
explain exactly why I'm doing this part
cuz it's a little bit more particular.
But just so you know, I'm getting paid
for this. And this correlates back to
how I'm actually getting paid to make
these videos with this thing called UGC.
But just for all intents and purposes
right now, I'm basically just going to
add one more overlay that shows me using
this app, which is called Anything AI.
And it's a company that I'm actually
getting paid to do UGC for. They didn't
sponsor this video, by the way. They're
just low key. I'm I probably should be
getting paid more cuz my account's
lowkey popping AF. But so far, we've
gotten paid around like $4,500
from them. So, pretty good side hustle
as well on this page cuz I got paid
$4,500 for 15 videos, [music] right? So,
here's exactly what I do. Means I'm
literally just vibe coding by myself.
And I'm going to split here and just
make sure it only stands on screen for
2.3 seconds by myself. I just want to
prove that in 2026. And lastly, at the
very end, I'm just going to add a
screenshot of the $2,000 store. And
we've made $2,000 so far. So, I'm going
to go to [music] my revenue cat for my
actual app and then just show my like
revenue, like total revenue.
So, I'm going to do this. I'm going to
do this. I'm just going to toss that
into the video one more time. One more
overlay with the photo. I'm going to
toss that at the very top so it doesn't
cover my eyes. When possible, I would
say try not to cover your eyes. It's a
small editing hack, but viewers like to
watch eyes. And if uh your eyes are
blocked by something on top of the
screen, it can be slightly less
retentive and slightly less engaging for
a viewer. So, small small hack for
editing. And I'm just going to trim it
to fit the clip like this.
>> Just from posting. And there we go. It
is done. So, now we are on to the final
step, which is posting the video. So,
what we're going to do here is just uh
make sure to hit that top right corner.
And these are the exact settings that
I'm going to show you how guys how to
use in Cap Cut. So, we're first going to
change the resolution to 4K. All right.
And then we're going to turn off AI
Ultra HD. Do not let Cap Cut AI affect
your your videos. I don't know. It
always just looks ugly, right? You want
it to look authentic, right? So, 4K 30
fps bit rate. Just do the recommended
for the video. Don't turn on optical
flow and don't turn on smart ad HDR.
Okay. And then we're just going to hit
export in the blue button top right.
We're just going to wait for this to
finish exporting on the video. So, we
are almost done now. We've we've
scripted, we've filmed, and now we
finished editing, right? And this whole
process, [clears throat] mind you, I was
also talking to you guys while doing
this process. It usually takes me half
as much time, but it's only taken me
about 30 minutes so far, right? So, it
should take you guys also a relatively
similar amount of time, maybe if it's a
little bit newer for you guys. [music]
It's okay to take an hour. After that,
what we're going to do next is go to
Instagram and also post it on Tik Tok as
well. Cross post it across both
platforms, but we're going to go to
Instagram first [music]
and then hit the plus in the top left.
Then, we're just going to select the
video, hit next. I just started vibe
coding 49 days ago. And now we're just
going to put a caption. Now I'm actually
just going to see the caption that he
used. Um the info video said, "Is this
the year that you finally start?"
[music] And then he put a bunch of
hashtags at the bottom. So
maybe I'll just say start vibe coding
with me. Let's change our lives
together.
And then at the bottom, I'm just going
to put a hashtag. Now, once again, this
is correlated with how I do UGC. In
order to track UGC videos that I can get
paid for, I have to add this this um
this hashtag. So, I like to put #
anything cuz that's the app that I'm
promoting. And then is possible after.
So, it's a little bit sneakier, you
know. And then all I'm going to do now
is press share. And boom, there we go.
Keep Instagram to finish posting. So,
obviously I'm going to I'm going to keep
the app open as it finishes posting.
Now, by the way, if you want to join our
community where you can hop on live
calls with me alongside three other
coaches every single week who can review
your content and tell you exactly what
to fix, what is missing for it to go
viral. You can just apply to join the
community in that first link in the
description and we'll see if you're a
good fit. Obviously, it's a paid
community because you're receiving the
direct coaching from me and a bunch of
other experts, but we have a super
supportive community. We've literally in
the last year had 10 plus people make
10K a month from the community in their
first year creating content. We've had
countless people hit 10,000 followers. A
couple people even had a 100,000
followers from the community. So, if you
want to be a part of it, right, and dial
in your content for 2026, go apply and
book a call with our team in the link in
the description. But anyways, we just
finished posting onto Instagram and we
are almost almost done. I'm going to
post it to Tik Tok as well. Okay. So,
I'm going to go to Tik Tok
>> and I'm just going to press the plus at
the bottom and I'm going to select this
video.
>> I just started vibe coding 40
>> and I'm just going to say the exact same
title. So, it's like um start vibe
coding with me. Let's lock TF in and
change
our
our lives.
together.
Okay. And then I'm just going to put the
same hashtags. Anything 161 is
is possible.
And I'm just going to press post.
>> 21 days ago. I had this IP.
>> And boom, bada bing. We are now
cross-osting it onto Tik Tok. Okay, we
are almost almost done. Right after
this, I'm going to show you guys exactly
how I get paid to make these UDC videos,
which is a sneak as an extra bonus just
for you guys for staying until the end.
I'm going to teach you guys exactly how
to get paid to make videos as well. So,
you can not just start learning how to
create content and build your personal
brand, right? But also get paid to
learn, which is a crazy opportunity
that's going on right now. Um, and it's
called UGC where you can basically get
paid to make videos promoting certain
apps. Okay, so once this video [music]
finishes uploading. Okay, so we have
finished posting the video onto both
platforms. Now the last bonus step to
actually start getting paid for your
videos is download an app that helps you
do UGC. There's a couple like Sideshift
Methods. There's another one called
Launchpoint, right? You can download any
of these apps and start getting paid to
join these UGC programs for apps [music]
who will start paying you just to start
posting. So, right, for example, on this
account, I've gotten paid now $4,900
just to post promoting this app called
Anything, right? And I'm going to teach
you guys exactly how I just post on this
app. So, first step is I just go press
this plus in the bottom right and then
all I have to do is select which program
I'm posting for. So, in this case, it's
this app called Anything AI.
I'm going to go here. I'm going to skip
because I didn't use their script. I
just actually made my own, right?
[music] Which is a huge, huge bonus if
you actually want to succeed as a UGC
creator. A great way that you can stand
out and get just an insane advantage is
[music] do this process of creating your
own script, right? Instead of trying to,
you know, just copy like most other
creators do, the scripts that a lot of
these programs will give you, [music]
you can actually just make your own
script using this viral video process.
And this is how I've been able to grow
an account, you know, to 30,000
followers in the in just like 15 videos.
[music]
Okay? So, you know, it's a huge huge
bonus if you're also doing other types
of content, whether you're building an
app like I like I showed you guys with
those 15 videos. Not only did I get paid
$4,900 [music] to, you know, on the app
that I'm building, but I also made
$2,000.
I also made $4,900 promoting with UGC
content, you know. So this style of
content works for [music] anything.
Whether you're selling, you know, an
app, whether you're doing UGC, maybe
you're promoting your coaching or
something. You know, all of these styles
of business model, all these ways of
monetization can work through [music]
creating viral content like this. And
yeah, basically once you can upload the
video, then you can get paid like I did
on this video, right, which is the
previous video I posted to this UDC
account. And if I check the payouts,
right, I got 70,000 views on this video,
[music] which gave me a payout of $150
just for, bro, that's like 30 minutes of
work, which is crazy. So, [music] if you
want to get opportunities like this, we
can actually directly plug you into
these kind of opportunities of UGC
programs in our private community
content academy where we have a a
basically a Discord channel that we're
sending new opportunities to via your
email as well every single week. And of
course, we train you every single week
as well on four live coaching calls on
how to create viral content and how to
improve your content. So, you can just
apply to join Content Academy and book a
call with one of our onboarding
specialists to actually get you
onboarded inside Content Academy and see
if it's a great fit for your personal
goals in that first link in the
description. That being said,
congratulations. You've just made your
first viral video. You've walked through
the entire process of making a viral
video in just basically the past couple
minutes. So, if you enjoyed this video,
honestly, just [music] hit the subscribe
button and I'll see you in future, guys,
where we walk through all the nuances of
creating viral content without spewing
all these BS tactics and content
strategy. Honestly, I think that's kind
of stupid. I'm just going to teach you
the actual raw skill, which is what you
actually need. You need [music] to learn
the raw skill. You need to get a bunch
of practice in and then just start
shooting out a bunch of reps and then
one video can literally change your
life. And that's exactly what I want to
do on this channel [music] to help you
build a career as a creator long term.
Let's [ __ ] get it. I'll see you guys
in the next video. Peace.