What the hell is up with all these AVGs
promoting study apps on Instagram reels
lately?
>> I studied like an hour. Let me put you
all in this method because finals are
here. Just upload your textbook or any
study material into
>> if you've been scrolling Instagram
[music] reels over the past like 6
months. You've probably seen a bunch of
Asian girls and a couple Asian dudes
making a harmless innocent video about
study tips until you see what the did he
just mention? The cluey AI. Why do I
keep hearing these kids mention these
same three AI study tools in every
single one of the videos? Well, this is
no accident. This is no coincidence.
[music] It's actually a secret
underground money-making method. And I
have had the pleasure of befriending
many of the founders of these AI study
tool apps who've revealed to me their
secret hiring method and how they've
been paying [music] up to 10 $15,000 in
a single month to these ABGs and also
ABS to make videos promoting their study
apps. So the goal of this video is
actually not just to tell you how this
[ __ ] works and like why it's happening,
but also how you can get in on this gold
rush right now. UC user generated
content. It basically means videos that
brands will pay you to make for them.
Now the interesting thing about this
method of UGC [music]
study app ABG methods of promoting and
marketing apps is that traditional
marketing is always hire big influencers
with millions of followers, pay them
hundreds of thousands of dollars. But
about 2 years ago, these AI study tool
founders found a really interesting
exploit. Instead of paying these [music]
Charlie DLOs of the world, which most of
their audience doesn't even watch them
for study content anyways, why don't
they actually handpick the ABGs from
college campuses who've never really
posted content before, [music] maybe
posted one video and train them in
factory farms to become viral content
creators to mass market their products.
This was the birth of ABG UGC. Now, when
I say brands have been paying like 10K a
month plus to just regular college
students to make these [music] videos, I
am not kidding. I know dudes who have
literally gotten paid $17,000 in a
single month promoting an AI app and
they've only been posting videos for
like 3 months. They're practically
beginners now. I don't know about you,
but I always grew up thinking, man, if
only I could be a YouTuber [music]
because all I'd have to do is work like
2 hours a day filming these silly little
videos and I could just be rich. I would
grew up watching people like Ricegum,
Ryan Higa, and back in the day, I don't
think YouTubers even made that much
money, but I just thought the idea of
[music] being able to create content for
a living and make a liveable wage was
cool as [ __ ] So, when I heard about
this thing called UGC where they're
literally factory farming beginner
college students into content creators
and then shilling them tens of thousands
of dollars a month in their marketing
budget to make videos. I was shocked and
I took an extremely deep dive and that's
exactly what I've done. So, for the past
6 months, I've actually been talking to
a bunch of these AI study app founders
asking them exactly what kind of ABGs
are they hiring? Do they hire nonABGS?
And how can you and I you're probably
not an ABG. Is it possible for a nonabg
to also get hired and make [music] money
with this thing called UGC? Now, the
answer to all three questions is yes.
This is how you get hired to do UGC.
First step is to actually go to one of
these job hiring platforms. And a lot of
these apps actually don't need you to
have much experience posting content.
That's the cool thing. Posting content
doesn't require you to have a degree.
You just realistically need to have
Instagram reels installed [music] and
create a new account. That's about it
actually because content creation and
social media is such a new industry.
There is no MBA and PhD for content
creation. Now, here are some of the best
hiring platforms that I believe you
should check out. Number one, methods.
It's an app on the app store. You can
literally just apply to any of the UGC
programs. Another one's called
Sideshift. It's just another job hiring
platform. There's another one called
Home from College. They all look the
same. You can just apply to a bunch of
these AI study app UGC positions. A lot
of these apps actually have hundreds if
not thousands of people applying for
these positions now because yes, there
are literal kids making $10,000 a month
posting reels for them. So, if you are
one of those ambitious kids who actually
wants to get hired, how do you actually
get hired? Because you do need to stand
out in an applicant pool of like 2,000
people. Step two is to actually post
your first video. Now, I know that
sounds daunting. So, I actually made a
video on how you can post your very
first video. I'm just going to leave
that in the first link in the
description cuz I actually been trying
UGC as well. I made $4,000 posting like
16 videos onto this new Instagram reels
account over the past 2 months. And I
made a video tutorial documenting my
entire process of doing that. So go feel
free to check that out if you actually
do want to start making videos and
getting hired Instagram reels doing UGC
for brands after you've somewhat
mustered up the guts to post your first
video, which I will not lie is probably
eliminating half of you guys watching
this video right now because most people
do not want to actually put their face
out there on the internet, which is
okay. But if you've actually somehow
mustered up the courage to actually do
that, you've now basically signified to
the brands that you mean business, that
you are actually essentially open to
hire. So on most traditional jobs, in
order to be open to hire, you might just
throw on like slap on a hashtag open to
hire on a LinkedIn. With UGC,
realistically, you just have to post
your first video and that will honestly
make you stand out enough in an
application pool where you might get
hired to your first UGC opportunity.
Step numero tress. How are people
actually making $10,000 [music]
a month with this? Like for example, I
just told you guys I made around $4,900
in the past like 50 days posting on this
brand new Instagram account. How did I
do that? Now, there's two ways that pay
structures work in the UGC AI app space.
The first one is something called base
pays where these apps will pay you
basically a base salary just for posting
videos. [music] A lot of these UGC
programs will pay anywhere between $30
to $40 per post. I personally got a
really cool UDC program with this app
called Anything and they paid me $50 per
[music] video. That means no matter how
many views the video got, I got paid $50
just to post a video promoting their
[music] app. Let's say you just brute
force consistency and you post 30 videos
for an app that's paying you $50 a
month. You just earned yourself $1,500
[music]
just for showing up. Now, however, I
didn't say we were in the business of
just making $1,000 a month. How are kids
making $10,000 a month? That's where
something called view bonuses comes in.
Now, a lot of these brands won't just
pay you the base [music] retainer. If
your videos actually go viral, like they
get over 10,000, 50,000 views, they're
going to start paying you higher
amounts. This is an example chart of
[music] basically how a brand might pay
you if you do get over 10,000 50,000
views. Let's [music] say you posted a
video and it got no views. It's okay.
You will at least get the [music] base
$30 base pay, right? But then let's say
you had a video pop off. Okay, you got
the base $30 base pay, but it got bumped
up to $100 because you got 20,000 views.
And then let's say a week later you
check in and you're like, "Holy [ __ ]
it's at $100,000 views now." Well, now
you just earned yourself $300. And let's
say in a month's [music] time you wake
up and you're like, "Holy [ __ ] this
video is at a million views. This random
[music] Instagram reel study app ABG
promoting video that I spent 2 hours on,
it's it's at a million views." you just
earned yourself pretty much like $1,000
just for like 2 hours of [music] work.
That is how UGC works. And that is the
magic of doing UGC. Now, I am not
promising that you're going to be able
to do this. Honestly, the largest
factors towards whether you're actually
going to make money from this is one, if
you actually show up and are consistent
on I'm I'm genuinely serious. If you can
just be consistent, you will get hired
and you will make money. But if you do
want to make like $10,000 a month,
biggest thing is you need to be good at
hooks and scripting. [music]
This is a nuanced skill in short form
content creation and it is basically the
skill set of being able to brainedly
capture somebody's attention in the
first 3 seconds and actually make them
pay attention without making them
scroll. So, how are they going to get to
your AI study app promo part of the
[music] video if they can't get past
your first 3 seconds? So, here are some
example hooks from these ABG study app
videos.
>> If you're the person that told me this,
I could kiss you right now because it
literally
>> You'll notice some of them are like kind
of thirst trappy. like they've literally
thirst trapped you into watching the
video and you can kind of see it in the
comment section. Now, if all of this is
super duper [music] confusing to you,
that's completely fine. I completely
understand. I've now built a whole
agency that helps hire creators to
brands. So, if you do want to be one of
those [music] creators, I'm running a
free class teaching any of you guys how
to actually start doing UGC and get
hired literally in your first month as a
content creator. And that free master
class is happening literally in about a
week's time. So, go register in the
second link in the description and I'll
teach you exactly how to start doing
this uh UGC thing. But yeah, now you
know, next time you see an ABG or a WBG
or an AB WB, okay, next time you see a
stranger on your for you page on
Instagram reels promoting subtly some AI
app, now you know they're probably
making a [ __ ] bag off of it. I'll see
you guys in the next video. Peace.