This is how I grew 30,000 followers in
the span of 30 days on a brand new
Instagram account. And after posting
just 15 videos, each of which just took
two hours, I was able to blow it up to
35,000
followers. And we're going to be
covering in this video the exact method
that I used to come up with the idea for
my page so I can blow it up. What my
actual workflow was for the winning
formats that I used and the actual 2hour
per day workflow that I used to make
these viral videos. Now this is my fifth
time blowing up a personal brand. It's
the fastest I've ever done it. I have
this other account on Instagram. my main
account where I document building my
business and I've also helped countless
other people in my paid community
content academy do the same. So, it
doesn't just work for me. It doesn't
just work in one different niche. So,
let's actually jump into [music] the
method. Let's start off with how do you
actually come up with a account series
idea. So, what is an account series
idea? It's basically the bigger picture
thesis for what you're actually making
videos about. So, in this page for
example, I'm in the niche of vibe
coding. These are the 15 videos that I
posted. So, if I actually pull up one of
these videos, I can show you guys what
the actual idea of the account was. I
want to make an app without writing a
single line of code and make $10,000
from it in just 30 days. So, the idea is
simple. Can I make an app and make
$10,000 from it in just 30 days without
knowing how to code? Now, this is real.
I actually don't know how to code,
right? And you can see throughout the
progression of this account that I
actually was learning how to code,
learning how to more so use AI to build
an app. And as a result, I was able to
then, you know, start blowing up the
account with these videos. Now, you
might be thinking, ah, man, like where
do you come up with such a good idea for
a page? Now, a lot of people say with
personal branding, the idea is the most
important thing. When it comes to
YouTube, for example, people say that
the idea for the title and the thumbnail
is literally 50% of the battle in making
a viral video. And the same goes with
your page. So, you don't want to spend
the next 90 days building your personal
brand, posting every day, slaving away
at a shitty idea that nobody cares
about. Okay? So, how do you validate an
idea for your page, which more so
realistically means just how do you
tailor the messaging so it actually hits
with people, which could be just the
tweaking of one or two words. Now, for
example, if I just said, "Can I learn
vibe coding in 30 days?" It's a very
similar concept, but I guarantee the
account might only be sitting at like
3,000 followers if I did that. So,
here's the actual applicable steps that
I took to blow up the Instagram account
and find the banger idea and make sure
that it's actually validated. I call it
the YouTube method. Now, 80% of short
form ideas and pages trail YouTube ideas
because the most intelligent creators
optimize for YouTube simply because it
pays better. So, big picture, the thesis
means or the thesis for your account
should literally just come from YouTube.
go on YouTube, search up whatever
keyword of your niche that you are uh
making videos in, and then find an idea
from YouTube. So, the idea for my
account actually literally came from
watching this one YouTube video, and I
felt incredibly inspired. It's this guy
named Blake Anderson, and he said, uh,
how I built a no code app and hit 10K MR
in, uh, 30 days, right? And that was the
whole idea for the the video. So the the
big picture thesis that I want to
explain to you guys is just think about
whatever niche that you are actually
trying to target with your account. Now
I know you might be thinking, "Bro, I
don't I don't know what my niche is. I'm
going to become the niche." Shut up.
Shut up. Unless you are a content genius
or you are an established influencer
with a big name online, you need to pick
a niche because you need to capitalize
on what people are already thinking
about and wanting and have a demand in.
So if I just came out and said, "Guys,
here my name's Mino. I'm unemployed.
guys, watch my journey of being like a
Mino, I guess, you know, talking about
my random [ __ ] interest about like
Celsius and [ __ ] Those videos would not
get views. I need to target a niche. So,
I picked vibe coding. Um, a topic that I
was actually just frankly interested in
personally. So, another rule of thumb
here is if you're picking your account
thesis and your account niche, think
about what you're just inherently
interested in. Now, it's going to take a
little bit of work because I actually
had to go out and build an app and learn
vibe coding in order to make this series
happen. So, I'm not going to say just
wave your wand, snap your fingers, and
then just speak on camera and people are
just going to love you and watch you. If
you want to actually have your your most
guaranteed, I guess, route to blowing up
your personal brand, you want to pick a
niche that actually has market demand
and then find messaging on YouTube that
actually uh has gone viral. So, I went
and searched up no code app, and you can
see this video right here is literally
number one. How I built a no code app
and hit 10K MRR. So, that literally just
became the thesis for my page. So then I
went I took how I built a no code app
and hit 10K MR and I just put that on my
page, right? So it's like the AI that I
used to code. It was this app and just
to prove that this is not just me like
spitting hogwash here. I did this for my
other account as well where I did a
series of road to 100K a month as a
broke college student and I actually
took that idea. You can literally see I
watched this video on YouTube. I went
from broke to rich in 30 days from this
guy named Jordan Welsh. So a lot of
times you as a aspiring small creator
should not be trying to think of
yourself as some Da Vinci trying to
reinvent the wheel of content. No. So
now you should have written down on a
piece of paper what niche you're going
to be targeting and then what is the
general thesis or series idea and
honestly frame it as a uh a YouTube
title. So for example, if you're
thinking let's I'm going to use the
example vibe coding again because that
is the actual page that I blew up. vibe
coding
equals my niche, right? Then I want to
ask myself for the uh title of my
series,
what what is it going to be? So, I could
be thinking like learn learn vibe coding
with me. Now, I could say that's my
niche, but would this blow up on YouTube
as a title thumbnail? Well, based on
what I'm seeing here, usually no. This
one's more controversial. It's no code
app development is a trap, right? Right.
So, that one's a more controversial take
here. Let's see another one. Right. You
don't need to like how to build your
first app with no code. So, this one's a
little bit better and more specific. How
to build your first app with code. So,
maybe that could be more so. It's like
how to build your first app, right? And
now we're tailoring the message a little
bit with vibe coding,
right? And we're tailoring the message
even more and more. how to build your
first app with vibe coding or without
coding. Clearly, that has uh market
demand and you're going to see that
actually play out in the way that I
frame my hooks in my videos. But how to
build your first app without coding
seems to be the title of my series. And
if I want to make it even more
interesting, I could say like how I
like how I built my first app without
coding grew it to 10K a month. and even
better bonus points if I'm actually
documenting it live. So, what I did was
I actually went and watched this video
and actually watched like what was he
actually doing? And you can see here,
this video is basically him uh walking
through his actual live process of
building the app and you can see him
this is literally him coding. So, I
thought to myself, hm, if that's
probably the reason why people watch the
videos because it's an actual live
demonstration, why don't I do that on my
own page and document myself literally
from day one, not knowing how to code?
So, you can see here, this is the video
that I made.
I'm literally pulling out my energy
drink, pulling out my laptop, and
starting coding with AI by shooting a
prompt into the AI. So, I don't want you
to go out into building your personal
brand on Instagram or Tik Tok without
some validated idea or thesis for how
you're going to stand out. Because if
you don't go with at least some plan to
differentiate yourself from the crowd,
you're just going to look like all the
other clones who are trying to film
themsel every day talking about some
random [ __ ] in their life. You're
not going to build an actual following.
And the more viral of an idea or the
more striking and shocking of an idea
that you can strike with this title of
your series, this thesis, this
hypothesis more so of your page, the
more quickly you're going to skyrocket
your growth. Now, I'm not saying that it
has to be as good of a thesis as like
how I like trying to build my first app
without coding to 10K a month. But the
better that it's going to be, the more
efficiently that you're going to grow.
So, it only took me 15 videos to
actually grow this page because the idea
itself was so good. The videos
themselves don't actually have to be
that insane. But you might be thinking
here, okay, I have a decent idea now.
You have it written down on a piece of
paper or Google Doc next to you. Good.
Good job. How do you actually then turn
them into winning videos? So, this is
the exact process that I did starting
off with actual ideation. And I call
this method Zoink and Twist. Credit to
this dude named Luke Bulch on uh on
YouTube. He actually talks about this
method called Zoinket twist which
basically means find a winning idea on
short form by doing some research and
take inspiration from it and then twist
it into your niche. So for example,
these are all the formats that I
actually won with POV uh you just like
XYZ. I'll put them in purple here.
Person A versus Person B XYZ changed my
life and is it possible challenge. These
are all the winning formats that I use
and there's realistically only four that
I needed to actually blow up my page.
You don't even really need four formats.
Just every single day try and find one
format that you see going viral on
Instagram or Tik Tok and then translate
it into your thesis/niche.
So I see a lot of people doing POV style
videos in the fitness niche. POV style
videos in the uh maybe student niche or
studying niche. I didn't see somebody
apply it to the vibe coding niche,
right? Especially because vibe coding is
just a hot trending topic and it's new.
So, there's not going to be as much uh
as many people attacking that niche
right now. So, I found this nice gap in
the market with POV. Your app got
accepted to the app store without
knowing how to code. And this is a live
reaction of me reacting to my app
getting on the app store. I literally
just remade that video. I remade that
video with a different camera angle. I I
filmed it twice. I got a million views
twice on that [ __ ] And if I actually
tally up the views that those videos
got, I don't know if I can actually see
it on the laptop. I'm pretty sure most
of these followers, like at least 20,000
of them came from just two videos. So,
that's how your personal brand's growth
will likely happen. Um, they're likely
going to come from just one or two
videos. Don't expect your growth to be
happening from like every single one of
these videos. It's going to be
consistent. No, it it's really like 8020
or 9010 where 90% of your followers are
going to come from 10% of your videos.
And that's exactly what happened. So,
this one video, right, 1.3 million
views. If I scroll down, it got me
12,000 followers. If I can get my camera
to focus here. This video got me 12,000
followers. this single video uh about
getting my app on the app store, right?
>> So, a lot of times your best video will
pretty much get you all your followers.
The second format that I did is person A
versus person B, which is just like a
clone thing where there's a person A 50K
a month versus 50K a year and they're
just like conversating with each other,
comparing their lives to each other.
Another one is XYZ changed my life.
Here's another one. AI vibe coding
changed my life. I'm just talking about
how I even started AI vibe coding. And
then an is it possible challenge where I
say is it possible to you actually saw
that video is it possible to build an
app without knowing how to code and get
it to 10k a month in just 30 days. Okay,
so those are the formats that I used.
And how do you actually find then your
winning format to go out and make your
own viral video? That's a great
question. What I want you to do is
actually I want you to go on to reels
just keep scrolling until you find a
couple parameters. [music]
One is is it above 5K or 10K likes?
That's usually an indicator on reals
that the video is pretty viral, over 5K,
over 10K likes. Uh, which usually
translates to around over 100 to 200,000
views. And that's usually an indicator
that the video went super viral. So,
here's another one. How I average five
likes per video, right? So, you can
honestly just take that, right? If I
were to actually go and zoink and twist
this video that I found right here, how
I average five likes per video, I'd
probably do it something a little bit
like this. So, now that I have my inspo
video, right? This is my idea that I
This kind of looks like a penis, but
we're going to ignore that. Uh how I
average five likes per video. Maybe then
I would just do how I
uh
Okay, this is my live brainstorming
process. It's not going to be that good.
Like five
bugs [music] per code. That makes no
[ __ ] sense. So just hear me out here.
Obviously, sometimes when you directly
copy an idea, it's just going to be
stupid and you're going to be like,
"Okay, well, I can't really copy that
idea." twi switch it up a bit, twist it
a bit, right? So, how I average, maybe
instead of how I average, it's just like
how I got an app uh on the app store in
4 days. Then maybe I'll toss in because
I know this will be part of the
inherently viral concept of my page
without coding. Boom.
now and I would and I would specifically
right we already know this was going to
be my kind of thesis for the page but
what I can do then is if I were to
actually simulate the video I would
literally copy the camera angle I'm
going to go and uh copy the camera angle
of this video where it's like me looking
at a screen right and just propping up
my camera and holding a laptop
and then maybe I'll throw up screenshots
like screenshot screenshot screenshot on
the page. SSS standing for screenshot
because that's what he did. He put
screenshots of results on his page. Now,
obviously, the reason why this one went
viral is because it's funny. It's
ironic, but for my own page, maybe this
could actually be value, right? And
then, um, yeah, this one also has like
the read caption style where he puts the
actual instructions in the caption. But
maybe I'll actually, right, it's like my
version
actually put value in the caption of how
I did it, right? And there's a ton of
examples where this is actually the
format. I just found I just happened we
just happened to stumble across an
ironic version that's funny. But you're
going to see a lot of examples of this
style of video. It's like the how I did
XYZ read caption style. you I like these
formats don't actually have names but um
right it would be like the rec caption
uh how I did XYZ video format the I you
know I I I can just like place names on
these formats but you know there's no
[ __ ] like textbook telling you that
this format's going to be called the is
it possible format just ends up being
like that once a bunch of people copy it
and that's literally how this is the
exact process that I use to find all
these viral videos now that is the
essence of the zoink and twist. But
you're probably wondering, okay, you've
given me all this theory. How do you
actually go and apply and do it in just
2 hours a day? And I wanted this video
to actually be directly applicable for
you so you wouldn't be just left uh, you
know, jerking yourself off to the idea
of making videos, but you can actually
go out and do it. So hopefully you've
been somewhat following along. And I
actually implore you to go out and find
like open up on a Google doc, find an
outlier, open up YouTube, and write down
an idea that you found on YouTube.
Hopefully you can do that and you can
come back just pause this video and then
come back because none of this will be
applicable to you unless you actually
have an idea for your page and you start
having viral format ideas that you can
start implementing on. So how do we
actually then implement on it in a way
where we can do it in just 2 hours a
day. So I have these three parts. First
research outliers. So let's say we
already did that. The second one is to
film in one take. Um, I'm not going to
go too ind depth on filming because
like, you know, filming is just [ __ ]
filming. [laughter]
Like, just [ __ ] film yourself, bro.
It's not that deep. No, I'm just
kidding. There's two pro tips I have for
filming to actually make sure that the
videos actually come out natural. One is
you want to index for emotion. You can
see here, this is the first frame of the
videos, and it's it's super slight, but
I'm I'm very clearly like emoting on
emotion. So there's like excitement
here, there's sadness here, there's
hypeness here, there's excitement here.
You really want to make sure the first
frame, the first 5 seconds isn't just
you being monotone as [ __ ] If you're
just standing there like, here's how I
vibe coding an app to 10K. But holy
boring, bro, you are so boring. Stop
being boring. Okay, the way you can do
that, honestly, just fake an emotion.
Like you don't actually have to be that
hype. I was actually pretty hyped
because I actually was pretty excited to
see my app get on the app store, right?
Right? You can even see here this is me
like you know being cocky maybe and the
other emotion is like like skeptical,
frustrated. Um so that's another example
of just showing emotion. So that's one,
right? Really try to make sure you're
getting into an energetic state when
you're filming so you I I know it's
unnatural. I do want to note it's really
[ __ ] unnatural to pull out a camera
and be like, "Hey guys, today we're
going to be going out and doing a day in
the life of vibe coders. Oh my gosh, I
feel great. Obviously, you know, it's
going to feel [ __ ] weird, but just
force yourself to do it. I promise. I
promise yourself. Especially my straight
dudes watching this, cuz I know 80% of
my viewers are [ __ ] straight dudes.
Especially for my straight dudes out
there. If you want to actually print
money with your personal brand one day
and become a big figure online. Get out
of your [ __ ] nonchalant shell for
once in your goddamn life, bro. And
actually show yourself emoting some
expression for the first time in your
life. Okay? One, it's going to make you
so much more interesting as a speaker.
Look at me now. actually emoted right
now. And two, it's going to make your
videos so much more interesting because
nobody wants to watch something who
somebody who literally clearly does not
want to be on camera right now. Force
yourself to feel an emotion. So, how do
you do that? Right there there's two
things I always remind myself before I
start filming. One is to get into a flow
state. And the second one, in order to
get into a flow state, then is to get
endorphins rushing through my body. So,
there's a couple things I do. One is
every time that I caffeinate in a day,
I'll always usually try to film like in
the 60 minutes after I've caffeinated.
This one's a little bit of a hack, but
basically um it it's really easy to get
into your own head and get kind of down
emotions like you know your emotions are
probably going to have this weird
cadence where you know they're kind of
up and down like you know they're
they're spiking. This you got to really
be conscious of like when do your
emotions spike in the day and you want
to be filming here. Um, now an event can
happen that can cause you to spike in
emotion. Like for example, my app
getting accepted to the app store. But a
lot of times you actually have to
provoke this emotion to spike because
you're not just going to naturally feel
hyped, right? So a key to do this is uh
one is caffeine. So I'm going to draw a
little energy drink here. First one is
caffeine. The second one is exercise.
Uh, so for those of my friends here who
actually do work out, working out right
before you film can be a huge hack
because your body has more endorphins.
It's in a little bit more of an
energetic state and you're probably
feeling a little bit more free flowing.
You're not overthinking your words.
You're not overthinking what you're
saying and thinking. That's exactly what
I did. I worked out about like an hour
ago uh before before I actually planned
out this video and then I uh started
drinking a Celsius as I was filming this
video.
Okay. Okay. So, I highly recommend you
do that because it's kind of like
filming drunk. Um, for those of you guys
who I I know this is such a terrible
freaking analogy,
but think about like when you're most
risy, it's probably after you've had
like one or two shots of alcohol. You're
not overthinking. Your inhibitions are a
little bit lowered. I actually think the
same applies for filming content. Or
this is like another side tangent.
Sorry, I I'm like low-key kind of ADHD.
Hopefully, this is helpful. [laughter]
But sometimes too, you can film in a
lower energy state. So, this is an
example of a video where I was actually
more in a sad, somber state. And I was
actually like kind of crying before I
filmed this video. Uh, you can call me a
[ __ ] but like, you know, I was
actually like pretty sad because I was
um, you know, talking about why I
started the page and I was feeling kind
of emotional and reflective. So, I was
actually like in a down state. So, you
don't have to always be happy, but you
want to show some emotion. [music] Okay.
Lastly, and this one's actually really,
really huge. This one's like [ __ ]
huge alpha that I usually charge people
for, but I call it the minimum viable
edit. Okay, so you're probably wondering
here, you know, I understand all the
filming and ideation and scripting part,
but how do I actually edit? So, I have a
very special special lesson planned for
you guys. I'm actually going to open my
phone and show you guys on Cap Cut my
exact editing flow, so you can see
literally the three most important
things to index for when you're editing.
The first one is to cut dead space
ruthlessly. The second one is auto
caption and the third one is how to pick
your songs. So, let's actually hop over
to Cap Cut and I will show you guys how
I edited one of my most viral reels that
month. All right, so I have my most
viral video open on Cap Cut. And you can
see I I know there's a couple complex
things with overlays happening, but I'm
really just going to focus on the first
thing, which is cutting out dead space.
Dead space is basically any time in a
video where you have over 0.2 2 seconds
of pausing in speech. So that's why you
can see so many cuts here. Like there's
0.9 seconds, 3.3 second clip, 6.5 second
clip, uh 0.4 second clip. So you can see
what did I actually do here?
>> Sped the past three.
>> Um so if I actually were to add back the
dead space, this is what it would look
like.
>> Just an idea.
>> Sped the past. So, instead of letting
that dead space actually stay, which
carried on throughout the entirety of
your video, will make your video feel
incredibly slow, incredibly slow paced,
just grab the uh white little scrubber
on the timeline and pull it as far back
as possible without cutting yourself
off. Idea.
>> And you can see you might want to
overcut it. You want to overshoot it a
little bit just to see what it looks
like to overshoot an idea. The
>> So, okay, ID. Now, it's starting to cut
off. It says ID instead of idea. So
maybe add back 0.1 seconds. And you want
to play in this 0.1 second range. If you
want to get even more precise, I
actually highly recommend you uh pinch
with two fingers on the timeline and
pull outwards, pull this way so you can
actually get more close and you can go
frame by frame in the video just to cut
out the dead space. You don't have to do
this for for the entirety of your video,
but just when you're cutting out the
dead space of 0.1, 0.2 seconds, I
genuinely believe it's so helpful.
Secondly, auto captions. You might
actually notice here uh there's there's
a text hook of POV blah blah blah blah
blah. But at the bottom, you might
notice, bro, we just got accepted to the
app store. Holy [ __ ] There's three
things that I did with the auto
captions. First off, if you want to
learn how to add auto captions, you just
hit text and then auto captions, and you
can hit generate. Now, there's clearing
current captions cuz I already have
them. So, I'm not going to hit clear
current captions. But uh once I actually
did add the auto captions, here's the
exact styling that I did. So you want to
hit the auto caption box, hit style, and
then the first thing that I did was I
used a template and I actually have this
saved, but it's a two words at a time.
You want to find this one, the quick
brown fox. I think it's somewhere in the
uh basic section. And you might actually
need to upgrade to Cap Cut Pro in order
to unlock this. But some of these don't
require Cap Cut Pro. Um like some of
this one, the quick.
>> Bro, we just got accepted to the app
store. Holy.
>> Now, this looks okay. It looks fast
moving, but you're like, "Yo, this looks
kind of lame." And I don't know how to
describe it. It looks like it was just
made by some like fourth grader doing
their class project. That's very normal.
What you want to do now is go back to
the style section, hit the uh remove the
the border border,
>> and you want to add a Tik Tok auto
captions here. So, actually I have it
saved into my font, but if you just go
into the classic section and you just
search classic, you want to find the
exact Tik Tok auto caption, which looks
like this one. I I know it's uh or or
looks like this one. I know it's super
precise, but there's classic 2, classic,
classic go. Honestly, any of them work
like at this point, we're playing with
minutiae here, but you want to select
the Tik Tok auto captions on classic.
The reason why you do the classic font
is something I genuinely firmly believe
in, which is visual familiarity. You
want the visuals to be familiar to the
viewers. So, I always use Tik Tok font
in my videos because it's the most
familiar to viewers. If you're not using
the Tik Tok font, you might scare
viewers away being like, I don't know,
this looks a little foreign and a little
unfamiliar. I don't really like how it
looks. So, I highly recommend you just
use the Tik Tok auto captions. It's the
safest bet when it comes to captions.
You don't you don't want to think of
yourself as some cinematic Da Vinci
coming up with some new font. Oh, I'm
going to use this like Times New Roman
looking font. Like, yo, people are going
to think I'm hella artsy. hella artsy
and [ __ ] Nine times out of 10, people
are going to think your video is weird,
amateur, annoying, hard to read,
illeible. You just want the most
convenient font that's easiest to read.
It's the Tik Tok classic font in Caput.
Don't overthink it. I guarantee once you
make this change and you start adding
auto captions this way, your your views
are probably going to double. I can
almost guarantee it. Okay, and that is
exactly how I add the auto captions.
Now, it has this weird animation cuz I
choose the wrong one, but hopefully you
actually can find the the uh the one
that says like quick brown fox without
these weird like flashing in fade in
fade out animations. Lastly, music. Uh
this one's very very very common
question that I get asked about my
videos. The the first thing that you
want to do is find a song that matches
the vibe of your videos. So, you want to
ask yourself, what emotion am I exciting
inciting in my viewer by watching this
video? Clearly here I'm reacting to uh
my app getting on the app store. So what
emotion am I showing here? There's not
one right answer, but there's definitely
wrong [ __ ] answers. Okay, took a
guess. Good. It's excitement. It's
getting hype. It's getting, you know, up
energy, high energy. Now, it's not
[ __ ] sad music. So, you don't want to
put like, you know, corecore sad edit
music over this video. It's just going
to sound really weird and it's not going
to feel right. And the biggest reason
why somebody will actually stay and
watch your video is because they feel
something, not because they're
cognitively thinking, "Wow, this video
was so intelligently put together." No,
people are going to be watching because
they feel something. Whether it's
feeling excited, whether they're feeling
pissed off, whether they're feeling sad
because you wanted them to feel sad,
right? They want you want them to feel
something. So, your music should match
the emotion that you're trying to make
them feel or else they're going to
scroll because they felt nothing in the
first 5 seconds of your video. As a
result, they're going to scroll and hit
that dopamine slot machine to hopefully
feel another emotion 5 seconds later
after they've scrolled past your video.
Boom, your video's flopped, got no watch
time, got zero retention. So, in order
to avoid that, think critically about
what emotion trying to strike in your
viewer with your video. Then, then then
you want to find the instrumental to the
song on YouTube, right? Uh, so let's
see. Congratulations by Post Malone was
the uh was the actual song that I used.
And then I just search up instrumental.
And the reason why you want to use an
instrumental is because you don't want
the lyrics of the song like clashing
with your voice. Oddly enough, I
actually didn't use an instrumental for
this one, but pretty much for every
single one of my other videos, I only
ever use instrumentals. And then lastly,
lastly, lastly, when you add your music,
it's usually going to be too loud. So,
what you want to do to make sure that
the music doesn't overpower your voice,
turn down the music to u to a lower
volume. So, you can see I believe this
is the audio that I added. I turned down
the music to around 30 40% volume. And
the reason why is because if I turn it
out too high,
it's probably a little bit harder to
hear my voice and understand what I'm
saying. So, I usually turn it down to
40%. So, my voice is the primary focus.
What I'm saying and narrating in my
video is the primary focus. The music is
just an additive uh emotional element,
but you don't want it to overpower your
video. So, that is how I edit my videos.
We just covered in the video one, how to
ideulate a broader thesis for your page
using YouTube research. The second,
we've covered how to actually find
winning formats by scrolling on
Instagram and zoinking and twisting them
into a viral format into your hypothesis
for your page. And then we covered how
to film. And lastly, how to edit in a
minimum viable editing, which should
only take you around 30 minutes to
maximum an hour if you're still a
beginner. All in all, that whole
process, every single day, if you're
doing it, should probably only take you
like 2 hours to make the videos. And
that is how I grew 30,000 followers in
the span 30 hours. Now, once again, this
is just a small percentage of what I
actually teach inside my bigger
community. I have a paid community
called Content Academy where I have
about like 12 hours of guides walking
through everything on how I make my
videos, how I script, how I think about
hooks, how uh we have a list of like 300
viral hooks that you can just steal as
well to save you some time starting your
personal brand. So, if you're looking to
start your personal brand, going all in
on it, you can feel free to apply down
below to join our paid community content
academy and we will help you blow up
your personal brand. But uh we have very
high demand right now. So you might not
be able to book a call. So just check
down below and see. Okay. Thank you guys
so much for watching. I'll catch you
guys in the next one. Peace.