Everyone tells you [clears throat] to
start posting content in 2026. Start a
personal brand, it's going to make you a
millionaire, but no one actually tells
you how to do it. So, in this video, I
want to reveal to you guys my four-step
framework that helped me grow 500,000
followers in the span of 2 [music] years
while growing my business to 100k a
month. Okay, step one. Most of you guys
think you need to pull out your camera
or start scripting right away and start
thinking and brainstorming of ideas. I
actually think that is completely
[music]
wrong. What you need to start with is
researching and scrolling on the For You
page or the explore page. So, that's
exactly what we're going to do. We're
going to open up Instagram [music] and
just literally start doom scrolling,
okay? Yeah, I just ended up [ __ ] doom
scrolling. What am I doing? And what
we're looking [clears throat] for
particularly is ideas that match both my
niche and format. So, my niche for my
personal brand is very simple. It's
related to the business that I run,
which is helping people start their
personal brands, make viral content, and
make money with content creation, right?
And then everything surrounding that.
So, that's my niche. And the format that
I do is talking videos or guides,
anything realistically that I'm just
talking to the camera. So, that's what
I'm going to be looking for
>> [music]
>> on my Reels. Either people talking about
similar concepts like starting a
business, starting a brand, or anybody
who's [music] just talking and giving
advice. So, let's actually jump into it
and let's just start scrolling and
watching all the content.
Mhm, this one is a pretty interesting
video and it's in my niche and format,
but I'm specifically looking for any
videos that are outliers, particularly
any videos that have gotten over 5,000
or 10,000 likes. That's usually my
indicator that a video is viral and it's
proven by the algorithm to actually
work. That way we can actually then just
copy it and templatize it. So, that's
literally what we're going to do. And I
call this phase phase one. It's
research. So, I'm just going to be
looking through and let's see this
video.
Okay, so this one actually does match
actually everything and it's very lucky
that we found it two scrolls in, but
it's a talking video uh about the niche
of day trading in this case. And I'm
just going to check if it actually is an
outlier for this channel. So, it looks
like it. 1 million views. Oh my gosh.
And he has 68,000 followers. That is
pretty much the biggest sign that the
algorithm thinks it's a good video. And
what does that actually mean? It just
means that all of the people that the
algorithm on Instagram has tested and
showed the video to have actually had
high watch time on the video because
that's all the platforms optimized for,
not some stupid freaking post times or
hashtags. No, it's just whichever videos
garnered the most watch time and
engagement from the users on the
platform. So, let's see. Here's my
trading strategy explained so simply
that a 5-year-old could understand. What
am I going to do?
Here's my content strategy explained so
simply that a 5-year-old can understand.
And it's as simple as that. So, now I'm
literally just opening up a Google Doc
and starting the scripting process. So,
I call this step two, which is when
we're going from research to actually
scripting. And you might think that
scripting requires insane levels of
originality and probably fluency and
being an incredible writer. And I
honestly think that's not really true,
especially if you are a beginner, you
don't have tens of thousands of
followers yet. Don't rely on your
intuition. See what works on the For You
page and put a spin on it. That is the
number one tip that I can give you to
instantly get your viral video tomorrow.
It's find a proven viral concept. Do not
try to reinvent the wheel from scratch
and then rewrite it in your own words.
That's what we're literally going to be
doing here today. Guys, that is the
method to getting your first viral
video. It is not by trying to be
original and trying to reinvent the
wheel. So, let's actually do it. Let's
see. Start on the weekly timeframe.
[music] And all I'm doing is writing
down his sentences and then under that
I'll probably just write my own version.
So, start on the blank. Right? That's
kind of the framework that I'm coming up
with here. So, in this case, start with
the algorithm.
It's taking notes on everything that I
am noticing both from what he is saying
as well as what are the visuals on the
screen. Because with short-form video,
it's not just a written platform or
spoken platform. The visuals on the
screen also matter. So, I'm also writing
down he puts very simple charts as
visuals. And the reason why I think this
is so helpful is because the video
itself is about his trading strategy
explained so simply that a five-year-old
can understand.
And in this case, too, I can even write
some bullet points on why did that go
viral? Trading strategy sounds like a
complex thing that most people want to
learn, but honestly can't even fathom
understand it. And the reason why I'm
actually writing down this thesis is
because I actually am not 100% sure if
content strategy is the right wording to
make the video go as viral as possible.
And now we're thinking more in the
psychology of the viewer's minds. And
this is getting a little bit more
advanced where it's not just copying,
but now it's critically thinking about
who our viewer is and what would
actually resonate with them. So, in this
case, they're probably appealing to
beginners to day trading, right? So, who
is my audience? Well, I'm probably
appealing to beginners to content
creation, and that is the ideal viewer
and ideal customer that my business
serves as well. So, here's my content
strategy explained so simply that a
five-year-old can understand. Instead of
content strategy, maybe it's here's how
to go viral explained so simply that a
five-year-old could understand.
Actually, I like this. This is our hook
right here. So, a hook, if you guys
aren't familiar, is the first sentence
of your video, and it's the key to going
viral because it is the make-or-break
sentence where you either capture your
viewer's attention or you essentially
repel them and make them want to scroll
instantly off of you. So, you have to
make sure you have a really compelling
idea and words that actually resonate
with what your viewers want to see. So,
that can be even comedic stuff. It can
be trending topics. In this case, I'm
appealing to the wants and desires of my
ideal viewer persona. We have the first
sentence. Instead of start on the weekly
time frame, maybe instead we say start
with the hook. Boom. The first sentence,
for those of you guys who don't know.
Maybe that's a sentence. Price go up,
you look to buy. Price go down, you look
to sell.
I'm [snorts]
going to talk through my viral video
creation process here and my thinking is
that like video is viral, you look to
copy. Video isn't viral, you scroll.
Start with your first sentence. Maybe
instead of saying price go up, price go
down. I like this analogy but it doesn't
really apply to content here. It doesn't
really apply to my niche which in my
niche it's content creation. So instead
of saying X go up and Y go or X go up
and X go down, maybe I could say pick a
viral proven hook. Show visual on screen
of list of viral hooks. Change two
words. In this case, I really do need to
show this visually because this is
actually kind of hard to explain in the
video. Video is viral, okay, we're going
to skip that cuz we already did that. Go
to the daily time frame. You know, my
brain instantly thinks viral content
creation is too difficult for a
five-year-old to understand. I need to
actually add nuance to the point where a
five-year-old cannot understand. But the
video is about a five-year-old actually
being capable of understanding content
creation. So in this case, I probably
have to dumb down my concept. I guess
this is another lesson with content
creation scripting like viral content
scripting. A lot of it is dumbing down
your concepts and simplifying it so it
fits within a 60-second video. If you're
watching this video, you might be an
expert at whatever topic or niche that
you're covering. Maybe you're a fitness
creator and you know all of these
complex things about muscle maturity,
muscle endurance, time under tension,
blah blah blah, you know, big complex
scary words. And you kind of want to
prove that because you have this ego
that wants to prove that you know what
you're talking about to the people. But
in reality, you need to be thinking
about what is your hook and how does
every single sentence tie back to your
first sentence. Here's how to go viral.
I like how to go viral. How to go viral
is a good outcome. Start scrolling
TikTok. I think TikTok is a word that
resonates harder with the audience. Now
I'm going to post this video both onto
Instagram Reels and TikTok. Let's just
say TikTok for now. Open TikTok. That's
even simpler for a five-year-old to
understand, right? [music] Stop on a
viral video. Write down their first
sentence.
Ah, so he uses charts as visuals. So he
uses visuals to explain a very simple
concept. [music] Change one word from
their sentence. Maybe in this case I'll
put visual of blank Google Doc changing
words. Cuz I like the idea of a simple
clean visual because that's what they're
using as well in the viral inspo video.
Note, I guess from the inspo video, he
>> [music]
>> uses baby talk. It's like big candle,
small wick. He doesn't use complete
sentences. Write down first sentence,
change one word from sentence. So
incomplete sentences, open iPhone
camera, film speaking sentences, open
CapCut. At this point now I'm kind of
just talking about editing. [music]
Ironic because this video is actually
also about how to make viral content, so
it's pretty funny. I honestly don't even
understand what's going on in this Day
Traders [music] video. This is an
interesting tidbit for me on why it went
viral. Maybe it's because a lot of
people don't actually understand what
happened here.
Hm, open CapCut, click auto caption,
TikTok classic font. The thing is this
video actually has real sauce, so I do
need to make sure this is my video
actually has real sauce, too. Here's how
to go viral explained so simply that a
5-year-old can understand. Open TikTok,
scroll, stop on viral video.
Write down first sentence. This is a
hook. I do want to explain some things.
I do think that does help the video
actually perform well. I'm not copying
exactly word for word here because
obviously we're talking about different
concepts. This is his hook. Now you have
viral hook. Do this for their whole
video. Now you have a viral original
script. [music] Film speaking sentences,
press record, speak, mess up. Right, cuz
I want this video to actually be
relatable and valuable. Keep recording.
Press stop, open CapCut, click auto
caption, TikTok I think this is the part
that's actually valuable cuz it's novel
information. On at this point, all of
these are going to have like b-roll
visuals, overlays on top of it. And I'll
show you guys how to do that later on in
the video. I'm just going to write that
down here. B-roll overlay. It's like a
close-up shot of the CapCut app [music]
on an iPhone. So, I'm actually going to
film this shot later. Click
auto-captions. TikTok classic font.
Something about this video, I'm not
going to lie, I'm looking at it, it
feels bare. Feels like yes, I am
explaining a way that a five-year-old
could understand, [music] but it feels
too simple and basic to the point where
it's not going to be valuable. So, this
is a key lesson for any kind of talking
content. You need to actually have some
unique value that a viewer will walk
away being like, "Oh, wow, this video
actually was helpful." So, [music] I'm
trying to think now. This This is where
I really need to empathize with my
viewer. A viewer knows generally what
CapCut is. They know what a hook is.
Now, you have a viral script. Maybe I
could talk about lighting. Lighting is
something that's also really helpful for
making viral videos. Mess up,
>> [music]
>> keep recording. Press enter, so it is
two words at a time. Press return, so it
is two words at a time. Let's see what
the Inspo video did. Here's how I create
viral Instagram Reels, explained so
simply that a five-year-old can
understand. I think this is it. I think
this is it. Open Instagram. Scroll. Stop
on viral video. Write down first
sentence. This is their hook. Or I
guess, read script. Mess up, press
return, all captions fit in one line.
Now, you have a viral edit. Open
Instagram. Press post. That's it. That's
how I've made all of these viral videos.
Point up at screen. Honestly, [music]
this is it. And I I think I can read
over the hook one more time. So, the end
of the scripting process is just me
essentially doing a revision and
thinking through clearly, one, does it
make complete sense? Are there [music]
any points that are hard to understand?
I really want to highlight here, if your
video is hard to understand, your
viewer's probably going to scroll off
your video. Especially in a 60-second
video, it's really easy to lose
comprehension or for a viewer to get
confused.
>> What do you mean by that?
>> And you just have to ask yourself,
[music] if I were a stranger watching
this video of this Asian dude with the
short hair on his For You page yakking
about creating viral Instagram Reels,
would I ever have any points where I
just want to scroll off it for any
reason? Maybe I get confused, maybe I
get bored, maybe maybe I stop believing
in him, right? So, let's actually read
through it. Here's how I create viral
Instagram Reels explained so simply that
a 5-year-old can understand. Write down
[music] first sentence. This is kind of
confusing. So, notice here, I'm reading
aloud the entire script [music] word for
word. And I'm reading it aloud. I'm
seeing how every sentence flows. And I
know this is kind of tedious, but me
actually reading everything aloud
>> [music]
>> helps me understand how the entire video
flows together, so at no point does it
feel robotic or confusing. I can say it
from sentence to your niche to a keyword
from your niche. So, this The difficult
part of me saying this is that it's the
most helpful version of the advice, but
it's not simple enough that a 5-year-old
can understand. Write down first
sentence. This is their hook. Change
three words from sentence. [music] Now,
you have a viral hook. Repeat for entire
video. Honestly, I think it's I think
we're at the place where [music] we can
record it. Now, I I do want to
highlight, I'm literally going to make
all of this on my phone on iPhone. I'm
not going to use
>> [music]
>> like an advanced camera obviously cuz
I'm recording it here. So, I want to
show you guys that you can literally
make viral Instagram Reels straight from
your iPhone
no other equipment. So, let's jump into
the actual filming process. And I'm
actually doing this in the morning cuz
it's [ __ ] 1:41 a.m. And I'll show you
guys my actual viral filming uh protocol
so I can get into the mood to help you
guys bring out the most charismatic,
natural, authentic version of [music]
yourself onto camera so then you can
attract the audience of people who [ __ ]
with you for [music] you and also want
to be your die-hard fans and customers.
So, I'll see you guys in 2 seconds. 1 2
Good morning. It is currently 10:30
a.m. the next morning. About to crack an
energy drink. Hold up. Oh, actual mess,
dude. So, something I like to do before
I film is I just chug an energy [music]
drink. It helps me just get out of a
groggy state cuz right now, honestly,
I'm just really [ __ ] tired. And I
think a lot of being on camera is
confidence and feeling like you're best
version of yourself. And whatever that
looks like to you, for me honestly, that
just means getting like really high
energy state, you know.
My landlord just scammed me for $7,000
this morning, so I'm not feeling great.
We're going to have to get into a better
energy state right now. But okay, we're
feeling good. Here's what we're going to
do. I'm going to hop onto my iPhone and
I'm just going to basically screen share
half of what I'm doing on my phone as
well. Now, for those of you guys who
aren't great [music] at memorizing
scripts like me, I have the memory of an
absolute goldfish. Don't worry, I'm not
going to force you to memorize your
entire script [music] front to back. I
actually have a hack for this and I call
it the transcript inside CapCut. So,
what I want you guys to do is first off,
open up the script on your phone. So,
I'm going to go to the Google Doc
itself, find the actual video real
script, highlight the entire thing.
Okay, I'm going to copy it. And what I'm
going to do is I'm not going to go into
the iPhone. I'm actually going to go
into CapCut. [music]
Then inside CapCut, I'm going to go
scroll down until I hit camera. I'm
going to flip the camera, do 3 minutes,
and then hit teleprompter. And basically
from here, I'm able to just paste. I'm
going to delete the previous script that
I had in here. And I used this method a
couple days ago to get a [music] video
that is sitting at I think 120,000 views
on TikTok. So, a lot of it is obviously
not just reading [music] off the script,
but making it seem really like you're
not reading off the script. That is the
whole goal with this is you still want
to bring good energy on camera, at least
the best energy you possibly can, and
the most natural feeling energy you
possibly can. [music] Right? Not just
exaggerating words just for the sake of
exaggerating words. Like you still want
to make the viewer feel like they're
talking to a real human being. So, that
is the goal, and that's what we're going
to do. I also I'm just going to change
the settings so it's it's a little bit
less fast, and all I'm really going to
do [music] is think now about the
lighting and the framing of this video.
Usually, I'll just hold it on my hand,
or I'll just put it down on like a desk
or something, and I think that's what
I'm going [music] to do. I'm just going
to put it down on a desk. Believe it or
not, this is literally what it looks
like right now. Computer, camera, and
then right under it I have literally
just have it stacked on top of some
books. I'm just going [music] to put
this on top of the books that I've
stacked as well. You're wondering why
I'm wearing AirPods, too? I'm actually
listening to Brain FM on my computer.
This is not freaking sponsored. Uh I
don't have any sponsors on this video
except my [ __ ] self. But, basically
what I'm doing is putting in focus music
where I I believe it's a certain
frequency that helps your brain focus.
But, honestly it just helps me drown out
all the background noise. Noise. I was
watching this interview of this creator
who has like millions of subscribers,
and she says that she specifically puts
on noise-canceling headphones, and then
just blasts music whenever she's filming
in public [music] to cancel out all of
the stimuli from everyone around her so
she can just focus and be super locked
in on the camera. I think it's been
helping me film YouTube videos, as well
as also filming these videos on my
phone. So, yeah, it's a little hack as
well. Just turn on some like meditation
music basically onto your AirPods, and
[music] it'll help you get in a flow
state. One other thing I like to do is I
like to uh
just get a good stretch in, and make
sure I take deep breaths before I film
so I can calm my nervous system. I I
want to show up on camera with an energy
of like, ah, like, ah, like feeling very
awkward feeling very tight and rigid. I
think it's actually very common for me
to feel this way on camera, especially
when it's like earlier in the morning.
Maybe my brain is still thinking about
other parts of the business and I need
to obviously context switch back into
being as charismatic a person as I
possibly can be for the camera. And
we're just going to hit record. It might
not happen on the first take, but I'm
going to try and get this all in one
take. I'm visualizing somebody in front
of me. Here's how I create viral
Instagram reels explained so simply that
a five-year-old can understand. Open
Instagram, scroll, stop on viral video,
write down first sentence. This is their
hook. Change three words. Oh, [ __ ] that
up. It's fine. Change three words from
sentence. Now you have a viral hook.
Repeat for the entire video. Now you
have a viral script. Open iPhone camera,
press record, read script, mess up, keep
recording, press stop, open CapCut,
click auto captions, TikTok classic
font. Press return so all the captions
fit in one line. Now you have a viral
edit. Open Instagram, press post. And
that's it. That's how I've made all of
these viral videos. Yeah, it's it's
super [ __ ] simple. I think the video
itself that the other guy made was
around like 30 seconds. So this is good
timing. I think the video itself was
fully finished in around 40 seconds. So
let's just watch back the video. I'm
actually going to take off my AirPods
cuz they just stopped playing. Let's
actually see now and we can just jump
into the editing process straight from
here. Basically, now what we're going to
do is press the check box at the bottom
right. And just see how the audio turned
out.
>> viral Instagram reels explained so
simply that a
>> Yep, audio is good. I'm going to hit
edit here in the bottom left. And now
we're literally in the editing process.
You fully scripted it and you fully
filmed and now we're about to fully edit
our video. And once we do that, it's
ready to post. So let's actually do it.
I'm going to make sure to cut out the
dead space at the very beginning.
And then I mess up here. So every time
that I've messed up and I have a
sentence that I don't want to keep, I
always make sure to uh split, press on
the uh clip in the timeline that I press
split, and then I cut out the bad bad
part of the sentence. Change. And then,
right here, I'm going to find this
little frame right here. I think it's
around this point that I'll actually
start speaking, and then I'll just
highlight the part in the middle and
press delete.
Like this. These three words from
sentence. Now you have a viral hook.
Repeat for the entire video. Now you
have a viral script. Open iPhone camera.
Press record. Read script. Mess up. Keep
recording. Press stop. Open CapCut.
Click auto captions. TikTok classic
font. Press ret- Oh. Pro tip here. I
noticed I have around half a second of
dead space, give or take. So, what I
want to do here, if you can I'm going to
play one more time. Very specifically
notice the time when I take a breath.
I'm I say TikTok classic font. Press and
that's about 0.5 seconds. But that 0.5
seconds makes the video feel slightly
slower. I can keep it in there, but I
think it makes the video drag on ever so
slightly. So, my preference, and this is
not an absolute rule by any standard,
but I highly recommend, especially as a
newer creator, that you are more
vigilant on dead space, which is any
space that you take a breath,
>> [snorts]
>> or any space that you're just not
talking, or you trip over a word. Try to
cut it out by doing what I'm doing here.
So, I'm going to press here.
options. TikTok classic font. I'm going
to split, and then yeah, I cut out about
0.2 seconds, actually. That's it. But
notice how much snappier it feels.
TikTok classic font. Press return so I
can actually maybe trim off now by
pressing the
previous clip and then just scrubbing on
the white part and pressing maybe
I'm dragging it leftward ever so
slightly. TikTok classic font. Press
return so all the captions fit in one
line. Now you have a viral edit. Open
Instagram. Press post.
And that's it. And I'm going to cut this
dead space here as well because I take a
breath. Post. And that's it. That's how
I've made all of these viral videos. And
I'm going to cut off the ending because
I want the ending to be snappy,
obviously. I'm going to delete that
part, and boom, there we go. It's a
30-second fully cut video. So, the steps
remaining for this video personally,
because right, I'm trying to match the
editing style of the Inspo video, I
highly recommend don't just blindly copy
the editing style that I'm doing.
Although, this is like a very basic
editing style, I want you to also pay
attention to what did you notice in your
Inspo video? Did they have B-roll or
text on the screen? Did they use auto
captions or did they not use captions at
all? Maybe they weren't even talking in
the video, and all of this part is kind
of just useless, and you're just
watching me yap on camera, but you're
not actually going to be even doing
that. I don't know. But, make sure
you're actually studying what the other
creator is doing, not just me, because
it depends on the style of video. If I'm
making like a fitness edit, obviously,
I'm not going to be speaking on camera,
probably. I'm probably [music] going to
be overlaying like a David Goggins quote
with some motivational music.
>> Real talk. So, guess what? You know
what? Hey, Darius knees are bad. Stay
hard.
>> For this video specifically, here's the
editing process that we're going to
follow. Now that I've rough cut the
video, the second part is I'm going to
add B-roll. B-roll, specifically
choosing shots that or choosing or
creating shots more so that actually
reflect what I'm saying in the script,
and then I'm going to add auto captions,
and then lastly, I'm going to add music.
So, that's about a four-part editing
process [music] right here. So, let's
start off actually with B-roll. And
actually, to do B-roll, I highly
recommend if you're going to go this
more cinematic, cinematic's a strong
word, but more intentional route with
your B-roll, where you do want to
overlay very specific clips onto your
video, let's hop on back to the
computer, back to our script, and let's
actually do a shot list.
All righty, we're back. Now, what I'm
going to do is I'm going to open up the
Inspo video. Once again, I just want to
take a quick gander at how he did his
B-roll, how he did his shots and
visuals. Trading explained so a
five-year-old can understand. So okay,
that's very interesting. He has trading
explained so a five-year-old can
understand in the middle of the screen.
I'm just going to take a mental note of
that cuz I'm probably going to edit that
way, too. But let's keep watching. He
has five-year-old can understand. I'm
just going to write this down, too. I'm
literally just going to take comments.
This is my preferred method of I guess
making viewer notes, but I I don't like
having this complex Notion document
where we have like on one side we have
the the script and the other side of the
shot list. I I don't know. I I think at
a certain point if you templatize your
creative process too much with like
Notion templates and all this [ __ ] it
just removes you a lot from the pure art
of doing it. But I I think it's
different if you have a whole team
behind you, but like that At the end of
the day, bro, short-form content for me
is pretty much a solo operation. So I'm
just doing this with mental notes so I
can quickly make the shots, right? So
here's how I create viral Instagram
Reels explained so simply that a
five-year-old can understand. I'm just
going to zoom in on this line, right?
Cuz he did a little zoom cut. I'm going
to show you guys one more time cuz you
guys probably didn't catch that. A
five-year-old can understand. So
actually zoom on five-year-old. And this
is all helpful because now it takes the
thought out of the editing process. It
doesn't require me to be hyper creative
while I'm editing. While like I'm doing
all the editing basically here in the
planning process, right? Open Instagram.
Open Instagram. So now it's a screen
recording. [music] Screen recording
opening Instagram. And then scroll,
right? And I'm kind of just writing like
this sentence equals X shot. This
sentence equals another shot. So scroll
then I'm probably Now I actually have to
think. I do want to do a screen
recording of me scrolling. I could do
There's two ways I'm visualizing this.
One is a shot where I'm literally just a
screen recording of [music] me
scrolling. Another one, however, I I
think there's a more comedic angle where
scrolling is kind of funny. [music] It's
like I want the scroll line to kind of
feel like, "Oh, man, this dude is just
doom scrolling." Like it's not that
deep, right? Cuz I think that helps me
visualize like what a 5-year-old would
understand. It's either a screen
recording just of a bunch of reels
scrolling really fast, and I want to use
very viral famous reels that most of my
viewers will probably recognize, like
funny [ __ ] memes, or I'm going to do a
shot of me scrolling in bed, and I'm
going to have this like third-person POV
where I am holding probably my phone
case. I'm looking at it, and I'm
probably doing this like gooner face,
like
So, those are the two shots that I'm
visualizing here.
Uh I'm going to say for the sake of
this, I think the gooner face thing will
be funnier.
Um and then stop on viral video. I think
here, this is where it's actually I
could either do the boop, like a
third-person POV of me stopping, but I
do think like extreme close-up of like
78k
plus likes. Yeah, I do think I'm going
to actually This is going to be really
[ __ ] meta, but it's going to be me
showing the video that I'm copying. I'm
literally going to probably pause on
this video and then show the like count.
And then write down the first sentence.
This is their hook. Write down first
sentence. In this case, I'm just going
to say blank Google Doc. I guess this is
kind of meta because if I'm showcasing
the process of how I made this video of
the reel, it's going to be this really
weird cyclical loop. Okay, I think I'm
overthinking this at this point. This is
their hook. You know, actually, I'm
going to
go back
to
face shot, you know, of the me just
saying, I guess. They call it A-roll.
And for those of you guys who don't
know, like quick little explainer with
Mido here. A-roll is the pure, like you
talking straight to the camera shot.
B-roll on the other hand is footage that
you overlay on top. So, right now, what
I'm seeing on the screen right here is
B-roll. But then, this is A-roll, the
shot of him talking. I think you guys
understand this, right? So, go back to
A-roll. And I'm probably going to
reference B-roll versus A-roll, B-roll,
A-roll here. Change three words [music]
from sentence. Changing
three words in the Google Doc. Now you
have a viral hook. I want to highlight I
I guess one thing I want to inject here
is kind of a dopamine hit for the
viewer. Like now you have a viral hook.
It's almost giving the viewer the
feeling of vicariously winning through
my content. I guess I say that in the
video so maybe my expressions can kind
of make the viewer feel encouraged. But
the whole goal of this video, right? And
I highly encourage you to also think
through this is to simplify the content
creation process in a way that anybody
can understand. I think that's the whole
goal of this video. So all of my B roll
decisions should inform all of my
editing decisions should be informed by
how I can achieve this goal. So if I
want to make my video as easy as
possible to understand
>> [music]
>> and I want to make it so a five-year-old
can start posting videos if they wanted
to, that means that I should probably
also not just cater to helping people
understand, but also make them feel
emotionally excited
um because I I feel like a lot of the
learning process when it comes to
content creation or learning any new
skill is not just about understanding
things, but it's about getting excited
and feeling motivated, invigorated, and
positively reinforced. And I want to
positively reinforce them with this
sentence. Holy bars, this is like we're
doing [ __ ] 8D chess here with our
editing.
So now you have a viral hook. I probably
just will leave this as A roll actually.
>> [laughter]
>> Okay, repeat for the entire video. I
think what I'll do is I'll just have a
shot of computer like sped up by like
5x. Entire video script is being typed
out. I don't know exactly how I'm going
to do this shot. I'll probably have to
like retype everything onto a Google
Doc, but I like this concept of a
visual, everything being filled out on a
Google Doc. It makes it feel like the
viewer is essentially doing the entire
video creation process like in the span
of five seconds, which is a really sick
dopamine hit. Now you have a viral
script. This is back to A-roll.
>> [music]
>> I'm just going to put parentheses here.
A-roll. Open iPhone camera. Uh you don't
want to do on the screen recording.
Screen recording of opening the iPhone
camera app. I I'm probably going to make
some funny face. Like I'll probably do
this face.
Because what's interesting is that when
I open the iPhone camera on a screen
record, they're going to see my face.
So, it's going to be a kind of funny
visual. Okay, press record. Hit record.
Uh uh ooh, okay, okay, okay. Um then I'm
going to look scared. Look scared, but
press record. I think this could help
the video hit closer to home. It's like
most people when they first record their
first ever video, they're scared. Uh
it's probably you right now, actually.
Uh they're scared. So, I want to
represent that emotion visually by
showing that in my facial. Read script.
[music]
Oh, this is so meta, but I feel like I
could have messed up the script here. I
could do it in straight extremely
complex B-roll clip, but I don't [music]
think that's necessary. Look scared, but
press record. That one's good. Read
script. I think this part is A-roll,
honestly. I I actually think this whole
part is A-roll. And then press stop. Oh,
because I have the screen recording for
you guys of me pressing stop on my
phone. I'm just going to do press
stop B-roll
from end of video screen recording. I
know you guys probably don't even
understand what the [ __ ] I'm saying on
the on the Google Doc, but trust bear
with me here, guys. Bear with me. I want
you guys to just absorb the thought
process here and the level of
intentionality that I have behind these
shots because the difference here of
putting 5% more intentionality in every
single one of my sentences can be the
difference maker between, let's say,
10,000 or 20,000 views versus a million,
2 million views, you know? Genuinely,
these 5% incremental differences in
retention will have like per potentially
a 10x in views for you. So, I really
want to highlight, yes, especially once
you get into the hang of actually
creating content, I want you to focus on
this level of intentionality if you are
serious about going viral. Okay, open
CapCut. This one's pretty simple. It's
same screen recording thing. I actually
wrote that down here. Click auto
captions. I'm going to do this actually
with cropped overlays, like stickers on
the screen, like I'm going to say
sticker cropped overlay, rather than
doing the whole screen recording thing
because at this point I think it can get
kind of obnoxious to keep looking at a
screen recording that's hyper zoomed in.
>> [clears throat]
>> And in editing UI is really complex,
especially for beginners. Like I'm
thinking I'm empathizing with my viewer
here. It's like if I screen recorded the
entire CapCut UI and then I was pressing
one button out of the 50 buttons, it
would it would be hard for a viewer to
visually keep track cuz there's so many
elements on the screen. And I really
want to maintain this level of visual
simplicity that allows the viewer to
just focus on whatever the one thing I'm
talking about is. Press return so all
captions fit in one line. I'm going to
do This is going to be an actual screen
recording. And now you have a viral
edit. Open Instagram. Press post. This
one's going to be a screen recording,
Instagram, pressing post. I guess I I
have to do this all within the span of
like 3 seconds. But I think the
fast-changing visual is what made this
guy's video go viral, so I'm banking on
the fact that me just doing all these
actions super quickly will make the
video seem very value dense and value
packed. And that's it. I believe this
That's probably what made this video so
saved. Yes, it's not showing on my Reels
tab here. But what I'm trying to
communicate here is that the most value
dense videos, especially if you're an
educational content creator, will
probably get a lot of saves because most
likely on Reels, and this is a little
bit sad, but it's like most people
aren't actually going to absorb the
value from your content. They're
probably just going to save it and
mentally masturbate to the thought of
applying it later. This is kind of a
tangent. A big goal of your content is
not to actually make it the most deep
valuable thing because most likely if
you actually have expertise, it's really
hard to condense an outcome for your
viewer down to 30 freaking seconds. Most
of the time, you're indexing harder for
making them feel like they are making
progress [music] and condensing it down
into a way that's easier for them to
understand, not in a way that's just
trying to get them to understand these
high-level concepts. So, a lot of the
the times in my Instagram Reels, right?
You kind of seeing this live. You're
seeing the whole PhD-level dissertation,
or this is more like a college-level
dissertation of everything here live on
this YouTube video. But, if you're
looking at my Instagram Reels, you're
noticing how much simpler it is. That's
because a lot of times short-form video,
you want to condense down your value to
the point [clears throat] where a viewer
[music] can just feel like they
understand one thing from it. Okay, they
you just want to get them one quick
dopamine hit or one quick feeling of a
win. So, press post. That's it. That's
how I've made all of these viral videos.
And I'm pointing up at the screen. I'm
going to add screenshots of my most
viewed videos.
Comment. Okay, done. Let's actually
start filming these b-roll clips. So,
I'm going to hop over back to my phone,
and I'm just going to run through this
entire shot list here. Okay, so we are
back on our phone, and we're going to
film the first b-roll clip, which is
opening Instagram. [music]
Okay, here we go. So, open Instagram. I
actually need to download freaking
Instagram real quick. So, I have it
deleted. I usually delete Instagram when
I don't have
actual videos to make because
I just end up doing [music] scrolling,
just wasting my time, and I just get
into a really bad funk where I compare
myself to other creators.
>> [music]
>> So, it's a little mindset hack here, but
I try to Oh, and also because I check my
views religiously then, right?
Obsessively to the point where it [ __ ]
up my mental health. Um
>> [music]
>> so, I try to um
Yeah, I just ended up [ __ ] doom
scrolling. What am I doing? Uh I
I I try to delete Instagram so I just
don't [ __ ] up my mental health, and I
only reinstall it when I post. So,
that's a little personal hack. But,
anyways, anyhoo, oh yeah, we we should
have we have Instagram here. So, now I'm
just going to put it in the middle of my
[music] screen to make it easier to
screen record, and I'm just going to
open Instagram. And I'm going to
actually My salary progression as a
therapist
Okay, and I'm just [music] going to keep
scrolling on videos. I think this cloud
video is pretty funny, so I'm going to
make sure it opens up to that. So, this
is a screen recording right here. Open
Instagram.
When I entered high school, I didn't ex-
I'm not even surprised that I've grown
21,000 followers. Hi, I'm Jerry, and 51
days Testing out the viral Home Depot
life Everyone thought it would be easily
removed. This is how to go from Let me
record something. What am I here with
today? So, people ask me all
I don't want to hear you kidding. You've
been hit by
You've been
Dude, I just failed my mid-
Hey, my fiance is going to be styling
me. I have such a bad habit.
Okay, I feel like that's enough doom
scrolling shots. I'm probably going to
cut out some of the more like the the
less funny videos, but then in the
middle I noticed like this NYC guy
flipping on the subway. I think that's
just a funny clip to throw in. And if
it's sped up, I think it's just going to
look funny.
Open Instagram scroll. Okay, stop on
viral video. Now, I need to actually
stop on a viral video. So, you need to
go to that video. Probably going to
follow bro back. I'm going to follow G.
My fault. Explain my trading strategy to
explain so simply that a 5-year-old
could [music] understand. Yo, that was a
[ __ ] tough accent, wasn't it? So,
here's what I'm going to do. This one's
a little bit of a unique tech here, but
I'm going to save it to my uh folder
[music] of saved videos. And what I'm
going to do is that I'm going to go to
my saved folder, and I'm just going to
keep scrolling until I find it. Stop on
viral videos. That's what I did. Write
down first [music] sentence. So, now I
actually have to do that on my phone.
And actually I think that's probably
better if I do it on my phone rather
than on my computer. My trading strategy
understand. So, I've written down this
first sentence. This is their hook.
Okay. Change three words from sentence.
Creating viral IG reels explain so
simply that a 5-year-old can understand.
[music]
Now, that's a viral hook. Boom! I I [ __ ]
with that. I like the fact that I only
have to change the beginning part. Now
you have a viral hook. Repeat for the
entire video. Now I have to basically
write down the entire script. This is
going to be kind of devious, and I
wonder if there's a way that I can speed
this up. You know what? Actually no. I'm
just going to raw dog this entire thing.
Now we have a viral script. So I believe
that's the whole thing written out. Now
open iPhone camera. That's the next shot
I have to do. So that's a screen
recording of my iPhone camera. So I'm
going to move the iPhone camera icon
here just so it's an easier bureau shot.
Open iPhone camera. There we go. Caught
that shot. Oh wait, I need to do open
iPhone camera and then I have to look
funny face.
Oh now I have to do the scared face.
Oh my god, what the [ __ ] do I do? I'm
drooling, bro. Holy [ __ ]
Okay. Read script.
Read script.
I'm just messing up on camera if you
guys
>> [music]
>> didn't understand [ __ ] I'm doing.
>> [laughter]
>> Um open CapCut. Oh wait, I have to press
stop. Okay, boom. I press stop. Boom
boom boom. Now open CapCut. Now I must
do the same with freaking CapCut, which
actually sucks cuz then I have like
these weird icon colors I just realized,
but whatever. Okay, this is like the
most minute thing, but I actually don't
like how my icons are black cuz now it
just becomes confusing for my viewers
cuz CapCut icon generally is white
actually. So I'm going to customize my
home page to make it so it's default.
There we go. That's so bright. Oh my
gosh. Okay. Click auto captions. Oh
wait, I need to screenshot this. So I'm
just going to screenshot and then crop
[music] this into just being the auto
captions, and then I'm just going to
press save in the top right. This is
actually a hack for you guys, by the
way. Don't use any other font that isn't
the TikTok classic font. Maybe I'll
actually keep this screenshot as is. You
know what? I'm going to keep this
screenshot as is. Okay, and now we have
that b-roll shot completely done. Press
return so all captions fit in one line.
So I actually have to do the captions
here. I guess now you guys you guys
going to watch me. This is a little
discombobulated, but now you guys are
going to actually watch me do the auto
captions live. Here's how I create viral
on a move it here to the middle of the
screen. And what I'm going to do is just
going to hit styles, classic. And what
I'm going to do then is just hit this
one, right? How to create viral reels.
And I'm just going to edit the captions
and now this is the part that I'm going
to use for the b-roll. Viral Instagram
reels explained so simply that a
five-year-old can understand. Open
Instagram, scroll, stop on a viral
video.
Write down first sentence. This is their
hook.
Change three words from sentence. Now
you have a viral hook. Repeat for the
entire video. Now you have a viral
script. Okay, I'm not going to do that
for the entire video, but I think I have
enough b-roll here. Open Instagram,
press post. I'm actually just going to
export this for the sake of b-roll. I
actually do want to be able to upload
something. And I don't want to I don't
want to actually upload it to my main
account, cuz obviously it's like a dummy
video. I'm literally just uploading like
random BS at this point, but whatever.
Okay, now I have to get this shot of me
basically posting. So, open Instagram
reel and then [music] follow me, lol.
I'm going to turn this as a trial
because I don't want it to actually be
in my main. Press post. Okay, I'm not
actually going to press post here. But
yeah, that's the whole process of all my
b-roll. Now let's actually jump into
CapCut and I'm going to start my screen
recording again. And now let's go
through the process
of actually making this b-roll, add it
all into my video. So at this point now
I'm probably just going to narrate over
as I walk in and actually edit. Here's
how I create viral Instagram reels
Here's how I Here's how I create viral
Instagram reels explained so simply that
simply that a 5-year-old can understand.
>> That a 5-year-old? I'm going to
>> [music]
>> edit the captions and then press return
right here. So, it's All right.
Sometimes CapCut does this. So, I have
to split here instead and then just make
it so all of these are on their own
line. And then I'm going to zoom in on
this part [music] cuz that's what the
original did. That. There we go. Okay,
now I'm just going to add overlay,
[music]
right? By clicking uh overlay then add
overlay. And now I'm just going to
attack in this
screen recording that's 11 minutes long.
It's actually going to take 2 years.
Okay, you know what? Actually, basically
add [music]
and then what we can do when we add a
clip is actually press on it and then
move it to overlay. So, that basically I
don't know why, but it it makes it
significantly faster to add an overlay.
Uh especially when it's longer. So, now
that I have my overlay added, I'm going
to find the actual part [music] where I
open Instagram. So, I'm going to find
this part right here. And what I'm doing
is I'm going going to press split at the
beginning of the overlay, delete the
beginning, [music]
and then move that clip all the way to
when I'm going to scrub. And I'm just
going to keep dragging this clip all the
way to the beginning. Open Instagram.
Open Instagram. I'm going to I'm going
to zoom super hard on this.
Open Instagram. I'm going to mute the
whole clip, too. Can understand. Open
Instagram. And I'm going to speed up
this entire portion right here by like
3x. Just keep scrolling. And I'm going
to zoom out here so it actually shows
the whole scrolling process. I might add
a little vignette here just so the
the parts around are not going to be as
visible to make to help the video feel
more focused.
>> Open Instagram. Scroll. Stop. Instagram.
Scroll. Uh
here, honestly, I think it's still not
fast enough. So, I think I'm going to
like 5x. I don't like this video here.
What I'm going to do is I'm [music]
going to split the b-roll
halfway through and then cut it to this
guy cuz this guy's way funnier. Uh he's
like trending right now, androgenic. And
then I want to find that one NYC subway
clip. Cut it to that. Move it over. I
need a stop on the actual video that I
need, right? So, I'm going to find this
video here. I'm going to delete the
[music] beginning part of this b-roll
clip. I'm just going to move it all the
way there. Notice how for my b-roll, I'm
making sure every single second of
b-roll is moving as quickly as possible,
so it's super precise. You know what?
I'm actually going to slow this [music]
down cuz I think this is moving way too
fast at this point. Stop on viral video.
Then I'm going to zoom in here. I might
actually use a keyframe. [music] And a
keyframe basically helps you move it.
And I'm going to zoom in on the heart,
the number of likes on this video, like
really hard zoom. Like a super hard
zoom. And it should do this hard You You
notice how it then zooms. [music] A
keyframe basically
you find a starting point and an ending
point and then you just zoom. And I'm
going to
>> [music]
>> get rid of the vignette here actually
cuz that makes it even worse to see.
And [snorts] I'm just going to zoom even
harder to the point where
>> [music]
>> you can only see the likes cuz I want to
make this b-roll feel very focused. It
should look like this.
>> Instagram scroll. [music] Stop on viral
video.
>> To make sure the captions don't Like
look how the captions get misaligned in
CapCut as well. So, make sure you're
you're fixing it. I'm going to do stop
on and then viral video. Okay, [music]
scroll. I'm just going to press this
caption text and then do this. Okay, now
I need to do the write down first
sentence. So, write down first sentence
and I'm going to just cut everything
before that. I'm going to move it over
so the Google Doc portion of the b-roll
now is [music] moved back towards the
beginning of the video. Okay, now I'm
going to write down the first sentence.
So, I'm going to remove the vignette
here cuz I don't think the vignette is
really helping. I might change I might
turn down the brightness of the whole
thing. And I'm going to I'm probably
going to speed this up as well because
once again, it's a very slow clip of me
typing [music] [ __ ] which is going to
be very boring and obviously it's not
going to fit. Write down first sentence.
I need to everything to fit within this
like
>> [music]
>> probably 1 second or 2 second b-roll
clip right here. So, I need to just
speed this up tremendously.
>> [music]
>> Write down first sentence. I want write
down to complete it. So, part right
after it's finished. I'm just going to
slow it down [music] again cuz I don't
want it to just move way too fast after.
Something about this shot here doesn't
feel easy to understand. Like
everything's super zoomed in here and
then suddenly I go to this Google Doc.
And I'm going to keyframe and zoom in on
the actual line that I'm typing. Maybe
this will help make it easier [music] to
understand. Okay, and maybe I'll zoom
out. I just want to see what this looks
like with the keyframes. I probably
should have used a narrower page on
Google Docs. But let's just see. So this
is this is kind of a fault in my B-roll
planning process, but we're going to
stick through it here and [music] figure
out the editing process. Sometimes
editing requires a little bit more
complex problem solving. That's okay.
That's okay. That means that you're
actually caring
>> [music]
>> with intentionality about your viewers'
experience. That's how you're going to
level up your content. Okay, honestly,
let's get rid of all the keyframe stuff.
[music] I don't think that's helping the
viewer [clears throat] understand stuff
better. I think honestly [music] the
first approach that we had of just the
whole Google Doc is probably the best
approach that we have. Honestly, [music]
I don't want this part to have the
blinking thing. So I'm just going to
freeze the frame on this last one, which
you can do by [music] hitting this
freeze button and what that does is just
freeze freezes it. Okay, and then I'm
going to cut it here. [music]
Cut. I want to make sure this part is
also deleted. This is their hook. Okay,
boom. So this is what the video looks
like so far with the B-roll. Open
Instagram. Scroll. [music] Stop on viral
video. Write down first sentence. This
is their hook. Change three words. So I
think here I think 23x [music]
or 19x speed is a little bit too fast.
Let's say 8x. Okay, I want to make sure
the auto captions actually align cuz
CapCut's auto captions for some reason
always misalign. I'm going to zoom in
here cuz I actually think zooming in on
the words that I'm changing helps. Well,
change. Okay, I like how that feels. I
like how that feels super snappy. Repeat
for the entire video. So at this point
now I'm just going to show [music] the
screen recording of everything getting
filled in inside the video. So at this
case, now I just need [music] to speed
this up insanely. Like I think even this
is not going to be fast enough. I think
it's going to have to be like 8 seconds.
Yeah.
>> P for the entire video.
>> Uh and I'm going to freeze this [music]
frame here. I actually think this is a
small knit thing, but I'm actually going
to increase the size of the font cuz I
just don't think it looks clear enough.
Uh something about how the beginning
feels doesn't feel aligned. Well,
if I actually go back to the inspo
video, he didn't actually use auto
captions at the beginning. He put one
block of text. Trading [music] explained
so a 5-year-old could understand. I
think I can just take out this and I'm
going to use the TikTok font here. How
to go viral year old can understand. I'm
going to move this down a little bit
here. I feel like this looks better.
Here's how I create viral Instagram
Reels explained so simply that a
5-year-old can understand. [music] Oh,
he uses yellow captions and I think the
whole point of yellow captions here is
so it contrasts better with the
background. So I'm actually going to use
yellow captions. Open Instagram, scroll,
stop on viral video, write down first
>> [music]
>> write down I'm just going to make sure
all the captions align. Honestly, I'm
just going to do this real quick for the
captions so I get it out of the way. At
this point we're getting pretty
advanced, guys. Pretty ironic because I
I [music] made this video for beginners,
but low-key like at this point we're
going into pro tips. So if you need to
pause the video, if you need to at this
point like take a [ __ ] break, like
it's okay. I I completely understand
[music] like this is a lot. I completely
understand me editing with all these
small things like changing the auto
captions so the changes don't apply to
all the auto captions. Hopefully it's
helpful, but I also completely
understand if it's [music] OD. You don't
need to go as crazy above and beyond.
This is my viral video editing process,
but you know, at the end of the day
Rome wasn't built [music] in a day. So
it's practice and don't feel
overwhelmed, guys. Please. Notice how it
does feel easier and [music] clearer to
see. It's like hook pops out to you. And
I did that intentionally to make it
easier to understand. This is their
hook. Change three words from sent I'm
going to use the number instead of the
letters because I think that just makes
it easier to read. Now you have a I
don't know why it just feels [music]
better if it's two words at a time. Now
you have a viral script. Okay, open
iPhone camera. We got to go here now and
do the iPhone camera. This is my
favorite B-roll. It's super easy to
understand, [music] but it expresses so
much emotion here. Um also we're going
to make sure this actually isn't a hyper
zoomed into the point where you can't
really understand what's happening. So
yeah, open iPhone camera. I'm also going
to turn up the brightness cuz now it's
too dark, I think. I'm going to make it
so it's actually all the way at the
bottom, like pinned to the bottom here.
I think that [music] looks cleaner.
Okay, now I'm going to make sure this is
also split into a different line by
editing caption. This is a small thing,
but I'm going to make the P script. Open
iPhone camera, press record, read
script. This part and [music] I'm going
to zoom into that, put that back on the
timeline right there. And now I'm going
to speed this up because I think it
looks funnier if it's sped up to like
1.5. Read script, mess up, keep
recording. There we go. I'm going to put
the press stop here. Man, this video is
coming together. This video is really
coming together with the B-roll. Okay,
now I have to open CapCut. [music]
Notice how all these B-roll clips
realistically like don't last that long
on the screen. And now I'm going to open
CapCut itself [music] right there. We're
almost done with this edit, guys. Oh my
goodness. I know it's confusing, but
just bear with me, y'all. Mess up, keep
recording, press stop. Oh, record. Oh,
that looks so clean. Notice how that
looks so clean where every single one of
the visuals matches with what I'm
saying. Guys, do you see that? Yo, we're
cooking. Oh my gosh. Yo, chat. Wait,
look at this. Look at this. Ready?
Ready? Script. Open iPhone camera, press
record, read script, mess up, keep
recording, press stop, open CapCut. Oh,
the way that that progresses so quickly
makes it such a satisfying video, guys.
Oh my gosh, we just cooked. Maybe I
actually don't need B- I don't I don't
need text on screen here cuz I can just
do this button. Okay, what I'm going to
do is I'm going to put the [music] word
click, but then move it out of the way
once I put the auto captions there.
Okay, and now I'm going to add the
overlay of the photo right here. Add
that, [music]
scale it down, put it there. Click auto
captions. Tick. Honestly, I don't like
how this how cluttered this visual is. I
think I just need to crop this classic
cuz I think this is
way easier to understand. Okay, we're
almost there. This looks hella clean.
TikTok classic font. Press return so Oh,
I have an idea. Let me cook. Shut up.
Let me cook. I'm actually going to
screen record [music] this part
specifically or I am pressing record. So
I just turned on screen recording again
and press return [music]
so all the captions
fit in one line.
Fit in one line. There we [music] go.
And now I'm going to stop the recording
and throw that in there cuz I think
that's a perfect b-roll clip. So I think
this is the simplest way of visually
demonstrating this. Press return so all
the captions fit in one line. Open
Instagram again. Viral edit. Open
Instagram and then press post at the
bottom which I think I did. The very
bottom of the screen. [music] At this
point I might just need to crop it. I'm
just going to crop this part where I
press share and then it's kind of like I
select and unselect that button. Open
Instagram. Press post. And that's it.
Maybe I'll add a little emoji pointing
up here. I've made all of these viral
videos. Okay, there we go. We just did
all the auto captions and the overlays.
So let's see the video so far. Here's
how I create viral Instagram reels
explained so simply that a five-year-old
can understand. Open Instagram. Scroll.
Stop on viral video. Write down first
sentence. This is their hook. Change
three words from sentence. Now you have
a viral hook. Repeat for the entire
video. Now you have a viral script. Open
iPhone camera. Press record. Read
script. Mess up. I'm going to add a vine
boom here. I'm going to add a little
vine boom in the audio sounds. And then
I have it saved in my audios. I'm going
to show you guys how to add an audio in
a second but just bear with me. Mess up.
Keep recording. Press stop. Open CapCut.
Click auto captions. TikTok classic
font. Press return so all the captions
fit in one line. Now you have a viral
Now you have a viral edit. Okay,
awesome. So now I'm going to do that.
I'm just going to add these two. Wow,
the video is really coming together.
Have a viral edit. Open Instagram. Press
post. That's it. Okay, now I just need
to like an actual picture of all these
viral videos. Now I just need to sort by
my most viral videos. It's going to take
a second. Okay, so first off is this
one. What what else really realistically
is using that? Yeah, this one also.
These all did use this editing process
by the way, guys. This is not cap. I
actually did use the [music] same exact
process of editing for pretty much all
these videos.
And then lastly, I guess this one. And
now that should be enough. So what I'm
going to do is go back to my overlays
and just add all of these. So add
overlay. I actually have an idea.
Because they Because I'm pointing from
in to out, I can do this. So my finger's
[music] pointing here, I'm going to add
these two videos. And think it it'll
look a little cleaner. It's kind of like
my hand is magically waving.
And it's adding all of these pictures
into [music] the frame. Okay, there we
go. So it looks like this. All of these
viral videos. Okay, and now I'm just
going to remove the ending piece of it
so [music] it doesn't Yeah, let's
rewatch it now. It's Everything's pretty
much done except the music. So let's
rewatch it one more time just for a
revision [music] process. Here's how I
create viral Instagram Reels explained
so simply that a five-year-old can
understand. I don't like how my eyes
kind of get blocked by the text at the
very beginning. This is a small thing,
but always make sure that your eyes are
visible [music] when you whatever you're
showing something. Here's how I create
viral Instagram Reels explained so
simply that a five-year-old can
understand. Open Instagram, scroll, stop
on viral video, write down first
sentence. This is their hook. Change
three words from sentence. Now you have
a viral hook. Repeat for the entire
video. Now you have a viral script. Open
iPhone camera, press record, read
script, mess up, keep recording, press
stop, open CapCut, click auto captions,
TikTok classic font, press return so all
the captions fit in one line. Now you
have a viral edit. Open Instagram, press
post. That's it. That's why I've made
all of these viral videos. There's a
world where I do want to put in
screenshots of the views at the very
beginning to show proof that I know what
I'm talking about in the the couple
seconds. I kind of also realized that
maybe that's too much visual clutter and
the visual in in the video that I used
as inspo didn't do that. Yeah, I think
[music] I do need proof though. And but
what I'm going to do is I'm going to
crop out everything except the views.
Now we added proof and this is a concept
called social proof that
>> [music]
>> persuades viewer to actually believe
that I am worth listening to and that
this video is going to be worth their
time. So that's a very key thing to add
in. Here's how I create viral Instagram
Reels explained so simply that a
five-year-old can understand. Open
Instagram, scroll, stop on viral video,
write down first sentence. This is their
hook. Change three words from sentence.
Now you have a viral hook. Repeat for
the entire video. Now you have a viral
script. Open iPhone camera, press
record, read script, mess up, keep
recording, press stop, open CapCut,
click auto captions, TikTok classic
font, press return so all the captions
fit in one line. Now you have a viral
edit. Open Instagram, press post. it.
That's how I've made all of these viral
videos.
>> Wow. That moved so quickly, but it
[ __ ] works, bro.
Oh my gosh. Let's add sound. Now last
last. One small thing though is that I
do want to make sure my volume is
audible. So something I always do is I
hit the volume for all these clips and I
just turn [music] up to like 400 and
then I hit loudness adjustment, which
basically makes it so
>> [music]
>> every single one of the clips are at the
same volume as this one. So now they're
all going to be generally around [music]
like increased a little bit. The inspo
video used like very casual music, so I
do [music] want to use something that's
also kind of casual and funny.
Now you're probably wondering how am I
adding music [music] from right inside
CapCut? Don't you need to have it saved
to your phone? I got you, okay? And this
is like the finding music tech. [music]
Uh I highly recommend you only use
instrumental songs that don't have
lyrics because you don't want you, for
example, competing over the attention of
like Kendrick Lamar, right? Kendrick
Lamar is rapping and then you're
speaking and then [music] just sounds
really confusing cuz you're both
speaking at the same time. So, what I do
is for example this song The Magic
Flute, right? The Magic Flute Queen of
the Night Aria. And what I'll do is I'll
basically copy link of a video, then I'm
going to go to Safari [music] and I'm
going to search up YTMP3.
I'm going to paste, convert, and all
this does basically is it allows you to
download the song straight onto your
phone as a file [music] as an MP3 file
from YouTube. And I just hit download.
So, I already exist on my phone. Uh so,
once you do that, then all you have to
do is go into the sounds [music]
device, select from device, and then you
search up. So, in this case Queen of the
Night Aria and it's right there. I
already have it added, so I'm not going
to press it, but now it shows up here.
And yeah, there you go. That's how I've
added this music. Here's how I create
viral Instagram Reels explained so
simply that a five-year-old can
understand. And I'm going to move this
part a little earlier cuz I do like
[music] this part of the song. It's like
the most famous and I want it to cut in
at like 10 seconds. And there we go. Our
edit is complete. Oh my goodness. So,
what we are going to do then is hit this
top right corner, go to 4K, do not
[music] use the AI Ultra HD. I don't
know why they have this as a feature. It
just makes it look really bad. Frame
rate [music] 30 FPS, bit rate just do
the recommended, and I'm going to hit
export. Oh my gosh. If you are still
watching, comment down below blueberry.
Who is still watching? Who actually like
Yo, if you actually did this, yo,
comment blueberry down below. Genuinely,
I really appreciate you doing this
entire tutorial with me. At the end of
the day, you know, I I really hope these
videos are actually beneficial,
informative, and you're actually taking
action on these things because at the
end of the day, yes, content creation,
you know, it's a difficult skill to
master at first, but it unlocks infinite
opportunities as a creator. [music] You
can get brand deals, you can get
business, etc. and it all is, you know,
gatekept behind building this skill set.
So, [music] if you are looking for more
help getting coached through this entire
process with me alongside other expert
coaches [music] taking a look directly
at your videos, at your profile, finding
all of the weaknesses in your videos
that are keeping your [music] videos
stuck under 10,000 or under 1,000 views,
and then helping you grow to 10,000
followers plus. We've helped hundreds of
people do [music] that inside our
Community Content Academy. So, if you
want to apply to join that, cuz we have
to very strict application process, just
apply in the first link down below in
the description. So, anyways, let's go
to Instagram and finish posting the
video. And all we have to do is press
view top left. And yeah, now I just need
to add a caption. The original video's
caption was "Your grandma could do
this." "Your grandma could do this." I
think that's hilarious, that caption.
And I kind of want to do something
similar. It's like a joking caption.
This part doesn't matter, by the way,
guys. No hashtags or posting times
actually matter in your caption, cuz
it's so small on the screen, it's not
that biggest of a factor, but "How to go
viral as a 5-year-old." Honestly, I'll
probably just reiterate the steps. One,
[music] research viral videos. Find an
outlier in your format. And then that
would be like 100k plus views. I'm
actually just going to use the caption
[music] to be a further like explanation
for anybody. It's a little nice
engagement farm, because now anybody who
reads the caption will probably just
give free watch time.
Trading turns into [music]
viral reels. Minimum viable editing in
CapCut. Just hit post, bro. Okay. Boom,
we're done. And we're just going to hit
it and post it by pressing share. We
freaking did it! Let's go! Uh and I
really, really hope this was helpful. If
it was helpful, I appreciate it. So, let
me know in the comment section if if
this all made sense, if you actually
applied it.
And
subscribe, because we're going to be
posting weekly value. Not just how to
start content, but then how to master it
and build a masterable personal brand,
so you can create a full-time career out
of this content [music] creation thing.
That is literally my pride and joy at
this point, helping people do this for a
living.
Cuz content's fun, man. Kind of just
like you get to play all day
and really creatively [music] express
yourself.
And [snorts]
I hope to be a translator for you in
your journey in going from absolute
beginner to a full-time content creator.
With that being said, I'll see you guys
in the next video.
Peace.