In the past 2 years, I've grown from
2,000 to 500,000 followers on Instagram
while growing my business from literally
zero to seven figures, and I did it all
with Instagram. And there's seven levels
I had to go through in order to do that.
So, level one is your first thousand
followers. Now, in order to get your
first thousand followers, I think the
biggest mistake that most people make is
that they try to be too original. And
the biggest advice after I've coached
now over a thousand creators, and in our
community of around 900 creators, we
have 50 people who have hit 10,000
followers. And the ones who get there
have just become really proficient at
copying content. So, I'll give you a
very systematic approach to stealing
videos on the For You [music] page. The
first step is open up Instagram or
TikTok on your computer. This is a hack.
You don't want to open up on your phone
because, let's be real, we love doom
scrolling, and we're [music] probably
just going to end up in a cycle of like,
"Yo, oh, wait, this video, yo, this meme
of like Charlie Kirk's like it's kind of
funny." Then we just fall to a rabbit
[music] hole for like an hour. So, you
want to avoid that, especially when
you're transitioning in identity from
the consumer to the creator. You need
[music] to start building habits of a
creator. So, one of the most helpful
habits you can do is start learning
[music] to consume like a creator. And
the mode of consumption as a creator is
more so doing research. [music] It's
constantly thinking about how you can
take the ideas that you're seeing on
your screen and then spin it into your
own content. So, once you open up the
TikTok For You page or the Instagram
[music] Explore page on your computer,
you want to open up also a Google Doc
and just start writing down every single
one of the videos that you find that are
in the format of content that you want
to make and somewhat related to your
[music] niche. So, you do need to have
at least one general idea of what format
and niche you want to tackle with your
content. The most commonly used
evergreen viral formats [music] of
short-form content are as follows:
talking head, yapping content,
educational how-to content that usually
relies on visuals to teach you [music]
something, skits largely with a POV
caption, vlogs that document a day in
your life, and they usually rely on
whatever profession or title that you
have in life. For example, day in the
life of a Harvard medical student,
[music] that'll probably do well. Or my
5:00 to 9:00 after my 9:00 to 5:00 as
[music] a investment banker. I know
investment bankers work 9:00 to 9:00,
but another harder format, but a
personal favorite of mine is a challenge
/ storytelling style of video. You might
have seen it. It's like, is it possible
to ace an exam [music] after studying
for just 1 hour? This requires you to
actually go out and do something, but
it's actually very helpful, especially
if you don't have some expertise to
teach other people about or you don't
have like a job, honestly.
And that's the style of content that a
lot of YouTubers make as well. They go
out and do some sort of challenge. Now,
once you've identified, and I highly
highly recommend to like do this [ __ ]
with me right now, identify what niche
you want to target with your content.
This is it. Whatever keyword or industry
that you want to make videos in. If you
don't know what your niche is right
[music] now, that's perfectly fine. Just
ask yourself what type of content do you
enjoy consuming? You can literally go on
the YouTube recommended page or just
look at your TikTok For You page and see
what generally pops up on your feed. The
algorithms are honestly one of the best
determinants of what type of content we
are most interested in consuming. And if
you're watching this channel, I would
guess that you're interested in content
or business. Maybe you can make a series
documenting your journey of [music]
starting your content or starting your
business or improving yourself. Now,
once you've identified a niche and a
format, and I'll just list tons of
examples on the screen here so you can
just [music] choose one of each, right?
Go on to the TikTok or Instagram Explore
pages, find videos with over 5,000 likes
in [music] the format or niche that
you're creating videos in. 5,000 likes,
in my opinion, is a good indicator of a
viral video. It probably means it has
over 100,000 or 200,000 [music] views.
But this is your indicator that you it
is right for you to be copying it. Now,
when I say copy, I genuinely mean write
down exactly word for word their entire
[music]
script, especially their first three
sentences, and then ask yourself one,
why did they include every single
[music] one of these sentences? What
about these sentences made it go viral?
Because when you are getting your first
thousand followers, [music] the biggest
belief that you have to understand is
that everything is your fault if you are
not going viral right now. If you are
not growing, it is not due to some luck.
It is not due to some algorithm thing.
It's not due to some posting time or
hashtag. That [ __ ] does not matter. It
is purely [music]
based on how good of videos you make.
And as you ask yourself, as you study
these viral videos that you see on your
For You page, [music] you're going to
start building up your intuition for
what makes an actual good video. As you
keep asking yourself that question,
you're going to start learning how viral
videos work, and that's going to help
you build the intuition [music]
to determine how to script your own
videos and then how to go about filming
the right angles for your own videos.
Phase one of getting your first thousand
followers is purely just research and
repetition. So, you need to be posting
every single day, but I highly
recommend, because this is a new habit,
do not go out and try to spend two or
three hours on every single one of your
videos. That's like a newbie to the gym
trying to do three-hour-long workouts
when you don't even know the proper form
for exercising. Odds are, if you put
this high bar of expectation of where
you need to be, you're just going to get
burnt out. You're going to feel like
you're never doing enough, and then
you're going to get really discouraged
when you see lower views. So, set your
bar very low and focus specifically on
getting consistent. I have not really
seen any of the creators that I've
worked with hit like a thousand, 10,000
followers in their first week. It is
very uncommon, but they will hit it in
their first 30 or 60 days. So, your goal
as a creator is get to your first 30 to
60 days of posting. Get to your first 30
videos that you've posted online. It's
going to give you so much more data and
practice than sitting around twiddling
your thumbs trying to get get the
perfect script and perfect video.
Meanwhile, you just haven't posted
anything yet. So, here's my prescription
to you as somebody who's posted daily
during his last semester of college
before he dropped out while I started a
business, and I was able to grow from
50,000 to like 150,000 followers during
like 4 months during that semester. And
it's all because I did these daily
steps. First one is actually woke up and
I journaled about what I was scared of.
This one that's actually something that
most people don't talk about, which is
the mental game of being able to create
content. You're most likely going to get
into your own head, and not only is is
that going to stop you from being able
to post more consistently, it's also
going to stop you from being able to
express yourself in the most authentic
way possible. What people don't
understand about being an expressive
communicator or an effective
communicator on camera is that you just
have to be very confident and believe in
what you are saying and believe that you
are actually worth being heard. No
matter if you're a college student, your
life will be interesting to somebody out
there. Your your thoughts and your
lessons will be helpful to at least one
person out there who is one step behind
you in the [music] journey. In fact, yo,
even if you have literally nothing going
for you in life right now, like you are
just a college freshman, you're still
trying to figure out what to do with
your life, document that process of
figuring it out because there are tons
of people in that same place as you who
want to feel heard. And sometimes the
best thing you can do with your content
is not to be an expert, but just to be
somebody else's comfort creator where
you can just express what you're going
through and make somebody else out there
feel less alone. I think that's the
value that you can provide with your
content. And being cognizant as well of
the value that you're providing helps
you
>> [music]
>> actually build up a following and get to
your first thousand followers cuz your
first thousand followers is just a
thousand people that have gained value
[music] from something that you've put
out. And the reason why I'm telling you
to copy content that you're seeing on
the For You page while just changing one
or two words in the hook, the first
sentence that they did, is because if
you're beginner to content, your biggest
issue is that 90% of the people who are
even exposed to your video on their
algorithm are just going to swipe past
it within the first three seconds.
[music] It's probably not optimized,
hyper-optimized like the other videos on
the For You page. So, that's fine. But
the worst thing to do is try to create
the most original hook, the most
original first three sentences of your
video, but then people scrolling past
your video before you even get to the
value, [music] before you're even able
to, you know, explain whatever
educational thing you're trying to
teach, [music] before you're able to
even show, you know, like the first hour
of your day in the life. People just
scroll before they even get to that
point. Learning how to package yourself
by copying how other people are
packaging their own personal brands is
the easiest way to learn. I I really
want I really really want to emphasize
this. Copy exactly word for word the
text on screen that they use. I still do
this as a creator, too, because I firmly
believe the meta is always shifting on
social media, and if you're not
constantly doing research, you will
[music] fall behind even if you're a
more experienced creator. And the last
point before you get to the second phase
of your first 10,000 followers, I know
some of you guys are thinking, "Man, but
I want to build a really original
personal brand. I want to be original."
First off, 90% of the viral content that
you see on the For You page [music] is
just other people copying each other.
So, that's the first part. The second
part is that when you really break down
creativity, creativity is just
synthesizing whatever inputs that you
have received subconsciously throughout
your life. Even though you think it's
the most creative idea, odds are your
most creative ideas are just a
synthesis, a combination, a culmination
of whatever ideas that you've consumed
in the past month on [music] your For
You page, in whatever books you've read,
in whatever life experience that you've
had. Being self-aware of that as
somebody who's [music] taken pride and
ego in being like an original creator
has helped me realize like, "Oh, I am
not that important, and my ideas
>> [music]
>> were never like truly hyper-original,
and I don't need to reinvent the wheel
when it comes to my titles and
thumbnails or the first sentence of
[music] my video." Because the algorithm
will already tell you what the market
and what the viewers out there are
wanting to see. And if you can just
create and tap into the demand that
already exists on social media, that is
how you're going to be able to build a
brand that people actually want to watch
right off the jump and not spend months
and months and months posting stuff and
wondering why [ __ ] is not hitting with
the algorithm. It's likely because
however you've packaged the first three
seconds is [music] just not something
that viewers have a demand for,
unfortunately. So, the easiest way is to
tap into demand that already exists.
Okay, moving on. Phase number two,
getting to your first 10,000 followers.
I really like this analogy with your
first 10,000 followers of thinking about
it as your first 10,000 true fans. This,
I believe, is a phase of doubling down
where you're not just testing,
practicing, and copying one-off videos.
But, if you've gotten to your first
1,000 followers, you've probably at
least had one or two videos get above
50,000, 100,000 views. That's usually
where people get their first 1,000
followers from a couple videos that do
decently well. So, now you're at the
point where I would assume you have
about 30 videos posted, and you have
enough repetitions and data from the
algorithm to understand what to double
down on and what to eliminate from your
content strategy. And this is where I
would say strategy is somewhat helpful,
but it's not some complex strategy where
you're once again reinventing the wheel
and coming up with a massive thoughtful
strategy. No, no. All you are doing is
looking at your page. You can even use
some tools like Sort Feed. It's a Google
Chrome extension that allows you to sort
through your Instagram profiles. Or you
can just go on TikTok and then there's
like a sort by popular button where you
can just sort by your most popular
TikToks. And literally go on to a Google
Sheet. I actually have a Google Sheet
that literally I I'll throw it up on the
screen here that analyzes not only my
best performing content, but my worst
performing content. And then I can just
do some pattern recognition. What did I
do before creating my best performing
videos? What ideas did I use when I made
my best performing videos? What did I do
in the first 3 seconds when I made my
best performing videos? What text on the
screen did I put in my best performing
videos? And then also do the opposite.
What did I do before filming my worst
performing videos? What were the hooks
of my worst performers? And you know,
what was I putting on the screen and
showing on the screen the first 3
seconds of my worst performing videos?
Those are the biggest influences towards
your videos performance, [music]
anyways. And I'll actually do this with
my TikTok page right here. If I just
open my TikTok, and I can literally just
watch through, let's say, the past 20
videos that I've posted. So, one and 13.
Okay. So, I have 13 videos here. And
what do I notice about the videos that
got 60K, 40K, and 40K, and even 9K
versus the ones that got 700 and, let's
say, like 1,000 views. So, these this is
the range that I'm seeing on my own
page. But, regardless, these this still
this math still applies to you even if
you only have 2,000 views as your max
views, [music] and then you only have
like 300 views as your minimum views,
right? You want to still analyze what
made these first three sec like what
patterns am I seeing in the first three
seconds [music] of these videos, okay?
So, let's start with this one. I'm
seeing an I threw up a number very early
on in the screen. So, 50K to to 520K,
right? [music] So, right off the bat,
one trend that I can just analyze in my
content is that people like seeing
the fact that I say I I made a million
dollars with my content. Or even this
one, plus 400K followers in 2 years. Or
this one, this is the exact script
template I copied and pasted to grow
100,000 followers in 30 days. Maybe I
should just say that more often. [music]
And then let's see the ones that didn't
do as well. Whatever you chase really
does run away from you. [music] If you
say you want to become famous, well,
you're probably going to ex Why did this
one not do well? My assumption, right?
And it's a pretty simple assumption, is
that people don't know don't know who I
am. At the end of the day, we are making
videos that appeal to strangers on the
For You page. So, if I don't say my
expertise really quickly, I'm not
essentially persuading the viewer to
actually trust me. Like I'm building no
ethos with the viewer that's that's
communicating, "Oh, this guy's worth
listening to."
>> [music]
>> Right? Especially when it comes to
social media advice. And you can see it
here. Complete story on how I went from
zero followers to a million dollars
made. Yeah, so it's flashing a really
big money number or a really big
follower number really early on.
Literally first 4 seconds, I believe. I
I don't I think the videos that don't do
well have have not had that, I guess,
social proof really put in in the first
like couple seconds, right? And if I go
to if I go to this one, I don't think
you understand how big of a money
printer this app that you're watching
this video on is, because if you did
have any content Yeah, at this point
people have scrolled past me because
they don't know what expertise that I
have. They don't know why I am
personally worth listening to. So, ask
yourself this, right? What words or
numbers are you specifically citing?
What names are you saying? Maybe you're
talking about celebrities or or current
events or trending topics
>> [music]
>> in the first 3 seconds. Maybe you're
wearing something. I've seen, for
example, people who talk about like
medical school, right? Being a medical
school student. And their best
performing videos are just like wearing
something that signals that they go to
medical school, right? So, there's this
kind of alignment and proof that they
actually are, you know, a day in the
life of a medical school student, rather
than, you know, starting their day off,
but then they're just showing themselves
in a regular pair of clothes. So, maybe
your clothing can literally impact your
setting can impact [music] how the
video's performing. And you can see off
these numbers, too. Especially with
TikTok, a 5% increase or like a 5 10%
improvement [music]
in the retention past your first 3
seconds can literally be a 10x [music]
20x in views. 20x in engagement. And
it's a shame because the rest of your
video can be the same. The rest of your
video can literally be just as valuable.
Yet, it's not going to do well just
because those first couple seconds don't
have whatever like key indicator that
makes people pay attention, right? So, I
want you to if you have actually posted
videos already onto your page, go to
your page and do this practice. Scope
for the visual. Scope for the words that
you're using. Those are the most
important things. Maybe even check like
audio quality cuz a lot of times at the
beginning you [music] might just have a
shitty mic quality. Like your iPhone mic
should be the best that you are using. I
don't recommend using some external mic
cuz those cheap external mics you're
going to find on Amazon are probably
going to [ __ ] up your audio and make it
really annoying to listen to, right?
But, just go through this practice and
see. Now, in this practice of doubling
down, you're going to figure out as well
not only what performs well for you, but
I also want you to ask yourself, what do
you actually gain energy from and like
enjoy creating? [music] This is an
important question because I want you to
actually think about longevity now,
right? We're going to start talking
about monetization. The next phase is
making your first thousand dollars, but
I believe in order to make your first
thousand dollars and start making like
this into an actual career, which I
have, you want to start thinking about,
too, what do you actually want to
create? Who do you want to serve? And I
talk about this concept of the ideal
viewer persona. I think it's super
helpful in building like an actual
long-term dedicated fan base. Who is the
one demographic or one person, [music]
one very specific persona that you want
to speak to in your videos? And you
might be thinking, [music] "Oh, but I'm
not actually speaking in my videos.
Maybe I'm just making, you know, music
plus b-roll videos. Or maybe I'm just
making like one of those vlogs that I'm
not actually narrating over it." That's
fine, but you still want to ask
yourself, "Okay, let's say I'm making a
day in the life of a college student."
Well, one of the most helpful things you
can do is think about, "Oh, maybe I
should make this for high schoolers who
are interested in getting into college."
And there's tons of people who've built
brands around that. They're serving
essentially a version of them you their
younger self who's just two or three
years behind them. And that's the whole
basis behind the pages that I've built.
Like I'm just serving a younger version
of me. And this is actually one of the
most powerful practices for also
building a business one day. A lot of
creators go into creating content, but
they don't know exactly what type of,
you know, monetization vehicle that they
want to pursue. Ask yourself, who is the
one person that you want to help? And
let's say you want to help high
schoolers, you know, improve [music]
themselves and improve their studies so
they can get into college better. I have
a friend who's literally built an entire
seven-figure-a-year business on that.
She's gotten onto Forbes, and she's
built a whole coaching business on
helping high schoolers get into their
dream colleges, right? And perfect their
college applications. So, you can build
massive businesses upon these really
niche problems and these really niche
ideal viewer ideal customer persona. So,
really ask yourself, you can make a
Google Doc, right? And I'll throw mine
up on the screen here of like who you
really really want to serve. And then
you can start informing your videos
around serving that type of person. So,
for my page specifically, I want to help
people build their personal brands. But,
something I keep in the back of my mind
is that it's not just my personal brand.
I like I very specifically want to help
a younger ambitious version of me who
was in college, who specifically wasn't
exactly sure of what he wanted to do.
And [music] then content creation was
the avenue that helped unlock his like
full potential in life. Cuz when I think
back to my ideal viewer persona, when
[music] I was kind of lost in college, I
felt like I wanted to pursue something
in the online money space cuz I watched
a bunch of YouTubers you know, flashing
their lifestyles. They can just like
work whenever they want. But, I was on
the path to get a regular corporate
marketing job. That aspect of my life
really kind of depressed [music] me. I
felt no motivation to really push hard
in school. And as a result, I was
getting like B's in some of my classes.
I just felt really lost. And I felt like
I had a lot of potential that I wanted
[music] to eventually pursue in
something. I was the type of person who
really wanted to find this one thing to
go all in on cuz I was a video game
addict growing up. And I wanted
something to, you know, pour my
everything into. And I just never really
found that. And content creation was the
thing that really unlocked that for me.
And I truly believe like
>> [music]
>> content creation as it has done for me
and unlocked my own creative potential,
I want to do that for everybody else out
there watching my videos. So, what I'm
trying to get at here is my mission and
the thing I'm trying to serve in the
niche I'm trying to serve is content
creation. But, the ideal viewer persona
is like a college student who wants to,
you know, start some sort of career out
of this, you know? And that really helps
inform the [music] stories that I tell
in these videos and the framing, the
packaging of my titles and thumbnails of
these YouTube videos as well. So, to
summarize for phase two, analyze what
went right and what went wrong about
your videos, and then double down on the
hooks, visuals, and scripts that did
well for you. And lastly, ask yourself,
who is the ideal viewer that you want to
serve long-term with your page? And just
as an encouraging note as well, trust
me, there is somebody out there who will
derive value from watching your videos.
You might not perceive it yet because
you're newer to this content journey.
But, I really want to assure you,
whoever you are, tell your story out
there and just think about [music]
perhaps a younger version of yourself.
You are an expert to somebody out there.
Unless you're like a five-year-old
toddler, then [music] I guess like you
probably won't be an expert to like Like
I've seen creators blow up for like day
in the life of a middle school high
school student. I actually think that
type of content would go super duper
viral. So, content at the core is the
repeated process of making something
that helps somebody else out there. And
that could even just be entertaining
stuff, like funny videos. But, if it's
funny to you personally, maybe it'll
probably be funny to somebody else out
there. So, regardless of what it is,
understand and just believe that you are
actually worth watching. What you will
create will actually become worth
watching. Just continue practicing and
really believe that you have what it
takes. You, [music]
your personality, whatever
communication, your lifestyle, your
story is actually going to be helpful
and valuable and maybe interesting or
entertaining to watch to somebody else
out there. These character traits that
make you an interesting person will also
show on camera and really think about
too how to how to add those things into
your videos. Let's talk about your first
thousand dollars made on social media.
Now, at the core, there are only two
ways to make money on social media and
every single creator, influencer, social
media person will fall into one of these
two buckets. One, A, you are either
selling somebody else's product, you're
either marketing some other businesses
product,
>> [music]
>> which falls under the category of brand
deals, UGC, or two, you are selling your
own product in which you are building
either some digital product, maybe
you're building an app, a lot of people
build clothing brands or they build like
supplement businesses
>> [music]
>> and you're selling your own thing. Now,
arguably I would say to start off, if
you have no idea how to monetize, I
would recommend actually looking into
brand deals, looking into UGC. [music]
There's this thing called UGC right now
where companies and brands and apps are
hiring beginner creators to market their
products. I think it's a great way to
get your foot into the door of marketing
and just start learning how marketing
works and [music] the core skill set
behind short-form content marketing. And
then eventually you can parlay that into
building your own product, building your
own app, building your own digital
product or coaching, right? I'll give
very two quick pro tips. A, if you are
looking to start doing brand deals or
UGC, create a business email. My
business email is literally my
name.business@gmail.com.
You can literally just do that, okay? If
you want like an easy one. You know,
some people create their own custom
domains where, you know, they have like
minoleemedia.com. I don't I don't have
that, but you can do that, you know, go
on Google Workspace or Google Enterprise
or whatever and then just like create a
custom domain [music] and email there.
Regardless, okay, you don't overthink
it. Just slap an email. The reason why
I'm saying this is because that is how
brands will reach out to you. A lot of
brands will literally just scrape TikTok
and Instagram accounts using these like
API tools and they will just look for
accounts that have an @ in their bio or
like something.com in their bio. That
just helps them vet for the people who
are actually [music] seriously looking
for brand deals because a lot of these
brands, they need good creators and like
as somebody who works on the other side
who talks [music] with brands now,
helping them hire for content creators
because that's what my community, my
paid community does. Trust me, there are
so many [ __ ] opportunities out there
even if you only have a thousand or ten
thousand followers. There are so many
opportunities for [music] businesses
that are looking to hire creators. So,
just slap a business email in your bio
and you'll never know what opportunities
will be thrown [music] at you. I
remember when I got my first $20 brand
deal as a 16-year-old on TikTok. I had a
hundred thousand followers and I
remember my friend told me, "Yo, just
slap a business email in your bio." And
I did a brand [music] deal for a like
some charger. Literally, it was some
like char- like phone charger company.
And that literally opened up my world
cuz that made it possible for me. And I
think the biggest thing with getting
your first thousand dollars is to
believe that it's actually possible that
this [music] internet money thing is
actually real and you want to make it
real as soon as possible. So, the
quickest action step you can take is
[music] throw an email in your bio and
you never know what inquiries will come
at you. And then from there, just keep
posting, keep posting, keep posting and
eventually opportunities will come to
you. Now, in terms of if you want to
start some sort [music] of business or
service that you are selling to your
audience, right? And this is what I've
been able to do to make my first million
dollars from social media. I'll
recommend something that will actually
help you because I can't teach you
[music] the like entire basics of
creating your own offer. Read this book,
100 Million Offers by Alex Hormozi. It's
the like ABCs textbook, right? It
literally takes about a day to read. I'm
not even kidding. It will take I I'm a
slow reader, took me one day to read.
It's probably like a hundred pages long
[music] and it'll teach you the ABCs of
what selling something is. It'll teach
you how to sell, what to sell, and how
to package what you sell so people
actually want to buy it, right? Even if
you're a complete beginner, right?
[music] It helped me get my first $2,000
a month client, right? [music] It helped
me sell my first $500 Now, it was like
$200 digital product when I first tried
selling a course on a TikTok. Now, I
just realized a lot of you guys are
probably wondering how to choose between
either doing brand deals or selling your
own thing. And as somebody who's done
both and made tens of thousands of
dollars from brand deals, I've charged
up to like $14,000 for a single video
and I've also hit like 100k months with
my own business. [music]
The pros of doing brand deals is that
you really don't have to work on
anything besides your content. Like all
you have to do is focus on making
videos, especially when you're starting
your personal brand and just learning
the skill of content, right? Cuz at the
end of the day, getting your first
10,000, 100,000 followers
>> [music]
>> is just learning the skill set of
content creation. And if you want to
just be focused on that raw practice of
that skill, [music]
do just brand deals, right? Throw an
email in your bio. You can even build a
portfolio once you start actually doing
work that just showcases all the work
that you've done and it makes it easier
for brands to actually convert to uh
working with you. But, the cons that I
have experienced is that I personally
didn't like being at the mercy of brands
and [music] I felt when I was especially
doing brand deals and relying on brand
deals that I had to always be going
super-duper viral. And I just realized I
didn't like having that pressure on
myself every single month. I would
rather have like 10,000 views per video,
but actually be able to like make, you
know, 10k months from that. And if
you're running your own business, right,
there's obviously a lot more work that
goes behind the scenes that is not
creating content. But, I would say the
game of business has allowed me to not
rely on going as viral. The only other
pro I can think of of running my own
business is that I do think it's another
completely different creative outlet.
Like I got to the point with short-form
content cuz I've been making it for the
past six [music] years that I started to
honestly just get a little bored of
making videos. Like I felt like I had
finally cracked generally how to
consistently make viral videos and it
just didn't feel creatively challenging.
But, now I would say like the game of
business is there there's like infinite
levels to it, you know? You can there's
all these [music] parts of building a
product, leading a team. And I think
that's been really helpful for my own
personal development. I I feel like I've
become so much better of a communicator.
I've been forced to become more stoic as
an individual under stress and I very
much valued that personal growth. This
is not me like whatsoever taking a dig
at being an influencer as well. Like
being an influencer is lit as [ __ ] and I
have friends who make way more money
than me as an influencer without running
any sort of business. They just do brand
deals. They like absolutely print. Like
you know, there are people who make
millions of dollars a year, 100k months
with being an influencer, with having
like, you know, a million followers at
this point and doing massive, massive
brand deals. I know people who have
charged $100,000 for a single [music]
TikTok video. I am not even kidding.
There are people out there who have done
that. So, do not underestimate the
amount of money you can make from being
an influencer, doing brand [music]
deals, okay? But, that also requires
getting your foot in the door and
putting your email in your bio. Like
don't think about it. I just want you to
know that there's massive income
potential in case you are doubting
[music] it, okay? But, for me, I've
personally taken the route of business
and from here forward, I will talk
specifically about, you know, building
an audience that actually helps you
convert towards a business and then
running I I guess in the sense like a
personal brand slash creator business
and scaling that up to $10,000 then
$100,000 a month. So, let's talk about
phase four now, which is going from your
first $1,000 to your first 10k month.
Now, for a little context, I hit my
first 10k month as a creator May of
2023.
And I remember putting specifically a
year prior $10,000 a month on my vision
board right before taking a year off
from college. So, I spent a whole year
chasing this number, 10k a month. And I
genuinely believe I could have hit it
sooner. I could have hit it within like
three, four months. And I have students
who do that. And what I didn't realize
is that one, in order to hit consistent
10k months, you do need to somewhat
systematize your creative process. I
think a lot of times, especially
starting out, I viewed content as this
thing where I need to spend the whole
day thinking of executing one video. And
once you're actually trying to run a
business to the point of getting 10k
months, that's probably like five
high-ticket clients at 2k a month or
maybe it's ten like mid-high ticket
clients at 1k a month, right? You have
this whole other arm of your life that
you're running now. Like you're running
a whole [ __ ] business. You're
communicating with people and you're
doing all these admin tasks. And now you
have this weird compartmentalization
game where you still need to focus on
the content cuz you can't let that slip,
but then you also have this business
aspect of your life where you're
communicating with clients and it's a
little bit higher stress. So, the
biggest recommendation that I can do is
figure out a system to post every single
day, but start systematizing whatever
viral videos that you've had and
systematize like everything from the
script that you're using, the hooks that
you're using, how you format the hooks,
like how you're filming the videos,
what's like a five to ten minute
pre-filming routine. And I have all
those systems that I've personally used
to consistently pump out viral videos
and grow my accounts. Inside my private
community Content Academy, this is like
not a subtle plug at all, honestly, but,
you know, we've helped like I've said,
thousands of creators now, many of which
have hit 10k months. And if you are
interested in blowing up your content
and getting direct coaching from me
alongside other experts, you can apply
and just book a call in the first link
in the description. But, anyways,
something that I also wish I knew sooner
about hitting 10k months is that it
really isn't about being a content
creator. I just assumed that if I just
became really, really viral, I would hit
10k months, but I've literally gotten
like 50 million views in a single month
making like skits and I made like 2,000
bucks. It really has nothing to do with
going viral and it honestly has
everything to do with you being able to
actually figure out an income stream and
then do that while maintaining your
content and personal brands consistent
posting. So during this 10K month, I was
taking sales calls and I was taking
client calls where I was basically
hopping on these one-to-one client calls
and helping other people with their own
social media brands and it massively
downsized the effort that I had to put
into my content because I used to spend
like 4 hours per video per short-form
video and they would go viral. They
would get 100,000 to a million views.
But I realized if I want to actually be
able to sustain running a whole business
on top of my content, I had to be able
to pump out videos in like one or two
hours. So what did I do? I specifically
wrote down in a Google Doc what is
exactly the pre-filming routine that I
do. So okay, what is a pre-filming
routine? I visualize whoever my ideal
viewer is, my younger self, and then I
speak to them. I specifically use a like
a template-ized hook and I have a doc
now of 300 viral hooks that I have
repeatedly used and I literally just go
to that now and just like close my eyes.
I'm just like, "Ah, this one." And then
I'll like use whatever hook that is.
This kind of goes back to the phase two
of doubling down on what works, but you
should have a bullet point list of what
to do and what not to do in your videos
to avoid common mistakes that prevent
you from going viral, words that you say
in your first 3 seconds that you must
hit in order for viewers to actually
resonate, things to avoid like dead
space, you know, overly scripting to the
point you where you sound robotic. Maybe
that's one of the bullet points that you
write down in your videos. You should
have a systematized standard operating
procedure, that's what you call it in
business, an SOP, to train yourself
every single day to be able to make
content without making it your entire
personality, your entire day because you
have a whole business to run now. And
that's something I wish I knew sooner as
somebody who started off as just a
creative and had to learn this whole
business side and juggling both honestly
burnt me out at times. And I'm going to
now transition this to sustaining 10K a
month because I hit my first 10K a month
in May of 2023, but I only started
hitting consistent 10K months about 9
months later in February of 2024, right?
So what was that whole gap there of
being able to actually sustain 10K a
month because for a really long time it
was up down up down up down. 10K a
month, $0 a month. 10K a month, 500
bucks a month. And that literally kept
repeating. Oh, I hit like a 15K a month.
Oh, we dropped down to 500 bucks the
next month. Like that happened for
around a cycle of 9 months and I do
believe sustaining 10K a month is
sticking to the boring work [music] even
when it gets repetitive. I think a lot
of people, especially content creators,
really chase these highs and the
dopamine of doing creative [ __ ] doing
the [ __ ] that's fun to you and exciting
to you because ideas for new videos are
really exciting and you kind of get to
entertain your shiny object syndrome by
making a new video every single month.
But business is not like that. Business,
you have to stick to one offer for like
3 months at a time. Have you ever
committed to a single business idea for
over 3 months? And if you're more of a
beginner watching this point, I'm like,
"Why the [ __ ] are you still watching
this point if you're a beginner? Like go
execute on shit." You probably aren't
used to like committing to any kind of
like business endeavor or side hustle
for longer than 1 month at a time. So
you have to get out of this side hustle
mentality of switching ideas all the
time and actually commit to one business
and one offer. And the month that I
actually committed to one offer that I
actually enjoyed running, which was
Content Academy at the time. We I
literally opened up just a Discord
server. It was the most bare-bones
thing. I charged 50 bucks a month. It
was one of those like WhatsApp
communities where it was just a Discord
server and then it was [music] like two
hours of Loom videos. 50 bucks a month.
And the first month, 40% we had 40%
churn. Literally 40% of the customers
that came in left. But I enjoyed it and
for the first time I really felt
fulfilled in serving beginners because I
realized for the whole time before I was
consulting these older business owners,
but I was a [ __ ] 20-year-old doing
this and I didn't resonate at all with
the problems that business owners were
going through cuz I was a 20-year-old.
So once I actually committed to an offer
and you don't need to like love your
ICP, you know, this this whole like
woo-woo [ __ ] Honestly, I don't think
that's true. But once you actually
commit to just one offer, stick with it
even if it gets boring, [music] even if
you have a low month. You're probably
going to have to tweak your pricing over
time. You're probably going to have to
tweak the deliverables, your onboarding,
your sales process. You might start with
sales calls, but then you might switch
to more of like a landing page funnel.
And then you might have to try webinars.
All of these different things, you're
probably going to have to get used to
doing a lot of different [ __ ] and
change. But throughout all this change,
you need to stick to one offer because
if you're constantly starting from, you
know, you're trying one thing. You're
treating business like a situationship
where you're just somewhat committed
living dickedly to like this one idea of
an offer, but then you stop after 2
months after it gets kind of hard and
you, you know, your clients and your
lead flow gets dry after 2 weeks. Like
you will remain in this perpetual cycle.
And I know people. I I've met people
years prior who got in this perpetual
cycle of trying something and then
quitting after like 3 months after it
got hard. And another thing that's
helped me is gunning for like a 20 or
30K a month rather than just 10K a
month. I genuinely believe if you want
to set a higher standard for your norm,
right? And if you want to sustain 10K a
month, which I believe is a kind of like
freedom number to be able to, you know,
travel the world, eat Chipotle by
yourself like a lunch and, you know, a
Plabo every single day and not have to
worry about the price of things. Like I
remember specifically the one thing that
I loved after unlocking 10K a month was
just being able to eat a Subway sandwich
every day after class and going being
able to afford one of those really
expensive, egregiously priced Plabo
smoothies that are 10 bucks a month,
adding a $2 protein scoop into it and
being able to afford it every single day
and not have to worry about that. Now
that's obviously still a really stupid
use of money, [music] but whatever that
visualization of freedom is, it really
does unlock when you consistently hit
10K a month. But if you're just hitting
one 10K a month, but then you're not
sure that you're going to actually be
able to sustain it, then you're probably
going to be constantly in this state of
scarcity where, "Ah, I don't know. Like
I don't know if I should be able to buy
this. I don't know if I'll be able to,
you know, I should pay for this because
I don't know how my income's going to
look next month." Sustaining 10K a month
is the key to freedom, not hitting one
single 10K a month. And trust me,
there's a big difference. It was a
9-month difference for me in being able
to do this and it was not views
whatsoever. It was my ability to
consistently commit to just one thing
even when when it got hard. So one other
lesson that I had to learn as a business
owner is just like there's going to be
moments that are like deeply
uncomfortable. And in content, I don't
think that's the case. In content, like
[music] most of the time you're actually
trying to remain playful. You're trying
to remain in a state of having fun. With
business, that is not the [ __ ] case.
Like you might hate sales. You might be
a really big people pleaser like me and
you hated being like trying to sell
people on a call and then sales always
felt grimy to you. Or managing people,
dude. I I hate managing people. Like,
"Oh my gosh. Like it it like stresses me
out. My core is all spiced and then I
feel like I can't do what I want to do,
which is create content." Well, I had to
learn that. I had to spend months
learning that in order to be able to
sustain 10K a month and run an actual
business that scaled past me because I
capped out at around 15K a month and
then once like I hired my friend Sam as
a content coach within our community and
then also this guy named Justin who I
met in the summer of 2024, the moment
that I actually hired a community
manager inside our community, our
business jumped from [music] 15K a month
to 50K a month. So sustaining 10K a
month is also how you set this kind of
foundation and floor to then build on
top of to then scale higher. And what I
mean by this foundation and floor is
that once you have 10K a month coming
in, now you can actually pay $2,000 a
month to another person. And that's huge
cuz now you can start outsourcing these
parts of the things like responding to
your DMs all the time. That was a big
thing that held me up is like I had to
be super [music] engaged inside my
community and I still love engaging
inside Content Academy, but every single
one of these small questions in the DMs
like, "Where do I find this resource?
Where do I find like the AI content
writer?" All these questions that I
would be literally repeating every
single day and have to context switch
every single day. Being able to invest
in a team member who helped out with all
of those things was [ __ ] massive to
me. I'm like genuinely so grateful that
I have the luxury of being able to work
with a team of people on my business cuz
it also makes it just more fun for me.
It makes it less lonely. Now it's
transitioning from sustaining 10K a
month to be able to hit 100K a
month. Now throughout all of this, I
know at this point I've deviated a lot
from content, but [music] like I said,
being able to get your first 10K a month
and systematizing your content creation
process will help make all of this
possible. You still have to create
[music] this You have to still have to
make this content engine keep running.
One thing that's helped me, one resource
that's helped me, is this concept of a
minimum viable video where now I don't
even script most of my videos. I just
have a general framework of bullet
points and I just lead with a hook in
the beginning of my videos. So that's
like one framework that's cut down 30
minutes of scripting time. Another
framework that's helped cut down like 30
minutes of editing time is using
transcript-based editing in CapCut.
Basically allows you to edit using the
the like script of your video and you
just tap the you highlight the words
that you want to delete and you just
delete them. So helps you delete all the
dead space and the repetitive moments
where you're just speaking again and
again and again cuz you have to resay
[music] the line. Helps you cut down all
those things. I am able to cut down my
videos now within the span of 5 to 10
minutes rather than spending 30, 40
minutes like I used to. Another one is
auto captions on CapCut. You press this
button and then I make my auto captions
the classic TikTok font. I highly
recommend the classic TikTok font. It's
the most, you know, universally
accepted, visually pleasing, visually
familiar font for short-form videos.
It's what people resonate the most with
and it's the easiest to read, frankly,
for most TikTok and Instagram Reel
viewers. And you just make them two to
three words at a time on the screen. Now
I set a goal of 100K a month back in
January of 2024 and only in January of
2025 did I actually hit that. And it was
exactly 12 months after starting the
offer Content Academy where we finally
hit 100K a month. So what actually got
us there to that first 100K a month? The
first thing was outsourcing sales. It's
a very specific thing, but I hired my
friend Prosper [music] to help take
sales calls and he took probably like
20, 30 sales calls during that month of
January. So, that allowed me to not take
any sales calls basically and just focus
on creating content and generating leads
for our business, [music] generating
demand for our coaching services. So,
that was one, outsourcing sales. The
other one was honestly just being able
to compartmentalize and create content
consistently for months prior. Cuz I
don't think honestly there was anything
special about that 100K month. It's just
that it was essentially a liquidation of
my goodwill that I built up for my
audience. I had around 300,000 Instagram
followers at this point on my page and
that is after posting around 400 [music]
daily vlogs in the series documenting my
business journey called Road to 100K a
Month. I don't think there was something
crazy about that 100K month. It's just
the fact that I had built up so much
demand for my coaching in the past year
of posting about it constantly and just
not selling too much. And then that one
month, I just posted on my story every
single week being like, "Apply to my
coaching. I I opened up one-to-one
coaching just for this month. I opened
up one-to-one coaching just for this
month." It wasn't sustainable. The next
month, our business actually only made
25K, right? So, [music] like technically
speaking, it wasn't really a sustained
100K month. So, I'm not going to pretend
like, you know, hitting that 100K that
first 100K month is the most like crazy
thing and you suddenly you just unlock
the freedom of a 100K month. Cuz
sustaining it is actually I believe
significantly harder and that's the
phase that I'm in in business right now,
trying to learn how to [music] sustain
100K months. But hitting that first one
I genuinely believe you just have to
build up a [ __ ] ton of goodwill with
your audience, right? Build up an actual
authority in a space [music] and then
outsource sales to the point where
you're just able to constantly be
selling. When I be When I When I say
constantly selling, I mean don't just do
like a couple days launch. Most likely
you're probably going to have to have a
closer that's closing deals like every
week for you. And I was able to do that
thankfully with a friend, but you can
hire closes just by like posting a story
and just by posting a Google form and
then you just interview them on like
Zoom calls for like 15 minutes each.
Outsourcing sales that helps you do the
highest ROI thing in your business. Cuz
at this point if you are actually are
serious and you need to scale to 100K
months, you need to be pumping out sh-
[ __ ] ton of content and you need to be
on top of your content game. Like in
that month of January, I was also like
consistently putting out pretty viral
videos like every single week I think I
had a video hit a million views and that
helped a lot. So, your ability and your
propensity to be able to do that [music]
will determine how much goodwill you
have in your audience and how many
people you're able to actually sell to.
And I think a lot of scaling to 100K a
month was being able to free up my own
time. Like at the time I also read this
book Buy Back Your Time by Dan Martell
and freeing up your time to actually do
the highest ROI thing, which is making
videos [music] for your business. And I
think a lot of people who get stuck at
around like 30, 50K a month in business,
especially coaching or online service
businesses, are so attached and so in
the weeds of their day-to-day work. Like
they don't have an operator helping them
behind the scenes run these small things
like their funnels, their sales
processes. They are managing the whole
thing. And it's not just the fact like
you probably have enough time to be able
to do that, but do you have the
bandwidth to both creatively think of
these big picture ideas that will help
you go viral while also doing these
short-term tasks like responding to all
the DMs, responding to all the messages
every single day, hopping on sales
calls. Like you probably have [music]
just enough hours to be able to do that,
but if you're on this investment banker
kind of routine, you might think you
have the discipline and the motivation
to be able to dog through it, but you're
probably just going to show up really
shittily in your content because your
brain's half thinking about what funnels
you need to make, what like customers
you need to sell and it puts your brain
in this scarce place, at least
personally, where that I can't show up
and be the [music] most creative person
and I can't be my most like expressive
version of myself. I don't feel
connected to my mission anymore because
I'm constantly thinking about how to
make money from it, which is necessary
to run a business, but as a creator I
think that takes me out of my like flow
state. And being in a flow as a creator
helps you consistently pump out viral
videos and I think the best creators who
run like the largest personal brand
operations are really on top of their
content and they don't let that part of
their brain slip up. Now, let's talk
really big picture about sustaining 100K
a month. Now, I will be very honest. I
am not 100% there at like sustained 100K
months. I'll I'll just like open up my
dashboard and just show you guys the
numbers. So, honestly just transparently
show you guys some of these things that
I'm like paying attention to on a like
daily or or weekly basis. So,
our business in November did 100,
>> [music]
>> our business in December did 85, our
business in January was a big month. We
also did like a hard organic push where
we're giving away $10,000 to our
students. So, that's 170K and then in
February we had a 82,000. So far in the
past 24 days, I think we might just
reach around 90 to 100 in the next four
days, but you know, we'll see. Like
nothing is for certain because we
currently have a a sales call funnel
where you either book a book a call to
actually join our community or we have
like webinars where we have a free class
and at the end we basically explain what
Content Academy is. So, that's like the
numbers in our business, but also I just
want to highlight some things like we
have obviously our whole internal team
Discord server now. We have a team of
basically around five or six people
working [music] part-time-ish and then
like we have like our whole like sales
dashboard where we track, you know, show
rates, close rates on our calls, etc. If
there's one thing that I feel like I'm
learning here is that one, as with any
kind of [music] setting a foundation of
a business, it probably makes more sense
to set a higher goal. And if I were to
sustain 100K a month with Content
Academy, realistically it's probably by
us setting a goal to aim for 200K a
month and that's kind of where we are at
right now. So, I think that's a lesson
I'm learning right now is that like, oh,
in order to sustain certain types of
months, you probably just need to aim
[music] for a higher month and that
pushes you to raise a standard across
all the board for these things like
sales, marketing, for product. It forces
[music] me to actually learn how to
learn these skills of systematizing,
delegating, managing a team and like
still marketing alongside all of that.
And it's been very, I would say, a a
lesson of stress for me [music] like
learning stress tolerance, being able to
see these moving numbers go up and down
obviously because everything [music]
fluctuates on a daily, weekly basis and
be able to be okay with that.
>> [music]
>> Like one particular thing in the past
month has been learning ads. You know,
actually learning how to do meta ads on
Instagram to promote [music] Content
Academy, specifically promote the free
classes that we're doing. That's been
really stressful to see the ads. Like
we're we're spending now like 20K a
month, 30K a month on ads
>> [music]
>> and that's like really stressful to see
that number go up, you know? Thinking
about the idea of our business becoming
unprofitable even for a month is like
really, really stressful for me. With
all those things I would say like what
I'm learning is to once again be okay
with surrendering the preferences that I
have for my lifestyle, be okay with
understanding that with growth comes
difficulty and stress and lots of
emotion. I I do believe all these
lessons of being able to deal with
higher levels of stress, tolerate more
levels of stress and push to a higher
level has made me a better person. It's
made me a more capable leader,
communicator and I think at the core
that's what's the most important. It's
not necessarily, you know, like just
growing a larger number here and there
cuz I I guess if this last part is
relatable to you, it's like I think at
the core my core driver now is just to
learn and grow. When I first hit that
first 100K a month, [music] I think I
felt kind of empty because I felt like I
mean at the end of the day I sold it
really hard to my [music] audience for
that. And and then it felt like I
extracted a lot of from this pot of
goodwill to the point where now I'm
like, "Well, I don't want to have to do
that every single month. I want to be
able to systematize it so I can actually
feel good sustaining these bigger months
or else what's the point of even running
the business long-term if I don't even
really enjoy the day-to-day process of
running it. Like why would I even want
to scale to larger months then?" And
I've also had to think deeper about like
why do I even actually want to push to
this deeper level of discomfort. I would
say 100K a month was like a big target
number where I could prove to myself,
"Oh, I know how to run an online
business."
>> [music]
>> And I could prove to myself that like
this content creation thing actually
could work. And it was just a flashy
number that I could chase. But now it's
like sustaining it, there's not as much
excitement. Now I've just settled into
[music] this boring day-to-day of like
running the offer, making sure that
everything is still running and all the
systems and all the people are motivated
and still working and
>> [music]
>> that's been really stressful and not
fun, you know? And I feel like I've had
to like change into a different person.
I think it's through all these
throughout all these steps of the
journey I have had [music] to change
too, but I'll say this journey is
specifically of scaling and sustaining
100K months
has been like deeply uncomfortable for
me, but throughout [music] that entire
journey
I think it's been worth it and I think
the thing that's made it worth it has
been just seeing myself grow and seeing
how I've been able to be comfortable in
more uncomfortable situations like in
more stressful situations. I I think
that's where I want to leave off the
video is like I guess as we grow cuz I
don't think this whole journey of
growing from like literally a complete
beginner as a creator to eventually
maybe starting your own business is just
like sustainably being a creator who's
constantly pumping out content. You're
going to go through these phases of
shedding off old skin and shedding off
old identities and all to say I think
that's good. I think growth and [music]
experiencing these new things of seeing
different sides of yourself is always
interesting, I think. And regardless of
like whether it's comfortable or not,
I'm just really grateful now that I get
to experience on a day-to-day the
emotions of stress and fear cuz I know
it's pushing me to be a better person
and just experience new things in life,
[music] experience new aspects of life
that I never had, which is like really
high stress tolerance. So, yeah, I guess
that's
that's the full journey of going from
zero followers to now running a I guess
[music] you could call it like a
seven-figure year business.
If you found this helpful, you know, I
obviously run a community that coaches
content creators and if you want help
growing your personal brand, starting
content and that is [music] a and this
is a journey that, you know, you want to
embark on. Um we do weekly calls [music]
where me and three other coaches, we hop
on a a call every single week to [music]
answer any of your questions, to improve
your videos, to look at what can be
improved in your content, and give you
feedback wherever you need. And yeah, if
you want help, just apply in that first
link down below, and I'll see you guys
in the next video. Thank you guys so
much for watching. Peace.