Quite possibly every single business
guru online right now is telling you to
build a personal brand. It's the way to
survive in the age of AI, but nobody
tells you how to actually do it on a
realistically time-bound schedule. So,
today with my girlfriend, because she
always tells me that I struggle to meet
time and I'm always super duper late, we
have agreed that I must script, film,
and edit an entire video in the next 60
minutes, or else she can post whatever
she wants on my Instagram page.
Guys, it's within your best interest
that he does not make the deadline.
>> [laughter]
>> 3 2 1 begin. Okay, let's go. Okay, we're
going to start with our process. So,
here's the process that we're going to
do. We're going to ideate, then we're
going to script, then we're going to
film, and then we're going to edit. I
probably should take around 5 minutes to
ideate, 5 to 10 minutes, then around 15
minutes to script, then around 10
minutes to film, and then around 30
minutes to edit. That's my usual
cadence. So, you can actually do this
process with me and I highly highly
encourage it because this is the exact
process I've used to grow 500,000
followers in the past 2 years, and I was
doing this process while I was literally
a college student and also building my
business during that entire process. So,
let's actually jump onto our computer
and start the ideation process. Oh [ __ ]
in the past 2 minutes I've literally
just goofed off cuz I talked to the
[ __ ] camera. The first step is
actually market research, and this is
what 99% of people won't tell you about
Reels. They'll tell you that you need to
make a hook, a viral hook, or you need
to use a storytelling framework. In
reality, you should probably actually
know your niche and format, and then
research videos on other platforms for
outliers. And I'll tell you exactly what
an outlier is, but this is actually my
recommendation to all of you guys who
are newer to Instagram. [music]
Don't guess around what actual virality
looks like. If you want to make a viral
video tonight, what you need to do is
find viral-proven ideas, and I highly
recommend you use YouTube. So, I'm here.
I'm not sponsored, by the way, but this
is a tool called 10X, and basically what
it allows you to do is find outliers,
right, based on certain parameters here.
So, these are the parameters that I
have. An outlier score of 1.4 plus,
which basically just means
a video that's performed 1.4 times the
average views of a channel, and I put
the minimum views to be 10K because I
don't want any ideas that are sitting at
like 1,000 views. That's not an outlier
in my opinion, that's just like a small
channel. And then lastly, publication
date in the last 6 months. So, once we
have these settings, we're going to
actually look for video ideas here. And
I'm just going to set a quick 5-minute
timer because I also like to put a
time-bound pressure on myself to
actually get these ideas done because if
I don't, then I'm actually just going to
not get it done. I think it's a concept
called Pareto's principle, but work
fills up the time that it's allotted.
So, you give ideating and brainstorming
more time, it could take 2 hours, you
might just end up doomscrolling. So,
let's actually scroll with intention in
the outliers. And I'm going to open up a
Google Doc video idea. What we're going
to do is I'm just going to look through
uh I spent 24 hours in the hood. And I'm
just going to screenshot these outliers
cuz these are all good video concepts,
right? And I'm What I'm going to do is
going to like paste them onto the
document just to jog my brainstorming
ideas. I spent 24 hours, and now this is
where our niche and format come in. So,
for me personally, my niche is content
creation and online business, and then
my format is challenge videos, it's
talking head advice videos, it's
educational videos. So, I spent 24 hours
making a video. I spent And I'm just
literally going to brain dump any ideas
that come to my mind. The goal is to get
out of our own conscious logical
thinking and just brain dump anything
that comes to mind. So, I spent 24
hours. Maybe instead of 24 hours, I
spent 1 hour making a vi- video. I spent
30 hours doing a side hustle. Nah, I I
don't think this idea works as well, and
I'm just going to keep looking and
screenshotting and pasting concepts. So,
the goal here is to find working titles
and thumbnails. And you're probably
wondering, how does this convert over to
short-form video? And the answer is a
YouTube title is essentially the spoken
or verbal hook of a Instagram Reel or
TikTok. So, instead of putting this as a
title, it would you would literally say
out loud, I spent 24 hours in the hood
to find out   , right?
That's pretty much what it is. And then
the visual hook is usually informed by
the actual thumbnail visuals because
this is what got people to click, hence
this is what will inform what will get
people to actually stop on your video
and find it interesting and compelling.
So, I spent 24 hours in the hood. I
don't think this is that interest- or I
don't think this is as applicable. I do
make challenge videos, so I do think the
I spend X hours could be a winning
framework here. I I like this 50/50
right here. I think it's a good like
transformation-esque video. I did spend
actually in December 30 hours learning a
side hustle.
You could also do, if you're making a
video right now, here's an idea for you.
It's like I spent 24 hours trying viral
blanks. So, like viral side hustles,
viral restaurant like restaurants
in in my area, or like viral video game,
or trying video game cheat codes, like
etc., right? This video is about I spent
10 hours mastering Bruce Lee. Let's
actually see the video itself. Uh let's
see the full title here. So, this is
obviously an outlier video. It has 750K
views on a 200K subscriber channel. So,
you can see it's a 1.9X 250K view
average versus well, the video itself
had 750K. [clears throat] So, clearly
it's growing very fast, but let's see.
This is Bruce Lee, the actor and martial
artist, taking on Elliot Hulse, the
terrifying Okay, I spent 30 hours trying
the most viral side hustle.
Uh in December, I guess I did try I
spent 30 hours mastering a side hustle
to find out like if I can make 10K a
month from it. 1 month. That's a little
wordy, but I have a hook here now, and
I'm thinking I can do a clip of the
first hour of that side hustle challenge
for me, and then I can do I'm guessing
the last hour, so like 30 hours in.
Okay, okay, so we're done we're done
ideating, and I think I have to settle
on this idea. But I'm thinking instead
of I spent 30 hours trying a new side
hustle, trying to grow a brand new
Instagram account from scratch to see if
it's a money glitch. And this is me like
I guess referencing footage from that
month, but hour 1 can [music] equal the
shot of me posting my first video, and
then
hour 30 equals shot of me making money
from it cuz I actually did make money
from this side hustle called UGC. So,
now we have the general hook structure.
I spent 30 hours trying
I still think this hook needs a little
bit of work. Trying to grow And right
now, what I'm basically doing is just
thinking through what will be the most
interesting, but also easy to understand
version of this hook cuz general rule of
thumb that I do with my hooks is that I
need to make sure they under- they are
understandable to a literal 5-year-old.
So, I spent 30 hours trying to grow a
brand new Instagram account. I don't
need from scratch. Creating a brand new
Instagram account, content creation is a
valid [music]
side hustle. Uh let's actually see the
video. It's now with the scripting
framework, what I'm actually going to do
is I'm just going to study how this
video actually scripted its general
structure. Obviously, it's 25 minutes
long, but for the Instagram Reel that
we're making, probably just going to
make it like, you know, 60 seconds. So,
we're kind of condensing down the
storytelling framework that this
person's doing in a 25-minute video down
to a 60-second, 90-second Reel. And
undefeated champion. See, I don't think
I would stand a chance against Bruce
Lee's level of stardom. The challenge
again is the activist is Bruce Lee, the
actor and martial artist, taking on Lee.
Mhm, this is Bruce Lee, the actor and
martial artist. I think the framework is
this is blank,
the and then a kind of explanation of
what it is. The viral side hustle where
brands pay you to post on a brand new
Instagram account. This is UGC, the
viral I spent 30 hours learning a new
side hustle cuz that's actually true, it
was a new side hustle for me, learning
this side hustle called UGC. Learning a
new side hustle to see if it's
a money glitch. This is UGC, the viral
side hustle where brands pay you to post
on a brand new Instagram account.
>> But here's the thing, I am
using Bruce Lee in some Mhm, so here's
something that the storytelling
framework I think uses, which is it
[music] says, "But here's the thing,"
and it introduces another premise here.
Because at the end of the day, a video
can probably hook you for the first like
[music] 10, 15 seconds on a YouTube
video, but then in order to get somebody
to watch 25 minutes, they need something
called a rehook, which basically sets up
the conflict and the premise for the
entire video to make you hooked into
watching it. It's like like I'm I
gathered here 100 strangers. When Mr.
Beast says, "I gathered here 100
strangers to find out who is the
strongest, but here's the thing, the
winner gets $100,000." So, it introduces
a stake. But here's the thing, I have to
do it on a brand new Instagram account
to prove I'm loaded with the sauce.
Okay, so now we're fully deep into the
scripting process here, and we're just
scripting out the entire video. Here's
what I'm thinking here. This is my hook,
and I'm just going to highlight it in
yellow, and then I'm going to put my
visual hook next to it, which is this.
But here's the thing, I have to do it on
a brand new Instagram account to prove
you don't need followers, you just need
the skills.
Let me actually see how he develops the
scripting structure, and something I
like to look at is the climax and the
conclusion of a video. That usually
informs what the ending's going to look
like, and then from there I can kind of
string together the middle, but let's
see here. The ending looks So, it looks
like he's You know what I do think? I
think I need to introduce
conflict or like struggle. And this is a
classic storytelling thing. I think a
lot of people just showcase their best
moments in a in a Instagram reel, but
what people and viewers really want to
see is real human struggle. That's why
we like watching movies, for example,
Hollywood movies, because they usually
portray a a protagonist going through
very deep struggles. What's a deep
struggle that actually went through? The
reason why I'm doing this, I wanted to
buy my dad a watch as a gift. I I think
it was it literally exactly like $5,000.
No, I think it was $6,000. The reason
why I'm doing this is I want to buy my
dad a watch as a gift that cost me six
that cost $6,000,
but was struggling because my Okay, I
have 43 minutes. You guys need context
on this [ __ ] video. I'm just
scripting literally in my brain. But let
me explain some context. So, basically
what happened in this actual side hustle
story, I started this side hustle and it
was this thing called UGC, where you
basically get paid to promote apps,
right, on Instagram reels. This is all
real, by the way. Like I'm not making up
this story. And simultaneously, I
basically in that UGC account, I
documented me building an actual app
from scratch with vibe coded. But the
problem was that people [ __ ] hate
vibe coders, so my app got slammed with
one-star reviews because people were
just like, "Yo, this is some vibe coded
slop." And it wasn't great, it was kind
of buggy, but you know, people are extra
critical because they hate vibe coded
content. Bombed [snorts] with one star.
How did he conclude this video? Let's
see the ending. Mom here has practiced
one kick 10,000 times, and that's when
it hit me. All these kicks are great in
his moveset, but true mastery comes from
mastering one move. And from Mhm.
Did you notice what he did there in his
storytelling framework, which we are
going to steal and twist into our own
video about side hustles? That's when I
realized the true point of a side hustle
isn't to become excellent. Uh isn't to
become rich in 30 days. It's to build up
the skill set and potential to turn your
skill set into a full-time business one
day. I think it's okay not to be
perfect. I like this message. After just
1 month, like every guru will pretend
like they are. When I thought hope was
over, I realized an Apple payout sent me
$1,000. This is actually what happened.
I realize how [ __ ] random it might
seem to you
cuz I'm just jaw like Hopefully this is
insightful. I'm literally just brain
dumping my actual scripting process,
which a lot of it's subconscious, I will
say, but hopefully you get the general
framework here, which is that I take
frameworks from really good videos from
creators outside my niche, and then I
spin it into my own niche and style, and
then I use those principles of why
things get attention and why things
create intrigue and emotion in a video,
and then I spin it into my own story.
That's what storytelling's about. I
think a lot of people say this [ __ ]
about storytelling, where it's like,
"Yo, storytelling, you just need to like
go with the flow and like use
descriptive words and use transitionary
words." And yes, that's possible, but at
the end of the day, nobody's born being
a [ __ ] naturally goated storyteller.
[clears throat] I think that's what all
these Instagram gurus don't tell you, is
that a lot of times to learn
storytelling, just study other
storytellers, and then, you know, copy
their frameworks first because you need
to copy before you can just, you know,
actually reinvent the wheel and be an
original artist. That sent me $1,000. It
was around $1,000. I forgot how much
Apple paid me for the app, but I
actually did make money from the app.
This is actually how much money the app
made, by the way. This is just a random
side tangent. That made 3K. Holy [ __ ]
Wait, that's actually a lot of money.
Damn. For my first ever app I vibe
coded, by the way. But just when I
thought hope was over, I got an Apple
payout that sent me $1,000 for my app,
and I could finally afford
uh and then at the end that's when the
music will turn into like a nice, happy,
uh fancy ending.
Just when I thought hope was over, I got
an Apple payout that sent me $1,000 for
my app, and I could finally afford my
dad's dream watch. Okay, bet. We're
basically there. And now at this point I
just need to actually string together
the clips, but this is a general
scripting framework. And now I'm just
going to fill in the blanks here. I
spent 30 hours Now, here's a little
thing. I like to read out my scripts
aloud just so I can imagine what it's
like to actually see the video come
together. Cuz it's one thing to write
with our fingers, pause. It's another
thing to actually intuitively script in
a way that we actually speak like and
humans actually speak like. And you want
to avoid the robot voice when you're
scripting, which is very easy and common
to to fall into, which is, you know,
it's normal because you're just
scripting with your fingers most of the
time. So, you actually have to get out
of that and speak out loud. Secret
marketing the videos for them. Oh, okay,
I like that cuz then I introduce the
brand new Instagram concept. I spent 30
hours learning a new side hustle to see
if it's a money glitch. This is UGC, the
viral side hustle where brands pay you
to post secret marketing videos for
them. But here's the thing, maybe that
transition worked, but the only problem
is I think it's a problem. I'm posting
on a brand new Instagram account account
to prove you don't need followers to
make money with social media. So, on day
one, I devised a master plan. I'm going
to vibe code an actual app, then post
on my new Instagram account documenting
this journey. At the end of the month, I
could afford my dad's $6,000 dream
watch.
Uh okay, and now we're going to
introduce struggle [clears throat] here.
Holy [ __ ] I only have 30 minutes left.
I should be editing by now. [ __ ] On day
one, things went smoothly.
Actually, I won't even say that. I just
posted my first video. Then 7 days in,
things [clears throat]
took a crazy turn. We just got our app
on the App Store. Clip. This is like a
clip from my camera roll cuz I'm going
to splice in B-roll clips as well. This
is a more advanced storytelling video,
by the way. I understand a lot of you
guys who are watching are complete
[ __ ] beginners who probably have
never done like complex editing before.
So, do not be overwhelmed by this style
of content, by the way. This is like the
most advanced possible guide I can give
you guys, but this is how I've grown
500,000 followers in 2 years. It's by
doing good [ __ ] content. Everybody
who'll tell you you can post absolute
[ __ ] dog [ __ ] slop just because you
have nice viral brand pillars, [music]
is [ __ ] lying to you to sell you some
[ __ ] I don't know, digital product
course thing. Ironically, cuz I also do
have a coaching community, but we do get
insane results. Like all these. Editor,
please throw up screenshot on the screen
so I don't look like an idiot. Anyways,
we got our vibe coded app somehow on the
App Store, and that video blew up. We
just got our first X dollar payout.
We're posting a video every 2 days,
started going crazy from there.
Actually, our X I think that's Maybe
instead of 30 day 30 hours, I spent 30
days learning a new side hustle to see.
Yeah, I think this is way better. 30
days is way better than 30 hours. 7 days
in, then day 20. Our video started
popping
off. At this point I think I can have a
somewhat unfinished script, and I think
I'm just going to [ __ ]
you know, like freestyle the rest of it,
figure out in the editing. Things
started going crazy from there. Videos
started popping off. My app started made
its first dollar by day 21. But then, my
worst nightmare happened. We got
bombarded hate comments. The app started
getting bombed with one-star reviews.
Okay, we're introducing struggle. Let's
[ __ ] go. And I started losing
all
motivation. Even though the UGC was
making money, side hustle was making
money because my videos were going
viral, it felt like every time I went
viral, I attracted more and more hate to
this app I was pouring actual hours of
loving effort into. By 30 days in, we
posted I think we posted 15 15 videos.
We made $5,000,
but we were still shy of 6K goal. Worst
of all, I felt defeated from all the
hate. That's when I remembered, even if
I didn't become Iga Iman Ghadzi rich in
30 days, I learned so much about content
and coding that I never would have
learned on my own. Made me confident to
build world-changing businesses. Okay.
Okay, script is over. Script is over.
Let's go [ __ ] film. Okay, so now what
we're going to do, I'm going to screen
record. I need to go onto Google Docs.
And now what I'm going to do is I'm
basically going to go to my my video
script here, and I'm just literally
going to copy and paste this into
CapCut. And I'll show you exactly why
I'm copy and pasting this. I have 24
minutes to film and edit. Holy [ __ ] I
have to one-shot this video. I've never
one-shotted a video on one take, but
let's do it. Let's Let's become goated.
Let's literally become goated right now.
What we're going to do now is go into
the transcript in CapCut and we're going
to read it out loud in the video. So,
here's exactly how it works. I'm going
to try this new trick where I saw this
guy say, "So, in this video and then he
says it." So, in this video, I spent 30
hours learning a new side hustle
I get so over my words. So, in this
video, I spent 30 hours learning a new
side hustle to see if it's a money
glitch. This is UGC, the viral side
hustle where brands pay you to post
secret marketing videos for them, but
the only problem is I'm posting on a
brand new Instagram account to prove you
don't need followers to make money with
social media. So, on day one, I devised
a master plan. I'm going to make UGC
videos promoting a vibe coding app, then
vibe code an actual app and post on my
UGC account documenting this journey.
And the goal by the end of this month is
to afford my dad his $6,000 dream watch.
Now, 7 days into this challenge, things
took a crazy turn. Our vibe coded app
somehow got onto the App Store and that
video blew up. We just caught our first
Okay, okay, okay.
Things started going crazy. Things
started going nuclear from there. Our
video started popping off and going
viral. My app made its first dollar, but
then my worst nightmare happened. We got
bombarded with hate comments after we
went viral. The app started getting
bombed with one-star reviews and I
started to lose all motivation. Even
though the UGC side hustle was making
money because my videos were going
viral, it felt like every time I went
viral, I attracted more and more hate to
this app I was pouring actual hours of
loving effort into and people just
didn't see that cuz it was vibe coded.
So, 30 days in, we posted 15 videos. We
made $5,000,
but we were still just shy of that 6K
goal. And worst of all, I felt defeated
from all the hate. But that's when I
remembered, even if I didn't become giga
Elon Godzi rich in 30 days like I
thought, I learned so much about content
and coding that made me confident to
build a world-changing business in the
future with these skills. But just when
I thought my challenge would end in a
motivational quote, I got an Apple
payout that sent me $1,000 for the app
and I could finally afford [music]
my dad's dream watch, even if it was a
couple months later.
Boom! Okay, we're done filming. We have
to literally edit right away. Holy [ __ ]
we have 20 minutes. Okay, let's do this.
I spent 30 hours learning a new side
hustle to see if it's a money glitch.
This is UGC, the viral side hustle where
brands pay you to post secret marketing
videos for them, but the only problem is
I'm posting on a brand new Instagram
account to prove you don't need
followers to make money with social
media. I'm going to cut out that space
here. Video. So, on day one, I devised a
master plan. I'm going to make UGC
videos promoting a vibe coding app, then
vibe code an actual app and post on my
UGC account documenting this journey.
And the goal by the end of this month is
to afford my dad his $6,000 dream watch.
And 7 days into this challenge, things
took a crazy turn. I'm hitting flow
state, baby. We're going to do this. Our
vibe coded app somehow got onto the App
Store and that video blew up. Things
started going nuclear from there. Our
video started popping off and going
viral. My app made its first dollar, but
then my worst nightmare happened. We got
bombarded with hate comments after we
went viral and I started to lose all
motivation. though the UGC side hustle
was making money because my videos were
going viral, it felt like every time I
went viral, I attracted more and more
hate to this app I was pouring actual
hours of loving effort into. 30 days in,
we posted 15 videos. We made $5,000, but
we were still just shy of that 6K goal.
And worst of all, I felt defeated from
all the hate. But that's when I
remembered, even if I didn't become giga
Elon Godzi rich in 30 changing business
in the future with these skills. But
just when I thought my challenge would
end in a motivational quote, I got an
Apple payout that sent me $1,000 for the
app and I could finally afford my dad's
dream watch. Boom! All right, we're
done. We're done. We're done. Okay, now
we need to Now, after we finished the
rough cutting, we need to start adding
B-roll. Let's go. Okay, I spent 30 days.
So, now, based on my actual script, I
see in the first sentence, right? I want
to match this visual hook, hour one and
hour 10. In this case, it's 30 days, day
one, day 10. So, we're going to do that
by actually finding the B-roll from this
month here, which was in December of
for me when I actually did this
challenge.
Now, we're going to delete [music] this
part. I'm going to mute the B-roll clip.
Okay, this is a B-roll clip of me making
my first $50 from it. Let's see. Let's
see. Let's see. You don't need followers
to make money with social media. Okay,
I'm going to do a wake-up clip for day
one. Oh, I got 13 minutes left. I'm so
[ __ ]
I am so cooked. Day one, I devised a
master plan. I need to actually show the
app now. Okay, I'm going to do this on
this clip of me vibe coding. You want to
make sure that each B-roll actually
matches what you're seeing. By the way.
Plan. I'm going to make UGC videos
promoting a vibe coding app. This is the
vibe coding app. Anything. videos
promoting a vibe coding app. Okay, this
is a clip of me in the freaking subway
of New York vibe coding. Which is pretty
sick. I had some pretty cool clips from
this this month. Fun fact, the app was
actually like content scoring app. app,
then vibe code an actual app and p- Bye.
Uh-oh.
I have 10 minutes.
I'm editing right now.
Uh-oh. Uh-oh. I'm choosing which photos
Oh, no. Oh, no. [clears throat]
My girlfriend's actually serious about
this. This is so bad. This is so bad.
Okay, okay, now we're adding this as an
overlay. Bro, we just got accepted to
the App Store.
>> And now I'm going to duplicate this,
turn into an overlay. This is a niche
hack, guys. I don't know if you guys
would even know what this means, but
it's basically extending the overlay to
make it look extra goated. Our vibe
coded app somehow got onto the App Store
and that And the video blew up. Okay,
where's the video now? It grew to 40K
followers in 15 videos, which is pretty
nuts. Please! Oh my gosh, it's literally
just frozen right now, bro. the App
[music] Store and that video blew up.
>> There was actually a point where I was
actually in the [ __ ] tank cuz I was
sad over the app getting hate. Then my
worst nightmare happened. Let's see if I
can find hate comments to to support
that. Found the hate comments. I
screenshotted it and now let's add it as
an overlay. Holy [ __ ] my phone
literally just froze. Okay. Yeah, I
might just have to take the L here and
let my girlfriend post whatever she
wants. Or let's We're still making a
goated video and it barely took It's
barely going to take over an hour. Even
though the UGC side hustle was making
money because my videos were going
viral, it felt like every time I went
viral, I attracted more and more hate
>> I needed Okay, I need to actually find
my App Store [music] reviews now. Yeah,
yo, if you're watching this video,
please leave me a positive review on my
app. Although, I'm building a new app
right now. It's literally three three
reviews. Well, I don't know what the
[ __ ] happened to the timer, but it's
over now. So, I should probably call my
girlfriend and tell her that she won.
Well, how did she know that somehow I
would not get my video done in time?
30 days in, we posted 15 videos. We made
$5,000. The shot of me at night. We're
just finishing up the overlays. And
there's two more parts after this.
There's captions and there's music.
After I add this clip, I'm going to call
my girlfriend. But we were still just
shy of that 6K goal. And worst I'm going
to do lower lower saturation. goal. And
worst of all, I felt defeated from all
the hate. Okay, let me call my
girlfriend real quick and uh
and get her to
tell her that she won.
Sarah.
>> [singing]
>> Oh, look at that.
Uh
What is it? What is it? Okay, well, they
can get us something to eat. You don't
get a look at Okay, let me Let me finish
the video actually then. It takes
another like 20 minutes, I think.
Do you want to This is one of them?
Okay, okay, okay, okay. But genuinely
like 20 minutes, I'm almost done. You
had to finish it earlier. No, I'm sorry.
Your hungry girlfriend is I'm sorry.
[laughter]
Ah.
And I could finally afford my dad's
dream watch.
Yeah. This is kind of confusing now, the
edit, cuz this part, it's like the
climactic music part. So, usually I
actually add music during the editing
process just cuz music is very integral
to [music] the storytelling process, I
am a Okay, I'm going to do a Ooh, I'm
going to do a transition here where he
looks up. Oh, yeah, that's tough, isn't
it?
Okay, boom. Now, let's add the
Let's add the music. Holy [ __ ] this
video is kind of sloppy cuz I was trying
to do it in such a time constraint. So,
I will say an hour is a bit ambitious. I
spent 30 hours learning a new side
hustle to see if it's a money glitch.
This [ __ ] bugging out. My phone is
actually about to explode. It's at 6%.
Screen recording while editing must be
like the most overheating intensive
thing ever. Okay, so we just finished
adding the captions in CapCut, which is
just auto captions, and this is the
final product. Now, right after I'm
going to add background music, which is
going to be Runaway by Kanye. Obviously,
I can't show you guys cuz it's going to
be copyrighted, but here's the finished
product after editing. I'll show you
guys. I spent 30 hours learning a new
side hustle to see if it's a money
glitch. This is UGC, the viral side
hustle where brands pay you to post
secret marketing videos for them, but
the only problem is I'm posting on a
brand new Instagram account to prove you
don't need followers to make money with
social media. So, on day one, I devised
a master plan. I'm going to make UGC
videos promoting a vibe coding app, then
vibe code an actual app and post on my
UGC account documenting this journey.
And the goal by the end of this month is
to afford my dad his $6,000 dream watch.
Now, 7 days into this challenge, things
took a crazy turn. Bro, we just got
accepted to the App Store. Our vibe
coded app somehow got onto the App Store
and that video blew up. But then my
worst nightmare happened. We got
bombarded with hate comments after we
went viral. though the UGC side hustle
was making money because my videos were
going viral, it felt like every time I
went viral, I attracted more and more
hate. 30 days in, we posted 15 videos.
We made $5,000, but we were still just
shy of that 6K goal. And worst of all, I
felt defeated from all the hate. But
just when I thought my challenge would
end in a motivational quote, I got an
Apple payout that sent me $1,000 for the
app, and I could finally afford my dad's
dream watch.
But basically, thank you guys so much
for watching this video. Sarah is going
to post
this post on my Instagram. So by the
time this video's up, it should be up on
my main feed.
So, yeah.
Hopefully this was helpful. I really
wanted to give a super in-depth uh
tutorial on how I make my videos, and
even the most viral storytelling reels.
If you guys found this helpful, please
drop a subscribe. Honestly, cuz I have
so many more of these guides coming out
for you guys. And let me know in the
comment section as well if you want to
see a certain type of video from me.
>> [music]
>> I've been making content for a really
long time. So, if you guys want any
guides, I am here, and I am here to give
you the best possible content to help
you make a full-time living as a
creator. And make this [ __ ] this this
vague dream being creator. Everybody
wants to be a creator these days. Make
this vague dream an actual reality for
you. All right. See you soon. Peace.