In the past year, I've helped hundreds
of creators in my Discord community blow
up, some of whom have blown up literally
from 150 to like 800,000 followers
across platforms, all because I gave
them brutally honest advice on what is
missing from their content. So, I want
to give you guys a sneak peek at what it
looks like to actually practically fix
your hooks, storytelling, niche inside
your content. So, you can sit back,
absorb the knowledge, cuz I guarantee
you're not going to find any of this
kind of advice anywhere else on personal
branding online. Now, I'm going to leave
timestamps here on all the different
questions that people ask, so you can
find the content review that actually
applies to your situation.
Ray, you've been trying to make the day
in the life videos, but they get no
traction. The video is about 30 seconds.
Should you add a voiceover? Let's see.
>> Guys, you can't You can't
>> I think we've talked about it before,
Ray, but I think the the main thing here
that I noticed immediately is that
there's just like no context on who you
are. If I know anything about the day in
the life videos that work really well,
if I think of somebody literally who's
built their entire career off of day in
the life content, this guy, Jack's day
in the life, they get like millions of
views. So, how does he actually do it?
My Friday as a 25-year-old in New York
City. So, if you think of words that
capture people's attention, keywords
that make people relate, signal to
things that people might relate to, it's
like his age, where he lives. I think it
was so quick, I actually missed it.
Yeah, it was like 1 second, I actually
missed it. I would put it just right
here at the top of the screen. Generally
with text hooks, you want to keep it on
the screen for like 5 to 10 seconds is
my rule of thumb, just so people
actually have enough time to read it.
And I would say like, dude, I know, Ray,
you're like 15 or 16, like the age card
with day in the life is the easiest way
to just get people to like instantly
relate or have some sort of context on
you. So, like day in the life of a
15-year-old future stand-up comedian or
like day in the life of a 15-year-old
high schooler. I guess this video is
more so about comedy. Honestly, I I
don't think this is a bad textbook
either. I think generally it is just the
fact that it's so quick that it comes
and goes so quickly. I I pretty much
missed it while I was watching the
video. Yeah, other than that, I actually
like this format a lot. I like the
silent like I don't think music actually
would have helped here. I actually like
the silent. It feels more authentic. I
do want to say Ray, cuz I've been
reviewing your videos for the past
couple weeks, they are improving. And I
actually what I do want to say like
that's actually really good thing. So, I
would not view it as like ah it's just
like completely flopping. I think these
small improvements will help.
My, hello My. Uh you're satisfied with
the video and you feel like you learned
a better sense of direction for the next
one. You don't know if the middle is too
long though, so you'd like thoughts on
this, especially the captions. If you
want to give like any more context on
like specifically what I should be
paying attention to in the middle.
>> Also, like this video is basically like
a date. I had a I was in a call with Sam
yesterday. He said like the beginning
and outro was good, but like the middle
I had nothing there. So, I just put like
the clips that I put it into the middle.
But, it's like two scenes. I don't know
if like that's too much.
>> Got you. Got you. Okay, let's take a
look.
>> I asked 100 girls from my following list
out on a date and Diana was one of the
girls that I asked out. At first, she
didn't know my intentions. So, I started
being more bold and let's just say I got
initiated into a frat. However, she did
give me a date. So, maybe I could get
out of the friend zone.
>> I'm so nervous right now. I forgot to
pick up my date.
>> If it's a date, shouldn't you be like
picking up the girl?
>> When I asked you out, you you seemed
really against it.
>> I wanted to make sure you didn't
>> This is fire. This is This is sick.
>> Diana, thank you. Um I asked Prosper, he
told me that I should use this line cuz
he used told him to use it. But, I'm so
nervous right now.
>> Yes. So, if there's one takeaway from
Prosper's, it's very quick. With a lot
of videos, it's like what is the reason
why somebody will get hooked in the
first couple seconds. I think you
recognized it, too, and you did a very
good job. What is the reason you would
say?
>> I feel like this is like asking out 100
girls is like crazy like it was like
captivating, you know? And then
feel like the Rocky music also was going
to attract their attention.
>> I think also the fact that you showed it
happened is proof. So now I as a viewer
I'm waiting for the date. Every second
that passes here, I'm going to draw a
little retention graph. Every second
that passes, let's say each increment is
5 seconds. You kind of hooked me in
here, right? Let's just say that hooked
me in. And now every second that you
don't show this thing, which is the
date, which is what I'm like waiting
for. It's like, "Yo, what's going to
happen on the date?" All these questions
of curiosity like, "Is it going to go
well? Are they going to like, you know,
like go on another date? Is he going to
completely fumble? What's going to
happen?" right? And that's the cool
part. But every second that the date is
not being showed, you're losing
retention, losing retention, losing
retention. Versus if you can actually
then follow up with the next thing that
the viewer wants, which is to see the
date, the sooner the better is what I'm
basically trying to say. So Prosper, I
know, gets right into the date. Like if
you look at his Prosper's original
boyfriend boxing content, I'll I'll even
pull it up. It's like the number of
seconds to get to the date, I guarantee
it's probably less than 15. Less than 15
and he's on the date. So the longer that
you delay that, the more more people are
going to scroll off, then your watch
time's going to go down, and then it's
not going to do as well. I think, if you
were to put a number to this, if you can
get into the date footage and just start
showing what happens on the date within
the first 15 to 10 to 15 seconds, like
that's perfect. But I think right now
you're starting here. What I think it
should be like here. So I think that's
what I would guess Sam is alluding to.
You show b-roll, but the actual
conversations between you two. It's like
you guys meet up right here, 21 seconds
in. And I think it's maybe just cut out
one of the clips that slows it down
slightly is like the only thing.
>> following list out on a date, and Diana
was one of the girls that I asked out.
At first, she didn't know my intentions,
so I started being more bold, and let's
just say I got initiated into a frat.
However, she did give me a date, so
maybe I could get out of the
>> I'm I guess I'm a little confused
between this segment between initiated
into a frat.
>> just trying to say like I got called a
brother
but in like a
funny way.
>> Oh, like
>> really in the frat you get called
brothers, right?
>> I didn't even I couldn't even read this.
It would happen so fast.
>> It was It was like I didn't know how I
could like zoom into it without zooming
into the whole picture.
>> You could honestly just
like crop just you saying potentially
like question you were saying
potentially cuz I don't think this
celebrate your text matters or you could
just circle it in red or underline it in
red. But I like this I like the for the
plot episode of life. That's sick. I
think you could cut out and at first she
didn't know my intentions. I started
being more bold. I think this part here
just slows down the video to be honest.
Like this segment here I think it could
be said slightly quicker because I think
by second number 13 you could be like at
the point where you guys have met up and
then the video progresses more.
>> I threw out and you seem really against
it. And yeah, I wanted to make sure you
didn't I did not like you.
>> A date gone wrong.
>> Oh, oh, oh, oh, okay. Okay. Okay. Okay.
Okay. Okay.
Niche niche [ __ ] pull. Here's Here's
another hack. Right here I think what it
why it feels bare is because I don't
know how it contributes to the bigger
question of is the date going well or
not well. So I think you should put
captions at the top being like what's
going through your head. Being like
trying to make small talk parentheses.
You see this in sales call breakdown
videos where they're like handling the
objection, building rapport. It's like
you could put that in parentheses to
give me context as a as a viewer to be
like, "Okay, that's what he's thinking
in the moment."
>> Mm, I got you. I I think I do something
like that but it's like for funny music
purposes.
>> Whatever you want to put in there
honestly cuz I I do agree it's like this
part feels a little bit like I don't
think it's bad but I think I'm confused.
Me as a viewer is just like, "Oh, is it
going well or not well?" And I can
always like thinking about that question
I think, since the hook. It's like the
classic curiosity like, "Oh my gosh,
like are they getting along or not?"
That's just like my thoughts as a
viewer.
>> And then I record all of the freaking
date, so like my B-rolls are limited in
clips, you know? But something rather
than nothing.
>> I think this is good footage. I think
just like text to supplement it.
Overall, like conceptually this is so
like so interesting. And I think it's
one thing to be like, "I asked out 100
girls." It's another one to actually
film a date, which is, you know, the
couple's content always I think goes so
hard. So, yeah, this is this is sick.
>> Um would you like to watch the end? It's
like the store ended up closing, right?
So, I had to like debrief at my place
instead of actual restaurant. I don't
know if that's like off-putting.
>> Before I finished my food, the store
ended up closing, so I took her back to
my place for a little debriefing because
I've been single my whole entire life.
In order to give my first eventual
girlfriend the relationship that she
deserves, I feel like I have to be in
more intimate settings like this so I
can learn more about myself and how to
treat others, right? This is why I
started this series for the plot.
>> The date, it was like catching up with a
friend.
>> Are there any tips that you would give
me?
>> One, pick up the girl.
>> Two,
>> Keep paying. Keep paying.
>> Three,
>> be genuine.
>> I think what stands out about you is
like your personality.
>> Tips?
>> On the surface level.
>> Yo! Yo!
>> I think you should have like follow for
part two or follow to see me like level
up or something, like the next try or
something.
>> I like that call to action. Hold on, I
like that. I wasn't thinking.
>> Dude, this is I like that sentimental
moment, too. I I I would keep the music
going cuz this is like this sentimental
music here, I would just keep it until
the end. It's a nice ending to the
video.
>> All right, I got you.
>> Dude, overall, dude, I mean, kudos on
the video, man. This is like I'm sure
there's like a lot of effort put in
here, and I think that's amazing.
I am cooked so bad at hooks. It's okay.
It's Let's uh we're we're going to work
on it today. Doing a series, pretty
crazy, and I think it has viral
potential, but I am flopping big time.
Tik Tok did okay though, got 50k views.
Nathan, if you want to get more context
actually.
>> Yeah, long story short, I'm doing a
challenge like Mr. Beast style. I'm like
literally locked in a room with like
only protein powder, and I'm doing this
until I basically lose enough weight and
get six packs or I'm going to make 6,000
cash. I'm like day six in. Yeah, I it's
like I know it has viral potential, but
I'm just really bad at making the
content. And truthfully, it's not the
priority cuz I'm actually just trying to
lose weight and build my business right
now. That's the top priority, but
obviously this is like kind of like a
effort to do marketing, and I love to
learn how to improve.
>> Is it tied with your business, the
content?
>> Sort of. You know, like overall my
account, like this account I want to
make it more about just like identity
transformation. Like long story short,
over the past few years, I tried like
every weight loss thing in the world and
like went up and down, up and down until
I really figured out it's not really
about like short-term discipline, it's
more about like your identity change
long-term. And now I'm in a good place
and I kind of want to share that. But I
haven't really shared about that message
specifically. I was like, "Hey, let me
just see if I can get get eyeballs in on
this challenge, and then I'll start
sharing more of like the value." But
maybe that's not the right way to think
about it either.
>> Like you're thinking eyeballs first,
then value later.
>> Yeah, yeah. But I guess like it could
make sense where I'm actually just like
sharing this off or like, you know, what
what I've learned as well in the
meantime. It's just one thing that I was
trying to do cuz before when I posted, I
would like do way too many different
types of content pillars and there was
no like no one knew what I was talking
about. And now I was like, "I just want
to make every single post the same thing
so there's some consistency. So people
like, okay, this is the guy who's doing
this." So that's kind of like why I
didn't scatter myself too much.
>> I I think that's actually a great way to
look at it. That's memorable. Locked in
the room until you like just eating
protein powders. Bro, I've never heard
that, that's insane. Like that that's
that's awesome. Before I actually even
look at it, one thought that comes to
mind, I just want to like say this
before, is I would I think the best way
to execute, cuz you have a good idea, so
now you're not bottlenecked by the idea,
bottlenecked by the execution, is to
just have one creator whose style you
really want to mimic and then piece
together how they're doing it because
you're not going to copy their idea.
It's like maybe you call copy a
challenge creator who's in the finance
niche, you know, and they're doing like
a finance challenge or something.
>> Just like take the same style of like
hook pacing. Yeah, no, that's a great
idea. Thanks for that.
>> Let's see. I haven't left this room in 5
days and I've only eaten protein ice
cream because I told myself I'm not
leaving until I either make $6,000 or I
get six packs.
>> The good news is I have lost I think
here.
>> First off is auto captions. Like this is
like a personal bias to me, but auto
captions in the videos, I think there's
a more efficient ways we can do it.
There's templates on CapCut that you can
use where it can do the auto captions
for you even if it's just one word at a
time. That's at least I think would
boost the retention. Another one is like
this is like now like my bias take on
like how this could be executed. If you
don't want to put the auto captions or
you don't want it to like heavy hyper
edit, I don't think you need to. You
could just do like myself
>> Or it's like actually no, not even that.
I cannot leave this room till I lose
Well, what was the exact goal?
>> It was like 6 kg. I was just trying to
play with the the six six pack 6,000,
but it's yeah.
>> I'm only eating I like the way you
worded it to me like
>> Yeah, yeah, I really That's like more
viral. I was thinking if I literally
just like hey, I'm only eating protein
ice creams for the next 2 weeks like
people would do like what the [ __ ] Like
that's a lot more catchy. It's like not
the core essence of everything I'm
doing, but for sure I can see that just
being like the hook.
>> This is pretty like literally just this.
Like if I saw this on my feed, I'm
literally like frame by frame like this
is how I would do it. Like if I was in
your CapCut, I this is how I would do it
and then you know, blow this up a little
bit, you know, got the little 6K 6 kg
and then your spoken hook out of your
mouth. This is hella weird visuals, but
we'll run with it. I cannot leave this
room till I lose six or make 6K with the
business that you're running. And then
maybe you could do like here up here.
It's like day X.
That's what I can see here.
>> You were the chef for a reason. Okay, I
appreciate this.
>> This is I think this it's just like you
need to give all the context as quickly
as possible because this is a sick idea
and if people can't see that in the
first 3 seconds it's a damn shame. So
you got to make that clear the first 3
seconds.
>> All right, I'm going to lock in on the
content today. That'll be my focus.
>> Let's go. Yo, W concept bro. This is
sick. This is sick.
All right, all right. Next question's
from Dan. You'd love a review. Maybe
your hook is too slow to start. Let's
see. If there's anything else you want
me to keep in mind like with the video.
>> Uh no, not really. I'm just trying to
take a bit of a break and I'm just
getting back into content. Trying to
make videos to promote my marketing
agency.
>> Awesome. Let's do it. If you're just
getting started making videos for your
business, there's a good chance you're
killing them before you even start
talking. And that's because of the
millennial pause. Now when you hear that
phrase, you're either thinking
Okay, okay, okay. Quick thought here
with text hooks. I think if there's one
thing that you can do to instantly lift
it's any slight improvements to the text
hook right here. I think you could do
the double text hook. I think Gabriel
had a really good example from earlier
where it's like text hook with a
parentheses hook like under it. Cuz this
is a more niche video.
>> Yep, okay. So what would be the example
like so this one second mistake kills
your videos and like in brackets before
you even start or like uh
>> One thing that Gabriel did is he put
social proof. It's a title hook and then
authority. So like Harvard. So we have
the title hook here. It's like this one
second mistake kills your videos. I
think this is strong. I think if you
want to give more context here then it's
like what's an authority parentheses you
could put like one that comes to my
mind.
>> Yeah, gotcha.
>> So like one easy example in my mind is
like the borrowed authority, right? Even
like this is also like borrowed
authority, Harvard. So for you could be
like Mr. Beast's like golden rule.
>> Yep, yep, yep.
>> It's an easy lift. Other than that I
actually think editing wise it's it's
like solid. The video's The video's
pacing is actually good I think. Like
spoken wise.
>> Awesome. All
>> Yeah.
>> Cheers.
>> All right, awesome, dude. Now, hold on.
If you've been finding this advice super
helpful and you want to get your
personal brand personally reviewed and
coached by me alongside three other
coaches on five of these weekly sessions
every single week so you can improve
your videos on Instagram and TikTok as
quickly as possible. I'm going to leave
a link to apply to join this paid
community in the first link in the
description and on to the next advice.
Gabriel, dude, welcome to Content
Academy. I'd love to get your
perspective on these questions. They
tend to stagnate at or below 100k views.
What components am I missing to break
past 100k? Two, visual hook feels weak
to me. How can I improve that or verbal
hook to make the beginning more
engaging? Three, generally speaking,
these videos perform best by far, but
they aren't the core to what you want to
do long term. Quick question here, Gabe.
What is your long-term goal? Cuz I think
that would help. You can un- feel free
to unmute as well to give context.
>> Yeah, thanks. It is uh it is new for me
here, but it's been great so far, so I
appreciate it. Long term for me, the
videos like that I've posted like this
that have performed the best tended to
be almost like I was relaying
information that was educational and
from research that just happened to be
popular on current topics, but I'd like
to kind of like demonstrate first hand
either through experiences of my own or
by sharing experiences of other people,
kind of like demonstrations of the
things that I'm talking about. So, like
this one is just relaying information
about Harvard's four emotional profiles,
but I get a lot more amped up about
creating content that's like yeah,
everybody tells you you should be going
after your goals and here's exactly how
to do it either with me as an example or
somebody else.
>> I was going to say, I think this does
represent what you're talking about
well. It's like depression makes the
best artists talking about becoming, I
guess, the best artist possible. So, I
do think it does serve that purpose at
least somewhat. Why depression makes the
best artists. So, the first question
though with plateauing at around like
100k, how do you break past that
plateau? Let me actually watch it with
audio. What if I told you that if you're
a happy person, there's a high
likelihood you'd be a bad boss. Research
coming out of Harvard indicates that all
human beings fall into one of four
>> I think at this point we're talking
about micro optimization. So, you
already have like the fundamental, which
is a really good hook, really good idea,
and like good speaking on camera. So,
like those things which are like the
necessary those are like 80/20, I would
say, the 80% that makes a good video.
So, it's like that's there. So, what I'm
telling here is going to be pure
nitpicking, but it could help like get
it to the next level. I think one thing
is depth on camera. It's like when I see
a lot of the best talking head, they
have depth of background behind them.
So, like this is just like a small thing
I've noticed. On my own account, outdoor
videos seem to do well, and outdoor
videos as well where or if I'm indoors,
it's like the wall is not right behind
me. I don't know what it is
subconsciously, but it can make a video
feel flatter, and it it's like a subtle
subtle thing. But, I think also it makes
you blend in a little bit with your
background, and it's like monkey brain
high contrast visuals capture the the
eyeballs like slightly hard. I'm talking
like 10%. So, that's like maybe a a tiny
incremental lift.
>> I like the textbook, by the way. I think
the the double textbook is fire.
>> What if I told you that if you're a
happy person, there's a high likelihood
you'd be a bad boss. Research coming out
of Harvard indicates that all human
beings fall into one of four emotional
profiles. These profiles are determined
by a term called affect, which is
essentially emotional intensity, be that
positive or negative. First, if you feel
both
>> Okay, this this at this point is
probably going to be like kind of a
subjective take. I've heard this concept
for YouTube. It's like does your
does your visual presentation match the
personality that you're trying to
essentially portray on social media. So,
it's like what's the outcome that you
want to get people in your content?
>> if I could get people that were
interested in in kind of like following
along and being interested like learning
through the self-improvement stuff,
that's kind of what I was trying to
convert off of these types of videos.
And this was almost more of like a
backing for like if I create other types
of videos, and it's like some of them
are like study marathons and stuff like
this. I want to say like, "Okay, here's
some credibility for like here's where
I'm getting the study habits that I talk
about in my other videos where I'm
demonstrating it, so I'm not just like a
random person."
>> Gotcha. Do you know the guy who does 75
hard and cold plunge every day?
>> Is it the guy
who eats like a million mandarins?
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I got you.
>> I think that's that's like a vibe that I
get. I don't I don't know how to
describe it. Maybe it's like the running
clothes. It's like all like the that
dude I know is like a a runner. That's
like an example of like you're combining
all of a really solid hook that is a
really coherent point that hits really
hard with another winning format, which
is like cold plunges, which is like a
very visual hook, a very visually
captivating thing. And maybe it's not
that, but it's like I know he films them
in the morning. So, that aesthetic feels
a little bit more emotional and has like
that depth to it. And I think that
creates this holistic personality and
vibe that then makes it like, "Oh, wow.
Like this person's really about it in
the sense."
>> Got you. Yeah, that makes sense.
>> Like cuz once again, this is not like
the biggest needle mover in the world,
but it could like maybe there's some
ideas here cuz I don't think there's
like a right or wrong answer here. But I
think of like self-improvement creators
like this guy Hamza. His like best
videos were in like a red LED light
room. And he was like in a bathrobe. And
then he just repeated that visual. So,
it was ingraining them as like his
aesthetic, which matched the I guess
like self-improvement bro aesthetic. And
then like one other example is like this
guy. He always films outdoors in like a
really I guess like nature-y setting,
which like these are examples of
background creating a vibe, which like
overall could be a little bit more
immersive. It's like small things like
that could add up.
>> Yeah, I know that's perfect. I
appreciate it cuz I was getting kind of
stuck on it. Like I could I could move
back and forth and I I noticed there's
something weird if anyone else is doing
like the self-improvement kind of
educational stuff. The subtext book
almost had more of an impact for my
videos than like the main ones. So, I
kind of get those, but yeah, I
appreciate it cuz the the visual hook is
really where I was getting stuck. And I
think everything you're saying makes
sense.
>> The thing is the
the topics that you're covering are also
I would say like more complex or
sophisticated, like Harvard's four
emotional profiles. That's such a niche
topic that I think the brain rot side of
me feels like it's not getting catered
for and it's like the brain rot side of
me just sees like wow, like like he's in
nature. He must be like hella
intellectual and that's it. It's just
like raw subconscious. But yeah, I I I I
think you get the vibe. This is fire
though overall, dude. This is sick, man.
And dude, 100k views is no joke, bro.
That's awesome.
>> Thank you, man. I appreciate the input
and I I got this format down. I'm really
working on some some serious content
now. So, I'll probably be back in the
next few weeks for a lot of a lot of
reviews on on series cuz I'm pretty bad
at those. So, I really appreciate it.
>> That's fire. I I think matching this
with a series, too. Like the Dane it's
like the 75 hard, but then he gives a
lesson every day. It's this type of
format, but then matched with a series.
I think it's awesome.
>> Sweet. Yeah, I might try and do that cuz
I was starting a marathon series next.
The problem I had is anytime I broke
away from this format where there was a
question at the beginning and then
there's some sort of eye-catching
college name like Harvard and Stanford
and then a University of Singapore one
all tended to really pull in the views.
I don't know. I got to figure out a way
to try and like transition from that
into the series. I think is what you're
saying.
>> Yeah, cuz this is a really good format
and it's like I would not just like let
go of it either cuz I think you're on
something really good here.
>> Cool. All right, thank you.
>> Yvon, would love some advice on this
video. Reply to the message with the
stats, too. It did decent on shorts with
30k views, but flopped on IG. Let's see.
>> I bet. "Grow the [ __ ] up." That's what
my best friend said to me after I ruined
his birthday. Six months ago, I was in
charge of planning my best friend's
surprise birthday party. But I was so
stressed trying to coordinate that I
waited to the last minute. I ended up
with zero plan and right as they pulled
up, I had to cancel the whole night. But
when my best friend said that, I got so
defensive. "Screw you, dude. I was so
busy and stressed. You just don't get
it." Damn, why did I say that? But then
I remembered this isn't the first time
I've done something like this. Someone
hit my car in 2024. Personally, it
doesn't bother me, but my dad called me
daily losing sleep about it. Every time
I promise I'll fix it, but every time we
both know I'm lying. I realized that
whenever I procrastinate, someone else
pays the price, too. My friend lost his
birthday and my dad's losing a hair. So,
maybe
>> I think it's interesting that you bring
up the YouTube Shorts thing. If there's
I'm trying to think if there's like a
difference here that would cause it to
do well on Shorts but not on IG. Like,
sometimes it genuinely happens.
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah, exactly. Wait, cuz like my last
two videos, they both did around the
same on Instagram, but like they both
got around 30k on YouTube. They got like
8 to 9k on Instagram. So, that's why
it's like I'm not really sure of like
how much like what the issue is, you
know?
Yeah.
>> If I were to guess, and this is like I I
think at this point it's more of a grain
of salt theory of mine. I think this
feels like the effects feel like higher
touch. And when I think of YouTube
Shorts, I think of there's more going on
in the screen. Whereas, when I think of
Instagram Reels, like the cinematic
stuff on Instagram Reels, it's almost
like there's not as much going on on the
screen, and they're really indexing for
just like really pretty shots. Like, the
shots themselves like it's like crazy
camera, there's like like high contrast
in the lighting. Versus YouTube Shorts,
it's like cool effects. And it's it's
like a very minute thing. And if like
TikTok is like completely different,
it's just like no edits, you know, a lot
of the times.
>> Yeah, TikTok this [ __ ] all flops.
>> And that that happens if yeah.
>> But like I I made a video like two
videos before this. They did pretty
well. Like, it has like I think 340k
now, and it's like still pretty similar.
But the But the contact the content of
the video is like very different. It's
like about like racism. So, I guess like
that also creates like some stimulus for
people, but But yeah, just kind of just
want to
get your advice on like the general
storytelling or like the hook. And like
if this kind of content can convert to
like a meaningful amount of followers.
And if it can, like how can I really
like optimize for that? Cuz I don't I
don't necessarily want to do like pure
educational, pure tutorials, and like
pure value in that sense. Like, I want
the value to be driven from me. Like,
about my own story, like myself, so they
care about me. And then they can relate
to me, too. But I just finding it hard
to find a balance cuz like my videos
that are 300k only got like 600
followers from that, you know? So that
conversion is not that great. Even
though I thought that the fact that like
it was high quality, it was scripted I
thought pretty well, all that stuff
would cause a higher conversion to
followers, but it it didn't really. So I
guess that kind of proved like my theory
wrong.
>> I'll answer this for conversion. First
off, I think this is a sick format. I
think this is like this is more just
personal opinion. I think this is good
and I would keep it up. I think these
are really well made and just like my
subjective opinion is I think these are
like I think your use of effects is also
super unique and the shots are very well
done. Like I see that as a strength. I I
think this is awesome. I would say in
terms of follower conversion, what
causes more people to follow or less
people to follow and you want people to
follow for your personal stories and I
think your this video is great. It's
like a personal story. When it comes to
educational content, people usually
follow when they perceive that you're
giving direct applicable advice. So the
more applicable and practically
actionable the advice is in the video,
like the more likely they will follow.
So like the furthest example of this is
like if a video gave that was a about
content advice said comment for XYZ
guides and then you just had like a like
a 100-page PDF. That's like, okay, wow,
it's so densely packed with value, so
they've really value maxed that. When it
comes to personal, my theory behind
that, it's like what causes more people
to follow or less people to follow to
follow, I think it's more so like with
the story, how deeply do they resonate
to you? I I guess to quantify that, I'll
speak for myself. Like the videos that
have converted best have been the most
vulnerable and my theory on that is that
the more vulnerable things, I guess they
have more of a moat because not only are
they unique stories to me, but also
they're unique stories that are also
difficult to tell. So the likelihood
that someone else would tell a similar
story is lower and I'm guessing too with
vulnerable stories, there's also a
deeper like emotional component to it.
But I think this does well. So I
actually I wouldn't say this lacks that.
I actually think this does great at
that. That's just like a general rule of
thumb that I have in mind. The deeper
the story, the harder the emotional
impact of the story, and then if there's
ways you can make it more unique that
you don't think other people would be
able to tell the same story. Because if
you saw the same style of content 10
times in a row on your feed, you
wouldn't follow one or the other more
than It's just like, "Oh, yeah. These
are all This is my feed." You don't
think, "Wow, this creator themself I
need to specifically see them again as
opposed to the last nine people." How do
you make it so you your stories have
that level of moat versus the other
creators? I think your visuals have
that. And this is also like I don't
think there's an answer that I can give
where it's like you should really target
this. I think I would have to like know
your story, but that's just like a
principle that I I like to think about.
What is What is it that you can do that
other people cannot replicate
story-wise? Or what are things in your
life that I guess are more unique?
>> Okay. Yeah, that makes sense. Yeah, I
think I mean the video that did really
well, it was about like me being half
Indian, half Latin, growing up in India,
and like people were being racist around
me cuz I don't look the most Indian, I
don't sound the most Indian. So, that
video did particularly well because I
think it's like a clashing, you know, to
what people's expectations are. But then
I also I'm a little worried that like
I'm only going to be known as the half
Indian guy that doesn't know any Indian
languages and like all that stuff if I
just keep milking that. But I guess like
momentum's hard to come by, so I might
as well just like keep riding the wave
if I can, you know.
>> I also think when it comes to
conversion, you you touched on a good
point there. The riches are in the
niches, and this is not just from a
business perspective, it's also from if
your personal brand is a business and
like them following is kind of them like
paying and becoming like a paying
customer or subscriber, then the more
niche of a story like that for example,
no one else like I I would guess almost
no one else here could tell that, you
know. And that And that's a sign that
because it's so unique, more people
would feel directly resonate to you and
you only. So, I think that's a good
sign, and like doesn't have to be just
that, but what are other ways you can
like test that and and find more more
elements?
>> Yeah, awesome. All right, thanks beta.
Appreciate it.
>> Yes, sir.
Awesome.
Uh Raymond, how do you find content that
resonates with your niche? You've been
saving a ton of videos on your explore
page, but they don't seem to have a a
lot of storytelling or maybe you're just
not understanding why these videos are
performing so well without storytelling.
If you're Yeah, you're here? What niche
are you in and what type of content you
trying to make?
>> So, I'm in self-improvement and
lifestyle and
I I created a a recent like video that
did like 3K views. That was That was a
really well-scripted video, I would say,
but obviously it didn't like resonate
well enough and I'm kind of stuck in
this place where I'm seeing all these
lifestyle and self-improvement content
creators kind of talk about like,
"Here's five different ways to do this."
Um but there's not like storytelling
involved with that and I'm so Maybe I'm
like a one-trick pony and I just don't
understand how to get out of this
one-trick pony phase of just pure
storytelling. First It was kind of like
this. Sorry, I I I know I'm going in
circles, but it was kind of like, "I
went through this and I learned this and
this." But then they're like, "Huh, you
know, recently I I went through
something like this, but here are five
different ways for me to figure this
out." And they would show like B-rolls
and stuff and I'm trying to find ways to
like incorporate more of that into my
content because the storytelling stuff
that I that I did do, it took like three
days just to post, bro. It kind of
sucked, man.
>> Got you. So, I'm guessing the
storytelling you said like you're you
feel like you're stuck in one-trick pony
with the Like you're stuck one-tricking
the storytelling, but you want to learn
how to do more like the list style?
>> Kind of like you, you know, you're like
you you like do experimentation stuff,
you know, like, "Is there Is it possible
to do this within a certain amount of
time? Is it Here are five different ways
I figured out how to dress better for
Asian dudes or whatever. Here's five
five ways to un-chop yourself. Stuff
like that, you know. And I'm just like,
how how is storytelling involved in
those things? Because maybe maybe I like
took it way too far in this in this
course, like the storytelling aspect,
and stopped kind of like trying to help
people, you know?
>> I mean, I don't think there's a one
right way to do it. And I also think
instead of using the word storytelling,
like I would say it's just like
scripting. Because storytelling is I
would say like you're telling a story
about your life. But then if I were to
make a video explaining the three-step
method to write hooks, I don't really
need to story tell. I just need to be
explain my point and be logical and then
explain the one two three. So it's a
different format I would say like and
then a challenge is different too. A
challenge is more like I relay the
premise, I show me going through it, and
then I give the payoff at the end of did
we yes or no did we win or not win.
>> Okay.
>> So that's the general framework, but
>> Oh, I was just saying so like basically
I should still be talking about like
self-improvement and lifestyle things,
but every time I
I should be able to experiment with
different formats but stay within the
same niche, correct?
>> I will say I think the best creators are
the ones who've been able to hit really
good targeting, have stuck with one have
found one format that works, and they
just do it. So it's like here here's
kind of the the steps and I think this
is what I referred to in the course. You
try out these three and there's a couple
more formats like you could include a
vlog as well, right? That's also format.
You try them out and then you pick apart
what does well. So in terms of like the
views and then also what you enjoy. Kind
of like an ikigai framework of like, you
know, you could you could stumble across
a format that you are really good at but
you might just not like it. That's fine,
too. So figure out what you like and
what does well. And then like I I say
then you start to like eliminate the
other ones and really just go hard on
just like what whichever one is working
really well for you.
>> Okay, cool. So, when I when I
go on like Instagram and on to the
explore page, just start saving the
videos that are like storytelling,
lifestyle, educational, challenges,
vlogs, and just try to like create a ton
of them to see which one works better
and which one I like more and basically
double down on whatever one works. And
as like a beginner page, you know, since
I just started, I should be okay to
experiment with all of these different
things without seeing some sort of
negative like effect on my account
performance, things like that.
>> Yeah, like How how many videos in are
you?
>> Probably like nine, bro.
>> Oh, dude, wait, that's sick. And you
said you got 3K views?
>> Yeah, only on one video, though.
>> Dude, that's fire, man. That that's
actually fire. Yeah, I would say right
now, so if I were to give general and
these are not in no way is this like
objective truth, you know, depends, but
I like to think of it this way. First 30
videos, data collection. You're figuring
out what does well, what do you like,
right? And also it's just getting the
reps in. And then past 30 videos, I
would say try to do this process where
you look back and you're just like, what
did well, what did I like, and then also
just like, what did not do well and what
did I not like? It's like a broken heart
emoji. You figure that out and then you
kind of that by process it's like maybe
dude, I [ __ ] hate vlogs. Like, okay,
well, we're not going to do that. The
storytelling takes me like 10 years and
honestly it's like not that like great
for me, so let's like take that out. Or
maybe the storytelling is good, so it's
like, okay, maybe it has one of the two,
so maybe we can figure out how to make
it more enjoyable and more sustainable.
But like the lists, not really like
resonate. And then like maybe it's like
one or two. But the goal is just to not
feel like you're trying everything past
30 videos or like for the long term to
make it simpler on yourself cuz juggling
a bunch of different formats, it's like
jack of many trades, but then it's like
harder to master one, you know?
>> Right, right.
>> And then in terms of the niche, I will
say this is like a blanket statement,
but I think the general niche of
self-improvement, I I think I think a
lot of us here are in general
self-improvement. Like I actually like
honestly
>> Right.
>> Drop a W in the chat if you're you're
into self-improvement. Like I I I would
say I I have the role. Like it's a very
common niche, and the reason why is not
because it's like oh, it's
oversaturated. It's just because I think
there's so many forms of
self-improvement. Like you could argue
that Nathan's video from earlier about
the protein powder, that's
self-improvement. And then Yuvon
storytelling, self-improvement as well.
Even Mohit as well, right? Giving like
an introspective take from his life,
also self-improvement. It's like there's
many different forms. So one question I
would also ask yourself is like is there
any other words or niches that you could
use to describe that might be slightly
more specific? Like within
self-improvement, maybe there's like
fitness or business or relationships.
>> Yeah, I think that's something I'm going
to really have to dig deep down cuz
there's like so much that I like about
self-improvement. You but you're all
right. It's it's pretty broad, man. And
I guess it's just like finding what I'm
good at naturally, right? What I do the
most on an everyday basis, perhaps.
>> And I will say do not be afraid to like
feel like you're oversimplifying your
life. Because I started off my page as a
general broad self-improvement page.
Like I actually was talking about like
my dating life and like my fitness
journey as well. I would talk about
trying to get leaner and like lower body
fat percentages as well. Now I don't
talk about that. Like I would say most
of my exponential growth on the page
came from when I really niched down to
business, turned it into a series, and
then just repeated that over and over
and over. And that can come later. I
would say like I used my business series
of road to 100K month as a medium of
documenting self-improvement. But at the
core, it still is self-improvement, but
now we're just using business as a
medium to like show that or fitness as a
medium to show that.
>> Ooh, okay. Cool. Cool. Cool. Cool. I
I'll definitely do like an Ikigai or
something to figure out what my North
Star is within self-improvement, you
know? I think that would help out a lot.
>> 100% though, dude. Honestly, if there's
any thought I want to leave you on, it's
like, "Dude, you're nine videos in.
Treat this as a testing phase and I
think you're making all the right
moves." So, like, just just keep at it,
dude.
>> Cool. Thank you, bro. I appreciate it,
Iman.
>> Of course.
Nelson, you're excited to start this
journey. How do you structure your page
when you have multiple things happening?
Restaurant, real estate portfolio, an
exciting high-earning 9-5, kind of lost
where to take your content. I'm on day
five of the content course. I didn't do
a challenge yet, but I'm not sure which
challenge to do. Long-term, I want to
share learnings of building, lifestyle,
motivational. Okay. It's both, I think,
a blessing and a curse to have a lot of
stuff to talk about. That's a strength.
I see you on the call, so if you have
any more, I guess, like, thoughts that
would help with this.
>> Yeah, I just I mean, I I I like I like
videos around self-improvement,
motivation. I've heard, you know, I've
listened to this cool Yeah, you the
thoughts about self-improvement and I
everybody's doing it, but I need a
particular niche. And I just find it so
tricky because it's quite a mouthful for
whatever that talk. Oh, yes, I'm I have
a blah blah blah, but I have a 9-5, but
then I have a this, I have a this. And
so, I find it quite hard and I don't
know what to talk about like doing this.
>> I think in that frame of like, sometimes
maybe instead of thinking like just
which niche to target, cuz it's like you
could target the real estate, or you
could target the 9-5, or you could talk
about like just the restaurant. And it's
like we've seen a lot of creators who
just nail down one. For example, Rogan,
right? He also He used to run a sneaker
business. He's obviously like super in
the whole like personal branding space
as well, but at the end of the day, his
whole thing is just his property, his
Airbnb. And it focuses just around that
because when it's really simple and easy
to follow along to, it's a lot easier
for followers to then, you know, a
complete stranger to easily feel like
they're they can be immersed in the
world. So, it's like 80/20. 80% of the
videos are documenting the main arc. 20%
are like, quote unquote, filler episodes
that talk more about like this is like a
younger self kind of deep introspective
storytelling video and state that's like
where you want to get to I say. Like you
choose kind of one main style. If
there's other side interest, treat it
more like a 20% filler, but you don't
have to feel like you just like choose
it now and then that's an irreversible
choice. I think that's something that
like testing helps you figure out. I
think one framework then to like figure
this out is rather than which one of
these topics do you want to just cover?
It's like what do you want to do with
your content? What do you want to do
with your personal brand? Like what is
the goal for you?
>> Want to be an authoritative figure like
motivation
and then also find a way to to monetize
that in future as a as another revenue
stream income stream.
>> I would say just right off the bat the
the format that generally achieves that
is like motivational authority is
usually talking head and some form of
either like advice or like how-to stuff.
So I don't think you would need to let's
say like turn it into a challenge for
example. Like I I I guess like this like
how to be dangerously confident. I guess
was there another question with like
figuring out where to take the content?
>> I guess I I should do I don't
necessarily have to do a challenge but
more talking head. Also, I don't know if
it's a mindset thing or I don't feel
like sometimes like I'm not like
super successful, you know? So I also
find it like quite hard to be an
authority when I speak about some of
these things like I've like I have done
in some of my videos. But I mean that's
exactly but that's where I want to go.
And and that's the kind of content I
like consuming and that's the content I
want to I do eventually want to put out.
>> I guess if you don't feel like you have
the place of authority yet, this is I'll
tell like an anecdote for me cuz I felt
the same way going into content and my
solution is just just show every day
getting towards a goal that I think is
like worthy of being talked about. Just
make it about me like pushing forward
towards it every day which then can be
like very relatable as well. But it's
like maybe not every video is going to
blow up because it's like, you know, at
the end of the day, like I was just
documenting me being like a college
student. So there's inherently like not
some crazy mode around that, but I was
able to build, I would say, an audience
of people who were relating to those
life moments over time.
>> I think that makes sense.
>> Sorry, I I I wish I could honestly
answer the question better, but I do
think a lot of these would probably be
just like you post, figured out, and
learn. And I'm guessing like cuz you
like you just got into Content Academy,
like I think a lot of these would
probably also just come as you
experiment more.
>> Okay. Yeah, that makes sense. I'll keep
going. Thank you. Thanks, man.
>> All right, awesome. Let's see, next one
from Jordan, one of our Content Games
winners. Let's [ __ ] go. I see you're
in the car here. Fabuloso comments on
the video, first time. Let's [ __ ] go.
What's something that did well and
something to improve upon the next one.
Yo, you got the fabula- Dude, that's a
fire like brand deal. Dude, like I I
wonder if there's like a brand deal
opportunity there. Just like side note,
but it What did What like a physical
product brand hits you up in the comment
section, that's like an easy like slide
in and work some kind of like collab
there. So that's [ __ ] sick. Yeah, if
you're in the car, I guess I'll just
give like quick thoughts here. So what's
one thing that did well from the video
and one thing that did not? Let's see.
>> Move. My fiance gets home from work in
less than 1 hour and our apartment looks
like this.
Yikes. So let's deep clean it together
and surprise her. Alexa, play Suave.
>> Quick thoughts. Hook was fire, like the
surprise. It's so quick, but it's such a
pattern interrupt, and it's it comes in
and goes, so it's like doesn't delay on
the screen for so long. I I like that as
a visual hook, first off. Second thought
is I think one thing in terms of an
improvement, I didn't really like I
guess it's a cluttered visual, and I'm
not the biggest fan of cluttered
visuals. They're kind of small and
there's a lot going on in the screen.
So, it's like right here, I think it
could have done well if you actually
just put them as B-roll clips as opposed
to picture them on the screen cuz I
think that would make me feel the
dirtiness of the apartment slightly
more. I feel like there's a way to make
it feel way more gross essentially.
Maybe dragging on the visuals a little
bit, using B-roll clips, and taking up
the full screen of it. But, that's like
a that's a very small tweak and I think
overall this is like this is really
solid. I also love the different camera
angles. I think that's [ __ ] sick and
really unique and I would stick with
that cuz I think in a lot of like these
vlog style at home content, people will
just be talking from one angle. But,
switching up the angle, like I like the
microwave angle and then I saw there.
It's like these these unique angles, I
would do them Yeah, like I like that. I
like that. That's fire.
Destroyed dirt, wiping.
Yeah, this is really tough, dude. I
Yeah, I love this angle. I don't know
what it is. It seems so unique.
Mhm.
>> Yeah, bro. Appreciate it. So, in terms
of like reaching out and and from that
comment, like what are some tips?
Cuz I've been talking to Diego
and he's been talking to me but from
your perspective too, what are your what
are your thoughts?
>> In terms of probably like developing a
relationship with a brand and then
working with them, right?
>> Yeah.
>> I would say like try to hop on a call.
>> How do you slide in their DMs?
>> If I were to give like a very simple
outreach template, it's let let me just
like put it in the comments. I I won't
actually comment this, but it's like yo,
like just saw like that I like your
comment like compliment the brand, like
specific compliment to the brand, like
kind of signals that out of all brand
deals you would put in more effort cuz
you like them. It's like brands don't
want to work with a creator who just
like, "Yo, I'm just in it for the
money." So, really signal value, right?
You're kind of pitching them like you're
kind of soft selling them. And then do
not ask for something. Just be like,
"Would love to chat with sometime like
about like how we could potentially work
together." Like a very easy like
low-commitment thing cuz I think it's
like, "Hey, like do you guys do brand
deals? Like I would love to do you know,
the obvious worst thing I think would be
like, "Hey, hi. My rates are this. Like
do you want to like pay me?" You know,
it's like there's no value that then
they can pursue. What I've heard from
brand managers uh is that they love when
the the creator themselves actually
feels like they're they're putting in a
lot of effort, and they really care
about doing a good job. That's actually
very rare, and if you can establish that
relationship of like, "Yo, like I'd love
to like just chat with like whoever on
the phone." Like that's another great
way because then that's easier to
negotiate. Cuz emails you can ghost each
other, you forget, but on a call like
you can really show how how much you
like, you know, want to work with them.
>> All right, that makes sense. And last
question, like it's in the terms of a
brand actually commenting on your post,
is there something specific that
happens? Like is there a certain quality
or reaches a certain metric, or do they
usually do that for like all of them
that they get tagged in?
>> I'm glad you asked. There's
So, this is for for anybody who wants to
do brand deals with like uh specific
like it's like physical product brands,
right? But this applies for any kind of
brand. If you think about who runs the
pages for the brands, it's the brand
managers, and what are they doing on the
brand page? They're scrolling the For
You page looking for creators to
outreach to for like social media
marketing, right? So, essentially your
content kind of becomes a funnel for
brands.
The brand needs to be able to see
themselves in a video. So, what did you
literally do? Like you showed a bunch of
physical product like this one like a
vacuum cleaner could easily see this and
be like, "Oh, shoot. I want to be
integrated with you guys." Actually
using physical products is is way to
obviously like signal to brands, hey
like this is a like a creator worth
working with. So like another creator I
know named Arman, he actually did like a
guest speaking call before
regarding like how to do brand deals cuz
he's done like five-figure brand deals.
He's He's like a He's [ __ ] cracked at
brand deals and negotiating. And
something he says is that he does a lot
of things like cleaning videos. He's
done videos where he did like he did a
video where he was doing makeup in the
car. So he can do a like a makeup or
cosmetics brand deal because those
people will see that. Those accounts
will see that or if they're looking to
be like who like should we work with
this person or not? And then they see
videos where they could easily see
themselves integrated with you, that's a
really good sign. So like if you want to
attract let's say a different ICP or
like ideal brand persona like a app or
software company, then make videos
reviewing software like tier list of
software or like here are the top five
tools I use for for like XYZ. That's
another one or like let me think like
finance creators are like oh he like my
favorite credit cards, right? It's
essentially kind of like doing a brand
deal without getting paid and that's and
if you can get those videos to do well,
it's an easy way to just, you know,
attract brands like like moths to a
flame.
>> Hey bro, thank you. I appreciate the
help.
>> Yes, sir dude. Dude, that's awesome that
you had a brand like see that and and
comment dude. That's actually very rare
and you know, I I think that's a great
sign. Like that's that's awesome.
>> Yes, sir. Shout out Creator Academy.
>> Let's go. All right, thank you guys so
much for watching all of the advice that
we gave the creators. I've been doing
this for the past 2 years and I realized
I've never actually shown any of like
the work that I do. Let me know
genuinely if you found this helpful or
specifically what questions that you'd
want to have answered in future videos
and I'll try to make more videos around
that. If you don't know who I am now,
I've grown three accounts on TikTok to
over 150k followers. My Instagram's at
like 520. I've been posting content on
TikTok and Instagram for the past 6
years. So, I've broken it down to a
science. Now, I just want to make these
videos to help you out in your personal
brand growth journey so you can actually
make this a career. That is my full-time
passion now as a 22-year-old. I dropped
out of [ __ ] college to run this
business. And if you want to be a part
of this community as well, we don't just
do these coaching sessions. I also have
a bunch of video modules and guides on
how I personally make my videos as well
as we send out a ton of monetary
opportunities for smaller creators to
get started in their earning journey to
make this a full-time [ __ ] career,
baby. So, I'll see you guys in the next
video. Peace.