All right, this video I'm going to do a
tier list ranking all the different ways
that I've made money through Instagram,
TikTok, and YouTube and then rank how
easy they are between one being really
bad and hard and 10 being really easy
and good to make your first 1K, 10K,
100K, and a mill and then how easy it is
to grow on these platforms. Now, this is
going to be an evidence-based tier list
as somebody who runs my business
literally through these three platforms.
In the past 90 days, our business has
done 256K in rev from these three
platforms. But if I actually do a
breakdown, I actually have tracked all
of these different platforms and how
much revenue they've actually brought
into our business. But the cool thing is
that I actually haven't had to go super
duper viral on these platforms. Just
thought that was kind of interesting.
Like 1.4 mil on IG, 57K on YouTube, and
then like 1.9 mil on TikTok. But I've
been doing this social media thing for
the past 4 years. I've grown three
accounts on TikTok to over 100,000
followers. You can see on the screen
right here. Boom, boom, boom. Across
three different niches. And I've
monetized all the way from doing brand
deals to doing UGC. I've even tried
TikTok Shop for a little bit. And now I
monetize through my own coaching
business where we teach other people how
to grow and monetize their social
medias. Let's start off with how easy it
is to make your first thousand dollars
with Instagram, TikTok, and YouTube. I
have them rated as a seven, seven, and a
four. Starting off with Instagram. What
is the easiest way to make your first
thousand dollars with Instagram? And I
highly recommend doing this thing called
UGC. It's pretty much guaranteed payment
just to be posting for these brands on
um on Instagram. And literally how UGC
works, I'm going to actually pull up my
Discord server here cuz we send out
these kind of opportunities pretty much
every single week and you can find any
of these kind of opportunities on online
job boards, etc. I will link one or two
in the description. But basically all
you have to do is just start posting and
most brands will pay you a retainer from
like of like 750 bucks for 30 videos. So
when I say making your first thousand
dollars online, UGC is probably the best
side hustle to do so. Now, is it going
to help you make hundreds of thousands
of dollars? Frankly, probably not. UGC
doesn't have that much scalability of
income. But we're talking about our
first thousand dollars here. So, the
reason why I put Instagram at a seven is
because you can really just get paid to
post. And the same with TikTok. So,
these two platforms have a unique
opportunity called UGC where you don't
even really need followers to start
posting on the platforms. For example, I
started this account, literally this
one. I started this account and in 15
posts, I did kind of pop off. I made
five thousand dollars from a brand new
Instagram account doing this thing
called UGC. Just to prove that you can
pretty much do it as with a with a brand
new Instagram account. Same with TikTok
as well. These brands do not
discriminate between Instagram or TikTok
when doing UGC. Most of these brands,
like these apps who are paying you
between like 30 to 50 dollars per video
minimum, right? Want you to post on both
TikTok and Instagram. They'll give you
these things called view bonus payouts
for when you actually stack up more and
more views. That's how I made 5K in a
single month posting uh 15 videos. Now,
I put YouTube as four. Most people try
and say that YouTube, YouTube Shorts,
Brain Bow Automation, and like YouTube
long form is the best way to start
making money online. And I low-key think
that's a little bit of BS because
there's no other opportunity that'll
realistically allow you with zero
startup cost to make your first thousand
dollars in the first 60-ish days of just
creating content. UGC is pretty much one
of these untapped opportunities where
you can do so. You don't have to be
super super experienced. I know a lot of
people who've made their first 10K
months with UGC within their first 90
days of creating content. It It's a
wonderful wonderful startup opportunity
to make money online. Whereas YouTube,
let's say you want to monetize YouTube,
there's like two ways you can do it.
It's either through brand deals or it's
through the actual like AdSense. Now, I
want to show you guys something [ __ ]
funny. I'll actually pull up my AdSense
on my YouTube Studio and I'll show you
guys how much my account has made. And
this is after having posted um I don't
know, maybe like almost a hundred videos
at this point on my YouTube. Maybe like
50 to a hundred videos. If I pull up my
all-time revenue on my YouTube. My
all-time revenue with this channel,
right? And I started earning in December
2024. So, in the past two years, like
one and a half years, I made $2,400.
But for the amount of actual time that I
actually had to put into this channel,
it's not nearly as much. In fact, I've
probably paid more to my editors in the
past for helping make these videos
because let's be real to it. To pump out
this volume of videos, it it takes a lot
of work and time. So, I would put that
as a four. Because yeah, it literally
took me like a year to make my first
thousand dollars with YouTube. But the
reason why it's not like a two or a one
is because if you have a business to
actually help monetize your channel, if
I actually go back to my internal
dashboard here, you can see YouTube
already attributes around 5% of the
revenue of the 189K. So, you know, it
has made a decent impact on my business.
But that being said, to make your first
thousand dollars, Instagram and TikTok
are also significantly easier platforms
to learn and grow, which we'll talk
about at the end on which platforms are
actually easiest to grow and pick up and
learn and get your first one, ten
thousand followers on. But let's move on
to making your first ten thousand
dollars with social media. This is the
point where it actually starts to become
a feasible like income for you, whether
it's on the side. I would say around
your first ten thousand dollars is when
you can start considering it to be like,
holy [ __ ] this is this is like can be a
real full-time income for me one day,
right? So, I actually made my first ten
thousand dollars with TikTok. So, I have
a little bit of a bias towards TikTok
because I made my first ten thousand
dollars doing their creativity program
and I'll leave a screenshot up here. I
think I made around nine thousand
dollars getting like a hundred million
views on their platform. This is back in
like 2021. Yeah, I had to get
a crap ton of views to make even a
sizeable amount of money. Like, you
know, like this is like rent payment,
you know, for a year. But I had to get
literally an absurd amount of views. For
that reason, you know, it's an eight.
It's definitely possible to make your
first ten thousand dollars. And I'll
also talk about other methods like
TikTok Shop. Now, TikTok Shop is one of
these opportunities where people are
making their first ten bands very very
quickly. Instagram I would put at a
seven and then YouTube I would still put
at a five for the same reasons that I
spoke of before because brand deals and
AdSense realistically won't pick up
unless you are a big big channel who's
pumping out volume pretty much every
single week doing like over a million
views a month. And at least frankly for
my own channel, we have a decent CPM.
We're still not doing nearly as much
volume. 45K views in a month is nowhere
near enough to like make that even a
sizeable income. But let's talk about
Instagram making your first ten thousand
dollars. Now, once again, I would
recommend UGC is probably the easiest
way to make your first ten thousand
dollars with Instagram. But the way that
I've seen most people actually monetize
on Instagram and make their first 10K
without becoming famous influencers is
through starting their own business.
Now, Instagram I would say is the
easiest platform to actually start your
own business on. The reason why I put
that as a seven is because it requires
you to actually have a business and
having a business is kind of hard. You
have to learn sales, marketing, product.
And these are skills that are quite
difficult to do. It's not impossible and
with Instagram, you can just be posting
a video every single day or every other
day. And just with a ton of volume, I
usually see around day 60 to 90 of
consistent posting is when people hit
their first five to 10K followers on
Instagram. And at that point, you can
just post a couple Instagram stories and
start selling whatever you have to sell.
reason why Instagram gets a seven is
because you can monetize through an
online business. And the way you can
very easily monetize your Instagram with
an online business is once you have even
a small Instagram following, I'm talking
even just a thousand people, there are
so many touch points at which you can
just start selling to this audience and
start making money, right? So, the
different touch points that I would
include are these three. First one is
stories. Now, for Instagram, I literally
have a KPI right now that's just one CTA
in my story every single week. That
basically means that every single week,
once a week, I'm posting one call to
action that directs people from my
Instagram following to one of my
products to actually take a look at
them. The second one is through
Instagram posts  carousels. Now,
Instagram posts and carousels are
actually one of the most underrated ways
to CTA and sell to your audience. I've
seen a ton of creators, like I'll bring
up an example here, who've been able to
pretty much launch a massive business.
I'm talking like for example, this guy
Scott. He's doing like multi six figures
a month, multi hundred K months selling.
And most of his selling actually comes
through these Instagram carousel style
of style of picture posts. And if I
actually pull up his initial launch
carousel for his business, The Bling
Empire, you can see this one pretty much
converted like a hundred K month or two
hundred K month right off the bat. It
was this one, right? Bling Empire
Mastermind. And And here's another
carousel example. But that being said,
it's it's There's no other platform
where you can just instantly reach your
audience once you've built it just with
the tap of a button. Whereas TikTok and
YouTube, you still somewhat have to post
organically viable videos for your post
to reach your audience. But in
Instagram, it's the closest thing to
actually owning your audience. And the
last one is still your Reels. Now, Reels
operate similarly to TikToks and YouTube
Shorts where, you know, most of your
views are inevitably going to come from
non-followers. But that being said, on
Instagram, you can still have a decent
like base of minimum viewership. And
that's because no matter what, Instagram
will still push your videos towards your
existing audience even if the video
itself has no organic pull. So, you can
see here there's not as much variation.
Like the lowest views that a video will
get is around like 35 to 40K views. You
might think, "Damn, but he has 500,000
followers. Like how is it not reaching
more people? Well, if you look at
TikTok, for example, just because you
have any followers on TikTok does not
mean TikTok will push out your videos to
your audience, right? All of these
videos are heavily optimized for the
algorithm, but even then, the slower
videos will still hit only like 2,000
views. Now, if I were to literally post
any promotional thing, like, "Oh, check
out these client results so you can
check out my business." That video on
TikTok would probably get less than
1,000 views. I'm not even kidding.
Because TikTok only cares about whether
video actually gets watch time and
engagement from a completely cold
audience of people who've never seen
your face before, right? And Instagram
Reels' algorithm still operates a
similar way, but at the very least,
because Instagram literally has this
home feed, you're still going to be
shown the post from the people who
follow you. That's why all to say, I
think Instagram's probably the easiest
to make your first 10K because once you
have any semblance of an audience, you
can sell to them the easiest way. Now,
TikTok, however, right? The reason why I
put it as an eight is because there is a
little bit of an anomaly with TikTok
Shop. Now, TikTok Shop, if you don't
know, it's basically a way for creators
to link some product in a video in the
bottom left corner of the screen. And
then if a viewer finds that product
interesting from the video, they can
just tap that button and then purchase
it from that video. Now, even though I
believe you need at least 5,000
followers to unlock TikTok Shop in
TikTok, I do think it is easier because
you don't have to learn how to sell or
build your own product. With TikTok
Shop, you're just affiliating other
existing products. Like if I like this
hoodie and it it was somehow being sold
on TikTok Shop, I wouldn't have to learn
how to make hoodies or build hoodie
websites. I could just link this
hoodie's page, and then if people want
to buy that hoodie, I can instantly
start making money. So, it's a lot
easier to get started if you have no
skills in business. Meanwhile, for
YouTube, I would say it just becomes
slightly easier because once you have a
business, right? I'm not talking about
brand deals or AdSense. I'm talking
about with a business, with some sort of
product, some coaching, agency service,
digital product that you're selling
through your YouTube videos. Because
YouTube videos are so much longer,
people are actually going to develop a
trust and relationship with you as the
creator. So, they're going to be a lot
more receptive to buying or purchasing
whatever you have to sell. Whereas on
Instagram or TikTok, if you're just
shilling brain rot or like 10 to
15-second videos, how is somebody going
to watch a 10-15 second video and be
like, "Yeah, I'mma pay this guy 100
bucks with their whatever thing that
they have?" It's highly unlikely. So, a
lot of times what people do with
Instagram, too, and this is something
that I've done in the past as well, is
from Instagram, they'll then post a
story promoting their YouTube videos. Or
if you go to their actual Instagram,
like this guy, he's his business
recently hit 400K in a month, but I
believe when you actually go to his link
in bio, he [clears throat] doesn't sell
anything directly. He actually gives a
free lead magnet, of which that will
probably nurture you way heavier. And
then at the bottom of this lead magnet,
which is I'm guessing some Notion
template, he has a link to like book a
call. All to say, you need further
nurture in between somebody seeing your
Instagram page and then actually
converting to being a paying customer in
your business. And that's why YouTube is
a great medium. And I'll actually prove
it to you. This video alone, how I grew
200K followers in a year, it got 124K
views. Even still to this day, it's
generating money. Like the attribution
link in the video is called YTVCL24.
It's generated $3,000 in revenue to my
business in the past 90 days. Not just
that, when I first posted it and it got
a majority of these views, I think it
literally generated like 70K in revenue
for subscriptions of Content Academy. No
single video on Instagram has done that
for me. And it literally just had a link
to purchase the Content Academy in that
description. And that video alone,
because it was 30 minutes, I was able to
explain why I'm trustable, why the
mechanism of Content Academy and the
product itself actually works. And then
I was able to explain what the product
is and how they can actually go forward
with purchasing that. But on Instagram
or TikTok, you're not going to be given
that level of time and leniency with
whoever your audience is. Now, let's
talk about getting your first 100K and
your first mill. Now, starting off with
generating your first 100K, I would say
Instagram, once again, is at an eight.
And obviously, I'm [ __ ] biased
towards Instagram because I mean, just
look at these revenue charts. The 50% by
the way is just like untracked revenue.
It's revenue that wasn't able to be
tracked for some reason by Hyros, but if
you actually go just based on the
tracked revenue itself, around 69%
of the tracked revenue came from
Instagram. Instagram is still, by far,
the best platform to actually monetize
your following. So, I gave it an eight
out of 10 because it is the first
platform that I was able to make my
first 100K. And once you're able to
actually start building momentum on
Instagram, the nicest thing is that once
again, you own your audience. And you
might not think that that's so powerful,
but think about what you are always
trying to do as a content creator when
you post videos. You're not just trying
to post into the void and then feel like
you have to wake up the next week
starting from absolute ground zero with
no existing audience anymore, right? You
want to feel like over time, you're
accumulating this asset that compounds
over time, where you're building a
little bit more of a moat and stability
for yourself as a creator. That's
exactly what Instagram can provide you
once you build this audience. Now, of
course, people can fall off on
Instagram, too, right? Accounts can go
through these highs and lows. But that
being said, even when accounts are going
through lows,
is going through a little bit of a low
right now, a valley, right? Where the
videos themselves are not going crazy
viral. But that being said, they're
still hitting a minimum of like 30, 40K
at the very least and still hitting like
medians of like 100K. This allows you to
stably run a business through your
Instagram. Or if you're doing brand
deals as well, it somewhat allows you to
run a stable funnel for brands as well
to continuously work with your page.
Meanwhile, TikTok I would actually put
at a four. Now, once again, I said
personally that I have made my first
$10,000 from TikTok, but then past that,
my brand deals would only be able to
make around two, 3,000 dollars. And the
problem with TikTok is that because you
don't own your audience here, if you
literally take a break from TikTok or
for some reason your videos just stop
hitting with the algorithm, then your
ability to monetize is going to be
absolutely shot in the gutter because
your follower count does not mean
anything on TikTok. So, even though you
might be consistently hitting like a
million views for a month on TikTok, two
months later, you your views literally
might be down to like 10K. Even if
you've built up an audience of like
100,000, 200,000 followers. And I'll
show you on my TikTok account. This is
my TikTok account, which I'd grown to
over 900,000 followers back in 2021 and
2022. And you can see here, if a video
just doesn't hit with the algorithm,
it'll still manage to only get 4,000
views, which is the same number of views
that I get on a lot of these videos on
this page, actually less views. And this
account is literally like a seventh of
the followers, a sixth of the followers.
All to say, I think TikTok's really hard
to build a consistent income. And you're
not going to just hit like skyrocket
100K a month on TikTok. Most likely, if
you want to make your first 100K, you
have to be consistently sustaining like
10K a month. And what platform allows
you to do that best? Well, probably not
TikTok. I gave it a four. Now, YouTube,
I'm climbing this up to a six because
once you can actually sustainably build
a system for YouTube, it can generate
sales without you needing to go get
nearly as many views at all. So, I'll
show you here. My videos here, if I sort
by the most recent date, they're not
getting crazy views, right? Like they're
averaging around maybe 5,000 views. Yet
even still, it's able to generate, you
know, somewhat consistent revenue. If I
go to the past 30 days of this business,
YouTube is already about a fourth of
Instagram's revenue despite only doing
like 36,000 views. So, all to say, I
would say I'm more so a beginner at
YouTube, yet it's still already paying
off a decent income and decent revenue
for our business. So, as a business
owner, I would say it's a six out of 10.
However, once again, if you are just
focused on brand deals and AdSense, it's
still going to be significantly harder
to make like your first 100K with
YouTube. The only exception that I would
say in terms of AdSense or brand deals
is if you're consistently able to hit
like 100K plus views on YouTube. That's
when I would say, I've heard from
friends that they're able to land like
five-figure brand deals, like $10,000
brand deals, or they're able to make
like five to 10,000 dollars on AdSense
from a video if it gets millions of
views. And they're in a decent niche,
too, like finance. But if you're in the
entertainment niche, for example, it's
significantly harder to even make your
first 100K with AdSense or brand deals
unless you're going stupidly viral. Now,
and let's finish off here with making
your first million. Now, this is going
to I'm putting a heavy caveat here. All
three of these combined, my business has
generated just over, I think, 1.2
million dollars in the past two years.
However, once again, a majority of that
income and revenue came from Instagram.
Like I would estimate based on the
revenue charts that we're seeing here,
about like 80% of that revenue
[clears throat] came from Instagram. So,
I I'm going to have to put that as a
seven out of 10. Now, I put TikTok as a
three out of 10. Honestly, I would have
put it as a one out of 10 if it was just
for my own anecdotal experience, but
I've met people who've done TikTok Shop
who've literally made over 100K a month
in pure profit, right? They don't have
to pay any team or expenses for making
this affiliate revenue with TikTok Shop.
Once again, those are outliers. Those
are like the top 1% of TikTok Shop
creators. It's possible, and I don't
want to completely discount that. And I
know that my experience is also biased
based on being a business owner, but if
you're running a business, right? That's
why I put the [ __ ] and Stripe logo. Like
I personally use [ __ ] as our payment
processor, it's a seven out of 10.
YouTube, the reason why I also put it as
a seven out of 10 is because just based
on the limited experience, I do know for
a fact that going all in on YouTube over
the next year will probably flip these
scales and make YouTube at least
equivalent to Instagram in the long term
of revenue, especially when the views
are able to somewhat catch up or creep
up on the Instagram views. Because if
you actually weight these based on
views, right? You essentially have to
like 20x the amount of revenue that
YouTube generates. Because if I were to
somehow match the amount of Reels views
that I was doing on YouTube, then
YouTube would make significantly more
than Instagram does in revenue for our
business. So while I will say I'm still
in the process of building up this
YouTube channel and building up an
audience, building up authority on this
platform, I do think based on the data
that I've seen, I'm significantly more
bullish on YouTube in the long run as a
creator. Now does that mean I'm going to
somehow take my ball off take my eyes
off the ball on Instagram? [ __ ] no.
Because Instagram is still so valuable
and consistent as a business owner
because of the stories, posts, and
Reels. However, the problem with
Instagram is just that for the amount of
time that you have to put into these
videos to make them actually pretty
good. Like I calculated the amount of
time that I spend on Instagram Reels per
week, and it's probably around like 20
hours every single week. That's like a
part-time job just to keep this
marketing machine going. However, with
YouTube, because you can just sit down
and film an entire video, right? You're
pretty much spending probably a similar
amount of time making these YouTube
videos as you are with the Reels because
Reels you have to hyper edit. You have
to make sure every single sentence is
literally scripted so it keeps your
attention all the time all the time all
the time. YouTube, I feel like it can be
a little bit looser and I feel like I
don't have to script as much. Like I'm
literally just yabbering over these uh
these images and pictures that I've
drawn on this mural board. So that's why
I think I would weight them similarly in
terms of making your first mill. And if
I invested nearly the same amount of
time that I had into this Instagram page
as I did into YouTube, it probably would
have generated a similar if not
significantly larger amount of income
from YouTube. That being said, however,
let's talk about how difficult or easy
it is to grow on these platforms and
actually get started so I can give you
my final verdict ranking these three on
what you should be going all in on in
2026 as a creator. Okay, starting off
with Instagram, I'll give it an eight
out of 10 score in terms of growth. Now,
in terms of growth very specifically,
I'll I'll very specifically break it
down. In the first 30 days on Instagram,
what I've noticed from a lot of accounts
is that you're going to have to go
through this warm-up phase where
Instagram won't be as quick to pick up
viral videos or pick up your account and
start pushing out the videos. I noticed
this on my own main account. So I've
actually sorted this Instagram account
back from oldest to newest. I've sorted
all of the 200 or 600 Reels. And at the
time when I first posted these videos, a
lot of these were actually getting over
100,000, some even over a million views
on TikTok. But for some reason, all of
them were stuck under around like 10K
views on Instagram.
Now they've been updated a little bit
because I've grown a larger audience. A
lot of people have just gone back to the
beginning and seen a lot of these videos
like by noon scrolling down. But when I
first started this account, essentially
what I'm trying to say is I was stuck at
around 2,000 followers for around like 3
months straight. Zero growth, okay? And
only about like 3 months in when I
actually posted this video about No Nut
November, it got 1.7 million views. And
then the other videos started to
actually take off like 70K, 100K, right?
600K. And then I would repost this old
video, right? Pay attention to this one,
Stop using your phone. It's at 500K
views. But if I scroll up this same
video that I posted about Stop using
your phone, only got 13K views. So a lot
of times, what Instagram will do is they
just like won't push out your videos as
much when you're a newer account. So
that's why I wouldn't put it at like a
10 out of 10. But once you hit that like
2-month mark of consistently posting,
Instagram will suddenly give your
account a little bit more authority. And
if the videos themselves actually do
deserve to be pushed out, right? Like
they're actually hitting decent view and
watch duration metrics on the platforms,
they're getting decent engagement like
comments and likes, then your videos
will start to grow. And Instagram growth
I've always noticed is a lot easier to
be linear, right? You don't need to be
hunting down these spurts of virality
all the time. You can be chilling in
like the 10 to 100K view range and still
getting a decent follower base from
that. TikTok, however, I would put at a
seven to grow. Because TikTok, you can
literally have your first video on an
account blow up. And for this account
right here, I actually grew this from
zero to 100K followers in the first
month of starting this account. If I go
to the oldest, you can see pretty much
all of these videos from the jump just
[ __ ] popped. 200K, 200K, 800K, 100K.
And suddenly these videos are hitting up
to the mill view range. 1, 4 mill,
right? 1.5 mill, 400K, right? 1.1 mill.
So this video literally skyrocket or
this account literally skyrocket from
zero to 100K followers in a single
month. However, it requires you to still
go viral. And I've rarely seen accounts
grow when they're hitting like the 10K
to 100K view range. It's usually like
this kind of all or nothing game with
TikTok. You're either going super duper
viral or you're pretty much getting no
reach. And you can see it on this
account as well where most of the videos
are they feel very polarizing. It's
either like gets a ton of views but then
the next day literally gets only like 5K
views. So that's I would I would say
it's a little bit more confusing of a
game than Instagram. But and I would say
in the long run, Instagram feels a lot
easier to build a consistent audience
over time just because of that factor of
you're not going to suddenly feel this
massive weight of everything falling
apart overnight like it can happen on
TikTok, right? Let me pull up this my my
largest account once again. 200K to 4K
views. Now obviously I haven't really
posted on this account. Literally like
the last time I actually posted like a
decent video was back in 2023. So
obviously like you know,
yeah that's I I probably could be doing
better on that account. I probably could
have gotten to a million followers. But
what I'm trying to say is also that like
you don't really own your audience on
TikTok anyway. So it feels like you're
just building like a nothing burger
asset on TikTok. Like you're just
building something that's always
depreciating over time because people
are always so quick to forget on TikTok.
Trends move so quickly, right? So it's
so hard to monetize as well because in
order to monetize long-term, in order
for you to like disperse your attention
to start running this business thing on
the side or maybe even start focusing on
building your other platforms, right?
You have to start taking a little bit of
your focus away from creating content on
the platforms, which means you might not
be putting out S-tier banger viral
content always on top of the trends like
a hawk. And then suddenly your views are
just going to tank like 10x downwards
overnight. And that feeling feels
horrible. And on Instagram at the very
least, if you're posting, you know,
semi-decent effort content, it'll still
get decent reach. But on TikTok, if
you're not putting out viral bangers,
you're you should probably be expecting
between like the 1,000 to like at most
2,000 view range. YouTube, I would say
to grow at to start off, once again, I'm
like very bearish on YouTube at least as
a beginning platform. I would give it a
four. And the reason why I give it a
four and not even like a five or a six
is because the feedback loops are just
so slow on YouTube. So if you're
literally getting like 200, 300 views,
but each video takes a week to make, the
cycles of improvement take weeks at a
time. So let's say it takes 60 videos
for you to hit your first 10,000
followers on any platform. I think
that's like a generally consistent
metric if you're putting in 100% effort
into those 60 videos. If you're doing
one post a week on YouTube, which is a
very realistic cadence, right? It's
still going to take you over a year to
reach your first 10,000 followers or
10,000 subscribers to the point where
you can actually like start monetizing.
So I can see I hit 10K followers on
YouTube or 10K subscribers around
February of 2025. So if I should go
back, February of 2025. Mind you, this
is also after having built like I I
guess a lot of experience media, too. So
right around this video, the NYC Content
Academy meetup vlog, did I hit 10K
followers. So let's see how many videos
it actually took. 43 videos. So like my
my estimate's like pretty decent, you
know? 60 videos, let's say like 40 to 60
videos on YouTube to hit your first 10K
followers. And I would say that's
generally consistent across these
platforms, too. From what I've seen
after coaching hundreds of students, you
can see this is just like a list of all
our students ranked based on their
follower count. So these are all the
people that I've personally helped in my
community. And generally the trend that
I've seen is around 40 to 60 videos in,
that's when you hit your first 10K
followers on these platforms. Now the
reason why I bring this up is because
you can take 40 to 60 weeks in order to
hit that amount of subscribers on
YouTube or you can take around 40 to 60
days on Instagram or TikTok in order to
not just get that follower count, but
also build up your skill set. And that's
why I would at least put TikTok higher
than YouTube because you're building a
skill set as a creator. You're learning
how to capture attention with hooks and
packaging. You're learning how to speak
on camera. You're learning how to script
things. You're learning how to edit.
You're learning how to clip things
together. And you're learning how to put
like good lighting, for example. All of
these things stack up as a creator. But
these are all skill sets that you need
to build up over time. And that takes
just raw numbers of repetition. So if it
takes around 40 to 60 videos on a
platform, I'd rather that you do it on a
platform that you can actually grow the
fastest on. So that being said, which
platform gets the crown for the number
one platform that you should be starting
to make your first 1K, 10K, 100K, and a
mill and start growing on? You guessed
it. I'm going to give it to Instagram.
And I would actually give
uh I would actually give TikTok number
two just because as a beginning channel,
bro, YouTube is freaking brutal. And you
I like I genuinely think if you want to
make it work long-term, you either need
to no life this [ __ ] and put in so much
time or you need to have the capital to
hire an editor. Of which, you know, no
starting channel or creator is going to
have like, you know, a couple hundred
bucks every single video to pay somebody
out if they're not making any money as a
creator. So, I would put Tik Tok as the
mini crown number two and then YouTube
as the number three cuz it takes so much
longer to build up a YouTube audience.
And that being said, too, it's really
hard to grow on YouTube if you don't
have like some special it factor to make
you stand out from the crowd. With
Instagram and Tik Tok, you can do things
like just edit frauding. You can do
things like cinematic content where you
don't need some crazy lifestyle to make
yourself stand out. But on YouTube, you
know, most people are looking for people
to watch and binge and, you know, like
spend their entire Thursday afternoon
with watching their 30-minute video. So,
it's like how do you make somebody
compelled enough to watch you for 30
minutes? It takes a little bit more for
somebody to be that invested in you. And
that's why it's harder. So, like also as
a younger person, right? Cuz I started
content at 16 years old. I started it
with Tik Tok cuz I was literally making
brain rot videos. Let me pull this [ __ ]
up, bro. Your boy started with videos
that looked like this.
You know?
Some like edgy Tik Tok memes, weird ass
duets, you know, that like unfunny odd
duets, bro. I would make like
trend videos.
Like anime trend You know, like you're
probably watching these being like,
"What the hell is bro doing?" And yeah,
it's like low-key how the content
strategy works on Tik Tok. You just can
make random stuff based on the trends
and it helps you learn and get a pulse
on what people actually care to watch
versus don't care to watch. And your
feedback loops are literally every day.
Like the instant you post a video,
within the first hour you're actually
probably going to know whether it's
going to go viral or not. Or at least
within the first 24 to 48 hours. On
YouTube, the half-life of a video, I
believe, is around 7 days, which is cool
because then you at least your video has
bit more length to grow on the platform.
But as a side effect, it's going to take
you a week to get proper data on every
single video. So, what does that mean?
Your 40 to 60 video timeline to actually
iterate and improve as a creator is
going to take you like a year. And I
showed you, hopefully with the data I've
been on my own channels, that this has
been true across my channels, across my
different pages on Tik Tok, and on my
Instagram. Because my Instagram in the
past 2 years has probably generated me
like 750 to like close to a mill in
revenue for our business.
It is literally insane how much impact
Instagram has had on our business.
Single stories have generated like 10 to
20,000 dollars in revenue just from
posting a single Instagram story. So,
it's freaking broken. So, I would highly
recommend Instagram. And if you want an
easy way to get started, I would
recommend starting by doing something
called UGC where you're just getting
paid to post on these platforms of Tik
Tok and Instagram for brands. You don't
have to build your own product or
anything. You don't even need an
existing audience. It helps you get paid
to just learn the skill set. And that's
how most of the creators that I've
coached and worked with have made their
first 1,000 to 10,000 dollars online.
So, hopefully this video was helpful. I
tried to give as much brain dumped
information on how this money in the
creator economy works in 2026 as
somebody who not only runs my entire
business and lifestyle and now pays like
a team of like seven people through this
business, but I also run a creator
community that coaches over 900 people
in short form on how to grow and how to
monetize. So, hopefully this was
helpful. If you found this helpful,
uh please just leave a like and a
subscribe. And let me know if there's
anything else you want me to cover in
these videos. Literally anything. I can
break down, for example, this like uh
this dashboard that I built. This is
Claude Code, by the way. So, I I was
working on this and I basically was able
to conglomerate all of our WOK Discord,
uh social media data, and our High Roas
data all into one place. I thought that
was pretty sick. It's not as related to
social media, but, you know, anything
that you guys want me to cover. I
genuinely want this channel to just be
as open book as possible for all of you
guys to [ __ ] ascend as creators and
make this [ __ ] a full-time income and
have the impact and influence that you
want to have in this lifetime. I know I
sound hella sick cuz cuz I am, actually.
I have the flu right now. Uh so, I
appreciate you guys for listening to me
with my nasally rice gum voice. All
right. Peace.