If there's one thing that helped me grow
500,000 followers on Instagram in just
the past 2 years on my personal brand,
it's understanding [music] exactly who
my viewer is and scripting, ideating my
content precisely on how to speak to
this [music] one person. So, in this
video I want to help you guys understand
exactly how to find your own ideal
viewer, the one person who's going to
fall in love with your content. So, your
content cuts through the noise and
actually speaks to your viewer's soul.
Because this strategy is not just going
to help you go more viral, it's going to
help you build a brand that genuinely
feels one of one in a market of content
creators that frankly feels incredibly
saturated, so you can blow up your
personal brand in the next 90 days as
well. So, in today's lesson I want to
basically help make your videos hit your
audience harder.
And I'll explain from the very start why
the ideal viewer persona is a framework
that's helped me make my videos
significantly more retentive with the
algorithm, aka get more views. So, let's
start off from the very basic principle.
Why does the algorithm push out one
video from higher view counts from like
10 to 100,000 plus views, while some of
our other videos get stuck literally in
like a thousand view jail, 500 view
jail? Right, why does that happen? And
it's not luck, it's not like some random
reasons. Very basic principle is average
watch time for your first thousand
viewers. So, at the very beginning,
right, retention, perfect. At the very
beginning when you first make a video,
every single time, every single time you
make a video this literally applies.
TikTok, Instagram, YouTube, they're
going to test your video amongst the
first 300, 500, 1,000 viewers, however
many, and they're going to see how well
people actually stay and watch till the
end of the video. And if let's say only
on average they watch like 8 seconds, 5
seconds, then that's like a generally
pretty low average watch time, then the
algorithm's going to say, "Okay, I don't
want to push this out to more viewers
because I don't want viewers to go on to
Instagram or go on to TikTok, see boring
content, and then close the app or feel
like our app is boring." They only want
to push obviously high watch time
content, right? So, the algorithm's
going to test your video on about a
thousand people or about 500 people. And
if you're in this like 500 or 300 view
jail, that means it's not making it past
this first benchmark of its first
initial test viewers, and that's
perfectly fine. We're going to talk
about how we can actually build a system
where just your words and your script
alone can actually make your video
interesting enough to get higher watch
time throughout all the videos that you
make. So, people pay with their time and
attention. So, think about your page
kind of like a business where it's not
just obviously getting views for free,
but at the very core, everybody's
attention and time is very precious to
them. So, they're not just going to like
sit and give you 30 seconds, 60 seconds
of their time when they literally have a
dopamine slot machine button just to
swipe and see their next hyper
interesting brain rot super optimized
video. But watch time always comes
first. And specifically, how do you
create higher watch time? Because
viewers will probably give you about 5
seconds to make them care. And if you
can't make them care within the first 5
seconds, then they're going to scroll
off. So, it comes from this concept of
perceived value. And perceived value
comes from getting clarity and a clear
reason in the first 10 seconds for a
viewer to care. The reason why
algorithms will push a certain video to
higher view counts, while maybe yours
will be stuck under a thousand views,
under 500 views,
it's not because of luck, it's because
of the math of watch times, how long
people are watching your videos for on
the platform. So, the whole game and the
whole like science that we're trying to
learn here in Content Academy with
hooks, with with editing, with
scripting, with storytelling is to get
your watch time up, so your videos get
pushed out more to the algorithms, so
the valuable message that you have with
your personal brand or the valuable
product that you want to show if you're
a business owner, right, gets shown to
more eyeballs on the platforms. Because
often times platforms are exponential
where it's not going to be like your
video's twice as good, it's going to get
2,000 views instead of 1,000 views. If
your video's twice as good, it might get
10 times the views or 100 times the
views. The algorithms are very
exponential that way, right? So, so, so,
so, average watch time is the key. And
this is a framework that I've used to
improve my watch time with my videos to
help people have a reason to pay
attention in the first 10 seconds, in
the first couple seconds even of my
videos. It's a framework that informs my
entire scripting, it informs the way I
write my hooks. The reason why this
helps is because it helps me understand
the value proposition of my videos. If
you understand who your ideal viewer is,
it's going to help make your value
proposition so much stronger in the
first couple seconds. If you understand
who is exactly watching, you can curtail
your video script, your hook to hit
exactly with the things that they're
thinking of, the things that are top of
mind for your ideal viewer, with the
pain points and the desires that are top
of mind for your ideal viewer. So,
that's how you create hooks and scripts
that are irresistible for your viewers,
right? And it's this concept of creating
perceived value, very clear perceived
value, very clear reason in the first 10
seconds for a viewer to care. Now,
here's the problem. A lot of you guys,
right, just drop a W in the chat. If you
feel like you have something very
interesting and important to share with
your audience, but you feel like for
some reason it's so incredibly and cool,
and your story is so compelling in your
mind, but when you put it out on video,
it doesn't come across the way that you
want to, and as a result, it feels like
it flops so much harder than you want
to. Like this happens to me so many
times where I'm like, "Holy banger
idea." Like I have this crazy story that
happened in my life that like, you know,
I went through some like emotional
journey in my life, and I have this
crazy story, I have it mapped out in my
head, and then when I actually put it
out on video, it hits like only half as
many views as like my average, and I'm
like, "Holy flop, I did not cook here."
And I used all the storytelling
frameworks, I used all like the editing
tricks and stuff. Yet for some reason,
it still didn't hit. And the reason why,
I think for a reason why for a lot of
you guys, right, including me as well,
is because you are so knowledgeable in
your thing. You are too knowledgeable in
your niche to the point where it
actually makes you forget what a
stranger thinks about it. So, for
example, me in the content creation
space, I'm so obsessed with these things
like ideal viewer persona, you know, the
storytelling frameworks, three-act story
structure, hooks. But then to an average
viewer, if I say those words, it's
really confusing, right? Like I had to
explain to you guys obviously what an
ideal viewer persona is for you guys to
care. But a stranger is not going to
give me that level of time. So, the same
goes with your hooks, with your
storytelling, right? At the end of the
day, if you're super knowledgeable in
your niche of like fitness or maybe it's
technology, you have to convey why you
care to the viewer because you have all
this context on why AI is so cool or
why, you know, hypertrophy is so
important into the in the gym or why the
ideal viewer persona framework matters.
But you have to sell and persuade your
viewer on why that's important at the
very beginning of your video, and that's
the whole goal of your hook. So, it
requires you to understand what exactly
your ideal viewer cares about or it it
requires you to understand what people
in general care about on the internet.
But obviously there's a billion users on
Instagram and TikTok, and that's why
this framework of the ideal viewer
persona was born because you're not
supposed to make videos for every single
1 billion people who are watching these
platforms because there's simultaneously
55-year-old,
you know, moms and dads, and there's
also 15-year-old kids who watch YouTube
shorts Riz party content, you know,
there there's too large of a spectrum.
You have to understand who your viewer
is. And the more specific you can get on
that, the more deeply resonant your
content can be rather than feeling like
it's in the middle being like AI video
made for technical experts while also
being an AI video for beginners. It's
all about missing context, basically
what I'm trying to say. And you're
trying to bridge the gap between what
you know and what you care about and why
these concepts in your stories in your
videos are so interesting and then where
your viewers are. Now, here's an
example. I actually have this right next
to me, thank goodness. Imagine if I led
with a hook being like this. 120 mg of
caffeine, here's how you match the
L-theanine to caffeine ratio from 120 to
240. And when we increase the L-theanine
to caffeine ratio from 120 to 240, bro,
you're scrolling by the time I'm saying
these [ __ ] words. Because even though
you might somewhat know what the words
caffeine mean, and you might somewhat
know what the words L-theanine mean or
yerba mate mean, this this has no
context to your real world value. Now,
imagine instead if I just led with a
much simpler dumbed-down hook. Yo, this
is the magic potion I drink every
morning to run my business, post a video
every single day. And you want to know
the secret? It's [ __ ] L-theanine,
right? Okay, maybe that's not the most
compelling hook, but that's
significantly more compelling than me
just jumping straight into the story and
the value of why 120 caffeine and 240
L-theanine and all of that mumbo jumbo.
It's so much more compelling when I
actually explain why the L-theanine is
actually important before I actually
explain the science behind it. So, lead
obviously with the hook and lead
obviously with the value that you're
going to provide from the information
before you actually lead with the
information. Very specifically here. And
and the reason why I bring up this
example cuz this is like a very obvious
example. I honestly I I would love for
you guys to for you guys to guess here.
What is the core drive and pain point
that my video is trying to solve for my
viewers with this the bridged version of
the hook? This is the magic potion I
drink every morning to run my business.
Well, what is the outcome that my video
is subtly implying it's going to help
people get by learning about yerba mate?
And just leave like any answers, there's
no wrong answers, just leave them in the
chat. Um I'll just read out the answers
right here. How to have energy, money,
success, procrastination, laziness,
productive productivity. Exactly,
exactly, that's the point. Because none
of you guys care enough deeply about
yerba mate on a random Tuesday afternoon
to sit 60 seconds watching some science
nerd break down yerba mate, right? So,
that video is probably going to get
maybe, you know, 2,000 views, 1,000
views of this niche audience of your
mate, like literal [ __ ] your mate
scientist who work in your mate
industry. Everyone else is like, that's
cool, I guess, scroll.
But because I connected it back to a
broader desirable
human core drive of success, business,
money, productivity, these things that
are super top of mind for who I would
guess is my ideal viewer persona, this
can get a larger broader reach. That's
the whole goal and the whole thesis
behind trying to make these hooks hit
with my ideal viewer persona. So, the
So, the key is to then try to understand
what are the core drives. Because am I
leading more into health here with the
your mate, or am I leading more into
business and money and success with your
mate? And to understand which core drive
that I want to lean into for my viewers
requires me to have at least a decent
understanding where I've somewhat broken
down the psychology behind my ideal
viewer persona. So, I created this
little document tool and it's not
complex whatsoever. I know drop the link
to this in the chat just so you guys can
follow along with your own personal
brands. These were great answers by the
way, like stop being tired, be
productive, etc. All you have to do is
just like make a copy, file make a copy
and then you guys can do this exercise
on your own. Look, before we go into the
next part about the ideal viewer and how
to actually apply it into your content,
if you feel like you're posting content
into the void every single day, one of
the biggest unlocks that I highly highly
recommend is having a content mentor
actually there to look into your content
and give you a content audit. So, I
literally created a completely
personalized road map that just takes 30
seconds to complete. I'm going to leave
it in the first link in the description
below, but you can just input your page,
answer a couple questions, it takes 30
seconds and it's going to help identify
exactly what the bottlenecks are in your
page based on your actual videos. It's
going to scrape your profile and suggest
resources that I've custom made for you
to help you actually break through those
plateaus in your content and actually
continue to grow. And I made it
completely free. It's in the first link
in the description, so I highly
recommend you check it out. Just get
your free content audit. All right, on
to the rest of the video. But it starts
realistically just with the most basic
basic [ __ ] Like how old are they?
Because the type of videos and the way
that you talk to even an 18 to 24 year
old is vastly different from the way you
talk to a 24 to 30 30 year old. This
person's in a life stage of like, you
know, building their early career,
um like probably investing, starting to
think about like having a family. This
person's still probably thinking about
going to frat parties. Like they're
literally living in completely different
worlds. So, when people are like 18 to
30 is my ICP, no [ __ ] it's not. You're
making a video that's pandering to
everybody and you're not going to hit
anybody in a very relatable manner. So,
how are your stories that you're telling
going to actually hit on a deeply
emotional level if you're trying to
appeal to both simultaneously a 30 year
old and an 18 year old. So, that's the
whole thinking behind ideal viewer
persona and I like to think of ideal
viewer persona even in like if you can
narrow it down to like one singular age,
that's even better. Like if your video
is specifically for a college freshman.
I see a lot of YouTube and TikTok titles
in self-development being like if you're
18 to 21 watch this video. And I think
that's so smart because it literally
calls out the I ideal viewer directly in
the first sentence. And the whole goal
is to make it easy to understand. And
specifically give strangers a reason to
care as quickly as possible about your
concept. So, you have your concept, you
have your primary idea in which case I'm
like, yo, I want to make a video about
your mate, but you have to give them the
reason now. Let's connect it back to the
reason, right? So, tie whatever you're
explaining, the tool, the tip, the news,
right? This is what's in your head right
now, right? You probably have a list of
things that you want to talk about. For
myself improvement creators who are
watching, or my gym creators who are
watching, you know, you have all these
tips and workout advice and advice that
you know the people need to hear. But
you have to think about now, how do you
make them actually care about the
advice? Because you might know what's
useful to somebody, but often times
what's useful to a viewer is very
different from what they would actually
want to hear. Like the person who needs
the productivity advice is most likely
very averse to watching productivity.
The laziest person who needs
productivity advice is probably the
person who sleeps at 3:00 a.m., watches
brain rot, watches like AI [ __ ] love
fruit fruit Love Island. I don't know if
you guys have seen that one. They They
The last thing they want to see is like
productivity advice. So, the The instant
they see like some David Goggins out
[ __ ] on their For You page,
they're scrolling instantly. So,
understand that this is part of the
psychology of your viewer. How do you
play into that and make sure that your
videos don't scare away those viewers.
To go even deeper into this, like
marketing 101. I I've heard this from
like consumer app founders. I think a
lot of core drives in life come down to
like survival, money, reproduction, and
another one can be like status or
approval. So, we put a third a fourth
one there, like status and approval. And
I think a lot of core drives come down
to this. So, when I think of like the
biggest pain points that I try to target
in my videos, let's say I'm making
content advice, right? Because that's my
niche. I'm not thinking about
necessarily just like, how do I make
hook advice like hit really hard? I
usually try to think one layer deeper.
It's like, what's the point of even
writing good hooks? It's probably so
they can like make more money with their
business or whatnot or like, you know,
eventually create a career out of
content. And that's what I've noticed
with my own content advice videos.
Content advice videos on like how to
make good hooks don't really do well.
But if I'm talking about like side
hustles and how content creation has
opened all these doors in my life for me
and like changed my life, that suddenly
gets like 10 times the views. And it's
because it hits the deeper pain point
that's way closer to like these core
human drives that we're thinking about
pretty much like every day, which is
like survival, money, reproduction, and
like status as well. Okay, and this is
like oversimplification and a lot of
things and a lot of desires in life,
like the gym. It's like you could argue
that the gym like comes from this desire
for status and reproduction. Or you
could argue that like um productivity
advice comes from just like wanting to
make more money, which then you can kind
of tie back to survival. So, it's not
like you're you're not overtly saying
outright in the videos like, yo, here's
how you can write better hooks so you
can survive in today's day and age. But
if you're you know, if you're writing a
video about let's say like content
advice, if it's just about content
advice, then I don't know if it's really
going to hit as hard. But that's why a
lot of like, you know, people in the
business space like flash cars and
stuff. It's because it's a subconscious
signal that they have status. That's
essentially how you can create hooks and
copywriting that hits with your ideal
viewer when you're at least thinking
about what triggers will be top of mind
and hit super top of mind with them.
Another framework that I like to think
about when writing hooks for my ideal
viewer persona, when creating visual
hooks that hit with my ideal viewer
persona, is like, what is What is the 80
IQ version of my ideal viewer persona?
Not necessarily like if I were to turn
my ideal viewer into an idiot, but it's
like we all have these like What What I
mean by 80 IQ is like, let's say the
most tired version of ourselves. When
we're on the toilet, when we're, you
know, at the end of a long day of work,
that's when we're scrolling reels,
right? Or when we just woke up. When we
just woke up and the first thing we're
doing is opening reels or TikTok and
scrolling. So, there's not much complex
thought behind the scroll, right? The
reason why somebody will be hooked by
your video is not because of some very
complex wording. Often times it's
actually the opposite. It's hyper
simplicity and it's just like one or two
keywords that hit them really hard. Or
it's one or two really interesting
visuals that hook them in. When we're
explaining once again like a hook or a
concept in our videos, when we try to
explain the super in-depth, you know,
technical PhD version, we're losing all
of our viewers. So, I often try to
refrain in my own videos from going
super hard on these words like viewer
retention and ideal viewer in the first
couple sentences of my video because
it's a little bit too much for my viewer
to swallow at least at the very
beginning. And this especially applies
to like more technical niches. Like I
think of like fitness, I think of
technology as these things that can go
super in-depth. And I'm sure like for a
lot of you guys' niches cuz I you know,
I've like reviewed a ton of you guys'
content, too. Like, you know, even
things like like culture as a niche or
like lifestyle as a niche, too. Like
philosophy. There's like these super
in-depth like 200 IQ version where you
try to go super in-depth. And honestly,
like a lot of times the most viral
content is super dumped out where it's
super understandable from like an 80 IQ
perspective. There's two things that can
make a video then go viral, right? The
first one is having compelling
information. Now, I'm very confident
that you guys have this. And this is
like this is why you guys are here. You
guys want to build like you guys have
this reason for why to create content.
You probably want to share your really
compelling stories, insights, and you
know, tips from life, lessons from life.
You have the compelling information,
basically what I'm trying to say. But if
the reason why the If the videos are not
hitting, but you feel like the topics
that you're covering are so compelling,
then it might just be missing this
emotional component. Does the viewer
feel viscerally the emotions behind the
information? So, you might be talking
about AI or you might be talking about
AI in your video or day trading strategy
in your video, but I don't feel that
emotionally. I can see logically how,
you know, [ __ ] Karpathy LLM memory
systems are really helpful to AI, but
like or like maybe you don't even know
what the [ __ ] that means. Good. Like
then you can see how that's like, wow,
that's really interesting, I guess, at
from like a logical perspective, but I
feel nothing when I hear those words
because it's way too high in the sky
technical. Or if you're explaining
something like really in-depth, like,
you know, day trading chart in your day
trading video. It's like, okay, that's
like cool, but all it's like a helpful
strategy, but like at the end of the
day, the videos that go viral in the day
trading niche are like, here's how to
day trade profitably explained as a five
year old can understand. Cuz you can
feel that emotionally. You feel
emotionally this feeling of hope. Holy
[ __ ] maybe I can finally learn how to
become profitable and make money that
hits my core human drive doing it in a
super super simple way. That's where I
can start feeling emotion and emotion is
when we actually buy into a video.
because once again, going back to this
ADIQ concept, people don't get hooked by
videos
when they see some really interesting
logical correlation. Like nobody's
thinking that hard when they watch
reels, right? You guys probably know
this too cuz we all watch reels and
TikToks. The reason why people get
hooked in is because they emotionally
feel like this video is going to give
them some like hit of dopamine, hit of
hope, or maybe they get fear-mongered
into watching the video. Like you ever
see those videos about like, you know,
the news, honestly, on TikTok and
Instagram. The way they hit you is
because they just create so much [ __ ]
fear in the first 5 seconds like the end
of the world's going to end. Yo, World
War III starting? Oh my gosh. And then
they tell you about some like peace
treaty that was like signed or whatever,
you know? Like eventually like the
actual meat of the information is like
some complex like global economical,
whatever, like political [ __ ] But like
they hook you in with World War III,
bombs, death, destruction, you know,
like things that trigger fear first.
Emotion first and then information and
the compelling logic and actual detail
later, okay? At the end of the day, your
goal is to uh provoke emotion with your
hooks and with your storytelling and
with your scripting. This is a
framework. The ideal viewer persona, a
real human being with a specific level
of knowledge, specific core desires, and
specific pain points. And I like to
think of the ideal viewer even as one
specific person. One person, either a
younger version of myself, maybe it's a
person in my life because it makes it so
much easier to write, so much easier to
speak when I know exactly who I'm
talking to. Because we as human beings,
I I think we're our brains are
programmed to be able to communicate to
a single person. So a lot of times when
I was like like rambling about this
presentation right now, I'm thinking of
like, you know, individual people who
are watching this presentation. It's
like how do I make this applicable to
you, for example, you know?
That's why I bring up all these specific
examples like AI, self-improvement
creator, fitness creator, day trading
creator cuz I know a lot of you guys in
here are those specific niches, right?
It makes it so much easier to
communicate with specific examples,
tangible, actionable advice when we're
speaking to one person, not try to make
the advice broadly applicable all at the
same time, all to you know, all a
thousand people are going to be watching
your video, okay? And the clearer that
you're able to identify exactly who this
person is, you know, the more authentic
your content's going to sound. And I
think that's at the precipice of like a
lot of authentic content. Honestly, it's
just being able to speak very clearly to
one person. And I think when content
feels inauthentic, it's like what does
that mean? I think a big source of
inauthenticity in content is when the
content feels like you're just pandering
to multiple people all at the same time.
Like you ever have that feeling where
it's like, man, I don't even know who
this content is for anymore, you know? I
I don't even know if this who this video
is for right now. I'm like trying to
speak to like this person, but I'm also
like not really giving my heart and soul
to really helping this one person, etc.,
right? I think it comes from trying to
imagine two different ideal viewer
personas. Age group, right? Who are you
talking to? Is it under college, high
school, or younger? Is it college age
starting their working life,
right? So i.e. their very early 20s. Is
it just out of college and they're
working for a few years? Is it 30 to 40
or is it 40 plus? And for this plate for
this sake, I simplified 30 to 40 and 40
plus because I have zero context on
those ideal viewers, but I'm sure there
is way more context if you are in that
age demo. So I'm not saying that has
it's like crystallized set in stone, but
generally speaking, I want you guys to
drop in the chat what age like what
general age range Try to be as specific
as possible. If you even just give one
specific age, that's even better, that
your ideal viewer persona is. And if
you're not sure, just like, you know,
give a guess. College age, 19-20. After
30, it's more about kids versus no kids,
to be honest. Yeah, that's a good point,
actually. I I see that distinction a lot
in content. Uh college age, right? 15 to
20, 23. I love that. 20 to 22, awesome.
25 to 40. Andy, if you could be a little
bit more specific then on like what life
situation they're in, perhaps, in the 25
to 40. Like for example, are they having
kids? Are they not having kids? Try to
be a little bit more specific there. 20
to 21. 22, graduating college. Moms, 30
to 45. That's awesome. I I like these
identity labels or like these specific,
I guess, groupings of like are they a
parent or are they in college or are
they just out of college? Because
generally people of that demographic
tend to like average towards very
similar focuses in life. Like college
kids are all looking for like jobs,
internships. They're all like, you know,
you you can summarize their problems
very very similar to each other. 17
years old, 24 to 30. Awesome. 27,
awesome. 27 to 30, people who don't have
a conventional life, not married, no
kids. That's awesome, Aaron. That's
awesome. That's so specific. That's
awesome, right?
One.
Okay, one is great.
Any students? 17, DJ. Musicians with
high potential but low conversion, 20 to
35. Oh, that's fire. That that level of
uh specificity is awesome. I feel like
that's almost like a dispatch
specificity of like having an offer in a
business. So that's awesome, right?
That's perfect. Question two, and this
goes even more specific now. And it kind
of ties back to this whole like life
scenario thing that we just talked about
of like are they in college versus out
of college versus starting to have kids
versus like has kids, no kids. What
dream result does your page deliver?
Don't think about the pain points for
now. Just think about this ideal viewer
persona that you've started to develop
in your mind, what do they want in life?
What What are they What are they looking
for in life? And just like general and
there's like a ton of bullet points,
right? Because in this like Google Doc
of the ideal viewer persona, the
specific dream result can be like super
duper long. For this case, just like try
to put any points of like things that
they would want in life. Life balance,
taking care of yourself again, seeing
it's possible to go for goals with kids.
Awesome. That's awesome. I like that. I
I like specifically go for your goals
with kids cuz I think that's it's like
within these dream results, that's kind
of how you carve out a very unique name
in this space because that's where
you're like, okay, you can become known
for being the person who serves people
with kids specifically, right?
Um a feeling of control over where their
time gets spent without having to
sacrifice the current stage of your
life. Feeling of control over where
their time gets spent without having to
sacrifice the current stage of their
life. So like time management in sense.
I think this is also where you can start
to carve out your niche as well cuz it's
like within the dream result, it's kind
of what, you know, sector of life you're
you're trying to serve. Is it like
productivity advice? Is it like Let's
say it's like parenting advice? Is it
like fitness advice, health advice,
etc.? And maybe it's not even advice,
it's like storytelling or vlogging. But
it's like a lot of times we vlog,
storytelling, etc., there's suddenly
like an outcome that we're helping
people get as well.
Uh balancing having big dreams while
living your life. Awesome. I like that,
too. I like that, too. Overcome the fear
of approaching women and having your
dream relationship. That's fire. I would
highly recommend talking to Prosper as
well cuz I think his I his uh ideal
viewer's uh outcome is very similar as
well. Self-acceptance and creating their
own life path, not based on what others
say or those around them have. We are
all different. Curiosity over judgment.
That's fire. That's fire. And there's so
many like there's like values and
principles that I've seen there, too.
23-year-old who's looking for purpose
because they feel lost. They just left
uni where they were the top, now at the
bottom competing against older adults.
Yo, that's so specific and that's fire.
Those You can literally tell stories
around. To achieve your goals without
making excuses or wasting time. That's
fire, right? And the more specific it's
like I would say a great example is what
Nelson just said. He put a specific age,
23-year-old, looking for purpose so it's
like striving for something. And they
just were in this scenario, they just
left university and they were at the top
but now at the bottom. It's like there's
a whole story embedded in that ideal
viewer. So that's amazing. And this kind
of leads me these this idea of creating
these specific constraints and life
situations for your ideal viewer, at
least to the second or the third
question, which is why do they actually
want it, right? So one level deeper,
let's say for a lot of these answers,
it's like to achieve your goals without
making excuses or wasting time. If you
were to kind of do this weird
psychoanalysis and go one layer deeper,
why do they want to achieve their goals
without making excuses? Why is making
excuses so personally painful to them?
Uh why is wasting time such a bad thing
to them?
Um and it's like you might think that's
obvious, but it's really not. It's like
why is wasting time bad? Why is excuses
bad, right? Then you can go deeper on
maybe some like backstory elements. Like
maybe wasting time feels really feels
really bad because they have ambitions
in their life. Making excuses feels
really bad because they have a history
of making a lot of excuses that led to
them not getting results while they were
in
college as an example, right? But in the
case of let's say if you run a niche
specific page,
uh and I use the the example of AI here,
uh let's say the idea of your page is
just to teach things about AI or teach
AI news. That's fine. And AI news and AI
or tech news, it's interesting and
compelling and it can scratch the itch
of curiosity, but I think the best pages
subtly have a deeper why behind why
people care about the AI news. It's like
a lot of the AI news channels that are
crushing it on YouTube, they have this
subtle backdrop of like making money
with AI. So an example here is like this
guy is absolutely crushing it in the AI
space. He also is running a school
community with like [ __ ] 400k a month
or something. And it's like a lot of the
the undertone around his AI content is
like how to build a business with AI.
And that turns it from just this
interesting, you know, brain-scratching
curiosity-scratching
thing to a holy [ __ ] this guy's
actually practically making a tangible
impact on the outcomes in my life and I
need to come back to his content every
single day because he's actually going
to like herald real tangible change in
my life. That's not because like Nick
Suriya's going to like come out of the
computer and like take control of my
computer, it's because the way he
packages the AI news is talking about
maybe like bringing up things like the
job market, bringing up how useful
things are in terms of getting actual
work done, etc. Right? So, tie it back
to real-world outcomes makes your
niche-specific content hit significantly
harder. And it also helps you build kind
of like this cult-like brand where
people turn to you as an authority
because they actually can tie back your
advice and your content to like
real-world things that they're applying
in their life and not just being like
entertaining or interesting. If being
kind of like an authority in your space
is actually important to you with your
personal brand. Now, let's talk about
practically applying it and we're almost
done and we can cover questions at the
end. So, now let's tie it back into the
hook cuz the hook informs the rest of
the video. And I used a very tangible
example from a a call that I had with a
one of our one of our content academy
members earlier, right? But basically, I
was reviewing Rostislav's video on Open
Claw, right? And I was basically telling
him, Open Claw he made a video about
Open Claw and APIs, which from a
technical perspective is very useful.
But a stranger scrolling is going to
hear the words Open Claw and APIs and
he's going to ask himself
subconsciously, you know, is this really
useful to me? Like and maybe they're
conscious like we're not consciously
thinking these things as a viewer, but
if a video doesn't spike emotion, then
most likely we're scrolling anyways. So,
subconsciously like maybe a video about
AI should answer the question at or at
least allude to being able to answer the
question, how does this help me not
become poor? How does this help me get
more done in my day? So, an easy way to
format an Open Claw video, which is like
an AI tool by the way if you guys aren't
familiar, an easy way to format this
video with a hook that can actually hit
and solve a pain point for the ideal
viewer is let's say that we know the
ideal viewer of this AI channel is an 18
to 24-year-old college student. Let's
say this Let's say I'm a personal brand
that serves college students and I'm
making a video about Open Claw. I can
say, "Holy [ __ ] Open Claw just did my
entire semester's worth of studying in 2
minutes." Another one, "Is it possible
to ace an exam after studying for just 2
minutes using my Open Claw?" I I think
that could actually kind of hit with the
algo right there cuz it hits the dream
result for a student of acing their
classes and spending as little time as
possible on it. So, that's like a dream
outcome for a lot of these like 18 to
24-year-old students and then using AI
as the mechanism. So, it's no longer AI
is this interesting thing that might be
able to, you know, teach you a thing or
two, but it's just like a hobbyist tool
and it turns it into a holy [ __ ] AI
could actually practically be injected
to do your work for you in school. So,
now the reason why they're hooked is not
just because AI is interesting, but
because they're realizing, "Holy [ __ ]
AI might actually solve my problems for
me in my life." And yes, this is
recording. I have it on the loom. If
this isn't recording, I'm going to
actually cry, but I am actually
recording. Now, tactically, the first 10
seconds is probably around how much time
you're given leniency-wise, right? And
that's what I would consider the hook
the first 3 seconds to hit them
with emotion. So, when it comes down to
like being able to hook your viewer, a
lot of times I talk about like, you
know, using hook frameworks. Like I talk
about taking just like picking a hook
from the viral hooks list and just
picking one and copying one. But you
have to understand like the psychology
of why hooks are even helpful. And the
way that you understand that is
understanding that like what makes this
person care? What What makes this person
care?
And before you even know that, it's like
who even are they? So, who is this
person? What do they care about? And
then how do I like insert my idea into
that narrative of what they care about?
And then how do I make them feel that in
the first 10 seconds. And then an easy
way to shortcut that is just like pick a
framework from like one of the many
viral hooks from like a template or find
a viral video on your For You page that
kind of matches that and then take inspo
from whatever hooks they're using. And
try to ask yourself too as you watch
videos, it's like what hooked me? What
specifically got me emotionally invested
in this person's story, right? Was it
Maybe it's their story about like, you
know, them talking about like growing up
with like Indian parrots, right? Like
Indian tiger parrots. And I was like,
"Wow, that resonates with me as an Asian
person." Cuz that like that's one of the
ways that can hit me emotionally cuz
it's like the nostalgia of like being uh
the the son of like immigrant parents,
right?
But this is more so a broad framework
just to keep in the back of your mind
not just as you're writing hooks, but
also as you're consuming content, just
asking yourself, yeah, shout out Rohan.
That's That's a [ __ ] W W catch with
the content. But yeah, ask yourself as
you're scrolling too, like which videos
hit me emotionally personally? And those
are actually great Like that's a great
way to also find out like which videos
should I take inspiration from? Because
the videos that hit me emotionally and
inspire me to be a viewer, like inspire
me to watch till the entire thing, maybe
that can inform me to make my art and my
content and my messaging and scripting
and storytelling hit in a similar way.
So, ask yourself what emotions were
provoked when I watch videos. Cuz a lot
of times we're watching subconsciously,
but it's oftentimes the best way to
understand what is hooking. And another
framework to ask yourself is like, what
emotion is your viewer already feeling?
So, an example is Let Let me go back to
my framework of like the 18 to
24-year-old. I'm just going to say 20 to
simplify it even more. The 20-year-old
college student who is just got just got
off the back of, you know, cold DMing a
[ __ ] ton of people on LinkedIn to try
and do networking calls over Zoom. And
then half of them did not even get back
to him. Half of his job applications for
internships in the summer did not even
get back to him. Well, what are they
feeling right now? Because I was able to
paint this picture of my ICP so clearly,
I can literally imagine what emotion
they're feeling. Well, they're probably
feeling panic and despair right now
because they just got rejected from half
the jobs that they applied to. How do I
make an AI video appeal to those
emotions? Well, then I could probably
say like, "Yeah, AI is probably stealing
all of your jobs right now, which is why
you're not getting accepted by any of
them. So, I made a free AI tool that
helps you scrape 1,000 jobs at the same
time and apply to all of them
simultaneously using and writes like
cover letters in your own unique voice
so you can ride the AI wave rather than
getting replaced." So, it leans into the
narrative of panic that this ICP, this
ideal viewer of a 20-year-old is
probably feeling getting rejected by
jobs, leans into the narrative belief
system that they're already probably
living in, which is like AI sucks and
and it's going to steal my job, and then
it leans into that and creates a video
into that narrative. And that's also a
great way to make like UGC videos as
well, lean into a narrative that people
are already thinking about and then
somehow like make your video solve a
pain point that your viewer is already
living in. Okay. Does that make sense?
Just like drop a yes or like anything in
the chat if that example like somehow
made sense.
Cuz that's essentially the thinking that
I like to think about like ideating my
video ideas. It's like what emotional
place and like what specific situation
is my ideal viewer in? And the the more
specific example of a situation that you
can paint in your ideal viewer, the
better. So, a lot of times too I I
another example. Okay, somebody give me
like their ideal viewer and then try to
paint as specific of a scenario as
possible that they're living in. So, I
painted the picture of a college student
who just got rejected from half the job
applications and is like desperately
trying to connect with people on
LinkedIn and not getting responses and
they're feeling desperate, they're
feeling panicking. Somebody paint like a
similar ideal viewer. Doesn't even have
to be your ideal viewer, just like paint
any picture and then we can try
strategizing like a hook based on that
pain point that they're feeling. And a
lot of the best TikTokers do this
actually. This is like a framework that
I learned from my friend, shout out
@davie on TikTok. You know, he he's in
your college and a lot of his content is
based off this framework of like helping
the people stuck in these very specific
emotional scenarios in college and
creating hooks that really hit hard with
that ICP. Okay, let's do it. Pre-med
student who got rejected from every med
school and is feeling lost after years
of hard work. Maybe then you can make a
Okay, pre-med student who got rejected
from every med school and is feeling
lost. Maybe you can make a video about
an academic comeback. Here's how I
Here's how to have the most insane
academic comeback of your career. And
then you have like footage of you at the
desk like Junia style. You know, you
ever see those videos of like of like
Junia or like Ali Abdaal at his at their
desk like studying with like the monitor
and stuff at night and it gives this
vibe of like it's 3:00 a.m. and they're
going to turn their life around at 3:00
a.m. because they're feeling really sad
about getting rejected and they're like
reflecting on their life doom scrolling
and you hit them then like boom. So,
like that's an example. Academic
comeback is a way to help people who
feel like they're just at like an
all-time low in terms of academics. And
I don't know the exact specifics of like
pre-med like, you know, the exact exams
to take and like the pre-med
you know, like school acceptance
process. So, I think like you could
probably script it better, but I'm just
like giving a general framework for like
what I'm trying to describe here with
it. 23-year-old college kid who's
graduating in 6 months and has no idea
what he wants to do with his life, but
has so much drive and ambition. Okay,
23-year-old college kid who's graduating
in 6 months and has no idea. You can
make one of those hope core videos where
it's like reframing limiting beliefs.
It's like I call I have no idea what I
want to do with my life and it's like
and then it reframes it as this like
hopeful hope core opportunity where it's
like I get to figure out what my life's
passion is. I don't know if you guys
ever seen those kind of videos where
reframes these like panicking beliefs
around like it's kind of like joy being
where it it hits the people who are
who are uh feeling down about a certain
life scenario uh feel really lost. I'm
graduating in 6 months and I have no
idea what to do with my life. I'm
graduating in 6 months and I get to
explore explore life with a with a blank
slate. 21 to 25-year-old try to build
lower this year and overcome one big
challenge that scares me. So here's a
door yo day one of DoorDashing to figure
out my life is fire. Like that kind of
cuz I think that makes people who are in
that scenario feel a lot less alone.
It's like hey, it's okay to start and
like do something that feels probably
low low aura like DoorDashing even if
you got a degree and like start over
from scratch to figure out your life.
It's like a way to hit that ICP and make
them feel related to and safe and it's
like it's like you don't give a [ __ ]
what people think about you and like the
prestige or like getting a a fancy job
title out of college you just went and
started DoorDashing. Like I think that
would be sick cuz it hits the pain point
a lot of a lot of new grad new grads in
college not having a job out of the out
of the uh
out of the gate and then feeling like
they're comparing themselves with all
their classmates who do have jobs at
these prestigious names and then they
just find themselves feeling really down
about themselves. You can like herald
the movement of those people etc. Notice
I'm like really trying to paint a
picture of a psychographic of the uh
like psychographics of this specific
person and like what they're going
through in life. Right? And this and the
timing really does matter too. It's
really important too like this is not
about fear mongering like I know I
described like hit them with their pain
point. Find out what their pain points
are. I like to think about it as once
you understand where somebody's at
mentally even if it's a darker place
filled with like fear and panic your
content can serve to become like an
example for them where you find people
who are in a state of fear panic in a
lower state going through maybe a tense
time in life and then the value that you
can provide your story your journey
documenting your journey can become an
inspiration and help people who are in
that scenario right now. So it's not
just about injecting fear for fear's
sake. You also get to find people who
are at the beginning of a journey
and take them through a journey and
that's what I believe the whole
storytelling kind of content is for. You
get people you hook people with a very
you know who who might be in a very dark
period
and in like a very stressful scenario in
their life and then you explain your
life story perhaps. Maybe you've gone
through that scenario before and you're
help able to you're able to help guide
them through it. Find them where they
are aka understand who your ideal viewer
persona is and understand what life
situation they're on right? Like we said
like the the 20-year-old kid who just
got rejected from every job application
got rejected from every uh networking
request that they had on LinkedIn. Find
them where they are. Hook them with the
words that you know will resonate with
them. Maybe talking about the things
that are top of mind like how AI is
stealing all their jobs and then bring
them closer to the truth. Maybe that's
by your video shaping their belief
system like changing how their their
perspective is on like the job market or
changing how their perspective is on AI
or change or maybe telling your story of
how you were there when you were 20 and
about to graduate college but then you
slowly went through the journey of your
own development yada yada yada and then
you eventually got to the better place
in life and you're like follow along to
learn more lessons from it. You know, so
that's that's the whole thinking behind
like the the 30 lessons before 30
creators who are more like the mentor or
even if you're documenting it public
like maybe you're in the same place as
that 20-year-old kid who's
um like struggling to find internships.
Like maybe you are also a 20-year-old
kid who's struggling to find
internships. Then the the kind of impact
that you can have in your content to
this style of ideal viewer is being like
yo I'm there too but I'm going to
document my life every day until I
figure it the [ __ ] out. So follow along
because I'm going to figure it out and
you're going to figure it out with me.
So that's another like journey follow
along style of content. So I believe too
the ideal viewer helps inform the
positioning of your content because if
you know who your ideal viewer is you
know whether you're going to position
yourself as the mentor reaching out
helping ahead to like a younger less ex-
or maybe less experienced ideal viewer
or you're going to assume the position
of like the friend who's on the same
level as them. They're in the same life
situation
but you're kind of like their
accountability buddy or like you're
you're you're their buddy who's going
through the the life journey together
and you're like document the journey
along with me
and you get to build an audience of that
ideal viewer who's very similar to you.
And that that was like the whole
thinking behind my own content too where
I feel like I built an audience of
people who are literally the same age as
me with my Instagram when I was
documenting my own series doing this
concept called road to $100,000 a month
trying to build a business from scratch
and I attracted a bunch of people who
were also literally my age like in
college trying to figure it out too. Let
me know if that makes sense. Quick quick
recap. We talked about the algorithm
why a watch time is important
and because watch time is important you
need to create perceived value very
early on
and in order to create perceived value
you need to understand
who you're talking to and what they even
want in life.
And then that's how you formulate your
hooks your scripts storytelling series
etc. Make this is helpful. I appreciate
it. I appreciate it. I yeah, let me know
if you guys want to do this lesson. All
right. Thank you guys so much for
watching our lesson on the ideal viewer
persona. If you feel like this was
helpful I highly highly recommend the
rest of my videos on this channel. I
promise they're not just theoretical on
what strategies to employ but actually
have a bunch of guides like this one on
how I literally step by step make my own
viral videos from ideating scripting
filming editing live. So I highly
recommend you check out and watch that
one. I'll catch you guys in the next
one. Peace.