In this video we're interviewing Brad
Shaw, who grew from zero to 800,000
followers in less than 6 months without
positioning himself as some guru cuz he
did it authentically while juggling his
full-time job.
>> afford to propose to my girlfriend, so
today's day one of DoorDashing for a
diamond ring. But let me start from the
beginning. Six months [music] ago I
bought a condo we both fell in love
with. Problem is it made me so house
poor I can't even afford to propose.
We've been together for a year and a
half. The ring she deserves $6,500.
[music]
And I'm starting at zero. So every night
after work I'm DoorDashing because
waiting for the perfect moment is just
fear with a deadline. And she deserves
more than my excuses. So I'm starting
now. Follow to see how long it takes.
>> So I sat down with him today and asked
him his exact story telling framework
that's gotten him anywhere between 10 to
15 million views on his videos. How he
uses AI and specific prompting to
augment his scripting and creative
process to make viral videos. And
lastly, what to do when you blow up
overnight so you can know what to do
once your personal brand blows up
overnight after you apply the advice in
this video. Let's get into the
interview. Thank you guys so much for
tuning in. This is Brad. Now in the past
6 months on his two accounts on TikTok
and Instagram he has grown accumulative
over 800,000
followers. And I remember like like
before you posted these videos
you were like you said that you were you
started off at like 150 followers before
that massive spike before you started
the series.
>> Yeah, yeah. I think I think on like
Instagram I had maybe like 23
or something like maybe 23 or something
something like that. And then on TikTok
I had 110. But I think that was mostly
because I did like that like teamwork
trend where people follow each other.
And so it wasn't like real followers,
you know.
>> Wow. So pretty much from from complete
scratch, like no base. When you posted
that first video, so he Brad started a
series and let me I can actually share
my screen to show you guys called
DoorDashing for a diamond ring. And that
first ever video got I like do you
remember the exact view count, but I
think it was definitely over 10 million.
>> Yeah, I think it's at 15 now.
>> Oh my goodness.
>> million, yeah.
>> 15
million that's mythical. Yeah, actually
15 million views, but not just that. A
million after that. A million after
that. A million after that. 19 million
after that. So, in the first week or
like in that very early time frame, how
quickly did you grow?
>> I think that first video, I think I got
like 70,000
I think. And I think by like day five, I
think it was like close to like 140,
150. So, in that first week I grew from
like zero to zero to like 150k I think.
And then
on TikTok it was even it was even higher
on TikTok. TikTok I think it was like
if I remember correctly.
>> 250k?
>> Yeah, I I don't have the screenshots. My
girlfriend has them.
>> [laughter]
>> But yeah, she's like yeah, it's like it
was kind of crazy cuz you'd refresh and
then the number would just go up every
time you I refreshed it. And it was it
was it was really overwhelming. Um
kind of going that viral.
>> Yeah, that that is nuts. And I would
love to ask more about also like not
just the technical side cuz obviously
like that is unprecedented and I would
love for you to share like your sauce,
but also kind of like on the human side,
like the personal side, like what that's
like cuz it it is and that's not just
like explosive, that's genuinely like
overnight almost probably felt like your
your life changed in that.
>> Oh, 100%. Yeah, yeah. So, I mean like
there were like people that I was watch
that I watched like their content for
like years
who were like commenting or like
following or liking the video. And that
felt like you know, it felt kind of
crazy. It's like, "Yo, I watched you 5
years ago during COVID."
>> [laughter]
>> And now it's like you've seen like my
reel, which is pretty cool. I think it
was overwhelming cuz like I I was going
to be happy if the video just got like
10,000 views. I think prior to that
first video, it was just my highest
views was like 3,900. And so I was like,
"Yeah, I got to I got to break the
five-figure mark. I hope this video does
it." Like I spent like a little bit of
time on the hook, a little bit time
editing. It's the first video I used
sound effects on. And so I was like,
"Oh, maybe that that's what will get me
over the hump." Uh so yeah, there was
like that aspect of like kind of being
in awe of like how how well it did.
Yeah, just how recognized it was.
Another part was pretty over like kind
of overwhelming and like being not being
able to trust others. When all these
people were in your DMs and saying like,
"Oh, like every jeweler under the sun
either sent me an email, sent me a DM
saying, 'We'll do the ring for you for
free. We'll do a shout-out.'" Uh
DoorDash was like DoorDash interviewed
or not interviewed, they they sent an
email. Shipped is another like delivery
service. They wanted to do like 8K for
one video to cover the ring and then
some. And then influencers too were
reaching out. Like there was someone on
like 2 million on like TikTok. And then
Tracks NYC also like DM'd me too saying
that they want to hook me up. Initially,
I was like, "Dang, like I could just do
the do the series and then um kind of
take advantage of one of these like
companies and then just uh you know,
>> [laughter]
>> take the ring from them." But one of my
friends, uh I told him about like the
the influencer wanting to buy it for me.
And he was saying like, "Oh, are you
going to take the ring from this this
person?" Her name was like Katherine
Epps or something like that. And like
when I heard that, I was like, "Oh, I
don't want this ring to be coming from
someone else. Like I want it to come
from me. And I don't want it to be like,
'Oh, that's the ring from DoorDash.' Or
'Oh, that's the ring from Katherine
Epps.' Or 'That's the ring from
Brilliant Earth.' Like I I want it to be
like, 'Oh, that's the ring from from
Brad, you know, that he worked for. And
so, I decided not to take any of the
companies. I didn't take any of the
money, any of the sponsorships, anything
like that. And it didn't feel like Yeah,
and I also just didn't trust them. I
feel like they were trying to like take
advantage of me.
>> [laughter]
>> And so, there's that aspect. And then
the final one that I felt really felt
was like kind of lonely, cuz it's not
like there's like like a channel where
you can look up and join other creators
who went viral, you know, other creators
who've grown like 100k in a week. Like
there's there's no like centralized hub
for that. And so, um all these I didn't
know what the right decision to make
was, and it was just kind of
overwhelming, kind of lonely, and um
that's like the human aspect, I think,
of going a little too viral. How did you
navigate? Because I think you made so
many like intelligent choices. Like
brands trying to take advantage of you,
like you being able to even recognize
that. Like you hear so many examples of
like I I feel like there's so many
classic examples on the internet of
people who blew up for some way like I
don't know, like hot tub girl, you know,
and then they end up watching a [ __ ]
meme coin, and they don't even know what
they're doing. They just got taken
advantage of. Yeah, how did you
navigate? I mean, prior to joining
Content Academy, I had a whole bunch of
I was in a other like content groups.
I'd interview or they'd interview, kind
of like this, and they'd hear from other
creators who like did the brand deals,
went the brand deal route. And a lot of
them said that they regretted it. A lot
of them said that like they ended up
feeling like a billboard. They couldn't
make videos that they wanted to make. Um
they were just show they were they were
they were like advocating for other
companies, and they felt like they
eventually saw the views go down, the
followers go down. And so, I I was under
the impression like like, oh, if you do
brand deals, that's how you you're going
to lose followers. And like, so that's
why I didn't really want to take it. And
hearing them regret that decision,
that's what really prompted me to just
not kind of take all of them, take any
of them. I haven't done any brand deals.
So.
>> Wow, that's that's crazy. But I I think
that's such a W move. It's one of the
classic cliches from people like Gary
Vee or Mosey, but it's like, give, give,
give, give, give. And like the longer
you can kind of pull it back, it's kind
of like a slingshot, where eventually,
when you find, I guess, not just a like
a lucrative opportunity, but also
something that really feels like it
aligns, you, in a sense, earned trust
over so long. I guess the reward is
significantly greater for all of the
goodwill that you built with that
audience.
>> Right. Right.
>> I I want to jump back into that, but I I
want to also talk like
it's something really interesting you
said that you almost were just wanting
like 10K views on the video. Like there
was no like like shot calling like, "Yo,
this one's going to hit like a million
like before." It was just like So it was
not expected whatsoever.
>> None of that. No, no. When I When I
posted I posted it at like 1:50 a.m. for
the Content Games or something like
that. I don't know if the Content Games
started. But yeah, I posted at 1:50 my
time, and like that's that's like 10
minutes before the cut off, and I was
like, "Man, this is the first video."
The reason why I took so long is cuz I
added sound effects. I was like looking
on YouTube like top 20 viral sound
effects, and I was adding them in. It
took a little longer, and I was like,
"Oh, man, all this effort, I hope I get
10K views." Yeah, it was there the
expectation was not there. Prior to
these videos, like I just did bunch of
like talking head and like cat videos.
That like prior to joining Content
Academy, I just posted cat videos. Like
videos of my cat that I thought was kind
of cute, and then I put like some
trending audio, and it would get maybe
maybe 1,500 views.
>> So did you have any goals of like What
What were your goals going in then to
posting this video and starting the
series?
>> Yeah, so for this series in particular,
I wanted to like number one, like keep
myself accountable and actually
DoorDash,
and like get the money for the ring.
That's That's like the the biggest thing
is like And then prior to this video, I
was posting every day for I think close
to like 50 days.
And so I always had like a video to get
audited by Sam or by Prosper or by you
even, because I wanted to keep posting
one a day. Uh I just was like, "Oh, I'll
just do what I'm doing I'm what I'm
doing is going to be DoorDashing. So,
might as well make a video about it and
I'll just post one a day.
Um, and also keep participating in
content games, too. So, a lot of it
wasn't like like, oh, I'm going to build
like a I I think that's like a
almost a misconception that I think a
lot of people have, which is like, you
know, you go in with this mindset of
like, I'm going to become a big
influencer and like maybe there's like
some complex strategy behind it. Like
you were just kind of doing it just to
show up and kind of one day at a time
mindset.
>> Yeah. Yeah, like I mean, my expectation
was like I wouldn't break 10k views
until like I posted 60 videos. I think
you say that in like the the week seven
or the seven-day like week one challenge
is like you got to like lower your
expectation and realize it takes time
and it's like a skill to do. Yeah, I
just wanted to do the reps and get that
in. Just post every day and try and get
that done as as fast as possible and
then
I mean, the I I watched like other like
Tik Tok like Chase, I think. Chase on
Tik Tok. He's another like content how
to create content influencer and he says
like you got to post like 30 times a day
and I was like, I don't know if I can do
30, but I do think you have to post
every day. So, that's that's just kind
of what I did.
>> That's awesome. It's very easy,
obviously, to like post-rationalize, oh,
the video blew up because of XYZ, but in
the moment, like what are things that
you did differently for this series cuz
you were starting, it was like a day one
of a new series idea that you did
differently versus the 50 videos prior?
>> I think I spent a lot of time on the
hook. I think the hook was a lot a lot
different. All the hooks that I was
using prior to these videos prior to
these videos were audience focused. They
were like trying to give value. They was
like, oh, you can't rely on your 9-5
job. Or oh, if you want to sell
something, you you need to be
persuasive. Or it was just like very
like you you you. Or like if you want to
negotiate, you need to figure out what
the other person wants. And like, for
the first time I feel like I made a
video that I wanted to make, where I
started with a hook started with I, cuz
I always thought it had to start with
you. And so, rather than like trying to
give value, I think I was just trying to
show just show off my life, I guess.
Like post about my life. The other thing
that I did, too, is I really made this I
I made it intentional to be under like
45 seconds. So, all the app videos that
are like over a minute long, they don't
do well cuz people just scroll.
>> [laughter]
>> People scroll, and your in then your
like percent watched is like single
digits. Whereas if it's like a 30-second
video, then it's twice as higher, or
it's like twice as much, and there's a
fighting chance that it might get pushed
more. That's why those 7-second videos
with trendy audio in the background,
that's why they do so well, is because
people will keep watching them over and
over and have it on loop while they read
a caption. And so, I I think those were
the two main things is I made it not
about I made it something other than
like business and like work and not
trying to give value, and then I also
made it under 45 seconds to try and
improve like the the percent watch time.
>> I know this is like a very specific
question, but if you were to go back
like all the way back then, how did you
exactly think through like I can't
afford to propose to my girlfriend to
today's day one of Door Dashing for
diamond ring? In my mind, when I see
that I'm like, that's a brilliant hook.
How like how did you think of that in
that moment? And what was the thought
process?
>> You're right. Let me Let me pull up my I
I actually did it with AI.
I came up with that, but or I I
finalized the wording for that hook, but
in terms of the inspiration, it was
through AI. And I was using Claude. I
wasn't using the hooker the the hook
bot. Not going to lie, I thought
Like I feel like it's good for like UGC
videos, but I don't think it would kind
of work for what I was going for in this
video. I think I asked it like, I'm
going to start a new series where I
DoorDash for my girlfriend's engagement
ring. What are some like hook ideas? And
it was as it was like rather than
jumping into the ideas like oh why are
you doing it? And I was like oh well I'm
broke, I'm house poor and I can't like
buy I can't buy it cuz it's like 6,500
bucks and I don't have that. And then it
suggested like
I can't buy my or like it's like I can't
buy my girlfriend's engagement ring or
something like that. I was like oh like
the series title I feel like I want it
to be catchy and DoorDash for a diamond
ring. They're both like both kind of
start with D.
And so I thought that kind of be catchy
and then oh it said no no no the it
suggested I'm so house poor I can't
afford to buy my or I can't buy my
engagement ring or something like that.
I was like that's way too long. Let me
just shorten it to just I can't afford
most my girlfriend. And so I think I
went through like seven iterations with
Claude
before we finally settled on that one.
And then the script that it gave me
the way that I kind of framed it is I I
had this one philosophy line. Like I
made the one line stand out. That was
like the main idea of the video. And the
main idea of that first video was the
she deserves more than my excuses.
I think. Those were like the two things
that I had. I had the hook which is like
oh I'm broke and I can't afford to buy
my girlfriend a diamond ring. And then
the main idea of the video is like you
know she I need to do something about
it. She did she doesn't deserve for me
to wait. I can't remember the exact line
that I said.
But if you go through every single video
there's people in my comments quoting
that exact line. And that's like the
goal that I had is like after every
single video I want people to quote that
main idea line.
And that's what I made the video about.
>> Interesting. Where did the line come up?
Was it like towards the end?
>> Yeah yeah. Because waiting for the
perfect moment is just fear with a
deadline.
>> Oh.
>> And so that was the main idea of the
video and that's the one exactly that
people are quoting. And so that's that's
the formula I followed for every single
video after that. And the formula that I
still follow to to this day.
>> Just to reiterate the formula is kind of
like what is the one line that you want
people to remember, quote from the
video.
>> Yeah.
>> I see. Uh, so was it the same across
like the rest of videos cuz then it's
like day two, day three, day four, day
five or did you come up with a new like
core line for each of these?
>> Yeah, a new core line for each video.
>> How did you go about coming up with this
core line? Cuz it's like there's a lot
of core lines then cuz there's so many
like you cuz you posted so consistently.
>> I think for the first like 20 videos, 20
20 25-ish videos it was easy cuz I feel
like it's just like oh like like what's
like a reason why I love my girlfriend?
After that I started to use AI a lot
more and I'd ask AI like what do you
kind of recommend or like what are some
like things that women want men to know
and men to want women to know and I kind
of use that and then just added like a
story
um about how like my relationship is
kind of like that too.
And so that's that's kind of where my
content is going now is like it's more
like oh how do I how do I kind of like
address like an elephant in the room in
someone's relationship and just kind of
like put my take on it or like what what
I would say to that certain situation.
>> I see. So let's let's say like on a
random day uh this is this is gold bio.
This is sauce, yo. Let's say on a random
day what is like step one of making
uh your video? Like I'm guessing it's
the idea. What is step one that you do?
>> Yeah, step one is definitely coming up
with like that core line um trying to
tweak that with Claude.
And so it'll be like
Let's say let's say like day 53 is like
oh she is the table or something like
that. That's that's the line that I want
people to quote.
Um I think day 27
was the
day 27 was another viral one. I think
that one was where my girlfriend was
sick and I was like oh I want people I
want like to share our morning waking up
together in the morning. Like I want
that to be like that's what I want and
that's why I'm That's why I'm
DoorDashing. And so, yeah, I I put that
through a couple iterations trying to
get it as close as possible with Claude.
And then after that, I would come up
with a couple story ideas that are
relevant, like personal examples. Like
if it's a video of about like money or
something like that. There's like a
couple key moments in our relationship
where we've talked about money, and like
what was like the the scenario behind
it. And I'd try and remember like key
details about that, right? About like
oh, like maybe
why does she view
Oh, okay. Like one example is like me
gambling. Growing up, I was a huge
degenerate gambler. My friend put me on
uh in in the state that I'm in, you can
gamble when you're 18. And so, on my way
to Before I started Before I went to
college, my friend took me to the casino
and I lost 40 bucks playing blackjack.
And I was like, "Shit, I got to I got to
make it back." And so, I got addicted to
gambling, basically. And but my
girlfriend, she's like she's very
anti-gambling because like kind of like
her family has been affected by that.
And so, that's like an example where
like I kind of take into the go a little
bit more into the details about like my
story about like oh, this is like what
someone in like a relationship what
someone with like a gambling um
addiction kind of feels like. This is
why how she reacted when like, you know,
kind of kind of got kind of made her
upset. And then this is what I did to
change to make our relationship right
again and for our relationship to be
healthy healthy. And then I'd feed all
that information to Claude. I'd ask it
to give it a script. I read it over. I
go through line by line, ask it to
change it.
Um change certain details or like add
certain details that are missing. And
then it kind of give me one last final
script. And then this is where I think
is like pretty important is I'd ask
Claude to read through that script again
and say, "As act like you're a third
grader, where are you confused?" Or like
what does this all make sense? And then
it'll give like points in the script
where it was confused or where wording
is a little bit confusing. And it gives
you suggestions. I'll usually just
ignore the suggestions and kind of come
up with my own one. Yeah, and then just
put it back through one more time, and
then yeah, and then it'll give you the
script, and then I'll add filler words
in between. Um I'll add like and, but,
because, so, cuz Claude just doesn't put
those in. And if you were to read it
without those like filler words, it
sounds AI. And like people hate hate
hate AI scripts now. And so, it's
important to like, you know, still make
it human. That's generally how it goes,
I think.
>> This is awesome. I I would genuinely
would not have guessed that you like AI
script. Like I would have thought like,
oh, like you're in there like I'm like
typing it like fully from scratch, but I
I think this is brilliant. It's like I
really like what you say about like
specifically how you're prompting it,
and then like what you're ignoring, cuz
I think that's what a lot of people also
like there that's like the nuance with
AI where it's it's either like I use AI,
I don't use AI. In reality, you need to
know when to not use it, and when to use
it.
>> Yeah. Right.
>> Wow, awesome. You Okay, this is like
super specific, but if you could
actually share like a prompt, if you
could like share like a conversation you
had with Claude, I think that could be
like insanely insightful.
>> Yeah, maybe maybe I'll put it in the
sauce later. Um like I feel like I don't
want to I don't want to ruin the audio
or anything like that. Yeah, yeah, I'll
put it in sauce later.
>> That's awesome. And you specifically use
Claude.
>> Yeah.
>> That is fire. Okay, dang dang, that's
that's sick. And so, it's like core
idea, pick a story, brain dump it, ask
it to first draft a script, revise it,
and then ask it again ask like your
third grader, where you confused?
>> Yeah. Yep.
>> Wow. Okay, so this is like scripting.
Then what's next after you you have the
finished script, you're like, okay, this
is revised, it's ready to go. What does
your like filming process after that
look like?
>> Yeah, so I'll DoorDash.
I'll go DoorDash for like two and and
half, three hours or something like
that. Make pennies, and then I'll uh
find like a decently lit parking lot.
Try and find a lamp post that
has the light showing my face instead of
behind. That way I don't show up dark.
Yeah, I'll just I'll record I used to
record on my iPhone 15, my 15 Pro Max.
And then
now my my
and now future in-laws, they gifted me a
DJI, so I record with that now. But
yeah, I'll record. I'll
go line by line. So, I'll memorize the
line, then I'll say it. And then another
thing that I do is like for and for the
lines that I want to emphasize, I'll go
closer to the camera. And so, my face
will show up more, and I'll kind of like
do that influencer edit, where I'll
start off start out like farther from
the camera, and then I don't know. This
is more more of my recent videos.
>> This one?
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah. So, this will have the
hooks. Coach Sam came up with this, so
he knows what he's talking about.
>> Let's go. Oh, so.
>> Yeah, and then
I'll add some B-roll just to keep it
engaging.
And then later on, I kind of go closer
to the camera when I want to make an
emphasis.
>> Oh, I see it now. It's you're closer,
and then I think you backed up.
>> Yeah.
Just to try and keep it engaging, and so
that there's like some movement on the
screen. And then I'll yeah, I just
follow the editing that you you say in
the the week one, where you want to
break it up two to three words at a
time. I'll add B-roll or a sound effect
every three to four seconds, and then
try to keep it engaging that way. Choose
one of the trending audios from the
Content Academy playlist that Gabe put
together. And yeah, I mean, just use
B-roll from like, you know, my
relationship, or of the ring, or oh, I
guess I'll have recently I've started to
like record specific B-roll, so I'll
like record, you know, my phone screen
like in that one, or me being upset, or
me at work, or something like that. So.
>> I love the sound effects every 3
seconds, too. That's a These are all
like so subtle. But I I really want to
highlight this, actually. It's like I I
like to think of it as like you do like
the fundamentals really well. Like
there's no VFX, like something insane.
There's no like crazy like I don't I
know some people do like Higgs field AI
like transitions and whatnot. It's just
like it's I think it's like the
fundamentals, like auto captions,
b-roll, sound, and it's just done really
really well. And I think it's like it
feels simultaneously engaging, but
simple. Like when I watch this, it's
never confusing, it's never
overwhelming, the visuals or the sound
effects. It's like it's a good middle,
where it's like the b-roll lasts on
screen, but it's not there for too long.
>> Yeah.
>> Even these small jumps, it's super
subtle. Wow. Hey, that's awesome. How
long does this take? Like do these
videos usually take? This whole process
now.
>> Oh, this whole process? I mean, it'll
take it'll take like an entire day.
>> [laughter]
>> When I was first starting out, it took
me
I would I would be scripting while
DoorDashing or at work or doing all this
AI stuff. Um so, that probably took like
probably like 2 3 hours. And then I do
the actual DoorDashing. So, I DoorDash
from like
6:00 to like 8:30 or something. Get
dinner with my girlfriend at 9:00. We'd
eat we'd watch like a couple episodes of
a TV show. Yeah, yeah, that's not
optimal. I could be scripting. Yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah, but I'd go record at
like 10:00. Uh I suck at memorizing, so
recording takes me a long time. And so,
I'd finish recording at like 10:30 or
11:00.
Um and then I would edit until like 1:00
a.m. It'd be It'd take like 2 hours,
basically, to edit, I think. And then
I'd post, go to bed at like 2:00, and
then repeat the cycle. Um like I'd get
up I'd get up at like 6:00 for work, and
then um
yeah, I did that, basically.
>> Wow, and you're doing this every day?
Like, you're on daily post pretty much
right
>> I did. I mean, I'm not on daily anymore.
Like, I I I got sick around like day 40
or something like that. Left the content
games. I was super upset about that.
Yeah, I had to take like a 2-week break.
And now I've been posting pretty pretty
inconsistently. I got to get back on the
daily daily posting again. But yeah,
after that video, I got sick.
>> But you're you're feeling better now?
>> Yeah, yeah. Yep, so.
>> Wow, that's dedication. So, it's
basically like you're waking up at 2:00
a.m. every day and like you're still
working a job from like 9:00 to 5:00 as
well on top of the DoorDashing, on top
of the videos.
>> Yeah.
>> Wow. Are are there any points where you
felt like you're going to burn out?
>> Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah, so many times. So
many times.
>> [laughter]
>> And like, honestly, I probably would
have quit my job if it wasn't for my
girlfriend. Like, she she's like the
degen gambler me is like, oh, I got to
go all in on my content creation. And
then my girlfriend's like, well, you
have a house. How are you going to pay
for that? And I'm like, [ __ ] you're
right. I don't know.
>> [laughter]
>> And so, that's why I'm still kind of
working my job and waiting for the
social media income to replace it for a
little bit. But yeah, I mean, every time
I feel like I get burned out, uh I feel
like I kind of have to remember like why
I did it. It's like, oh, it's it's for
my girlfriend. Yeah, usually that just
kind of keeps me going. That and then
I'll watch like Love Is like I'll watch
like TV like dating TV for like
inspiration on like a video topic or
some something like that.
>> What shows?
>> Uh right now, I'm watching Temptation
Island.
>> [laughter]
>> On Netflix. Uh I used to be watching
Love Is Blind or like Singles' Inferno.
Um so, those were
those were uh some good inspiration.
>> Interesting. So, you're watching like
reality dating shows for inspo.
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> Wow, that's sauce, too. I think that's
actually hella underrated cuz the fact
that you can think of new ideas on daily
posting, like and it's like a new right?
It's like it's like a new, I guess, core
idea. The ability to even do that, it's
like that's hella tough.
>> Yeah, yeah. I mean I think the what the
Sam Coach Sam, he told me like when he
was auditing my my my page when I first
started out and he was watching my
videos,
he'd say like these topics are not
interesting.
And like like it's it's a kind of like
hard to watch. Like I'm and like truth
be told like I myself probably wouldn't
have watched my own videos back in the
day.
And like I think you have to do and like
people's attention spans are kind of
shot now and like they've kind of all
seen the same things and like value like
middle of funnel content I think is kind
of played out and I think you need to do
something interesting, document doing
something interesting first before you
can start doing middle of funnel
content. I think that's kind of the meta
now is that you have to do something
interesting or have some kind of
compelling story or
um do something do something interesting
while having a compelling story and like
share that in like a 30-second
30 to 45-second clip and then after that
I think you can establish some authority
or people actually kind of want to watch
you or want to hear more and that's when
you can start to like inject uh some
middle of funnel value content.
>> I I want to actually I'm very curious
here. How do you integrate both the
DoorDashing and the story cuz it's like
it it is a lot to kind of fit into one
video. You're simultaneously going out
and doing the whole thing like for
multiple hours a day and you have a
whole story that's about your
relationship. How are you intertwining
both into the video?
>> Yeah, so I never want to be I like 10
years down the line I do not want to be
known as the DoorDashing guy.
And so I've actually started phasing out
a lot of like the DoorDashing clips
because I don't want people to associate
that with my face.
Uh right now I feel like the next step
for me is like to be kind of like the
relationship guy. Um relationship
boyfriend guy and so I've like stopped
trying to include I've included DoorDash
less and less and less. So, the
DoorDashing is less of a side. Um I
think the main focus is just on why I
want to get my girlfriend the ring or
what is the what what's like a story
with my girlfriend and I
that people could relate to. And then at
the end, I'll just kind of tag in like
I'll throw in like a and this is why I'm
DoorDashing for a $6,500 ring. And then
I'll just give the update.
>> Yeah, I'm noticing most of the footage
is like outside of DoorDashing. It's
like like I'm guessing you you probably
went out like maybe your girlfriend
helped you or something like film
separate from the film like a shot like
this.
>> For only for this video. I did it didn't
do well, and I was like, "I'm never
doing this again. It's not worth the
effort."
>> Yeah, that's so real.
>> Yeah, I'm like, "Nah. Nah, this takes
too much time."
>> Yeah,
it really be sometimes like the more
effort just does not pay off, bro. So,
yeah, I I noticed it here. It's like
like this video I'm pretty sure or like
a lot of these videos don't actually
visually show DoorDashing. Like a lot of
it's I'm guessing like either B-roll
from the past or yeah, like just you in
the parking lot. So, I I think that's
cool. Like you you kind of get the best
of both worlds. Like you don't have to
let's say like be probably I I'm
guessing it's probably really difficult
to try and be filming DoorDashing while
you're DoorDashing all the time.
>> That's true, too. Yeah, like especially
cuz it's after work and it's at night
and it's dark. And some of these houses
don't have like
the welcoming light. And so, you it's
literally just a black it's just black,
and it's just unusable footage that
people would scroll on. So, I've also
just stopped stopped recording it.
>> This is something I noticed, too, is
that I think you you said early on that
you kind of phased out you language in
the hook. But I'm noticing that in the
middle of the video, it's still kind of
like you still tie back to value. Like
have a story, but it's not just a story.
You subtly tie in what you learned and
like a lesson to somebody who's going
through something similar. Like what
someone in a gambling addiction feels
like and then kind of thinking about how
to help them in that situation. Like
very empathetic and like still thinking
about how to I guess provide value, just
not shoving it down their throat. Like
using a story, using something that
you're doing in your life as like a kind
of a reason for them to pay attention
and care.
>> Yeah, exactly. Exactly. Like I feel like
whenever I get advice, right? If someone
leads with a dude, you should stop
gambling. Like I would not listen I
would have not listened to him. But if
someone's like, "Yo, this is like how
gambling affected my life." I'd be like,
"Oh, shoot. Well, I don't want to turn
out like you." Or something like that.
Or like, "Oh, like I want to kind of
like learn from their story. And I think
that's what's really important is like
having leading with the story before you
get to like the lesson. Cuz I think
that's a lot more relatable.
>> That's awesome. And
>> [clears throat]
>> I think a lot of people This is what I
hate about hearing like storytelling or
like it value videos, right? These are
like these two camps of content gurus
online. But in reality, they they kind
of need each other. You need a story to
give for somebody to care enough to
listen to your advice. But you also need
some form of like value or advice to
make the story feel like it kind of uh I
I guess hits home with the person. So
it's like your your core idea, I think a
lot of it seems to revolve around like a
message that you want to leave people
with. But you don't just have a message
in isolation cuz then it feels like
preaching. You also have a story to back
up why they should listen to you and why
this is coming from experience.
>> Exactly. Exactly. Yep.
>> That's awesome. That That That's a
That's a fire framework. Like lead with
story, lead with proof, and then by the
end subtly subtly weave in a takeaway.
Not even just like Like I never feel
like you're preaching in your videos at
all. I never feel like you're telling me
like
>> That's good. Yeah. Yeah. Um and I mean I
I honestly have so much to thank to my
girlfriend for that. Cuz she'll watch my
videos or like she'll read the script um
and then she'll be like, "You sound You
sound like too much of a guru." Or like,
"I You sound You sound slimy." And so
I'll take that feedback and I'll be
like, "Okay, what parts make me sound
like a guru or what parts make me sound
slimy?" And I'll just cut those out and
then add something new. So.
>> That's powerful.
Uh
cuz it's so easy. I struggle with this,
too. It's like it's so easy to to just
end up sounding like a guru. Yeah. And
like it's it's hell repulsive. And from
a consumer's perspective, I [ __ ] hate
when people are like, "Here's the best
method that you like scroll."
>> Exactly. Exactly. So I think it's really
important to have
I mean, avoiding saying you. I think
that's pretty important. I think having
another like person to bounce ideas off
of or having another person to
who says or like to read over your
scripts to make sure that they check for
that.
And honestly, you could probably run it
through a Claude and being be like,
"Make
like set its personality or prompt it to
be like, 'I hate being sold to. If
there's any mention if I even get a
inkling of being sold to, this is a bad
script' or something like that." And you
could probably prompt it that way to
respond like that. Yeah, but that's a
that's an untested idea. I've never done
that, but that's something you could
probably try and do.
>> I mean, I like to act like you're a
third grader. I think it's kind of
correlated with giving advice. Like
third graders also
never like being told what to do. So if
you tell somebody what to do, it's kind
of bulletproof to act like you're a
third grader.
>> Yep. Yeah.
>> Wow. I think that's beautiful how like
at the end of the day, like your
audience is old, right? A lot of these
people are in relationships. They're
probably mid-20s. And yet you're
thinking about how to make it appeal to
third graders. Kind of it's it's so
telling. Like
>> Yeah, yeah. I mean, there was a I don't
know if Einstein said it or there's a
quote that I always heard growing up and
it was like, "Oh, if you can't explain
it You can't explain to an idea an idea
to a fifth grader, then you don't know
it well enough. That's how That's always
something that I've tried to do, no
matter whether I'm at work or like even
in college and stuff, too.
>> I I have a more personal question.
Um how do you balance having your
content about your relationship, which
I'm sure like, you know, there's things
that it's not just the content doesn't
just impact you, but it impacts your
girlfriend and how she's perceived
online and how she feels about the
content. Like how do you balance being
essentially very public and open about
your relationship without letting it
like kind of impact you guys?
>> Yeah, yeah, that's that's a really good
question. And so, my girlfriend, one of
the things that she'll say jokingly is
like like God put me in her life to
challenge her because she hates the
spotlight. Like she hates she's like 97%
introverted. She hates attention. Like
she hates that people like people know.
She hates it when people just like look
at her. And so, one of the things that
we did
um and that we can like been trying to
communicate is like oh like set like
boundaries on like what topics we're
never going to talk about. All right,
these are topics that we're not going to
talk about. And then when it comes to
like B-roll, like all the B-roll that I
use is like is now like approved by her
for like use. It's like okay like this
is a video that's okay for me for you to
use. Or I'll just ask her to like send
me B-roll, too, that she's like
comfortable with being shown. And she
knows that like you know, hundreds of
people will probably see this. Um
and so, uh yeah, I just I just I just
communicate
um over communicate. I think just Yeah,
she's just an amazing amazing girlfriend
and an amazing person. And so, she's
really patient with me and lets me lets
me be crazy and post content like this.
>> It's it's inspiring how also like
collaborative it sounds like it is, like
>> Yeah.
>> Like this is something I I personally
have struggled with, which is like it's
so easy for for to get into this mode of
like oh it's just about like the way I
create content is just a very solo
exercise. Like I'm not really thinking
too hard about like it sounds I guess
like you communicate so much about like
not just what you like boundaries, but
also like she's involved in helping you
make the videos better.
>> Yeah.
>> So yeah, she's
>> She's in every step of the way and even
if like the idea even the ideas too,
she'll help me come up with like some
ideas or some stories too. And if I like
like if I'm like she'll always ask me
every day like oh, what's the script?
What's the script? Number one to like
read it and like kind of kind of keep me
accountable. All right, yeah, to read it
and then also like give input, but
number two to keep me accountable. Cuz
she's she actually thought I paid like
$5,000 for Content Academy. And I just I
just paid it in full. Um instead of like
I think it was like a thousand or like
the the 500 or something like that. And
so she was like, yo, if you're going to
drop $5,000 on this instead of like
instead of like, you know, saving it,
like you better you better be posting.
And so um yeah, she just she she runs
I'm the face, but like honestly like it
wouldn't be anywhere near as successful
it was if it wasn't for her.
>> Wow, that that's awesome.
I I I see a a dope question here.
Um Prosper asked like, what are the
topics that you can't talk about? Like
what are the boundaries that you guys
have set together?
>> Sure, sure. Yeah, so like intimate like
details, specific details about like her
family, like sex like sex life or like
intimacy like that's also a no-no. I
think I think those are the main two.
And then everything else is kind of Oh,
and then also like
I don't want to I don't want to paint
her in a negative light. Like that's the
other thing too. That's the the big
thing. And like any kind of problems or
issues that we've had um I have wanted
to be about myself. Like like the the
problems or issues that I had in my
relationship and learning, you know, cuz
I mean technically she's she's my
longest
longest long-term relationship. And so I
feel like I still have a lot of like
growing and stuff to do. Any kind of
issues or problems that we have like uh
it's always from my perspective or my
problems that I have.
>> Have there ever been points where you
like it's like you posted something and
then
she felt like, hey, like, I didn't
appreciate how that like portrayed me or
like were were there ever moments where
that there was like conflict there or
>> yeah, like certain bureau that I use,
she's like, oh, like, you know, I don't
I don't like how that that bureau how I
look in that bureau that like clip. And
so, I won't include that anymore. Or
even she'll even say like, oh, like,
you've used that too much, find
something else.
>> [laughter]
>> She'll be like, yo, this you've used
this clip way too much. Stop stop lot
relying on it. Go go do some go find
another one. But yeah, I mean, when
those situations happen, it's like,
yeah, she I'm glad that she feels like
safe and comfortable enough to tell me
that she doesn't like that or she
doesn't appreciate that. But in terms of
like the overall video message,
there's certain videos she's more of a
fan of or less of a fan of, but she
always watches the full video before I
post it. And so, anything that she
doesn't like gets changed.
>> Wow. So, cuz this is at like you said
you're posting at sometimes like 2:00
a.m. So, like, is she up to with you
like after
>> Yeah, she's a she's a night owl. So,
it's a little she's more comfortable, I
think, than I am. Like, by the time it
hits like 2:00 a.m., I'm ready to fall
asleep. But she'll she'll like doom
scroll a little bit, too. I like she'll
be playing
Pikopia. I got her the Switch, too. So,
she's been playing Pikopia a lot.
>> That that's fire. Damn, that that's
hella like W W relationship that cuz
that's how you have
>> Mhm.
>> That's awesome. Yeah, I'd love to open
up the the questions for for the chat as
well, but I'll I'll start with this
question from Sean. Are there times
where you feel like the audience didn't
notice that like  one-line
emphasis?
Like, how do you make sure that it
stands out that line stands out to the
audience?
>> Yeah, I mean, And happened a couple
times.
And I think when it gets missed, I think
it just wasn't impactful enough. I got
either like build it up more. And so
I'll take that as like feedback as like
oh like I got to maybe make the story a
little bit more. Like I got to build up
the story a little bit for that
one-liner to be impactful. Or like
sometimes I just have too many of them.
Like Claude will throw in like two or
three of them. And I'm like oh okay next
time I got to remove some of these ones
that I feel like stand out a little too
much. So it all builds to that one um
main line that I want people to to
recognize.
>> I I feel like from my observation too
you emphasize it like the way you speak
it out loud too is like maybe slightly
slower.
>> Yeah yeah slower and then I'll I'll
always try and be closer to the camera.
Like I'll make that the close shot.
There's like a close middle far.
So I'll usually start with like a
farther away farther away shot. As I'm
building I'll try and get to the like
the middle. And then if I really want to
emphasize it I'll
I'll do a close-up. And then I used to
do like like another like kind of riser
or like a boom like a cinematic boom
sound effect. But to be honest I've just
been so lazy. I just don't add it
anymore. I just just do the close-up.
>> That's fire. I yeah I I think too like
the riser and then if you can time your
music's like beat drop moment
music shifts.
>> Yep that's the other one too you can do.
>> That's fire. Cuz I I feel like it is
actually quite quite noticeable for your
videos. And I think it's like a
combination of all these small things.
Next question from Ray. How do you make
sure that the videos don't get too
repetitive?
>> I mean I think it's just changing up the
one-liner. Like it could be about the
same topic but the one-liner could be
different. And so like I'm pretty sure I
use like the the same idea of like our
my cat's cat's vet bill.
In one video I'll spin it into like me
not wanting to go into debt. Another
another video I'll spin it into like me
that's the reason why that's like my
previous experience Door Dashing. And so
it's like just like slight changes that
you can make. Like the less Like I feel
like any experience you have in life,
you could probably take away like five
different lessons from it. And that's
like five different videos that you can
do. And then the other thing, too, is
just like
audience fatigue is real. Like people
don't remember the same video or the
same topic a lot of the times.
And so, you might do it 1 month, and you
could probably run it again another
month. And like you don't have to be
worried that your followers aren't going
to recognize it, cuz a lot of the times
your followers don't even see the video.
And then new viewers are new viewers
who've never heard the story. And so, I
don't think that's something that you
should be worried about.
>> That's That's gold sauce right there. I
I feel like because it's so easy as the
creator, cuz you see all your videos.
You're not just watching it for your 30,
40 seconds. You're working on it for 4
hours. So, the time literally feels
like, "Man, like this is so burned in my
memory from last month. How could other
people forget?" But for them, it could
have been like 10 seconds on their feed.
Randomly between scrolls, like
>> Might not have even watched the full
video or gotten to the point where you
even bring up the story, too. It's like
there's so many things that So many ways
people can not see the video.
>> Yeah.
>> So, here's a Here's another question
from Rich. Some say that you shouldn't
be using I or me a lot because you're
making it feel less relatable to the
viewer and making it like too much about
yourself. Um and that you should use
like you more, so the viewer sees
themself through your content. How do
you distinguish when to use I and when
to use you in your scripts?
>> I'm like As a cop out, I'll say it
depends.
Uh but I think in general, like starting
with I or me can be helpful when you're
like trying to show something off kind
of wholesome. You You kind of have to be
on like the two extremes, right? There's
like an Andrew Tate, where he went super
viral being like, "I am him. Like I am
that guy. Like I am like, you know,
saying some like auto pocket stuff." And
he went viral um that way.
There's like Like Roy Lee is also like
he's been going viral, too, being like,
"Oh, like I um I did this or like I me
and like those are like very like
ego-driven. But then there's also like
my side or the opposite side where I'll
be like, oh, this is my relationship and
this is like super wholesome. So, I feel
like you got to kind of got to gauge
where it is on the spectrum of like how
polarizing it is. And I think the more
polarizing it is, the more you can use I
or me. And I think I think with yeah, I
think that's that's when you should use
I or me is when you have to show off
something cool. And then for you,
you can use you I think when it's not
directly obvious that you're like trying
to sell them something or like trying
like give a lesson. I think like there
has to be like some build-up for you to
eventually use you or for you to
eventually earn the right for it to talk
to a viewer and you have to build that
trust, I think.
>> That's fire. Yeah, like the first video
that you mentioned, right? You said the
takeaway line was, she deserves more
than my excuses. The takeaway line was
still a me sentence rather than
you deserve she deserves more than your
excuses. That subtle difference could
make you feel more like, man, why is
this guy telling me what to do, bro?
Like [ __ ] you, bro.
>> Exactly, yeah.
And I think I think the other thing too
is like the the relatability factor.
Like I I I try to like I imagine myself
like, man, if I would if I looked like
if I looked like Prosper, would the
series have done as well?
Honestly, I don't think so.
>> [laughter]
>> Like if I was as if I was like if I
looked better, like I don't think the
series would have done well.
>> [laughter]
>> Like I was I was I was reflecting on
that and I'm like, man, like part of
like part of like the unnatural
advantage that I have
is that like I have a baby face and I
kind of just look like look like not
threatening and I look more like cuter
like wholesome or like younger.
And like but if I looked like if I
looked like too attractive or if I
looked conventionally attractive, then
I'd be like, yo, this guy is like kind
kind
kind of full of himself, you know?
>> [laughter]
>> And so, I feel like you kind of have to
like, kind of have to be real with
yourself and like, kind of kind of see
where you fall.
>> I think that I think is actually the
difficult thing about storytelling is
that you have to know what strengths
that you can lean into, which requires
you to really ask yourself like how are
you being perceived? Cuz like, one
person can play a personality online
like the arrogant guy and it can work
for their like Roy's a good example of
like he plays more into like the Andrew
Tate persona of like like yeah, like
hate me. Make sure you hate me like
really trying to rage bait that in cuz
it's it's so easy to just be like, oh
just tell your story. But the reality is
that like a lot of people tell their
story online and they don't get
attention for it. And it's like, what is
the small differences here that can make
one video that's telling your story hit
like 15 million, but then like another
person whose script feels very similar
or like they're doing all the same
tricks like the same editing style, but
it only gets 1,500 views. I think it's
like knowing exactly
what strengths that you can lean into
and like knowing how somebody would
react to your story. Like would they
react with like a oh, this person's an
underdog? Would they react with being
rage baited and disliking you? Like even
knowing that really weird perception, I
think. Cuz you played into that so well
of like I I feel like you do play the
underdog. Yeah, it it's like relatable.
I think a lot of the times when you use
stories, it feels very vulnerable. Like
I can't do this or I struggled with this
and I think that's also just like a
really subtle way where you can talk
about yourself, but it doesn't feel, I
guess, boring and it doesn't feel
random. It feels like it still provides
value to hear your story because I think
also like your ability to cover topics
that most people probably would be too
scared to say. Like I can't afford to
propose is such a vulnerable thing that
I think probably hits so many people.
Like, yeah, that's like
>> Yeah.
>> That's low-key me, but I would never say
that.
>> Mhm.
Yeah, I know. That's a good point, too.
I think uh yeah, some some other like uh
content coach uh she said the same thing
of like, "Oh, this is like extreme
vulnerability hook." And then like
that's that's why it did so well, too.
>> The extreme This is an extreme
vulnerability hook.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> That's fire. Um I I don't want to take
up too much of your time. I think this
is a great place to finish off here.
>> Okay.
>> How are you monetizing or how do you
plan to monetize and what are your plans
for the future with your content after
you get the ring?
>> Yeah, yeah. So, I think
uh for monetizing, there's like kind of
two main ways,
three main ways that I think I
eventually want to go about. Uh first
one is eventually doing a brand deal.
And so, I do want to do a brand deal
with either like, you know, DoorDash,
Uber Eats, one of those. I mean, I
haven't signed anything. I'll just say
it. Like, I hate DoorDash. Like,
DoorDash sucks. Like,
like I want to Yeah, like the the video
that I do, like I'm like I also signed
with a talent management agency. Uh so,
they could kind of cuz a lot of these
brands don't take me seriously. Yeah, I
want to do like a Uber I want to partner
with Uber Eats, do like a pretty big
brand deal there. And then the video for
that is going to be like uh I broke up.
And then it's going to be like, "Not
with my girlfriend, but with DoorDash."
Uh
yeah, and yeah. And so, that's
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah. That's what I was
trying to pitch to them.
So, yeah, brand deals. And then
obviously, uh there's like The Knot that
fits pretty well into like, "Oh, what's
next after a proposal?" It's a wedding.
Wedding planning. I'll probably do a
series about that and try and partner
with The Knot. I think those are the
main two that I had. So, I would kind of
want to be like some kind of partner or
get like a pretty Hope my talent agency
negotiates a pretty fat deal. And then
the second way is I'm thinking of doing
kind of like relationship coaching cuz
I've gotten a few quite a few people
asking for advice. And so, now that's
kind of where my content is doing for at
least for this chapter is like more
storytelling, giving advice, um and
eventually
uh kind of launch that when I after I
propose. And then, the third way is also
doing YouTube. I think YouTube is
probably YouTube or some kind of live
streaming. I think that's like the
future, you know?
And so,
um
>> go subscribe to his YouTube right now.
>> Um yeah, so some kind of long-form
video, I think uh that way you can gain
more trust and actually have like like
true fans of like kind of what you're
doing.
Like I don't want to be pigeonholed into
always having to be like the
storytelling guy. Like I would like
people to be invested in like me doing a
me doing like dates with my girlfriend
or me doing like me talking about like,
you know, my finances or something like
that or just have like different kind of
like offshoots.
And so, um YouTube and I think long-form
is probably the best way to get the
trust of the audience. So, those are
like the three ways. It's like brand
deals, coaching, and then eventually
YouTube, and continuously like uh
having that flexibility to either launch
physical product, keep doing coaching,
double down on that, or or just like
like just be like a streamer. Be like
Jason the Ween or something like that.
So.
>> That's fire. Are Are there any creators
that you look up to the way they built
their brand? You kind of use them as
like a like oh, I wanted to do what like
Steps Lee did.
>> I mean I mean your brand for one. Like I
watched you during COVID
>> [laughter]
>> when you were doing the entertainment um
all the entertaining uh content. I think
it's Ryan Trahan.
Um that's another one that I've been
watching a lot. I'm trying to
um see if I could do something like him.
And then, Prosper when it comes to like
relationship coaching, I've been
watching him a lot. Oh, Ali Abdaal's
another one, too. Ali Abdaal. He's the
lifestyle business.
I've been watching his YouTube a lot.
>> That's fire. I I think like using
long-form creators cuz one like most
long-form creators have been in the game
for significantly longer than any
short-form creators, but also like
they're usually the ones that have like
taken it to the next level in terms of
not just virality, but also depth. Their
audience like connection. So, I think
it's great that you bring up like Ryan
Trahan, Ali Abdaal cuz I think they've
built such such deep audiences, too.
Yeah, and and also buy their products.
>> Yeah, and I think Logan Paul's a little
too controversial for me. Like I feel
like I I don't think I could say some of
the stuff that he says or do some of the
stuff that he does. And I mean, I don't
even look like him, too. So.
>> No, but I I think Ryan Trahan's a great
example. I saw a video of him recently
talking about it. It was actually about
his like Christian testimony, but he's
physically said like there was a time
when he used to do controversial content
and it got a lot of views cuz he would
do like controversial not like hit
pieces, but one of those like commentary
channels like kind of roasting other
creators. And then he said the pivot was
difficult because it was like he got all
these views through kind of being like a
roast creator and he wanted to he felt
called to do more like family-friendly
stuff. As a result, long-term it paid
off like super duper well and he found a
way to to make it work to get way more
views with still like a very wholesome
brand. So.
>> Yeah, yeah.
For sure. Yeah, I mean, that's that's
that's what I'm hoping to do. So.
>> That's awesome. Okay. Thank you guys so
much for for tuning in as well and
asking your questions. And dude,
everyone please drop drop a huge W to
Brad in the in the chat for for dropping
this much sauce, taking time out of his
day as well. You have a hell of a busy
schedule. You still have the Door
Dashing and obviously the the videos to
make. So, thank you so much for for
coming on right literally right after
work.
>> Yeah, yeah. And like if there's any
other questions like I still I still
lurk in like the the Discord here and
there. And
you want to like DM me on Instagram, I
can probably try and answer, too.
Or we could like hop on a call. I don't
know. We'll see what my schedule what my
girlfriend will allow for my schedule.
>> Yo, one more round of W's in the chat.
>> Dude, bro, thank you so much.
>> Also, for anybody who's watching, cuz
I'm going to I'm going to put this on
YouTube. I'm going to leave Brad's
channel linked in the description. Go
sub up. He's about to drop some drop
some banger content on YouTube as well
very soon.
>> Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
>> And yeah, I mean, like personally Brad,
like, you know, if there's any other
questions that come up like with
anything, you know, you feel free to let
me know.
>> I appreciate this so much.
>> Yeah, of course. No, thanks for
letting me join and like no, it's super
cool to super cool to get back.
>> Awesome. Now, before we end this video,
I do want to make it very clear if you
are serious about growing your personal
brand, Brad's results are an anomaly. He
has been the biggest case study, the
best like literally he speed ran 100k
followers in a week. And I don't want
you to go into content creation
expecting this. I want you to set
realistic expectations. Because one of
the hardest things when you're starting
your personal brand is not necessarily
just the strategy and the scripting, but
it's staying accountable and it's making
sure that you feel supported in this
journey that's largely alone. Where most
people in your life, like your friends,
your family, my parents, don't
understand. So, that's why I built
Content Academy. The same exact
community actually that Brad went
through, attended all the coaching calls
in, got his videos individually coached
and given feedback on. I literally
remember reviewing his day one video of
his series that got 10 million views and
giving it advice on how to actually go
about the rest of the series, cuz I
remember I saw so much potential. But
don't take it from me. Take it from Brad
himself actually, who made this very
heartwarming video about his experience
in Content Academy.
>> Hey, my name's Bradley or Brad J Chow on
YouTube, Instagram, and TikTok. I just
want to talk a little bit about my
experience working with Mino and joining
the Content Academy. So, prior to
joining the Content Academy, I had
uploaded maybe eight videos. They They
all like cat videos or videos about my
cat. I think I had like 100 followers on
TikTok, maybe 20 on Instagram, and then
like five subscribers on YouTube. And so
really I think my biggest problem is I
didn't know how to record good video
content or good footage to use in my
videos. I didn't know how to edit the
video and structure and even just how to
script out a video and just put together
a video that people want to watch. I
didn't know how to film, edit, script. I
didn't even know how to do any of that.
So I started as a complete beginner. So
I joined Content Academy in September of
2025. And after joining the Content
Academy, the coaches and some of the
friends and the community really helped
me stay accountable. And so in three
months, in December of 2025, I had my
first viral video. I went from 170
followers on TikTok, maybe 23 followers
on Instagram, five on YouTube, to now
400 over 450k on TikTok, over like 400k,
I think I'm at 414k on Instagram, and
then 40k on YouTube. And so all of this
is thanks to the help of the coaches
inside Content Academy. They do a really
good job of coming up with helping you
come up with good ideas or things that
are going on in your life, how to make
it so that the hook grabs attention, and
that the content itself is actually
something that is interesting and makes
people want to watch it. And so they'll
give a lot of direct feedback,
especially on your videos. And also the
community itself is really helpful in
making some friend making friends who
are also creating content and also
keeping you accountable. And so
everyone, all the coaches, everyone in
the community really helped me figure
out what to post and then package it not
only to go viral, but also convert the
views into followers as well. If you're
thinking about joining the Content
Academy, I wouldn't hesitate. It was
well worth the investment as well. If
you have any questions, I loved my time
working in Content Academy. Feel free to
give me a DM. And yeah, hope you have a
good one. So if you're interested, I'm
going to leave the first link in the
description to join our paid community
Content Academy. If you're serious about
growing your personal brand, I'll see
you inside. Peace.