The hook is the first 3 seconds of your
video, and it's the make or break moment
whether your video gets 300 views or it
gets a million. And I have studied
hundreds of hooks because I've literally
posted over 2,000 videos growing these
four accounts. And today I want to walk
you guys through the four levels of
viral hooks all the way from 300 view
jail trash hooks all the way to 1
million plus view hooks that also
attract your true fans. So let's jump
into it. First off, if you are stuck in
300 view jail, it's because your hook is
absolutely trash and you're probably
doing one of two things. You're either
asking ChatGPT or AI to write your hooks
for you, and it just sounds like the
most bland, robotic, non-value additive
stuff ever. Or you're trying to be too
original to the point where you're just
being your authentic true self, but what
ends up happening in reality is that
your videos are just boring in the first
5 seconds. They convey no value. They
convey no potential demand. Most
importantly, they're not shocking or
novel in any way. At this If you're at
this point, you probably just don't even
understand hooks, and that's fine. So
here are the common mistakes I see, and
this is coming from a person who's
literally studied now thousands of hooks
because my community Content Academy
literally has over 900 members, okay?
And these are all the people that I've
helped get to over 10K followers. You
lack keywords. You have no particular
niche that you're targeting. You have no
clarity on who your viewer is, so it
just feels like it's meandering and
pandering. You start off way too slow.
You literally just talk You're not
talking fast enough. Your lighting is
bad. You don't even have a front-facing
light in front of you that's making your
face contrasted from the background. You
don't have any captions or text on the
screen, so there's nothing for your
viewer to be captivated by in the first
3 seconds where they're making a
subconscious judgment about you and
whether you are worth their time. Your
audio quality is awful, or it's way too
quiet, or your music is way too loud,
and your audio just of your voice is
just not there.
Okay, I'm done roasting you guys. Let's
move on to chapter two, where you start
to become a beginner. It's like when
Minecraft when you're just dropped onto
the board and you start to learn how
viral hooks works by copying. In order
to make hooks like Beethoven, you must
first walk. So, let's walk first and
let's crawl by learning how to copy
videos bar for bar. So, first thing you
have to understand is what niche and
format you are targeting. Niches can be
any of these things. They're subtopics
that exist and if you have no [ __ ]
clue what your niche is or you've been
sci-op'd by this idea that you can just
become the niche and talk about whatever
the [ __ ] you want, literally go onto
YouTube, go to your homepage, and just
see what you enjoy. You're probably
actually going to see like two or three
niches that you like. For example, for
me, productivity, creative potential,
right? Studying, business, content
creation. Wow, big whoop. Of course, my
40-page and my homepage literally looks
like that. So, if you're not sure, just
do that. Secondly, the format. Now, in
order to understand what formats even
exist, you probably should scroll TikTok
or Instagram just a little bit so you
understand what formats exist, but
there's generally three styles of
content that exist. There's three
purposes that content can serve and you
kind of have to know which one you're
targeting. Are you trying to educate
people? Are you trying to teach them and
get them to an outcome? Are you trying
to inspire them and show people or maybe
tell your story in order to inspire them
to take action in order to get an
outcome? Or are you just purely trying
to entertain people, make them laugh,
give them a dopamine hit, right? I used
to make comedy content on this account
with uh 800,000 followers. However, now
I make more inspirational or educational
content on this account with vlogs and
talking head educational stuff on how to
grow with content creation. So, you have
to understand which one of these are you
choosing and you kind of just have to
choose one. Then, task number two is to
go onto your For You page, go onto
Instagram or TikTok, and identify three
of your favorite creators who match the
niche and the style of content, whether
it's educational, inspirational, or
entertainment, that you're trying to go
for. And list out those three and then
literally just go to their page. So, I'm
in the education and inspiration niche
just like this creator, Shelby Sapp. So,
what am I going to do? I'm literally
going to go through her page and look
for educational or more inspirational
type of videos and just copy her hook
bar for bar, word for word, write it
down on a Google Doc. So, let's say this
hook right here, six sales objections in
60 seconds. I'm not going to play the
audio for you guys, but it's literally
just six sales objections in 60 seconds.
So, what am I going to do? I'm literally
going to go into my doc and I'm just
going to write down six sales objections
in 60 seconds. Now, if I was an actual
gooner, I would probably just straight
up steal this hook. But at the very
least, I know what my niche is and my
niche is in content creation and content
creation advice. So, what am I going to
do? I'm going to replace the keywords in
this that are niche specific to sales
for Shelby Sapp and I'm I'm just going
to change it to something that's
relevant like six viral hooks in 60
seconds. That video itself probably
would do very well. And I'm going to
copy as well the visual format, right?
And you could even take a screenshot
here. I actually recommend it just to
really make this as easy as possible and
kind of just break down all of these
specific things that she's doing, right?
So, she's filming in the car. So, I'm
going to probably go in my car, right?
Next one, six sales objections in 60
seconds. What am I going to do? I'm
going to put text above my head with the
classic TikTok font with the little
white text with the black border around
it and I'm just going to make six viral
hooks in 60 seconds, right? And let's
see the actual words that she's saying
at the beginning of this video. So, she
says, "F it, I'm going to roll six sales
objections in the next 60 seconds,
right? F it, I'm going to roll six sales
objections in the next 60 seconds." Now,
I know you're probably thinking, "Oh,
Mino, it can't be that easy." or "Oh,
Meno, I'm not going to copy people. I'm
going to be original." Yeah, okay, go
for it. All I know is that after
coaching hundreds of people, in order
for them to get their first viral video
that even breaks past, let's say, 10K
views, it's almost always been by
studying what works and then taking
about 80% of what another creator did
and just changing the words to apply to
your story or your niche. So, in this
case, I'm taking somebody in a
tangential niche, right? Cuz sales and
content creation, they're both in this
similar space of making money online and
business, right? And I'm just changing
one word in the hook, or two words,
actually, right? And that's all I'm
doing. And then for the rest of the
video, I'm just going to see how she
structured it. It's a listical-style
video, right? What does that mean? I'm
probably just going to make a list of
six viral hooks, like, is it possible to
blah blah blah, like, six blank in 60
seconds, right? And I can just make this
video script up now, right? But that's
literally the style of video that I want
to go for, but I'm not going to try and
reinvent the wheel, cuz imagine if I
just started to throw in random words,
trying to be overly original, like most
of you guys might be wanting to do. I
might just throw in a bunch of sentences
here. [ __ ] it, I'm going to roll six
viral hooks in the next 60 seconds. But
instead of going straight into the value
of point number one, imagine if I just
started riffing about like, "Guys, so
I'm in the car right now. I'm drinking
my Red Bull, right? And today, I'm so
excited to share these six six
viral hooks, because I've been posting
for a while, and these ones really made
me start to pop." You'd probably watch
and be like, "Bro, GET TO POINT NUMBER
ONE." RIGHT? And it's the same thing
that's probably happening. You don't
realize it because you don't have an
intuitive sense yet of the first
principles of what ga- gathers and
garners attention on social media. So,
you just need to copy other people
who've already gone viral. Steal their
secret sauce. Steal the structure of the
video. Steal their pacing. Steal the ga-
You you mean the cadence of their voice.
Right? If you haven't found your creator
voice yet, because that takes a ton of
time and practice, just see who you
really like and resonate with online,
and just make videos like that. The
people who inspire you. You don't want
to reinvent the wheel because honestly,
that just creates more room for chaos
and entropy where you're probably going
to mess up because you don't know what
you're doing yet, and that's completely
fine. That's my entire strategy for
YouTube. I'll be honest cuz I only have
28K subscribers right now. I am not
going to try and reinvent the reinvent
the wheel. I'm literally just going to
do the same hook and then listicle style
of format where I'm not going to riff
off about my own personal story in the
first 30 seconds, and I'm going to make
sure that the in the first 30 seconds of
my YouTube video, I am getting into
point number one, which is trash. I
literally did that, and I copied that
structure from my favorite YouTubers,
Alex and Mozie, Iman Gadzhi, etc.,
right? So, that's what I want you to do
as a beginner, right? And that's how to
even get your first 5K views, but even
copying, twisting this can get you all
the way to your first 10K views. So,
let's talk about it. How do you go from
this copy and paste where you're always
needing to in a sense be given a fish by
the algorithm in order to eat? Cuz
eventually, you want to be authentic.
Eventually, you want to express yourself
in your most authentic way where you're
being honest to yourself. You're not
confined by these rules of other people.
Well, I call it these oiken twists, and
this is where not only are we going to
start to add a little bit more of a
twist of our own style of content, our
own voice. In order to do that, you
still need to understand content and
hooks from first principles. So, this is
where I want you to start thinking
through and developing a first
principles understanding once you've
already learned, however, to copy and
get your first 10K views. Because
getting your first 10K views, being
stuck in that sub 1K view jail on short
form platforms like TikTok or Instagram,
it's freaking grueling, bro. And I don't
want you to be stuck there because
you're going in circles trying to
reinvent the wheel, trying to reject
everything that you're seeing on the For
You page because I don't like the way
they make their content. I don't like
that video. I'm never going to copy
anybody else because I want to be
original. I want to be a special
snowflake who goes viral just by dancing
on camera, being myself. Yeah, I'm
sorry. The way that the algorithm works
and pushes your video out is Instagram
and TikTok, they sample your video to
the first 300, 500 views, how many
viewers you're stuck at. And if it
doesn't get sufficient watch time, if
your video gets scrolled off in the
first 3 seconds, aka skip rate too many
times, or it just doesn't get enough
likes or comments from these base test
sample group of people, your video's not
going to get pushed out anymore. So, you
need to understand then the core
psychology of what drives generally most
people's behavior on social media. And
after making hundreds and hundreds of
videos and hundreds and hundreds of
hooks, flopping hundreds of times, and
going viral my fair share of over 100
plus videos over a million views, I have
three core principles that I want you to
understand here. The first one is
demand, the second one's value per
second, and the third one is social
proof. So, the first one, demand. I kind
of touch upon this here in this concept
of copying because in order to
understand what demand exists out there
on social media, the best way to
honestly understand this is just by
doing research, market research, aka
scrolling on your For You page,
scrolling on the explore page, and
seeing which videos get over 5K likes or
over 100K views. That's my barometer for
a video that I believe has done well. I
recommend you just take that as the key
performance indicator of whether a video
is good enough for you to copy. 5K plus
likes on your For You page. I do not
want you to be copying. I'm sorry. I'm
sorry. I don't want you to be copying
videos that are sitting at 400, 500
views. Even if it's too early on to know
if that video's going to eventually go
viral, it's just not the best data. You
want to just be using proven data. Like,
look how many likes this video has, 100K
likes. Clearly, this video hit with
these strangers who are sampled the
video, and they giga engaged. That's
what you want, right? You want to see
and study and build a mental model of
how to think like that, not think like
the 500 view, 1,000 view creator. And
the best way to gauge that is by
studying what already gets demand on
social media, aka researching. I'm going
to give you guys one more method of
research here for short form. This is
actually a kind of OP way that I do
research. I like to go and study what's
working on other platforms because I
believe TikTok and Instagram generally
trail Twitter and YouTube in terms of
the trending topic. So let's say a
concept trends on Twitter or on YouTube,
you'll probably see it trending about a
week to a month later on TikTok and
Instagram. So the best way to get good
signal is just study what works on
YouTube. That's what I do. I look
literally look up my niche or keywords
within my niche like content creation,
personal branding, and then look for the
videos that are outliers. So this is one
of the platforms, oneof10.com. I'm not
sponsored whatsoever, and I just look at
the videos that have gotten at least
1.3x more views than the creator's
average views for their channel. Then I
look at videos published in the last 6
months, and then I look at anything
above 45k views cuz I don't want to be
studying outliers from a channel that
averages 200 views and got 1,000 views.
Oh yeah, no, that's not really an
outlier. ammo. How to make millions from
content. Content masterclass. Yo, I'm
sorry. I hate to break it to you. I
studied 1,000 hooks, here's how to
actually go viral. I just studied that
because I wouldn't even trust my own
intuitive mental model what works on
YouTube right now. I would say I'm still
in step stage two and three of YouTube.
Put down your pride a little bit and see
what has demand already on social media
and just literally rip the hooks. Rip
either bar for bar the hooks or rip
whatever sentence structure they use. So
you could easily just take the sentence
structure. This clearly this structure
conveys a lot of value. I studied blank,
here's how to actually outcome. So you
can apply that to for example, I studied
1,000 fitness creators, here's how to
actually build muscle. That's guys,
that's another example. I studied 1,000
papers, here's how to actually build
muscle. Here's how to actually lose
weight. Here's how to actually body
recomp. That's a fitness niche example
cuz your boy watches a ton of fitness.
Okay, damn, that did not look as
impressive as I thought it would. Okay,
we might need to cut that editor. Stop,
sir. No, I said I'm
>> Well, STOP SAYING IT. NEXT, WHAT IS
VALUE per second? What does this mean?
There's two components to this. The
first one is how much value per second
you convey in your first 3 seconds. AKA,
how much value that you're alluding or
hinting that your video is going to get
into. So, for example, the six sales
objections in 60 seconds. One lower
value per second version of this hook
could easily be three sales objections
in 60 seconds, right? Isn't as high, so
I'm watching that my dopamine is
probably not spiking as much with the
excitement of getting to learn, right?
Or maybe it's two, that's even worse.
Another one is six sales objections
without the in 60 seconds. Why is that
worse? Well, because there's two things
we're gauging for when we stop when we
scroll social media, right? As viewers,
as consumers, and these are the two
things that people are going to gauge
your video subconsciously on when they
stumble across it on the For You page.
Is this going to be valuable, and how
much time is this going to take me? So,
the longer that your video is, the less
likely that somebody's actually going to
want to watch it, and the more value you
have to give. So, if I'm making a
10-minute video, I best hope that it's
going to convey a ton of value. I've
created this gap between what I know and
what you know as a viewer, and I've made
that gap feel as large as possible, so
it's justifiable for you to invest 10
minutes of your time, right? But in
short form, even 60 seconds is actually
a very long video. And the second
component of value per second is how
much value you're actually able to give
within the first 3 to 10 seconds of your
video. So, I'm going to extend this part
to the first 10 seconds of your video
because it's realistically hard to like
give somebody a novel nugget of
information in the first three. You want
to get to the point as soon as you
possibly can. There's a lot of It's very
easy for us to leave in fluff about our
personal story. Why am I making this
video? What am I trying to convey to the
viewer by teaching you about hooks in
this video? And I make a very
intentional choice in all of my viral
videos to try and get to the first piece
of valuable information within the first
5 to 10 seconds. If I'm making a
storytelling or challenge video, is it
possible to ace an exam after studying
for just 1 hour? It's a challenge video.
Well, actually finish the studying
process within the first 15 seconds of
that video that got 12 million views on
TikTok. AKA, what I'm trying to convey
with this is just move your video and
progress it as quickly as possible. Be
more vigilant towards the fluff, towards
the dead space, any 1 to 2 second parts
that you're not speaking the video,
that's where you have to go in and edit
it out. Any sentences that you don't
think are relevant to the main point and
the main value that your hook is
alluding to. So, in the example of is it
possible to ace my exam after studying
for just 1 hour? There are moments where
I talk about how much energy drink I
consumed, how I'm feeling about the
energy drink. I talked literally about
this one sentence where I rambled about
how I got onto the news on Business
Insider for overdosing on caffeine, but
I actually cut it out in my edit because
I knew, "Okay, this has nothing to do
with the midterm. It's kind of
interesting, but it ultimately has
nothing to do with the studying." So,
understand what is the point of your
video. Why is somebody going to watch
past the first 3 seconds? There's
clearly a core reason, and it comes back
to what are you teaching them if you're
educating, what outcome are they trying
to get, and what outcome are they
wanting if you're trying to inspire
people, or where the main beats, the
jokes, the interesting, shocking moments
in an entertaining video. For example,
if I'm a streamer and I'm clipping my
streams, I'm probably going to try and
make sure every 3 seconds there's
something shocking going on. I'm doing
some crazy facial expression. There's
some crazy fan interaction, public
interaction going on, and I'm cutting
out all the bits where I'm just walking.
Last one is social proof, and this
specifically applies to educational and
inspirational videos. Why? Because
educational and inspirational videos are
helping somebody get to an outcome by
watching your video. If somebody's going
to get to an outcome by watching your
video, the clear question is are you
qualified to help them get to the
outcomes? If you notice, I just hard
injected, like I was not subtle about
this [ __ ] I just hard injected social
proof. I've gotten these results, okay?
It's a little corny, but at the end of
the day, you probably would not be
watching if I had never grown a single
account before. So, you probably have
some experience, and even if you're
younger, right? Because I know a lot of
my audience here, you guys are probably
like in college. Maybe some people are
even in high school, and you feel like
you've done nothing of merit in your
life. Two things I want to say. First
off is that you are always an expert to
somebody else. When I was 19 years old,
I took a gap year to try and learn this
online business thing. I used to make
productivity content despite being a
19-year-old who had not even hit like a
$5,000 a month online before talking
about some productivity. I had never
even gotten straight A's in school, so
why did I feel qualified enough to make
productivity how-to videos that got me
100k followers in 1 month on TikTok? I
talked not to the other smart kids, I
talked to my former self from 3 years
ago in high school when I had hideous
addictions to gooning, to video games,
to staying up until 3:00 a.m. writing
down goals that I never executed on. I
spoke to that version of my former self,
and because I was so clear on who I was
helping, I knew that I was qualified
enough to talk to them. So, the way I
developed this social proof, right? Of
why should I listen to you, I would
always start off the videos in the
second sentence by saying, "I know
you're probably thinking." And that's a
subtle way for me to communicate that I
understand what the viewer is thinking.
And when you can make the viewer feel
heard and understood, it's a form of
proof of why they should listen to you.
So, another form of social proof is
actually relatability. Sometimes people
don't go viral for saying, "I made a
million dollars in 3 years," or "I got
these big muscles. Here's how to listen
to me." Honestly, those are kind of
corny and probably won't get as many
views as you telling a storytelling hook
of like 3 years ago I was in the most
hideous hinge addiction of my life
swiping for 5 hours every day just to
get a hint of emotional validation.
That's actually a proper hook. Now, in
no way did I convey that I am some
dating expert in that hook. But, what I
did convey is that I understand deeply
somebody else's pain points. So, there's
probably somebody else out there who
watched that video being like, "Damn, I
just literally just got off a a Hinge
session, and then I low-key gooned a
little bit, and then now my dopamine is
like giga below baseline, and now I need
to scroll some reels to up my dopamine
levels." Yo, if that was you, leave a
like on this video, okay? Damn, that's
Yo, if that's you, oh man, damn, you're
cooked. No, I'm just playing. I'm just
playing. I'm just playing. I literally
go on such ADHD tangents sometimes. Make
your viewer feel heard. There are
multiple reasons why somebody else will
watch you, and there's for sure at least
one person out there that would value
your advice, value your story, value
your take. And you have to understand
this, not just believe it, understand
it, because even if you're an
18-year-old, there's probably a
16-year-old who wants to learn the
lessons you've learned of turning 18.
That's why a lot of these day in the
life of a 25-year-old, day in the life
of a college student studying for
medical school, day in the life of a
dental student. These do well because
there's somebody in college who wants to
learn what medical school is like, or
there's somebody in high school who
wants to learn what college is like.
Always remember that. And even though it
might be cringe to your fellow college
students being like, "Yo, why is Mino
making productivity advice even though
he's a [ __ ] loser gooner?" Well, it's
because I knew there was a deeper loser
gooner version of myself back in high
school who needed to hear what I had to
say. ISN'T THAT FAR? Kind of leans in my
final point of how to actually develop
confidence in yourself as a creator to
the point where you actually can just be
magnetic as a personality. And that's
what I believe is a special trait that
helps people ascend to a higher level of
creator where they can just be magnetic
on camera, where you have an audience of
true fans, where you're somebody's
favorite creator, their comfort creator.
How do we do that? Well, once we've
understood these core principles of,
okay, copy a winning framework that I
see on the For You page, then I think
deeply about who is this video serving?
What is the point of somebody watching
this video? What are they wanting to get
out of that? And how do I make sure that
I'm cutting out every part that's not
related to this goal of the video? And
then lastly, how do I make it so people
want to listen to me for this video and
make sure that the viewer feels like I
am actually worth listening to for this
topic, whether it's making them feel
heard or related to or establishing your
authority early on in the video. Then,
how do you ascend from that to just
becoming magnetic, attracting true fans,
right? And I call this the S-curve, the
giga hook. And now I'm going to
genuinely just get a little bit [ __ ]
esoteric because if you're watching here
and you're trying to consistently hit a
million plus views, at this point you
probably understand all of these
retention hacking mechanisms, right? If
you watch my channel, it's because
you're probably low-key autistically
obsessed with these little
micro-optimizations of your content. And
as somebody who's literally been posting
for the past six years on short-form,
there's a point where
micro-optimizations and trying to think
overly tactically and logically about
your content will actually fall flat.
And I actually think it's right around
this like 100k view range where you can
you can't just gimmick with the Subway
Surfers on your screen, you know? You
can't just gimmick with the hooky hook
or taking somebody else's winning hook.
It's like, at a certain point it's
People are now making subconscious
judgments on how much charisma you have,
how much energy you have, whether your
tonality is actually good and authentic,
and whether your text hook hits them in
a certain way that makes them feel super
heard and uniquely heard, and whether
your content feels like you're being
present, whether you show empathy, and
you make somebody be like, "Damn, I feel
really understood and I feel like this
creator is very unique." How do you get
to that point? And I'm actually at the
point where I still consciously think
about this because I don't think I'm
there yet. I say this because I study
and I've talked to much of creators who
have millions of followers, who have
super fans. One of my friends, let me
actually shout him out here cuz I'm a
gigachad blazer, okay? This guy's name
is Justin Han and he just literally
makes talking head videos. Often times,
he's just like yapping to the camera or
he's just making a funny odd video,
okay? I find this guy giga talented and
his personal brand feels really unique.
Holy glit- Bro, I'm literally bouncing
on it. Bro, I I know one of my one of
our friends probably watching this be
like, "Yo, holy bouncing on it." But,
I've literally gone to the mall with him
in California. Bro, I [ __ ] you not. This
dude got approached by like 35 people
wanting to take pictures with him. That
level of influence and dare I say it,
aura, I don't think you build just by
being the type of person who's always
copying and scraping for the next hook,
okay? That's essential. You need to
understand the psychology of why
somebody else will watch you. But, how
do you get to the point where you
genuinely just feel like you show up
with energy and charisma and confidence
as a creator? Where you genuinely just
feel like, "Yeah, like people like me
for me." And that's what we all want at
the end of the day, right? Yes, we want
a business that can run and thrive off
of our content. We want a way to
monetize so we can do this full-time cuz
we like creating stuff. But, how do we
get to the point where it's just, "Yo, I
feel like our con- like my content just
exudes uniqueness." And I'd like you to
understand this concept of energy when
you show up with your content. Because
for the longest time, I felt like the
next winning hook and people watching my
content was always a skill that was
outside of myself. What I mean by that
was that that's the reason why I
developed all these cope tactics like
copying viral video bar for bar,
studying someone else's content, trying
to think from all of these logical first
principle reasons why somebody will
watch me rather than just showing up as
myself. Because I was subconsciously
afraid of being seen for myself and I
was honestly freaking scared that people
just would not want to actually watch
me. Like I need to edit fraud. I need to
text hook fraud. I need to, you know,
script fraud. I can never just show up
and yap and be the type of person that
people want to listen to, all right? A
lot of people call this imposter
syndrome, but I actually think there is
a skill to showing up with a level of
energy and presence and flow. And this
is coming from somebody who studied true
influencers, true creators. And a lot of
them that I talked to who genuinely rip
consistent milli plus view hooks every
single time, and they don't feel like
they even follow some sort of concrete
structure. They usually say that their
creative process with content is super
intuitive. Like, yeah, I just make it
when I feel like making it. I don't have
some planned strategy or some like
content pillars that I follow. And it's
fair. You you might think like, damn,
bro, these [ __ ] are lucky. And
maybe they are, but maybe they also have
some inherent deep faith that they're
worth listening to to the point where
their energy exudes on camera. Like,
think about the people that you kind of
walk into a room, and you might only
know like one or two kids who are like
this where you're just like, damn. You
walk into a room, and they're magnetic.
They effortlessly pull attention.
They're not loud and in your face being
like, "Yo, listen to me, guys. Listen,
listen." Like, it's confidence, right?
And I like to study the creators who I
feel genuinely inspire me. I genuinely
look up to. Not the type of business
creators whose entire content is
scripted by their content team, whose
team uses some amalgamation of market
research and Claude, and you can kind of
hear the the Claude in their voice where
they're like, "That's not this. It's
this." And honestly, you're real for
that. Like, you know the [ __ ]
[ __ ] you hear like nowadays actually
incredibly often on these like
documentary channels on YouTube who
clearly use AI, okay? I'm not naming
names, but there's a ton of them. And
there's a ton of business creators who
do this, too, and it's obnoxious as
[ __ ] But these true creatives that I
know is that they don't strategize. They
actually just show up on camera, and
they're able to with their raw skill of
being an entertaining and attractive
personality just garner attention. And I
genuinely have autistically studied them
because I'm like, yeah, I gotten to the
point where I feel like I can logically
break down and rip apart a script in the
most anal way. Yo, keep a pause. Where
I'm just like, I'm literally going
literally meticulously changing each
word, tweaking it to the point where
each word has its like keyword value,
etc., etc., etc. But it's lame, okay?
And at a certain point, some people plop
down a camera. I've seen kids like
Like when I first met this dude Justin,
he literally plopped down a camera,
right, and just started speaking to the
camera. No script, no prep. May- maybe
he thought of it a little bit in his
head. And boom, I saw that video get 5
million views. I saw that and I was
like, what am I doing with my life? What
am I doing studying market researching,
bro? I'm a loser. This is pathetic.
Okay, but in a really inspiring way. And
I think these true creatives also just
create what they want, not just what the
market needs. They're probably still
conscious of what the market needs and
what people find interesting about
themselves, because they also have a
level of self-awareness. But at the end
of the day, they also just create what
they want, and they like showing up to
create. And I think that's actually a
necessary tenant. Now, I'm not going to
sit here and be like, yo, I am the
gigachad creator. Like, I am him, okay?
But I've studied, I've met tons and tons
of creators, because, you know, I At the
end of the day, once you start growing a
following, you will start to become
connected with like larger creators. And
I believe it's a power I've tapped into
a few times where I've genuinely just
plopped down the camera. I felt it, the
flow and intuition, and showed up and
got like 2 million views. But not only
that, the content felt like it
resonated, where I spoke to the camera,
and people in the comments were like,
"Dude, you spoke to my freaking soul.
How do you make videos like that? And
how do you do it in a consistent
manner?" I believe, "How do you do
that?" Because it's [ __ ] difficult
sometimes, right? It's true novel
authenticity, where you're not where
you're where where your content doesn't
feel like you're just some recycled AI
GPT rapper or some other content creator
rapper. All right? Think about your
favorite creators. I'm talking about the
ones that changed your life. I'm
thinking prime Ryan Higa, prime RiceGum,
prime Hamza in the self-improvement
niche. I remember some of his videos
genuinely made me question my entire
life and like my entire male
self-development. Whoever it is, did you
like them just because they felt like
they were structured? Did you feel like
they were trying to hook you? Like they
were fighting and clawing for your
attention? No. It probably felt like you
were in the room with them. Like for
once, you found somebody on the internet
who genuinely made you feel understood.
And you felt like every time their video
popped up on their on your feed, it was
like, "Yo, this person just dropped a
freaking gem for them." And I don't even
understand how they made this. I think
there's real magic here. And I think
that is an incredibly underexplored
concept in the space of content
creation, okay? And I'll I'll rant here
for a little bit because let's be real,
you're probably looking for the next
strategy and every other creator here is
talking about this brand strategy,
talking about the complex pillars. But
as somebody who's had a data set of
hundreds and hundreds of creators,
studying them, helping them, messing up
as a coach to other creators, I realized
a lot of it's in the emotion as well, in
the intuitive motion that you can tap
into. And yes, you need to start with
the basics because Stephen Curry didn't
wake up as a two-year-old shooting
threes from mid-range, bro, you know?
That made no sense. You start with the
basics, you copy the form of giants
before you. But eventually, there's a
point where the science of content,
right? That we spoke about, the demand,
TAM, right? Value per second, social
proof, it converges with true
spontaneous source. The moment where you
kind of forget for a second that you're
creating content for this algorithm.
You're creating content to appeal to
some viewers and you're constantly
fighting for their attention because you
know that they are once one one slow
moment away from scrolling, looking to
the sidebar, and clicking on somebody
else's video. You forget these fears
around being perceived, on what he's
going to think, what she's going to
think about me, what [ __ ] cringe
perception that other people have of me.
And you're just here as a creator,
right? And it's hard. It's hard because
it's easy to hide behind a script. It's
easy to hide behind editing. It's And
And I say this genuinely from
experience. And that is the state of
mind and body and emotion that I try to
tap into and that I know intuitively
that where when I am in that state, I
can actually show up and be like
genuinely loving towards my viewer. Like
I I make I create not from this forceful
energy of I need to take your attention,
but I genuinely feel like love towards
my viewer. Like I'm making this and I'm
putting in all this effort because I
want to help you. Right? And I think
there's another abundance the best
creators convey where they don't need
you to watch and yet you are
effortlessly retained. And it's hard
because views are literally survival,
especially as a business owner, right?
You You literally need to get views for
your business to bring in leads for your
business to survive and thrive. You have
people maybe even counting on you,
right? Your Your Your mom who tells you
who probably doesn't believe that this
content creation thing is ever going to
be a real job for you and you feel
scarce because of all of these people
who either have expectations on you or
who you feel don't really believe in
you, who don't believe that this content
creation thing which you're kind of just
trying out as a hobby is ever going to
be a real thing. And it's [ __ ] hard
because that weighs on your emotions.
And if nobody's ever told you this,
genuinely, it's hard and I've I've I've
cried, you know? I felt truly alone. I
took a gap year trying to make this
content creation thing where it felt
just like like I'm staring to this abyss
every day and it's lonely and it's hard
and how do you wake up with that these
pains of anxiety and get and and still
show up on camera with confidence, try
to be a leader, an influencer when you
when you're waking up to 2,000
followers, half of these people are just
people that you know who you don't even
want to see your videos, man. What do
you do that? And for me, I developed a
lot of practices to find this ample
level of self-love to be perceived
exactly how I am as this flawed person
that I am, as not as the perfect guru
that I try to be in these videos, being
the perfect educator, but just like
being the like flawed, somewhat like,
you know, spontaneous, unorganized,
disorganized version of me now that I
am. And these practices for me are like
morning meditation, trying to spend at
least the first hour of my day every
single day off of Instagram, not
checking the views cuz that [ __ ] with
your mental and it makes you suddenly
like literally the social media
algorithms are really designed for you
to lose your self-confidence because
you're either checking your own views
and feeling insufficient insufficient
about them or looking at somebody else's
views or somebody else's lifestyle
that's perfectly curated and feeling
worse about yourself. How are you then
going to see and be exposed to all of
that insufficiency about yourself and
then suddenly show up with the energy
where people are magnetically attracted
to you. It's hard. And I think this has
a lot to do with the delivery of showing
up on camera. So, a couple of things
that I do is I like to meditate on death
and I know that sounds corny, but just
hear me out. This is something that I
often do in my mornings. I I wake up and
I just think, "Today was my last day of
life. How would I want to spend it?" And
eventually I I go through these weird
circles of thought where I'm like,
"Yeah, I mean, it's it's kind of hard to
imagine if I were to die tonight, but if
I were to die tonight, I guess I
probably wouldn't care so much about
that high school kid who's watching my
videos and judging me from afar and used
to [ __ ] call me corny and like cringe
in high school. I guess I wouldn't for
once I wouldn't care about them because
I just wouldn't have time to worry about
it. And you know, maybe I would actually
like to make a video. Why? Because it's
a medium of expressing myself. It's a
medium of being able to leave at least
one thing that could have permanence of
impact and legacy on this earth in this
limited time that we have. That's the
purest reason for creating that I can
think of and I think it comes from
contemplating death and realizing that
none of this [ __ ] really does matter.
So, all these things that I should be
doing, like being more productive,
working, getting a job, right? Doesn't
matter in the grand scheme of things
because we're going to die. And being
qualified enough to be on camera and
showing up, being a hyper retentive,
doesn't really matter if I have one day
left on this earth. I don't have time to
worry about that [ __ ] You know, I
don't have time to worry about my views
because [ __ ] even if this video got
three views, I would want to say this
message, you know? Because I care about
it. And I think that's when I finally
tap into this flow and intuition as a
creator where I'm like, yes, I feel it.
I feel like I'm actually talking to a
real person. I feel like there's a
reason why I'm here and it's not just to
farm views and take and take and take
from where I was watching and sell them
on my content academy who yeah, I kind
of have something to sell, but you know,
showing up with a genuine sense of
enjoyment for this craft. And that's why
we started off in this journey of
content and then we started feeling all
this scarcity. Oh, [ __ ] Well, my views
weren't good, right? We started off with
this pure energy. Damn, I just really
want to make something today and I
really want to explore my creative
passion because I feel like my normal
life, school, doesn't scratch that itch
of genuinely creating something from the
heart. So, at the very least I want
content to be a channel for that. And I
know we talked about the tactics, right?
And these matter. These matter because
at the end of the day, to be a good
musician, to be a good violin player,
you can't just tap into the flow of
becoming Mozart overnight, right? We
need practice. We need practice the
scales. And the scales in this case are
understanding what gets demand and
copying it, right? Studying other
creators' viral videos, value per
second, thinking empathetically about
what the viewer is thinking about you as
you're making the video, which is a
really weird skill. But like past that,
you know, I like to think if I can show
up as the most giving version of myself,
I can show up as the most passionate,
present version of myself, things will
align. And I think that requires an
immense amount of just blind faith as a
creator because this game of social
media it kind of feels like you're just
waking up and throwing down a slot
machine every day. It's like, is this
going to get 300 views or is this going
to get 100k?
I don't know, honestly. And it takes a
lot of [ __ ] energy to be cringe, know
that people are watching you, right?
Maybe even showing up to school the next
day looking around knowing that
somebody's being like, "Yo, I've seen
your videos, bro. Like, good stuff, man.
I see you trying." Like,
like, "Yo, like, what what are your
plans with that?" And you feel this
[ __ ] shame around it, man. Living
with that and so showing up requires you
to be a little [ __ ] delusional. And
the skill's not going to be built
overnight. Okay? As As As much as I
would love to be just like twice as
good-looking, twice as naturally funny,
twice as naturally act like insert XYZ
so I could just wake up with million
views tomorrow, you know? As somebody
who's helped normal people change their
life with their personal brand,
sometimes it just takes blind faith
because realistically, there's no reason
why I should be on camera right now
being able to talk to hundreds and
thousands of people with my content.
Yes, I could logically, rationally break
it down in hindsight, but in the moment,
I had no clue as a 19-year-old how I'd
get there when I was stuck at 2,000
followers, not growing for months,
feeling like I had no way to make income
from this content creation thing,
either. I honestly wasn't even sure if I
was doing the right thing with my life.
You know, you you might feel that way
with your content. But, I think the
craziest content unlock for me was
realizing that I can actually feel whole
about myself despite not getting views.
And it's really backwards, but there's a
really funny thing that happens once you
start feeling whole and start
recognizing that you deserve to be
heard, that you are a person worth being
heard and worth having impact in this
lifetime. Makes you show up with a level
of confidence and energy and passion
that you otherwise wouldn't have been
able to tap into. And it's really
backwards, but I genuinely believe the
delusion comes first. Stepping into that
identity comes first and then usually
showing up with that energy of like,
"Yeah, I'm freaking him and I am going
to help somebody with this video.
Somebody's going to watch this video and
be genuinely touched from whatever I'm
saying, even though I'm just [ __ ]
yabbering in a hotel room, man. Damn."
And yes, of course, then you remember
where they're at and you hook them in
with a mixture of the tactical
copywriting from your, you know,
hundreds of reps that you've put in and
practiced and studied the tape and you
mix it in with showing up with a genuine
energy of true presence that no AI
scripted, that's not this, it's this,
creator could even come close to. That's
when you become the [ __ ] hook. And
not just that, you ascend to becoming
the true creative that you grew up
needing as a consumer. And that, ladies
and gentlemen, I believe is level four,
the S-tier. So, I hope this was helpful
because I could easily made this video
just the first three cuz I honestly feel
like I'm just kind of yabbering in this
S-tier one, but this genuinely, I think,
was a big unlock for me. Not just
growing accounts cuz I grew these
accounts, I would say, like just by
utilizing a lot of strategy, but also
getting to a point where I felt
genuinely proud of my personal brand,
where I felt like I showed up the way I
wanted to, not trying to be necessarily
like an Iman Gadzhi clone, a Hormozi
clone, Shia LaBeouf, Justin Halpern
clone, but that sounds hella hella sus
to say, man, cuz that sounds like really
glazy. But like showing up as myself and
like showing up genuinely with an
excitement to create. Cuz that's another
hard thing, too. It's like you can
become good at content and good at
people's attention getting people's
attention, but like are you truly proud
of the impact that you're having with
your content? I don't mean that in some
you should feel bad about the type of
content you create. Man, I was making
memes, I was making Among Us memes and
skits back when I grew this account,
okay? And I needed that to learn and to
practice, to build my skill set. And
yeah, I did do I did do a couple brand
deals that made me like two, three K a
month as well, you know, it's not bad
income. But accept where you're at, you
know, understand it will take practice,
but also understand that you deserve to
be heard. And maybe, you know, if this
just inspires you to make something that
you feel passionate about today, then
that's a win at the end of the day, you
know? Go out, create something that you
feel passionate about that you genuinely
think will impact people. And if you
want to work with me and my community
and you want to learn more not just
about what we do, but also how I was
able to grow 200,000 followers in a year
working just an hour a day using some of
the tactics I've told you about today
that I'm going to link in the first link
in the description, a video that I made
of the three biggest tactics that I've
employed in my content to make it hyper
retentive and to grow 200k followers
authentically in a year's time. So, go
ahead and watch that one. I'll see you
guys in the next video. Blah, blah,
blah.