So after helping 55 creators with their
first 10,000 followers on their personal
brand in the past 2 years, I've realized
personal branding and content are wildly
overcomplicated online and you're
usually just one unlock, one shift in
your content or your messaging away from
getting your million view format, which
will catapult your personal brand to the
point [music] of actually being able to
monetize, which will catapult your
social media career to the point of
actually starting to make money. So in
the next 53 minutes, you're going to get
never-before-seen footage of me live
coaching people's personal brands. One
person of which was a 16-year-old who
just hit his first 1 million view video
and off that I think got around 3,000
followers on his personal brand. So
you're getting actual real sauce here.
This is a live coaching call inside our
community Content Academy where I'm
dropping actual practical sauce, not
conceptual BS that you'll see on most
gurus' channels. Let's jump into [music]
it.
Dude, Justin told me very briefly that
you're on MasterChef? Yeah, and also I'm
going to move to LA in 2 weeks. So I'm
in a very like, I guess, important part
of my career. I have a lot of stuff I'd
like done. See, I know. Yeah. Um there's
a lot of stuff I'd like done, but I
don't like taking up anyone's time. I
have a video that I'd like you to
review, also one script. And if you have
more time, then you know. Yeah, let's do
it. Is it possible to wear a white
beater on the world's largest cooking
show, MasterChef? The second I get
casted, I I know I want to wear one for
my audition because I love to wear white
beaters. But there's one big problem.
The wardrobe team explicitly says no
tank tops allowed. However, I decide to
only send pictures of me in a white
beater. I pray I don't get kicked off
the show for that. One week later, they
respond and they say they like my pants
options, but I got to bring a couple of
shirts, too. So I do bring a couple of
shirts to the show, but maybe they don't
match with any of my pants and maybe I
don't iron them. As the wardrobe team is
going through my clothes, I notice
they're a little frustrated. And that's
when I pull out a white beater and ask,
"Does this work?" After a lot of back
and forth, they finally cave. And next
thing you know, I'm doing push-ups in a
white beater for Gordon Ramsay. What
seemed like a small wardrobe choice was
proof that the best decisions are the
ones that you believe in the most. And
if you're willing to get kicked off of
MasterChef over it, that's exactly what
you should be fighting for. Dude, that's
hilarious. It's a troll ass video, but
yeah, and like I try to follow your
storytelling structure video, but I
think like I don't know my music choices
and I've like I [ __ ] spammed the
right side a lot.
But just like overall, I can't change
the script or anything, but from an
editing standpoint, like what's your
opinion? Two small things cuz I I agree.
I I think like the Yeah, like obviously
I'm not going to like be like, "Yo,
change everything." I think there's it
might have been the first or second
sentence that I think you could cut cuz
I think the funny like the part that got
like me re-hooked, I guess, was the but
there's only one problem. My brain
instantly thinks, "Why can't you just
wear a beater on MasterChef?" Cuz like
that's the first thought. Cuz like the
sooner that you can answer that question
like why is that a problem, the sooner
that the premise will feel like it hits
really hard. And then the second thing
is I think there's two I I think the
music definitely I'm not the biggest fan
of the rap. I think it could either be
like I think there's like two editing
styles. I I see like a Ryan Trahan angle
where it's like
>> Yeah.
it's some sort of recognizable intense
like classical music. Yeah.
>> Or I think of like the meme music. Like
just pure like this this [ __ ] is purely
satire and it's like the Wii Shop music
or something. Yeah, okay. I might do
that. I might do the Wii Shop also.
That's my bad. I'll do the Wii Shop
music like that.
I agree so with the when I say like the
problem is that would that was like the
the conflict in the story. So I didn't
just want to introduce that off the bat.
And maybe I'm thinking in the viewer in
the mindset of a MasterChef viewer, but
like if you watch MasterChef, like you
would know no one's ever worn like a
wife beater on the show. Um but maybe
not everyone knows that, so I see your
point. I I think the second sentence
like the second I get casted like it
kind of feels a little bit redundant
from the first one, but it's kind of
hard to cut it cuz if you say is it
possible to wear a white beater on
MasterChef, but there's only one
problem. It's Yeah. What do you say
after but there's only one problem? The
wardrobe team explicitly said no
wardrobe TikToks allowed. And then I do
like a boom sound and then the email.
Honestly, this is this is good. I I like
it. I like it. I think this is like
super nitpicky and I also think music
can go a long way to like building the
suspense in the beginning. Okay. Yeah,
so I actually chose the 50 Cent song cuz
like he was known for like making white
beaters like a big thing in rap or
whatever. But I think like that's just
so like small. Like nobody gives a [ __ ]
So like I might do like We Shot the
Sheriff music or something like that. I
think at the end you can put that in cuz
that's like the victor- the victory
moment and it's like oh like it ties
back with the tank. It's like if you if
you know you know. Okay. Yeah. Okay,
that's smart. Okay, so in the beginning
it could be like We Shot or some [ __ ]
Yeah. And then the middle is the
the handsome the handsome thing reprise
whatever. You use that song, but yeah.
It's like the dramatic song. I mean I
was I was thinking like
some like
>> [laughter]
>> It might be
Four Seasons Winter. Okay, I'll look it
up. I have something else like a lot of
stuff, but I there's someone else and I
have like 3 minutes left, so it's like
chill. You can just look at their stuff.
Yeah, I mean I can go over time cuz I
know I
I dragged on really early on, but
>> I want to do the script you wanted to do
really quick. Also, I already recorded
the script, um
but I can just like re-record it. How's
that for you? Yeah, I'm going to put it
at the very bottom. Also, before you
read it real quick, I said originally it
was is it possible to graduate college
without a job so I can become America's
next MasterChef. But I think the is it
possible like didn't make sense with the
graduating part. So this is not a
question, but I just want to hear your
thoughts about that. I graduated
I graduated college without a job so I
can become America's next MasterChef.
When I started college, I only had one
dream. Inspire others through my passion
of cooking. I created my college's
culinary club and a couple years later.
However, I'm about to graduate college
and have two choices. Get a a job and
live with the regret or risk it all to
fulfill my culinary dreams. I graduated
college without a job so I can become
Something about A and B feel like they
It's like hard for me to see the linkage
slightly. Yeah, that's what I thought.
That's what I thought. But like you see
the premise is like I graduate and don't
get a job instead of go to MasterChef
instead. Uh but like I I see how they
could seem like disconnected if that
makes sense. One side thought cuz I've
seen your other like videos before.
Uh like the culinary tutorials. I know
you go in with like crazy funny hooks
and I wonder if there's like Maybe it's
not in the hook but it's just like
throughout the script like that style of
almost like deadpan humor. Yeah, yeah.
Let me let me see like this one or this
one. There can be too much of a good
thing and I think that's true for most
things but the only time I disagree with
that is when it comes to garlic. I eat
so much garlic that I get that
especially after MasterChef but like if
you go down and down there's some like
some rancid [ __ ]
>> Yeah, let me let me find like one of the
more You would not [music] believe me if
I told you the best sisig in the world
is actually made with salmon. So I'm
going to show you all how to make it.
The rest of the video is fine and the
rest of the video is fine but like
Japanese curry is or Japanese Oh wait,
that one
Don't even watch that one, bro. Oh man,
I I wonder if there's like a a way to
kind of incorporate the strengths of
that style of content into this. When I
started college I had only one dream
like The The thing I'm trying to
emphasize is is like the sacrifice
between like applying for corporate job
versus like pursuing culinary dreams but
then also culinary dreams aren't
directly linked to MasterChef.
Um and honestly I can abandon the whole
college thing. I obviously MasterChef
should be the primary focus. What What
if it was like I only had one dream, be
unemployed and cook food all day. Yeah,
something like that.
>> at home.
He's so
stay at home dad.
>> [gasps]
>> So [snorts] I can cook all day. I don't
know like preserving I guess a little
bit of that like humor in the hook.
>> Mhm. And then just like go into like,
"However, as I'm about to graduate, I
have two choices. Get a corporate job
and live with the risk." This is more of
a risky play cuz I know America's Next
Top MasterChef, like, so I can get on
MasterChef or like join MasterChef is
such a like It's kind of like a
guaranteed like you save a name, it's
going to hook. It It almost feels a
little forced right now in the hook. And
I know it's such a powerful line, but it
feels kind of disconnected right now
from the like passion, college. Yeah,
that's fair. Also, small thing, and I I
hate to give like big feedback, but I
wonder if this part could be shorter and
this part could be longer. Or
specifically like Okay. this this part
could be longer and this part could be
shorter.
Cuz this is like your backstory, which I
think doesn't progress into the
MasterChef part. But then once you start
talking about the MasterChef part, it's
like, "MasterChef." Especially cuz the
hook leads with MasterChef. So, it's
like if this could Okay. be down to like
half the length, and then this about the
MasterChef, which is like a guaranteed
like interesting hitter, you know? You
draw that on, which is like, "But then
they rejected my first thing. But then
they said, 'No like like no wifebeaters,
wifebeaters, wifebeaters.' And I thought
I was going to like I thought I would
lose my spot until like dragging on a
little bit cuz I think you I think
that's actually what the viewers would
want, which is to Yeah. hear more about
that process. It kind of feels like that
was condensed a lot. Wait, I I'm asking
you this. Do you think it makes sense
because like I think the MasterChef
stuff is related, but kind of
disconnected to everything here. Do you
think I should do one explaining
explaining solely the MasterChef stuff,
and then one explaining like just my
journey and like me wanting to be a
cooking content creator? Or do you think
I should have them like combined?
>> You could actually do two videos. I
don't see why not. I would even say like
maybe you could just try them both out.
This is something I learned from Prosper
about uh like he was on a show. I mean,
it was like a YouTube show, like a
dating show. But it's like when you get
that external motion, milk the hell out
of it. Like make as many videos possible
on the topic. So if there's a way you
can make two videos about it, why not
instead of just one, you know? Like why
not?
>> Okay. Okay, that makes sense.
Yeah, I'll probably do two videos cuz
that was my original thought with the
script. It just seemed like two separate
things kind of. You could also like I
feel like there's a lot of angles of
like I almost It's like something
something MasterChef. Like I almost got
kicked out of MasterChef because blah
blah blah or when I got on MasterChef
like happened or this is like a random
thought like POV my mom's reaction to
like me getting on MasterChef. Like
[ __ ] like I feel like there's so many
angles. Yeah, dude. I'm like not really
looking enough. Like it's kind of ass.
Like I'm still trying to grind right
now, but um Dude, there's so many Wait,
is the full video like full thing filmed
now? Like was it No, so yeah, they they
they pre-recorded everything.
>> So now you're just like full full free
time to just milk videos about this and
like farm videos. Yes, bro. And I'm
Yeah, I'm moving to LA in like 2 weeks
so I can just like I don't know if I can
lock it, I guess. Yo, farm these videos,
bro. Like honestly, like yo, I see my my
feedback low-key doesn't even matter,
bro. Just like if there's two angles
like yo, [ __ ] it. Just make two videos,
bro. Like Yeah,
yeah, that makes sense. That makes
sense. I I guess like one last thought
is like I I feel like there's a strength
here that I see in these videos of like
the humor that I wonder if like
>> Yeah.
we can do these videos. I was thinking
like as my audience expanded especially
with the MasterChef audience, I didn't
know how much I want to play into that.
But also I think it's one of my more
unique strengths. So it's like I think I
should. Like maybe it doesn't have to be
like vile humor, but it's like it's just
a humor in general. And I think like
this script right now could use a little
bit of it. Yeah, that makes sense. All
right, that's hype, man. That's hype.
That's hype.
Yo, if you're still watching this
coaching call recording, first off,
comment blueberry because I genuinely
appreciate you. I need to know who y'all
are who are actually consuming the
information. But secondly, I probably
know who you are. You've been posting
for around a year, maybe 6 months, and
you feel stuck. That's the reason why
this advice even feels applicable to you
right now. If you feel genuinely stuck
or lost, and you genuinely just don't
even know what to do, I made this video
of how I grew 200k followers in a single
year as a college student and the exact
three-step system that I used to do that
and farm many multi-million view videos
to blow up my personal brand. Go check
this one out. It's a 32-minute video.
It'll teach you everything you need to
get started with your personal brand.
Awesome. Next one, uh Yaya, you finally
found a series with love advice. Let's
go. Oh, damn, serving 10k homeless
people with your startup. Wait, that's
fire. Do you have any specific questions
on this uh on this video? Um so, it
didn't do as well as I initially thought
it would. I mean, I remember I talked to
you about like in the general chat about
like a series that I should start.
Initially, it was like um try to make a
startup without selling my soul. Then
like you asked questions and I thought
more about it and I realized like I
don't really have a past of like doing
degen stuff to where I could like relate
to someone on that level. So, I kind of
like went back to the drawing board. I
was like, "Okay, what can I like bring
to the table in which like I can relate
to them?" And so, I own a nonprofit
that's like statewide. Uh we were
interviewed by the news a month or two
ago. Um and like we we like I grew it a
lot over the past year or so. And so, I
was trying to incorporate that aspect of
me into like the creating my startup
journey. Um and I guess like besides
like what to improve in the video and
like how to structure it so I can get it
to actually like pop off. The question
that I had is, "How do I like integrate
like faith, family, friendships, like
other aspects of me or fitness that like
I value into the series as well?" Cuz I
want to again like I want it to be a
personal brand and people to have an
inside on to my life. And the whole
point of this series is kind of like so,
I'm working to become a doctor and I can
do my startup as well. Like you don't
have to drop out in order to make a
startup. Like you can do both. And like
I'm trying to do it for a good cause. Um
I talked to Sam yesterday and he said to
kind of have a goal that's physical, not
just like a 20K or like a monetary value
cuz that's hard for the viewer to
visualize. So, that's why I chose this.
So, I know it's a mouthful, but like
hopefully kind of like helping you along
those lines cuz I'm just just getting
started. I like it. I like it. I I
appreciate the context actually cuz this
helps like think about um, so I'm not
just kind of saying like, "Eh, this part
was I don't know about that." Like, so
this is good. This is good. Let me Let
me see. 10,000 homeless people with my
startup before I graduated. Here's how I
plan to do it. See, here's the catch. So
many people hype dropping out and that's
just not me. I want to prove to people
you can graduate, have a successful
startup, and become a doctor. Let's
address the elephant in the room. Why
10,000 homeless people? Why not get a
Lambo instead? See, a year ago I created
Bridge Care, a nonprofit that helped
over 200 homeless people with health
care, got it on the news, and are
expanding across Texas rapidly. The
reason why I want to give back is
simple. None of my success will be
possible without God, and giving back is
just showing gratitude. That's the least
I could do. I think if there's one thing
that can I see all the elements that you
actually mentioned here. And if there's
one thing to really build in that like
This sounds so bad, but like parasocial
effect with the content where people are
bought into your story. Not in a weird
way. Like in like a very like you
actually like the video feels very
deeply impactful to them like
Um, the one piece of feedback I would
say is like
there's a lot of good things about like
your mission and your why that you're
saying here, which is awesome. I feel
like there's So, while watching it I
felt a little bit of a distance between
me as a viewer and you as the creator,
and I think that gap was vulnerability.
Like, I see the why and the mission, and
it's kind of like this is the goal I'm
working towards, but in every good story
the hero experiences conflict and
struggle. And I guess I don't see a
picture or a clear picture here of
conflict or struggle either. I see the
the mountain that you're going to climb.
I see why the mountain matters to you,
which is all very valuable. I feel like
I don't get as clear of a picture into
like like what are the deep deep
challenges that you're facing, and also
like then
if you can paint those pictures of like,
okay, like what is actually difficult
about this? What is like more deeper
layers of like the struggle in this
journey, then I can start relating to it
as well. Then me as a college student or
me as someone else working on a
business, like, oh wow, like this is
real. Like, damn, like bro
bro articulated this like a hella real
feeling that I'm feeling in this video.
You have like the difficult part, which
is clarity on where you're going. Now
it's like, how do you get people more
bought into you
and feeling like, oh damn, like I really
want to like, I guess root for this
person and see them win. And I think a
big part of that parasocial is built
from like a oh damn, like bro's hella
real for that. I see a lot in your
documenting style and content. So sorry
to cut you off. I just wanted to say so
like my hook like completely like
planted down, so do I really just want
to like this? And so like it it like
also incorporating like my series,
right? Like the name of the series and
what I'm standing for. Do I add that
vulnerability like right off the jump?
Like should that be my hook? I think the
here's how I plan to do it is not what I
would have not the question that I
wanted to answer in my mind. I think
that's a brutal part. If I would guess,
I actually think the like serving 10,000
homeless people, it's like, okay, uh
here's how I plan to do it. And I think
it's pitching value when you're starting
a journey. I guess I don't see the value
in it if you aren't talking about a
result that already happened in the
past. If it's a result that's going to
happen in the future, then it's like, oh
yeah, like but then my thought as a
viewer, especially seeing you as a
stranger, is just like, can't everybody
just make a plan and just say it? I
think the powerful lines actually come
towards the end where you talk about
like your story before of the
non-profit, for example. Like maybe you
could even say like
after the hook, after my first
non-profit that served 200 homeless
people and got me on the news. It's It's
almost like subtle social proof there.
It's like proof proof proof. I realized
or I faced a problem. It's like rough
I'm just thinking off the top of my
head. I I faced a huge problem. I fell
into the biggest rut of my life. Cuz
once I got into college, oh, here's
here's another here's another here's
another. So, the the hook paints you as
a very selfless person. But I actually
think like one angle that would be very
interesting to me is like but then I
swayed into the dark side. After I
helped 200 homeless people, I swayed
into the dark side. I started watching
videos of kids flexing their Lambos and
I thought, man, I want to get a Lambo.
So,
>> [laughter]
>> so I ditched my homeless brothers. Okay,
this is getting it's touching to
absurdity, but I think the the I I guess
the thought that comes to my mind here
is that if the hook and the and the
script only paints you good, then like I
I I guess I struggle to feel connected
with you. But it's like if you talk
about the struggle of like morality, for
example, of like trying to be like a
good person in college and and juggle
like altruism with personal ambition,
that's a story where I'm like, yo. Yeah,
low-key that's me. Like example, like I
I find that concept itself pretty
interesting where it's like when you
make a business or a startup, you're
constantly kind of choosing between like
are you going to
I don't know charge more money to make
more profit or are you going to like
charge less to serve your
I don't know to like be a better
business owner to like kind of your
business owner to your people etc. I
don't know. But I think that's like
there's a concept there that's very
humanizing where it's like there's
enough people I think on social media
also who like portray themselves as like
perfect and I think that's like the one
thing that makes a lot of personal like
the best personal brands stand out, in
my opinion, is that they usually feel
like very real. Like they're sharing
something and a struggle that I am going
through but I could not articulate on my
own.
>> Okay, and and for like kind of
incorporating other aspects of like my
lifestyle I want to in this series, how
would how would I do that? So, from what
I'm getting right now is like I could
either like go about the hook like say
exactly what I said for the title and
then go into like the dark side of
everything and then show like that
comparison of my struggle and then show
what I'm doing to come out of it. Or
like I've had struggles in my life
before. I feel like I could have like a
deeper hook of why I even started the
nonprofit in the beginning and then go
into that and then go into like my whys
now.
How that shaped me into um
kind of who I am now. Is that is that
kind of like a the road map of it? First
step I would say is identify exactly
what format you're doing and I see two
formats here. One is storytelling the
other one's educational. I would choose
like I I should between those two like
storytelling or educational, which one
do you think resonates more? Like
educational is like how-to, purely
logical,
fact-based, like it's like a list video.
Storytelling is more like emotional
hero's journey. Like which one of those?
So, storytelling definitely resonates
more with people. Okay, great. So, let's
let's take the storytelling, right? I
think within every storytelling
framework I'll actually share my screen
here. I generally like to always follow
this framework, which I know this is
like the classic Hollywood three-act
story structure and I
I know it's kind of weird to apply this
to the freaking TikToks and Instagram
Reels, which I like to stick with me. Um
hook is act one, right? That's like
exposition. So, this is like the hook,
right? This is like the first 5 10
seconds uh is the hook and there's two
things that it must achieve. One is to
obviously capture somebody's attention,
right? So, that comes right here, right?
You got to like capture somebody's
attention, got to make them go "Oh."
"Oh my gosh." Right? You capture their
attention, then what do we do after?
It's the inciting incident, right? And I
think this happens in like sentence two
three is you introduce conflict.
Because if we don't introduce conflict,
it can end up sounding like a list where
it's just like "And then this happened,
and then this happened." But when we
introduce conflict in the second
sentence, it's a but sentence. It's "I'm
trying to achieve XYZ, but this
happened. But then
my biggest hater opt me out." But then
um like we we saw it in Daniel's script
earlier. I don't know if you're there
for Daniel Meng's script about
MasterChef, but it's like I want to wear
a beater on MasterChef. If you didn't
mention the but, the biggest problem is
that
no matter what they do not allow you to.
If you didn't include that sentence,
then we just kind of jump from like
this, which is the hook, into the
ending, which is
like the resolution, which is like it
happened. Or another one is like the
lesson/takeaway,
right? It's like lesson is that you
should always chase your dreams. But the
lesson needs to feel earned for a story
to really hit really hard.
Um
And in order to make that lesson feel
earned, we want to overcome some sort of
conflict. So, I think that's what makes
storytelling content hit really hard is
that it kind of allows you to fight
vicariously live out a difficult journey
and a challenge through watching
somebody else talk about it. So, in this
case, right? You have the goal, right?
You kind of have this North Star, which
is the goal of the series, which is
great, right? You have this, the North
Star. But what we need here is between
you right now, or or you before too,
right? We can even say like your your
stories in the past.
Whether it's your stories in the past or
your stories now, both apply. Let's say
your stories in the past, it was younger
you, right? We got younger Yahya.
I'm pronouncing your name right, right?
Yahya?
Yeah, it's like Yahya. It's weird.
Yahya's fine.
Okay, Yahya. Sorry, sorry, sorry. I I
want to make sure I I pronounce your
name right.
Um but younger Yahya and I guess like
slightly less younger Yahya, or like
maybe present day. Honestly, let's just
say present day.
Um
it's like in order for
younger Yahya, who let's say didn't even
have a nonprofit, to get to the the you
now, which
had a successful nonprofit, it's like
what
you know, you can describe that story
right here. That's a whole video right
there.
But then you have to describe, you can't
just say like, "So, I didn't have a
nonprofit and then I made a nonprofit
and I inspired a lot of people and yeah,
you know, guys like followed me." Like
then that's more of an educational video
cuz it's like, "Okay, the logical
thought is, oh wow, that was very
successful. Let me learn from you." So,
then you can probably be like, "Three
things I learned from my nonprofit,
right?" That's a different style of
video. That's educational. But if you
want to be storytelling, you need to
introduce conflict and conflict really
early on. So, if you say like, "Back
like 4 years ago, I didn't have any
purpose in life." I'm just like
introducing random like backstory you,
right? I'm just like
throwing up random stuff. And that was
kind of like the problem. That's the
conflict here. And then the way you
solved it is eventually by I don't know.
Well, you don't say right away I made a
successful nonprofit because then that
kills all the suspense. You want it to
build up into that. So, it's like maybe
the conflict is, let's say and I'm just
going to at this point completely make
[ __ ] up, but it's like, "I didn't feel
any purpose in high school and I thought
getting good grades would solve that for
me. So, I studied for a year straight. I
got a 1580 on my SAT." I remember I
still remember the look on my mom's
face. She was like, "Wow, Yahya, good
job." I just remember I wanted to hear,
"I'm proud of you" just once.
I didn't hear it. And then I realized
while walking home from the SAT that
day, I saw a guy eating food and I
thought it was the end of the world. I
saw a guy sleeping under a tunnel. And
in that moment I just realized, "Wow, my
problems about the SAT are so
minuscule." And then I started nonprofit
blah blah blah blah blah blah blah
again. I'm I'm going to summarize the
ending, but like basically what I did
here is I introduced conflict, right?
The desire for you to, let's say, like
have purpose or approval.
And instead of going right away, I made
a nonprofit.
You do what the stories classically do
as a rising action and plot twist,
ascending action, disaster, and
midpoint. So, this is kind of the ups
and downs of the story where you don't
just say, "I had a problem and then I
solved it." You say, "I had a problem, I
thought I almost solved it, but then I
realized, no, that wasn't true. Or but
then this happened that stopped me. But
I almost got there, but then I realized
that was not the I was climbing the
wrong mountain the whole time." There's
different ways that this is This is told
in the stories, but general structure. I
know I'm now speaking very just like
randomly, but
the general structure that I like to
follow is hook and then conflict,
introduce it, then attempts
at solving, and then climax/realization,
and then teach something, right? So, a
lot of times, too, this is something
that Brad Show talks about. He talked
about this in one of the guest beating
calls in our community on like how he's
able to make such retentive scripts
about his like DoorDash and two
uh diamond ring series. He doesn't just
say like, "Guys, you need to become
better boyfriends, guys. Here's how you
become a better boyfriend." Cuz then
that would get no views and people would
kind of hate him cuz he sounds like
really preachy and guru-y. So, instead,
he talks about, "I used to struggle with
blah blah blah in my relationship." So,
struggle, highlights the conflict. And
the more relatable this can be, the
harder it's going to hit and the
probably more viral it's going to be.
Right? Cuz people are going to resonate
way deeper.
And then you have these multiple
attempts at solving until it
reaches the climax. When you have this
grand realization or something big
happens or you finally achieve what you
wanted. And then the lesson at the end
is So, the takeaway is that you
shouldn't do things for people's
approval, I don't know, right? It can be
cliche, it actually doesn't really
matter. Because you can earn the right
to to say a lesson. Sorry,
I wasn't sharing this part, but this is
a general framework that I like to
cover. So,
all that to say, I would always try to
like ask yourself, I guess, like, how
can you identify a conflict in whatever
stories that you want to tell? And this
could be any story. It could be story
from the past. It could be story from
literally today. I think some of the
best storytellers are able to make
really interesting up, down, sideways
stories, climb back they
stories and narratives around nothing.
Like, how their friend didn't get lunch
with them today, and they somehow turned
that into a million views of people
caring about their random friend
dynamic, you know? Well, that helps a
lot. Thank you so much. I think my I
don't want to take anyone's time up too
much. I think my only questions are A,
how do I like kind of integrate like
other aspects of me into this series?
Cuz like like for example, like faith or
fitness or whatnot. And then kind of
like how do I like cuz if I start off
with a hook, and then a conflict, and
then attempts of solving the conflict,
that kind of doesn't really reflect with
the
um how I bring 10,000 homeless people
with my startup before I graduate. Like,
I don't know where I should fit that.
And then my third final point is just
like how do I kind of like talk about my
startup as well? Cuz right now it's all
about my story and the storytelling.
Like, where does my startup come in?
Like, oh, like by the way, this is what
I'm creating. I actually want to
challenge you on this one. I think you
can weave in all of the details that you
just said into a framework like this.
Yeah, right. Unless you want to make
educational videos, in which then you're
teaching stuff, which you can too. And
you can always mix in multiple formats,
you know? So, another example is like
three things
This is an educational style, but like
three things I do
Let's say like three weird habits I do
with my startup that XYZ outcome, that
got me blah blah blah outcome. So, it's
like desirable outcome here, desirable
outcome, and now you can just do one,
two, three. And that's like grounds for
you to explain like maybe method one
that you're doing.
Product hack two and mindset tip three.
So this is more in the angle of like I
just got this outcome and here's how I
achieved XYZ, which is a great that's a
great
format as well, you know, like I've
often times mixed in both, you know,
depending on the day. However, with the
storytelling
it always always revolves around
conflict. So you can still talk about
how your product
or how your startup works, right? Maybe
how you structured it, why you started
it, how long you've been running it for,
but you still have to kind of narrow
down a conflict, which is actually what
makes storytelling content like kind of
difficult because a lot of times like we
just want to explain stuff like for
example, I I built a project recently
and I really just want to market it.
Like I just want to talk about how I
built this product that audits your
content. So here's how it works, guys.
So the first thing you do is you put
your profile in and then it scans your
profile, but by this point by the time
I've explained like and this is how it
works, people have already scrolled off,
you know, damn, it's not even worth it.
Brutal.
I can frame it in a way where it's like
today I pitched my product in front of
three investors, but the product broke
the moment I showed it to them and in
that moment I thought I was going to
lose the $100,000 grant. It's explaining
I'm actually weaving in the product. I'm
weaving in what the product does, right?
I'm weaving in this thing, but I'm
framing it in the conflict so it doesn't
feel pitchy, it doesn't feel like I'm
just hating from the viewer. It feels
like I'm
like it doesn't feel like I'm pitching
or selling either.
It feels like I am just like using it as
a device
to progress the conflict, which is but I
almost lost the $100,000
>> So thing is like I do a hook and a
compliment and then I introduce my
series cuz people are hooked on now. And
then from there I kind of explain like
more about my conflict and whatnot. And
then okay, okay, I get it. Thank you so
much. Thank you. It's It's actually
really hard. I do want to say this is
probably actually one of the hardest
forms of content. And I personally think
it's objectively like harder than an
educational video because this is just
like purely logical. Like you just say
like whatever. It's just like three
things I did to XYZ outcome. Outcomes
are very simple. It's just like what
outcome did you get? And then 1 2 3 boom
list done. But this requires you to kind
of think creatively about like
how do I get people to care about this
random arbitrary thing? So, I would
study also other storytelling creators.
Like I love like Ryan Trahan. I love
like Jenny Hoyos is another great
creator as well. I'm just going to drop
there.
The reason why I like them and the
reason why I recommend studying them is
because they're able to make stories out
of nothing.
Jenny Hoyos makes stories about how she
got like how she cooked a meal for her
mom and it got like 10 million plus
views on YouTube shorts. That's good
storytelling, you know? So, it's like
>> Okay. Yeah. She always makes good story
out of random stuff. I feel like the
storytelling is a higher ROI in terms of
like people liking me and the personal
brand. Um I don't know if education I
want to do that too. I feel like I'm
going to mess around and kind of produce
like more educational stuff too and then
hopefully get critiqued on that too. But
so far like I I have a way better like
pathway on how to do storytelling. So,
thank you so much.
Your question was around the hook and
then what emotions you need to have and
build up in the payoff. The hook
retention was better. So, your question
is generally just like what to improve
in the hook. The hook like usually the
hook is like it goes down but like this
one is not it's not like a straight
down. Like it was like steady and like
over time like I think in the middle
that's where people kind of like broke
off and then kind of like it was like
this kind of short. There we go. I don't
know what How do you explain that chart?
It's like a decent like C plus you could
say out of a A chart.
Got you. Do you know what your like
scroll [snorts] stop rate was? Cuz
usually that's what I pay attention to
with uh with hooks to see how like
strong it was.
Scroll stop rate. Is that in the
insights as well when you scroll down?
Like the percentage. This real skip rate
was like 38%.
>> That's actually pretty good, I would
say. I like general benchmarks that I
see is like 30%
is like pretty good. If you get somehow
below 30%, that's like excellent. And
then above like to like 40% is like
okay. And then like 50% plus is
generally like okay, there's probably
something that either confused the
viewer or like just made them
disinterested, but yeah, it's pretty
good. Let's let's see. I have a $100,000
check sitting in front of me that
expires at midnight.
For me it was
Porsche GT3RS. Three weeks ago I applied
to a program that picks 10 solo
entrepreneurs a year and writes them
each a $100,000 check and has an
acceptance rate of less than 1%. You see
the day after I applied, they emailed me
saying that I was in the top 5% of all
applicants. I'm 19 years old building
out of my bedroom in South So the hook
was I have a $100,000 or there's a
$100,000 check sitting in front of me
that expires at midnight. Today's day
five of five coding so I can afford a
Porsche GT3RS. Three weeks ago I applied
to a program that Oh, I see. I see. I
see. I see. Wait, this is a good hook, I
would say. Like there's a $100,000
check. It's definitely I I remember I
think a week ago I took a look at your
like a day one video and I definitely
think like this is a stronger hook than
like a day X of the journey hook.
Generally like when you have a crazy
claim,
the next question is just like does the
second sentence right after that back it
up or double down into it? So I think
and it sucks because it's like it's a
series video, but I would actually
either move the today's day X like
today's day five sentence later on to
the end of the video or maybe even just
move it to like text on the screen. But
I think my initial thought when I see
there's a $100,000 check waiting for me,
I want to know more details immediately
on that. And if I can sniff cap on that,
then I'm like instant scrolling. As in
like if I don't feel like like
immediately that prompts curiosity and a
question in my head. But I feel like if
I don't get it paid off or at least like
somewhat like okay, he's being serious
about this $100,000 check, then I will
probably scroll right after. Cuz it's
like very easy for anybody online,
right? To just say a crazy claim.
Honestly, I could have probably put that
like later in the video probably like
let's say 30 or 40 seconds into the
video then say oh today's day five of
XYZ. Cuz it's like oh yeah like the
$100,000 check and then like maybe
explain the program that I applied to
and then like the whole back story and
everything and then say day five. So
like if a viewer is like hooked and then
they'll probably like okay like day five
of XYZ. I I think that's a great point.
Honestly, that would be like the primary
piece of feedback. Cuz I think right
after that you actually explain what the
$100,000 check is. There's a $100,000
check sitting in front of me that
expires at midnight. Today's day five,
right? So let's say we move that later.
Um
three weeks ago I applied to a program
that picks 10 solo entrepreneurs a year
and writes them a $100,000 check. I
wonder if here you could also insert a
sentence because when you say there's a
$100,000 check waiting for you, but then
you say it's a less than 1%. It's kind
of like oh like it's kind of like saying
I have my Harvard acceptance letter
waiting for me on this desk. See Harvard
has an acceptance rate of less than 1%.
It kind of feels contradictory a little
bit cuz it's like you explain oh it's
waiting there right for me. And then the
next sentence right after explain like
yeah, it's pretty much impossible to
get. I want to feel that like reconcile
a little bit being like but here's how
I'm going to win or here's exactly why
nobody else is going to beat me. And
then that kind of ties it back with some
like confidence of like yeah, this is my
plan or like oh wow, this person's
different. He's actually going to win
it. Like he's serious about it cuz I
think that's where it's very easy. I'm
just thinking about like what are points
of doubt and like points where I would
just stop believing something was true,
especially with a shocking hook, that
would prompt me to scroll. So, like the
whole goal I would say once you have a
shocking hook is just like how do you
constantly build up on top of it so it
doesn't uh somebody would be like,
"Yeah, this is just like not real or
like not true." Cuz with something as
like shocking as that, it's very easy to
just scroll off. Makes sense. I mean, I
did like they did email me about like
getting in the top 5% of all applicants
and I I had that B-roll shot of me
actually showing the email. So, probably
like do you think that makes the viewer
kind of like oh like he's like somewhat
legit? Let's say cuz there's like a
maybe I could have explained how there's
like I maybe I could have shown like the
X post of how I got like 600,000 views
and then saying like, "Oh, if he's the
top 5% of all applicants and they
emailed him." That's like building more
trust with the viewer that I'm not just
like larping, quote unquote, or like cuz
I actually showed the email in there.
>> Uh 100,000 chargeback and has an
acceptance rate of less than 1%. You see
the day after I applied they emailed me
saying I was the top 4%. I actually I'll
be honest, I missed that detail. I don't
know why I did. Like that detail
actually like didn't register in my
brain. I actually think like there's a
bunch of numbers that it was like number
into new fact of like, "Okay, so there's
this program, but they accept 1% and
actually got an email saying they're top
5 like I don't I think the chain of like
and then this happened and then this
happened and then this happened." I
think my brain kind of got lost as a
viewer in the sentence before this. So,
I actually it slipped my mind that it
said you were top 5%. uh an easy way to
to bridge those gaps is to use but, so,
therefore, however sentences. So, they
feel like they're logically tied into
each other as opposed to the this
happened and here's the thing about that
and here's another detail and here's
another detail. Yeah, I I would say
that's actually like one small thing
that could have helped make the video
probably feel like logically has this
through line. Mhm, makes sense. I mean
other than that, I mean dude that this
is a sick concept. I think another small
thing that could have hit is if you
filmed some sort of like reaction.
Because that is a very impressive thing,
but I think because you just dropped it
as a number, it didn't register to me as
a very impressive shocking thing. My
brain was just like, "Oh yeah, 5% 1%
yeah okay yeah yeah." Like versus like
Oh yeah. Yo, 5% like top 5% Oh my gosh.
Mom, I look at this.
Mhm. Wow, that's very impressive. Like
really playing that out cuz I think
that's a really cool moment too that you
can turn into a a whole moment.
>> Makes sense, yeah. Well, what's going to
be even crazier is like I don't know
what the cuz the cohort starts in like
May 22nd. So like now like I'm I'm going
to post a video if I get accepted. If I
don't get accepted then like holy [ __ ]
Like if I I get accepted then I'll like
make sure to be like freaking hyped, you
know, like it'll actually be insane. So
yeah. But yeah, we'll see. But honestly
yeah, this was like probably like the
hook I even got was from Claude as well
cuz I was just thinking about hey like
XYZ. Like I saw you post like the 255
hook thing. So I gave like Claude the
doc. I'm like read through all of this
and like I like I don't know like how
like I was on Discord and like yo like
Mino just dropped this document 255
prompts. Like I got to feed my AI this
like ASAP, you know. So my AI like gave
me that hook. I'm like, "Oh, it's
actually pretty good." And then yeah, I
was like struggling with the butt but
like with the butt sentence or like a so
sentence. But yeah, I'm going to work on
those probably next like however, but,
so and like yeah, therefore. So that was
a good tip as well. Yeah, I was I was
going to recommend just like one last
thought is I I like clearly imagined
this video. Um this is like
um I had this video pretty much build my
entire account. And I farmed it twice,
which is the POV reaction hook. POV your
app got accepted and the whole hook is
just me being like, "Oh my gosh." So
like you could easily be like POV you
just won $100,000.
Like literally just that. And it's like
did bro with a lot of the what? You're
like geeking out over it. That's an easy
like
>> Yeah.
shocking hook right there. I think
that'll be fire. Yeah, I think I'm just
like too nonchalant. I don't know. I'm
just like sitting. Also like I took that
video like at midnight. Literally
yesterday I'm like, "Holy crap." Like I
was busy that the whole day. It was like
midnight 12 at 12:00 a.m. I'm like, "I
got to get like lighting, whatever." And
then I shot the video and like I think I
went to bed like at 2:00. So like I'm
like, "I just got to post this video."
Like I got I can't like skip a day, you
know? But yeah, I'll definitely work on
work on those aspects as well. That's
fire. Yeah, I'm excited to see it, man.
I I I don't know if it's like locked in
or anything, but wishing for the best,
man.
Thank you, Meno. Thank you.
All right, awesome.
Let's see. Next video was from Ray. Day
19 road to high school varsity
basketball. Wait, was this the video
that 400k?
Yo. Yo, Ray, are you in here? Yo, you
are. You are. Yo, let's go. Dude. Yeah,
it's it's been a grind. I started
posting like a year ago. Nine I've I've
been posting for nine months on
Instagram and this is my first video to
break 10k. It it like got half a million
views. This is the first video to break
10k? Yeah. And then the other ones like
behind it like those ones hit after like
later. Yo.
And then everything else climbed after
10 10 11 17.
Yo, congrats actually, bro. I feel like
I I know we've talked about like these
small things like um how do you make it
relatable to other relatable to other
high schoolers? I think this is fire.
Varsity basketball. Dude, this is
awesome, man. I mean, is there any like
thoughts that you have on this or like
[ __ ] we could just say congratulations,
call it a day like I'm just trying to
replicate this and try to get it like
more videos like this. You know,
actually there's like an NBA player who
commented on this video, too. Like from
from Houston, like the city I'm from.
Jabari Smith Jr., yeah. He plays for the
Rockets. Like I'm
I was like dang, crazy. Wait, this is
fire. Let let me see.
>> head coach of my school's varsity team
saw one of my videos and told my friend
that varsity isn't realistic for me. He
said he's looking to build a serious
program and that I should aim for JV
instead. To be honest, he's right. Right
now, I'm nowhere near varsity level. I
can barely dribble the ball, my shooting
is horrendous, and I have no
athleticism. But what I do have is time.
Dude, this is awesome. Wait, I love the
vulnerability here. Like, I actually
relate to this very deeply cuz I told I
got told the exact same thing as about
soccer when I was in high school. So,
your question was just like how do you
double down? I actually think like
there's So, there's two things. One is
obviously day blank of journey to high
school varsity basketball. I think
that's a winner. Like, you just keep
going with it. Let me see the other
hooks. This is day 20 of my journey to
becoming a high school varsity
basketball player. On my last video,
lots of people Let me see the visual
hook for this. This is day 19 of my
journey. This is day 21 of my journey to
becoming a high school varsity
basketball player. Today, I bike to a
court so I can put some shots up on a
10-ft rim. I think the one thing that
made this one hit is the vulnerability
aspect of like your coach telling you
that you're not going to make it. Which
is such like It's all really It's
already a relatable thing to be like,
"Yo, I want to get to high school
varsity in any sport, right?" Every
single high schooler who's ever touched
a sport thinks about that, whether
they're making to varsity or like how do
they succeed in varsity, whatever. And
then the second component, which hits
even deeper. Like, with hooks, I always
like to think about what is a vulnerable
detail that other people are thinking
that they're too afraid to say. And
that's exactly it. Your coach told you
that you're like that you're going to
get cut. That's a perfect. How do you
hit those kind of sentences that are
vulnerable like that in the hook or in
the first couple sentences? That's the
golden like I I actually think that's
the golden ticket right here. Like, how
do you turn 400K into like multiple
extra 100K view videos, you know? Or
like even like up to a million plus. I
think that's like how do you make it
feel really vulnerable in the first
sentence? Like, cuz you can talk about
what you did in your day, but doesn't
hit the emotions as hard as like this
person told me this or I overheard from
a friend or like the other day my
friends saw my like one of the the
captain of the team saw my video and
they said blah blah blah blah blah. Or
like I guess struggles honestly. I think
of like relatable struggles, especially
in journey based content, as like if you
can nail down those relatable struggle
points that make people be like, "Damn,
I'm going through that too, but I would
never tell a single soul that." Those
are the gold mine sentences. You're just
saying to I guess be more vulnerable in
the videos cuz like the other videos I
posted after this I was kind of just
going through what I was doing every
day, but I'll try to like have a story
and emotion and all that.
>> Yeah. When I When I think of structure,
I just think of like so you have the
hook, right? Today is day blank road to
high school varsity basketball. I think
if I were to like really templatize it
here, that's the hook, sentence one.
Sentence two is a vulnerable detail.
Like I would prompt you to ask yourself
like what is one vulnerable detail that
somebody would find relatable? Extra
bonus points if you know that it's
something relatable but other people
would not be brave enough to share. And
then number three, then you can go into
what you did today. I would kind of
templatize it like that as like a very
simple template where you hit them with
the one-two combo of the first and
second sentence. And then by that point
they're sold enough to like be curious
about like, "Okay, so what are you doing
to actually prepare for that? What does
your day look like?" etc. So it kind of
gives you permission to then talk about
your day by hitting that like one-two
combo in the first two sentences. And
then from there, you kind of have them.
You have you you've hooked them, you
know? And I think I see that in this day
19 video. But dude, congrats, man. I saw
the video I saw the message yesterday, I
think, in the general chat, man. Like
genuinely congrats, dude. I'm so happy
for you, bro.
Yo, first call. Thanks for pulling up,
bro. Um
And this video figured out viral.
>> And you wanted to recreate it. Yeah, if
you want to give any more context, bro.
That was my first video that ever went
viral. So I've been creating content for
a while. I started a year. I didn't grow
anything. I was stuck at 180 followers
for a whole year. And so I decided to
delete my account and started to create
decided to create a new one about 4
weeks ago and I got my first viral video
which is insane. Wow. Wait, that's
awesome, bro. It's also sick because
this wasn't even like crazy b-roll or
anything. Like this is just you talking.
This is This is awesome. So, what was
your question? What made this video
special because I I really tried to
recreate it, but I haven't been able to
get the same virality. I've got other
videos that have gone 20,000 views or
5,000 views, but not the same as this
one. So, I do want to say it's usually
one small thing and like a 10%
incremental increase can make a video go
10 times as like or like maybe like a
50% better hook retention could
literally lead to like 10 times the
views, by the way. So, often times like
I would probably guess that most of your
videos are like 90% similar. I tend to
make my content more less cinematic and
to be honest, I've been getting a lot of
messages too about how people are
relating to my content which is insane
and I only been posting for 4 weeks and
a lot of people have messaging me on my
content and I only have like 700
followers. It's I don't know. It's
crazy. So, I'm trying to keep my account
more raw. Yeah, I mean I like this
format a lot. I think especially like if
you can make a video that doesn't
require you to edit. That's like harder
to do cuz you can't fraud people with
the b-roll and the music and whatever.
It's just you with the viewer and I
think it also makes for more like
connected video. So, that's awesome. Let
me try to really
piece apart. Body's insanely [music]
beautiful and I don't mean it in a cheap
thirsty way. I don't even like women.
No, I'm just kidding, but I mean it in a
sacred artistic [music]
way. I love the curves, the softness,
the design. That's nature's [music]
masterpiece and it shouldn't be
objectified the way it is objectified. I
love to often times also look at the
comments to see what people say. So,
there's a lot of people agreeing with
like the artistry of this. So, it's like
philosophy
>> Actually, I think I think that's a gap
that I found because a lot of a lot of
men are too scared to say what they
actually think about women. And I I've
seen a lot of messages of guys agreeing
with that, but also women, which is
insane. And I'm not sure I know I think
a lot of women like when men talk about
them. I don't know if that's true, but I
I've seen it because most of my videos
that have gone viral, that have gone
about 20 20k views, are of me talking
about women in a respectful way that's
that is. I think you actually like the
reason why this video went viral, I
think it was actually hidden in one of
the lines in the script. I think it's
when you say like, and I don't mean that
in like a weird like What What is it
like perverted way or like or thirsty
way? Or yeah, thirsty way. A lustful or
thirsty way. I think what's interesting
about the fact that you said that is
like you're kind of cognizant of the
fact that people are probably going to
be like judging you for the sentence
that you said, which means that it's an
impactful sentence that makes people
like
It almost makes people like, "He said He
said that, yo, like yo, what? Like,
aren't people going to think he's like
mad thirsty for that? Like, yo, what?"
Exactly. That's the sign like I almost
think that's like a internal process you
can think about. It's like Yes, I I also
tried testing that sentence in other in
other in other videos, and actually I
think that sentence is helping a lot
because of some As I said it, other
videos have gotten me around 20k views
or 5,000 views when I add that sentence.
And maybe that's that's the sentence
that I may maybe need to switch it out
in or try to test it in different ways.
Yeah, I I would say so. It's like Let me
Let me try and find the the actual video
that you sent. It's not just on trial
reels, right? It's It's up on the your
main page? I I didn't post it on trial
reels. I tried I've been trying to post
on trial reels, but Instagram detected
and it blocks my video. It doesn't allow
me to post it. And I tried changing it,
too, and it's still detected. I don't
know why. I see it in this video, too. I
know it's not like, you know, not
anywhere like as viral, but like I once
liked a girl so much that I couldn't
look at her in a lustful way. I do think
there's like and it depends on if you
want to go down this niche. I know like
the relationships niche, like dating,
relationships, videos about like a
crush, those videos hit like one of the
most, I guess like deep, vulnerable,
emotional places in viewers, you know,
and in us as people. Versus let's say
something about like the gym. It's like,
yes, the gym is like a very, you know,
there's a whole niche around it, yes,
what not, but I would argue actually
like a lot of the gym content somewhat
has this undertone of dating. Just like
looks maxing, too, it like has this
undertone of like wanting to get
approval from girls. So, I I think
you've almost niche here of like dating,
relationships. I'm testing everything. I
like to talk about everything. I'm I'm
seeing what's working, what's working
for me and what's not, and I'm I'm
putting more work on the things that
that is that are working for me right
now, which is the those videos about
women. And I'm posting more on trial
reels, more I record about 10 videos of
talking about women, and then I post
them on trial reels, and I'm seeing what
is working, and then I I'll try to
recreate it and post it on the main
feed. I I think that's cool. Like, I'm
trying to think cuz everything else,
like let's say like just general general
motivation, like prove to yourself
people won't believe you anyways. Like,
I guess it doesn't feel as like
emotionally shocking or striking as like
a something that cuz it I guess it
doesn't paint you in like a
risky way. It's like the sentence is
just like, oh, yeah, this person's a
normal person. Actually, also, those
videos, the ones that I record on car
videos, I've been recording those, and
those are about two two one to two
minutes long, and I've been getting even
though they are not getting a lot of
views, I've the beginning and a lot of
messages from people saying that they
really like that type of content. So, I
think that's it could be my bottom
funnel. I think that's what you guys
call it, bottom funnel, which gives me
more credibility. Well, I I I like that.
I think you can also kind of view
getting followers as a funnel. It's like
people might find you for like one
individual video, but then like they
might follow you after they get to learn
who you actually are, like your story,
and that can be a longer video that
might not get as many views. So, a lot
of times people pin to the top of their
page like a video about their story.
That helps kind of be like a high
converting video. Maybe not converting
sales, but converting followers. Cuz
people actually get to know you, see who
you're about, and then they feel
connected more so than like
you know, talking just about yourself.
Also, another question I had about the
video that I posted about the series
that I wanted to start. And actually, I
was thinking about it and I realized
that I've been doing something that I
could actually just put it out there and
it's more risky, I guess, and people
could follow and see the results faster,
which I'm writing my first book. And I
was I was trying to I will try to frame
it as a way
writing a book and publishing it in less
than 60 days is it possible in some way
some way like that? I think that's a
better series to start.
>> I I like that. I think it's something
that people can tune back into. And it's
shorter, too. I mean, people can follow
faster and see the results if it's
possible or not. Is there any way that
you can tell me how to frame it, how to
name the series the series, or maybe the
first video for the hook? I actually
think the hook can be something like
that sound a sentence that sounds very
artistic. Like I I imagined it this cuz
if you lead with like today I I wrote
one page of my book. It's like dog, I
don't know who you are. Scroll. But if
you say something like very poetic as
the first sentence and you say, "So, I
was writing about this today as I'm
writing my book." And then you make the
video not about, "Hey guys, I'm a
writer. Please follow my book." You make
it about what you actually wrote about
that day. Or maybe it's like one of the
parts of your book. So it's subtly
marketing the book. It's not making it
explicit like, "Guys, check out this
book I'm writing. Guys, please follow me
cuz I'm writing a book and I need you
guys to like follow me cuz I'm writing
the book and you guys need to buy a
little booklet like, you know, it feels
very salesy if you say like, "Today's
day one of my like writing a book, blah
blah blah." That's what I was thinking.
I want to I was thinking of adding this
a little a little part of my book every
day to hook the person to keep the
person hooked. I'll I'll I'll send you a
screenshot of a little part that I
wrote. As I said, I've started writing
it already, but I never actually wanted
to I don't know why I didn't want to put
it out there yet. Put a screenshot in
the chat.
>> "Sometimes you become a monster in the
eyes of the world is the price one pays
to protect what he loved." Yeah, I feel
like you could kind of just leave with
that as the hook and then be like, "This
is a line from a book I'm writing." And
then go into the the rest of the video.
Like I I feel like that's a you weave it
in, but you don't make the whole video
about like, "Guys, I'm writing a book
I'm book book like my book me me me me
me." You make it more about the message
that you're saying. Yeah, I I guess
you're right. Maybe I could start with
the last line as a hook, but try to
frame it more so it sounds spooky.
Yeah. But I'm I'm I'm I'm going to try
that and see see what happens. I'm going
to start tomorrow. My last question, do
you do you think it's fine if I post as
many times as I can every day? Because
for me it's really easy. I can literally
record 20 videos in 2 hours and then
because most of my videos are raw. I
don't really edit them. I don't really
add any B rolls or anything like that.
Yeah, I would go for it, dude. I would
say like, and I'm sure you already do
this and I'm sure you already know this.
Just try every day to find patterns.
Because once you collect that much data,
it's not just data of like, "Okay,
you're shooting shots." It's like you're
not just gambling. Like you're
collecting data to see what works. And
then let's say at the end of every 20
videos, you could also be like, "Okay,
what worked? What didn't? What hit?
Which hooks hit? Which hooks didn't?" If
you approach it with that lens, too,
like the rate of improvement is going to
be like exponential, you know? No, I I'm
actually getting better because I
try to record at least four videos raw
four videos every single day and I'm
noticing that I'm improving slowly
slowly I'm improving on my hooks and my
videos are getting more views and I'm
getting me more followers which is
insane. The videos that take me less
than two minutes to record are the ones
that do better than the ones that take
me two one hour to script and then
record which is insane, bro. Thank you
so much for watching. By this point we
average around like 10 to 20% retention
on these videos because it's actual
practical sauce which means 80% of the
tire kickers who've never posted a video
before are gone. But if you're still
here, genuinely props to you. I have one
request. Comment down below what you
found helpful from this videos. I'm
always looking to make these videos
better on this channel. With that being
said, thank you so much for watching,
bro. I appreciate you. Hella gang, we're
almost at 30k subs. Holy [ __ ] All
right, I'll catch y'all in the next
video. Peace.