So, I created a brand new Instagram
account to see how much I could make in
just 1 month of posting Instagram Reels.
And after 1 month, the account grew to
40,000 followers with just 15 videos,
but not just that. I did something
called UGC, and in total, I earned
[music] $5,000
from posting UGC videos to this [music]
brand new Instagram account. So, I made
an entire full masterclass breaking down
exactly how I hit my first 5K [music]
month with UGC in just 30 days, how
beginners are getting off opportunities,
and how you can get started earning from
content without having any [music]
experience. So, the way UGC works is
basically brands will pay you between 50
to even up to a thousand dollars per
video that you post promoting their app
on a brand new Instagram account. Now,
everyday college students, 9-to-5ers are
building full-time incomes off of this
thing called UGC. So, let's get into it.
For you guys today, I have prepared how
to make $10,000 a month with content in
2026, and I'm [ __ ] hyped. Just so you
guys know that I actually know what I'm
talking about social media. 30 days ago
I or not 30 days ago, it was a little
over, but I basically posted 15 videos
on this brand new account, grew it from
zero to 30K followers, and I'm going to
be relating the experiences that I've
learned not only to grow this account,
but also to grow my other personal brand
on Instagram, obviously to a large
following. So, who am I? Why am I
yabbering and jabbering on the screen
telling you guys that I'm going to teach
you all these things posing the stream
to you that I can help you achieve
things with content creation. What gives
me that level of insane confidence? And
why should you listen to me in this
presentation? So, my name's Ben O'Leary,
and I've been creating content now for
the past 5 years, and I have grown four
accounts to over 150,000 followers
across TikTok and Instagram.
I started in April of 2020.
So, I've been through many eras of trend
hopping. I used to make comedy videos,
and I grew this account to 900,000
followers at the bottom left. Then I
started making productivity videos, then
I started making vlogs, then I started
making some videos in college about
studying, and then I finally ended up
here where I help other people build
personal brands and start their own
content creation journeys.
The reason why I say this is because I
want to show you that I actually have a
diverse experience in helping with
content. I am not just one person who
got lucky and blew up off of one
concept, one video style. There's a lot
of creators out there who will tell you,
"I know how to blow up with content
creation." but they've only blown up one
account or they've only tried one viral
format. I have probably tried pretty
much every single format I've seen, I
have tried, and probably at least gotten
a million plus views with on these
accounts. Just to show you that
everything you are learning today is the
first principles understanding of how to
go viral with social media, and then how
to apply that to actually make money,
build this a career for you guys. Okay?
And now it is my personal mission to
make content creation an accessible and
sustainable career path for anyone.
Okay?
Now, I'm no fortune teller, but I do
believe content creation will become a
larger and larger space throughout the
next couple years. So, this is where
I've poured a lot of my eggs into. I am
genuinely such a firm believer that
content creation unlocks so many of our
creative potentials. I believe that
content creation is such a
transformative experience. It's helped
me throughout my own personal
development journey for the past several
years.
And I want to help as many people as
possible continue in that journey and
then actually turning it into real
incomes so they can do it full-time,
create full-time, and eventually build
businesses, create movements.
And I believe that's the power of a
personal brand.
And now, to do that, I run an agency and
a paid community that trains content
creators, teaches them how to go viral,
and then I also help give them actual
paid opportunities with brands. So, I
don't just teach them now, we also help
hire creators to brands. All that to
say, everything that I do nowadays is
pretty much to help content creators.
And that is who is teaching you in this
presentation. So, if you give me the
next 90 minutes, I promise you that I
will help teach everything that I've
learned
from helping
over 10 people last year make 10k a
month with content. Some of these people
even 15-year-olds like Seb here in this
little corner. He made 10k a month at 15
years old and he's from Indonesia. Other
people running businesses like Thomas.
He made 42k and I I believe that's a
span of 2 weeks.
And then a bunch of other people with
UGC as well, what we're going to be
learning today.
I've also helped many people hit 10,000
plus followers in their first year. Here
are just some of our students from our
paid community content academy.
And here are some other people from our
paid community content academy who
achieved even more insane results that
got past 100,000 followers with their
social media followings. And this is
what I'm going to be teaching you guys
today, how to get started in this
journey and eventually achieve the
results that these guys have.
Okay?
And this is not to brag.
I want to prove to you what you are
capable of when you will apply what
we're going to learn together today.
Now, big picture, I don't want to
overwhelm you guys. I would say I've
broken down the content creation journey
all the way from posting your first
video all the way to 10k a month and
there's a lot of steps in between that.
And that's what our business does,
content academy. We train people getting
them through each of these steps from
posting their first video all the way to
starting monetizing, all the way to
building their following to their first
thousand, 10,000 followers, all the way
to getting the first 10k months. This is
not to overwhelm you. I just want to let
you know this is a big picture of what
the journey looks like. And I want to
simplify this as much as possible by
giving you guys the nuggets of wisdom to
get through, especially these first few
steps here of posting your first video,
getting momentum as a creator, and then
stacking up wins. That is what I want to
get you guys today, your first few wins
so you can start getting your
exponential growth journey started
today. So, that starts with you just
hitting post.
And if there's anything that any of you
guys who put a zero in the chat can take
away from today's presentation, please.
If you can do anything here, just hit
post. And even if you haven't made a
video yet, or if you Sorry, if you have
been making videos, but you maybe feel a
little stuck, or you feel a little lost,
just hit post. Regardless, that is the
number one thing that I always try to
remind myself as a creator as well. So,
this presentation is Content MBA, and it
is the full workshop to make $10,000 a
month with simple videos on your phone.
Now, I'm going to make this real clear
for you. By the end of the class, I'm
going to give you two things, okay? Not
only am I going to give you all of these
lessons here, what is UGC and how to
land your first deal with no followers,
how I've seen multiple of my students do
that, an interactive workshop, making
your first video with me live, write
your first viral video. I'm going to
walk you guys through the exact viral
video process that I teach all of my
students, and that I repeat on a daily
basis. And then lastly, the road map
from a beginner to 10k a month as a
creator, and how to get there.
Not only that, I'm also going to give
you a bonus at the end of this, a bonus
offer.
And it's a $97 workbook covering exactly
what we're teaching today, how to get
your first deal,
right? And a jump start to get your
first first couple wins as a creator.
It's 26 pages long, it's a full PDF, and
it's going to teach you the basics of
UGC and a guide to making your first
video. I have a couple helpful templates
in there.
But at the end of today's workshop,
during our Q&A,
this PDF will be yours to keep. For not
$97,
but for free.
As long as you stay live until the end.
Now, why did I leave it until the end?
Because I know a lot of you guys are
just going to try and get the PDF, and
then if you try and understand it now,
you're not going to have the context to
actually be able to apply it. I want you
guys to actually stay locked in with me.
So, if you want all the free sauce, stay
tuned with me today. I want you guys to
genuinely get nuggets of sauce so you
can apply instantly tonight and tomorrow
to start posting and to start getting
your getting your content creation
journeys started. I saw somebody saying
0% attention span. All right, for those
of you guys who are actually locked in
with me,
and I know all of us here have
short-form attention spans. Our brains
are rotted, mine included. I'm going to
try and explain this as simple as
possible so a five-year-old can
understand it, and I'm going to move
quickly. So, guys, stay tuned with me.
Let's start off. True or false?
It is harder now than ever to make your
first dollar with content creation.
Because a lot of people say that content
creation is now saturated with way more
competition.
Everybody here Yo, we got 340 people in
here all interested in starting content
creation. That's a lot of competition,
arguably. That's a lot of people trying
to compete with each other in this
content game.
Right?
Now, here's why.
Four years ago, businesses literally
spent half as much on social media
marketing. It makes sense. Four years
ago, TikTok and Instagram Reels were
practically brand new. So, four years
ago, businesses spent literally half as
much as they do now on social media
marketing. Their budgets now have quite
literally doubled. And I'll show you
guys where this budget is going into
later and how you guys can actually take
advantage of it.
But in 2020, just to really prove to you
that the game is actually easier now.
When I had 100,000 TikTok followers back
in 2020, I did my first ever brand deal.
I was 16 years old. I was new to TikTok,
but I had somehow grown 100,000
followers in the comedy space.
Right? And I did a brand deal. I got
paid 20 bucks.
Nowadays, I see students that I work
with all the time who are making $1,000
in their first month doing UGC.
And they don't have massive followings.
They don't have even over Some A lot of
them don't even have over 10,000
followers. Okay?
In fact, in one of our last workshops,
there was a guy named Ricky who joined
our community after and said they made
their first online money
after submitting a video through one of
the processes that we're going to learn
today.
And he just said like he'd never do it
before. So, this is the same
presentation that there are other people
applying to actually make their first
dollar. And when you make your first
dollar, like I I'm joking about the $20
that I made back then,
but that genuinely helped build the
belief in me that this online money
thing is real
and eventually turned it for me from
just a side hustle that I was doing on
the side to my full-time income now as a
22-year-old. Right? My business now is
literally hit like 100k plus months. And
the whole It's all centered around me
being able to make viral content on a
consistent basis.
Right? This is everything This is all
the sauce that I'm regularly doing to
make a full-time income. Many of my
students are doing to make a full-time
income.
Right? But I believe it starts with
getting your first dollar online.
And then that's how you build the
momentum to actually then turn it into a
full-time income. You need at least
1,000 followers to land paid brand
deals. Now, I told you there are people
with under 10,000 followers who landed
their first paid deals, but do you need
at least 1,000 followers?
It's false. And I'll show you exactly
why. So, 3 years ago, like I said, you
actually did need a following. There
were no opportunities as far as I had
ever seen, as far as I had ever known,
to make money without a following.
Back then it was the age of influencer
marketing, the Charlie D'Amelios, the
Dixie D'Amelios, the big celebrities.
And you need to build an actual name for
yourself.
Practically be a celebrity on the app to
actually make realistically any money.
But back in 2020, 100,000 followers got
me the equivalent of a Chipotle bowl
and a bubble tea.
Now, I was actually pretty happy with
that, but it's pretty absurd for getting
100,000 followers.
But in the past 3 years, a couple things
have changed.
And this is why I'm able to literally
tell you guys now it is easier than
ever, if you know what you're doing, to
make your first dollar with content
creation.
In the past 3 years, a couple things
have changed and it's due to the
algorithms on social media. So, now more
than ever and it's moving more and more
towards this, the algorithms on TikTok
and Instagram care way more about
retention than follower count. So,
creators with a lot of followers now are
falling off because they still live in
this old system of thinking you need to
be a celebrity. I'm just thinking, "Oh,
as long as I have a name for myself
online, people are just going to watch
whatever I put out." That's not how it
works anymore. All the attention is
going to newer creators who actually
learn how to make high retention content
and that's exactly what I teach inside
our community and that's exactly what
I'm going to teach you guys today. Okay?
Retention is basically how long you keep
viewers watching your videos. It's the
art and science of keeping viewers
watching your videos, keeping random
strangers on the internet watching your
videos.
And it sounds really simple and it is,
but it's not easy. There's a very
There's a lot of different things.
There's hooks, there's angles, there's
visual hooks, there's editing. And I'm
going to cover as much as I can, but it
is a complicated art.
But, people who have actually spent the
time to learn it, I can tell you have
been massively rewarded. Like Alfonso,
right? He started UGC and in literally 2
months, he hit 14K in a single month
creating UGC for one of these brands
here.
Right? This is his win this channel on
our Discord server. He was just shouting
out the community
W Content Academy. But, it's crazy cuz
he actually got this opportunity while
having only 170 followers on Instagram.
It's nuts. He got this opportunity This
is a newer screenshot of his account.
Alfonso's an incredible creator, but he
got this opportunity without needing a
large following.
Here's another example.
And this is one of the longer stories.
Richard. He was a 23-year-old software
engineer and he joined our community in
July of 2025.
And he was starting content creation cuz
he wanted to learn how to help his
family friends business. And you can see
at the bottom here, he actually only
posted five videos when he first
started. So you're probably wondering,
oh wow, like man, five videos, that's
insane. Like I've posted more than that.
That's awesome. Because five days later
after joining our community, he was
celebrating getting his first video that
got a thousand views. Right? It's
actually like this is a good win, I
would say. And if you haven't yet, it's
okay. Like this is a good win that you
want to strive for. This is what we tell
all of our community members who are
newer to content, celebrate these small
wins, like even a thousand views. It's
not viral, but it's not viral yet, and
I'll show you guys why. 18 days later,
he was able to get his first UGC
opportunity.
And this was around when he was getting
his first 10,000 view video.
But just a hundred days later, he sent
this into our Discord server.
Right?
He got 20 million views for a brand by
applying all the systems that we teach
inside our community, and then they paid
him $16,000 in a single month doing this
thing called UGC. So when I tell you
there are so many beginners who are
starting content and making a [ __ ]
bag, yo, I mean it. This is why you
probably have heard a little bit about
UGC before if you have already, right?
This is probably one of the best
opportunities for beginners to actually
start monetizing with content creation.
There genuinely has never been such a
good opportunity to get paid as a
[ __ ] beginner. This is coming from
somebody who spent like seven months
building a following of a hundred
thousand followers, still could only
make 20 bucks his first year as a
creator.
So here's how. Richard was posting
daily, and he applied the content
systems to make higher retention videos
that I'm going to give you today.
Okay? Just get you all excited for what
we're going to cover today. So,
these videos, I really want to make
clear, they don't need to be cinematic
or complex. I think a lot of people view
content creation either from the lens of
becoming a celebrity, and it's man, I
just have to be really good looking, or
man, I just have to be like hot or I
just need to I don't know, I just need
to show my boobs or something or it's
ah, I just need to have a complex
camera. I need to have an expensive
camera and that's what's stopping me
from blowing up on social media. I need
to buy equipment and it costs a lot of
money.
In [snorts] reality,
this is Richard, right? The creator I
told you who made $16,000 in a single
month. Now, this video, the editing and
the storytelling might seem a little bit
complex, but I really want to highlight
this was all filmed from an iPhone.
Right? Everybody here has a phone that
they're tuned in from. My my social
media
promoting this live class has been from
iPhone videos. So, you guys all have an
iPhone here. You guys all have at least
an Android phone.
Like, you have to understand, I really
want you to picture that this is
somebody who's probably started content
at similar time as you,
right?
And was able to not only make all of
this on his iPhone, edit all of this on
his iPhone, but generate 28,000 likes on
this video by learning how to go viral,
mastering higher attention content,
and he was able to even land a UGC deal
with this company called WhisperFlow,
which is basically it's like a dictation
AI on your MacBook.
It's a very simple AI company, right?
And they paid him $16,000 in a single
month for making iPhone videos.
And businesses right now are actually
really leaning heavily towards hiring
regular students and 9-to-5ers to make
talking head UGC videos. A lot of
businesses that I speak to who are
hiring creators specifically want
students. They want college students or
they want people working in 9-to-5s.
And the reason why is because your lives
are really
relatable and a lot of products are
actually built around
9-to-5ers and students.
And that's been like a big reason why a
lot of these creators have succeeded.
Like, why is LeBron teaching me history?
A lot of the successful UGC content is
actually it's made about study tools
like study apps.
Right? So if you're a student, I highly
recommend you especially lock the [ __ ]
in. It's one of the best side hustles as
a student. So if you want to pay for any
trips that you're going on as a student
in college, if you want to pay for [ __ ]
if you want to be that friend who's able
to ball out and just eat out whenever he
wants, like
UGC's probably one of the best side
hustles to actually build that level of
income and build it as a complete
beginner.
Now, what is UGC? UGC very simply, I
don't want you guys to overcomplicate it
cuz it's a big word, user-generated
content. All it really means is getting
paid to make videos for businesses that
they can use for their marketing. So the
only thing that you really need is one,
being able to actually find these brands
and actually be able to get hired into
them. And then secondly, learn how to
make viral videos that they then will
will actually want to use for the
marketing. So it's these two things. So
you need to essentially have access to
the opportunities and you need training
on how to learn how to make higher
attention content.
So how do these payments actually work?
Right? Cuz I'm talking about how Richard
made $16,000 in a single month. Alfonso
made $14,000 in a single month.
Here's the actual very simple process.
So you take your phone, right? You're
going to write a script using one of the
proven script templates. Most UGC videos
are literally using copy-paste scripts.
Okay?
Then,
you send it to the brand. Sometimes
you'll just send it literally over an
iMessage. Sometimes it'll be through a
platform or a Discord server.
And then whoever's running the UGC
program, whoever essentially works at
the brand who manages all the creators,
will give you feedback or they'll
approve the video. Nine times out of 10
they'll just approve it. Right? As long
as you're not swearing in the video, as
long as you're not doing something
insane, as long as you're not insulting
the brand that you're getting paid to
promote, you'll get approved. And what's
nice is that once you post it onto your
UGC accounts, you just make a new
Instagram or make a new TikTok profile
to make videos for these brands, and you
just get paid out. So, literally just
like that. The feedback loop can
literally happen in a day.
So, a lot of creators are making between
50 and a couple hundred bucks a day from
doing this, just for making videos.
Because all you have to do is show up,
make a video, use their proven scripts,
post it onto these two platforms, TikTok
and Instagram, and get a payout. And you
just repeat daily for an infinite money
glitch.
Now, most UGC payment structures look
like this. Okay? And I know this all
sounds complicated cuz there's a lot of
big words, but at the core, there's two
things. There's one, a retainer that you
get paid no matter what, just for
showing up and just for posting. So,
once you get accepted into these
opportunities,
you literally just get paid for showing
up, even as a beginner.
And then secondly, you have infinite
upside. So, this opportunity
specifically paid $1 per thousand views.
What does that mean?
If you got a million views, you would
get a thousand dollars.
And now you can make a million view
video if you know the system, you can
make a million view video, and it can
take you one or two hours.
Okay?
So, there's a world where a lot of UGC
creators who have actually mastered the
skill of making high retention videos,
they're pumping out a video, and once a
week they're getting a viral video. So,
they're probably putting in 10 hours of
work a week, and they're getting a
thousand or multiple thousands of
dollars a week.
Okay? And I actually tried this out.
In December, I made a new Instagram
account.
I'll show you guys this is actually new
Instagram
account I made. I posted just 15 videos,
and because obviously I have a lot of
experience in making content, and
virality is a repeatable system, I know
a lot of you guys here are talking
about, "Oh, I don't know how to make
content. I'm stuck in 300 view jail."
Once you actually learn the system, you
can just repeat it across any platform
that you have. So, I started a new
account to test this thesis. I posted 15
videos,
and
for the 15 videos, I got paid $5,000 in
a single month. This is This is the
literal screenshot of the money getting
sent into my bank account.
And I probably put in a cumulative 30
hours of work into making these videos.
Right? So, it was $5,000 for 30 hours of
a side hustle.
Obviously, I still have my main business
to run, and I was still doing that in
that month, but I got paid 5K for a nice
little side hustle. So, that's a nice
little picture of what UGC can look like
once you're just putting in the effort
and learning the skill.
Okay?
But, posting is simple at the end of the
day. Like I said, the simple the
system's really simple. You just make
videos, get them approved,
and then get paid.
But, it's not easy. Going viral is the
complicated part that requires practice
and training.
But, just for you guys, today I'll teach
you guys how to get your first win with
content creation to start your journey.
So, let's start off with the pro tips of
how to post your first video. So,
pro tip for all of you guys who've not
posted your first video yet.
I highly recommend this style of
content. A lot of people on Tik Tok call
this the higher up wellness speaking
challenge.
A great way to practice posting your
first video is just treating it like an
exercise to get better at public
speaking.
So, you might be listening to me and
say, "Wow, this guy's pretty capable of
speaking off the fly." It's because I've
posted thousands of videos, and I've
just practiced over and over again,
showing up, putting down a camera, and
practicing the skill of talking straight
for 60 seconds.
And I highly recommend if you haven't
posted any videos yet, try it.
Literally, open up a camera and do this.
I'll literally simulate simulate it for
you guys.
You can do this literally right after
the class, right after we hop off, and
I'll do it in the back camera just to
prove to you guys.
Today is day one of posting every single
day to pub practice my public speaking
and not trip over my words and mumble
and stumble over my words. I am not
exactly sure what I'm going to say in
the rest of this video, but I'm here on
a live webinar,
and I'm really trying to not use the
words like or because I have a very
strong habit of using these words, but
I'm just going to keep talking until the
timer gets to 60 seconds. I'm not going
to actually finish the video cuz I don't
want to waste your guys' time, but that
is literally what a lot of videos these
videos on TikTok look like. Okay? It is
that simple. I don't want you guys to
overcomplicate it if you've never posted
a video before cuz the main thing that I
want you guys to do is show up and feel
good about showing up. Regardless even
if you are a bit more experienced
[snorts] to content. In fact, me as a
person with 500,000 followers, sometimes
I will get into a slump and then I would
just be like, "Okay, I'm not going to
place any expectations on myself. I just
need to show up." It's like maybe you've
taken a month off on holiday and you
haven't exercised in a while. You're not
going to jump straight back into the
most intense workout and try to lift the
heaviest weight you ever have. No.
You're going to set your expectations
low and just reward yourself pat on the
back for showing up. And the same goes
with content. I am a firm believer in
this. Do not beat yourself up and do not
compare your views with other creators
when you're first starting out cuz this
is all a mental game.
It's just one cesspool of comparison
bias that's going to make you feel worse
about yourself.
And if there's anything that I implore
all of my students, right? The 50-plus
who have hit 10,000-plus followers, none
of them go into it with a perfectionist
mindset. All of them go into it with
just a yo, I feel good about showing up
and I'm putting in the work every day
even if the numbers don't reflect it.
Cuz it's crazy until it works. And
obviously building the viral content
skill set takes time and practice. I'm
not going to promise to you that you
post a video tomorrow and it's going to
get 2 million views like this guy who
posted his day one video, which is
pretty [ __ ] insane. That can happen.
You can have a lucky case like that.
But at the end of the day it takes
practice and I want you to feel good and
get comfortable practicing. Now, to post
your first video, one other pro tip is
create a new secret Instagram account.
Like you if you knew none of your
friends would watch your videos, you
would post as much as you want. You
would post more passionately.
You would be maybe more expressive on
camera.
But because well, you don't want to lose
aura with the husband or something, you
don't want to maybe lose aura on your
public Instagram, so you're like, "Fuck,
bro.
I'mma be a little bit more nonchalant
type shit."
That's me, bro. I'm not even going to
lie.
Like, I remember thinking, "Damn, my
Instagram is dead ass going to help It's
going to make it harder for me to find a
girlfriend."
Like, I remember thinking that. I was
like, "Bro, I post my entire life. I
look like such a try-hard, and I feel
like girls just want Duke Girls want
Duke Dennis. They don't want me."
Now, very fortunately, I was able to
find a very happy relationship with my
girlfriend, but so just so you know, it
didn't actually stop me from
being able to get a girlfriend. I
actually think it helped me find someone
who who actually realized could accept
like me for me.
But,
I I feel it. That's all That's all I'm
trying to say. I don't know why I made
this whole tangent on dating, but
I have a little hack for you guys, okay?
Post videos on a secret Instagram
account, and actually feel free to block
your friends. Block your friends on this
new secret Instagram account. I know
that sounds OD,
but if it stops you from making videos,
and you're constantly overthinking it
like I have for really long, just block
your friends. Honestly, that's going to
save you a little bit of hassle. I
remember like overhearing
that
some of my friends were thinking my
older videos were cringe, and that's
when I really put my heart and soul into
these videos. I remember I talked about
my like self-improvement, my gym
journey. I was super vulnerable online
about all of my struggles, and I
remember I had friends like I overheard
friends. They didn't say it directly to
my face. I was like, "Man, like this is
kind of cringe, man. Like, why is Meena
trying to do all that?"
And it like did hurt my feelings a lot.
And I'm really grateful that it didn't
stop me, but just so you know,
if you want to start posting content,
but you're afraid people are going to
judge you and talk [ __ ] about you, they
probably will.
And it's fine. And this is like a
natural part because nobody else is
going to understand your vision and your
goals,
right? I can stand out I can stand up
here and be like, "Yo, my passion is to
help content creators." And that
probably sounds hella cringe, like I'm
just like a hella try hard and [ __ ]
Man, this dude
Or like some of my friends too probably
look at me like, "Yo, this guy is just a
course seller, bro." Like they don't But
they don't see the actual lives that I
have helped. They don't see all the
people who have been inside my community
and said thank you. And I have to remind
myself, just as you guys have to remind
yourselves, that like why are you
actually posting content? It's not for
other people, it's for yourself.
So, you can block other friends to help
you
not getting your own way.
Okay?
Sorry. A little bit of a personal
tangent here, but
a new account is also a good way to
build a portfolio.
Now, a lot of brands, let's connect it
back to making money for a second. A lot
of brands want to know whether you're
actually going to be consistent. That is
the number one thing.
It's
UGC is essentially like a remote online
job. And the worst thing that a brand
can do
is hire you, give you training, give you
scripts, right? Invest the time into you
just for you to post two videos and then
[ __ ] off.
So, the number one thing that you can
prove to brands so they actually feel
confident about hiring you and get a way
higher likelihood of actually getting
accepted into these super lucrative UGC
opportunities is post consistently on a
new account.
So, if you haven't posted yet or you're
a very on and off with content, there's
a chance that brands might be really
hesitant to hire you because you haven't
shown proof online that you can be
consistent. So, a big playbook for a lot
of you guys,
create a new secret account, block your
friends if you need to,
so you can just make this your own
personal side hustle journey,
and then post every day. Practice
posting, it's going to be a shitty video
where you're just talking, and you're
not going to sound amazing at the
beginning. That's how all of my students
are at the very beginning.
But a month ago, I started a new secret
Instagram account from scratch as well.
I didn't reveal it to any of my
followers.
But once you actually learn the skill
set of high retention viral content,
I posted 15 videos and you have so much
upside into doing this. I got paid
$5,000 from it. So, just remember, all
of you guys here who do want to turn
this into a vehicle to make financial
freedom, understand that yes, it is
behind a wall of cringe, but just
remember, there is so much infinite
potential and upside behind this. So,
remember that as you post. This is not
that this is not for anybody else. It's
for yourself and for your own goals,
okay?
Cuz it's very easy to lose sight of that
when we start thinking about all the
hate comments, all the negative
comments, all the judging thoughts that
might creep into our minds every single
day,
right?
It just starts by posting your first
video.
Now, let's actually talk about making
viral content, right? Don't you need a
crazy or unique story? How many of you
guys here feel like you're you just
don't live an interesting or crazy
enough life? Like you're not Mr. Beast,
you're not traveling to Europe and Bali.
So, how can you go viral?
You're just a regular student or you're
just working a job,
right?
Or, I I am not the most talented and
creative individual.
And don't you need to be super talented
or creative to to blow up on social
media?
I get this question a lot in my own
coaching calls as well. It's like, how
do you blow up if you don't have
anything crazy going on in your life?
Like you just live a pretty ordinary
life.
And the lucky thing is actually that
when I first started blowing up my page,
I was in college and I was literally
just documenting my day in college. This
was me in my parents' house
in the bedroom, just waking up and
talking to the camera.
So, a lot of the strategies that I want
to teach you guys today, right now,
is is rooted in not being hyper
talented, not having a crazy life going
on,
but making your ordinary life
interesting and packaging your ordinary
life in a way that's interesting.
And one of those things is obviously
hooks.
But I'll let you in on a little secret
that the best creators, however, won't
like to admit.
Right? So, a lot of you guys might look
at big creators, even you like all of
you guys might actually look at my
videos and be like, "Man, like this
looks so complex. [ __ ] like I could
never make these style of videos."
90% of these creative, crazy, original
ideas are just copying other viral
videos with a single twist.
At the core, that's actually a lot of
content.
Okay?
Honestly, from my experience, 90% of
creative videos are just copying other
viral videos with a twist.
All right. And if you actually look at
the For You page, you're going to notice
actually a lot of videos are strikingly
incredibly similar. It's almost
formulaic
how all the videos look similar. Some
people some of you guys actually I
believe might have this averseness
to copying creators. Like you don't want
to steal other people's videos. Man,
that's like unethical.
Let me explain.
For example,
this is my own video process.
I found this video while scrolling and
it had 2 million views. It was about
making money online. I was like, "That's
in the style of video that I want to
make. I want to make videos about making
money online. That's the whole thing
that my content documents."
So, then what I did was I literally
watched this video and I wrote down his
script sentence by sentence. And when I
say sentence by sentence, I quite
literally mean sentence by sentence.
This is his exact script that I stole
from his video.
Right? So, it was this video right here.
Is it possible to make $1,000
in one day?
Last day before I quit Google.
Right? And I wrote that down on this
Google Doc.
Open up a Google Doc
and next time you're scrolling on the
For You page,
start doing research. Treat it like
research. And I want you to now treat
scrolling on and consuming and watching
videos on social media like it's
research. That is the essence of
scrolling and consuming like a creator
and not just like a consumer anymore.
And I believe this is the biggest
difference between viral content
creators and just people who are
aimlessly throwing [ __ ] at a wall and
not knowing how to consistently put up
big numbers on social media. Okay? So
let's go even deeper, right? Because
anybody can just write down words on a
piece of paper. How do you actually
translate that into your own video? So
first off,
what I did was I wrote down the script
of their video. In fact, you can even
you If you're genuinely you don't want
to copy their entire video, that's
perfectly fine. Just write down their
first five sentences. Their first five
sentences or their first 15-ish seconds
are the most important part of a video.
It's the make or break of whether you're
going viral. If your video is not at a
million views, it's probably because
your first 15 seconds something went
wrong. Honestly, that's that's genuinely
the reason why your video is not at a
million views right now. It's because
you have not optimized your first 15
seconds. So what you want to do is study
all the videos that do have over a
million views, right?
Like I just showed you guys.
And then write down their sentences word
for word. And then ask yourself, why did
this specific sentence What about their
specific sentence made it go viral? So
let's do this interactively now, guys.
Actually, I want you guys to practice
training your viral sense. This is one
of the most important practices that you
can do as a creator.
What about this sentence made the video
go viral? What about this sentence here
do you think made the video literally
get
a hundred thousand likes? A hundred
thousand people liked the video.
Two million people were shown it. What
about this sentence here? Right? So if
we were to really break down what made
this video go viral, right?
It's one, the fact that everybody wants
to make a thousand dollars, but doing it
in a day seems impossible. So he took an
impossible
relatable
desirable
amount of money
in an impossible
challenge, right? That's one way that I
could frame it. At the end of the day,
this is just my way of saying
what you guys said in the chat.
Now, what about this sentence here? This
one's a little bit of a doozy here, but
if you guys can actually get this right,
it proves that you actually do have a
little bit of a viral sense here. Let's
see how many sales we got last night.
Let's see how many sales we got last
night. Why was this sentence important
to the video going viral? Okay?
Why was let's see how many sales we got
last night so helpful to the video going
viral? This highlighted sentence right
here. What about that sentence?
This one seems a bit more boring. This
is a big mistake that I see a lot of
beginner creators make, which is they
move too slowly. You say a hook to get
people's attention,
but then you don't show that you're
actually doing it.
This guy within I believe it's literally
within 8 seconds says, "Let's see how
many sales we got." He doesn't wait 10
seconds. He doesn't wait 15 seconds. He
says it literally within 8 seconds,
"Let's see how many sales we got." The
key to going viral
is
introducing a topic that people want to
know about and then delivering on it
very quickly. Now, you do this with
scripting. You do this with editing.
And I'll teach you guys editing in a
second, but the key here that I really
got I want you guys to highlight here is
that as you practice writing down the
scripts of other viral videos that you
see on the For You page, you're going to
start asking yourself the right
questions of what exactly made this
video go viral.
And then you're eventually going to
build up your skill set to apply these
principles to your own videos. So, if
you think proof/evidence
in the first 10 seconds is important,
how many of you guys don't do that in
your own videos right now?
And if you did apply that, if you were
able to apply proof and evidence within
your first 10 seconds to back up your
hook,
how much more viral do you think your
videos would be as opposed to taking 20
seconds, 30 seconds?
Right? And these are the questions that
then help you make these 2x, 10x jumps
in your videos. These are small things.
These small 1% improvements
can literally 10x the views on your
video. Now, I wrote down the script
sentence by sentence.
And then, what I did
was I rewrote the script in my own
words. I applied everything that I saw
made the first 10 seconds go viral.
Relatable, desirable amount of money in
an impossible, quote-unquote, challenge.
And then I showed proof and evidence of
me working towards that goal in the
first 10 seconds.
So, how did I turn this into my own
video? $1,000. I think people like money
numbers, right? A lot of you guys said
that in the chat. So, I wrote, "Is it
possible to make an app without writing
a single line of code, an impossible
challenge, and make $10,000 from it in
just 30 days?" I pretty much copied this
hook and I just changed a couple words.
And I call this method, I've actually
saw this method on YouTube, the Zoinken
twist. You find a viral video on the For
You page. You analyze each sentence, and
then you change their words into yours,
just a couple of their words. So, this
guy made it in the online business
niche. I made it about building apps
without writing code, five coding.
And then I did apply exactly what he
said. Let's see how many sales we got.
He's showing proof and evidence of work
of all of this working in the first 10
seconds. Key is that it's in the third
sentence, not the 10th sentence. So, I
immediately jumped into the action. I
was initially thinking maybe I'll drag
on a little bit, maybe I'll talk more
about the challenge and why I'm doing
the challenge and AI and what I think
about AI. We're going to jump straight
into the action because that's what made
his video go viral, and I'm not going to
retry and reinvent the wheel. I see a
video that went viral, I think about why
it went viral, and then I apply it.
Let's start coding with AI, and
instantly jump into the action. The
result was this video right here.
Has 3,000 likes.
I literally copied the visuals as well.
Today is day one.
Let's start coding. So, I jump into the
action as soon as possible. I show my
laptop to show that I'm actually working
towards this goal, and the result
when applying this that I just showed
you guys was 100,000 views. And not only
that, obviously, I was getting paid to
promote an app while doing this. I got
paid $300.
So, this is the process that I want all
of you guys to do once you start doing
UGC
is learn how to just copy videos
effectively. You want to learn this
skill not of reinventing the wheel, not
of being hyper original,
but learning how to copy videos
effectively because not only is that
going to help you get your first viral
video as soon as you possibly can, but
it's also going to train your viral
sense to learn to think as a viral
creator cuz
you at the end of the day, when you're a
beginner, you don't know what you don't
know.
Genuinely, all of you guys here, if you
still struggle with getting views, a lot
of you guys probably came into the class
thinking, I honestly don't even know why
my videos aren't doing well.
And that's really frustrating.
And how do you bridge that gap? Cuz you
know exactly what it looks like to go
viral, and you know you're not there,
and you know your videos are maybe down
here, 1,000, 2,000, or couple hundred
views.
Don't try to but somehow turn your
original ideas into this mega like mega
viral banger thing.
Just see what's working.
Write it down, analyze why other viewers
would have liked it, and why you thought
it was interesting.
And then recreate it.
And a lot of people have fancy names for
this, like stealing like an artist,
but at the end of the day, it really
just does come down to this repeatable
process.
Okay?
Now, editing. How many of you guys here
want to learn more about editing? I have
a very simple simple framework for you
guys, and I teach more about this inside
my paid community, but
editing at the end of the day I do
believe
a lot of people get stuck on.
Right? So, what if I told you I
developed a system to edit my videos in
literally 30 minutes to an hour,
and I've been able to repeatedly go
viral just spending about 30 minutes to
an hour per edit?
So, I want to tell you guys about a
system that I have developed and that
I've battle-tested with hundreds of
students. And I call it minimum viable
editing.
Now, specifically, a minimum viable
video format.
Okay? So, here it is.
The minimum viable video format is as
follows. You think of a main idea based
on your ideal viewers' desires or
interests or daily pains. Right? Another
way is just copy a video that you see on
the For You page or the Explore page
that's going viral,
and then
copy it down.
Right?
Specifically, I want to highlight the
filming and editing process cuz this is
where I believe I'm able to save so many
people time by just telling them exactly
what the right things are to do, and
then don't do anything else.
Now, a lot of people spend like multiple
How many of you guys have spent multiple
hours editing and you just felt like it
returned literally no gains?
You You spent multiple hours editing a
video and then it just got no views and
you're like, "Fuck, I just wasted all my
time."
So, I think that's the most frustrating.
Right?
Here it is.
Filming. If you're filming a talking
video, I highly recommend
you film all of the video. You film the
entire video
without stopping. A lot of people do hit
record and then stop record. Hit record
and stop record. I believe that'll add
an extra 15 minutes
on average at least for me onto talking
videos. I just record everything in one
take, and it also helps me get into a
flow because realistically, when you
were talking with a real human being,
you are not talking by start, stop,
start, stop, start, stop. You're just
saying everything in a row. The second
thing, editing. Now, I edit everything
in this app called CapCut. If you don't
have it already, I highly recommend it.
It is the easiest editing app, and it is
free on your iPhone. It looks a little
something like this.
On the on the iPhone, right here,
CapCut.
Right there.
It's the simplest app, and I literally
edit my videos while I'm in an Uber, on
the subway. I just plug in AirPods, and
I just start editing, and it only takes
me 30 to 60 minutes.
So, how do I do this?
First off, is this button called
transcript-based
editing. And I want you guys to
screenshot this, because obviously, you
guys aren't in the midst of editing
right now, so you're not going to be
able to remember all of this. Just
screenshot this and write it down. Write
it down especially, so you can actually
commit it to your memory.
But, transcript-based editing, that's
going to help you cut down all of your
talking footage by looking at a script.
It's basically like this was a
transcript of all the words that I spoke
in my videos, and I'm just like, "I
don't like this part. I'm just going to
cut it. Boom, delete." And it allows you
to cut your edit cut your videos not by
watching through the whole thing over
and over and over again, which takes
multiple hours.
Just just let me do it on a transcript.
Then, trim dead space. Guys, the number
one thing that stops your video from
going viral, right? Well, it's not the
number one thing. The number one thing
that stops your editing from going
viral, I would say is dead space.
Especially for beginners, you have space
in your video where nothing is
happening. Another way of framing this
is the 2-second rule. Ask yourself, when
you are watching your video, is there
even a span of 2 seconds where there's
no music, no audio, or nothing moving on
the screen? Is it just a static shot of
maybe you at the desk? Maybe it's you
cooking something, but then nothing's
moving on the screen. Cut it out, or
reduce it down to just 2 seconds.
Okay?
And I want to show you guys, for
example, a vlog creator who does this
really well, Jack's Day in the Life.
Now, this guy, you guys might have seen
him before. He is He's a somewhat Yeah,
I guess he's a cringe, too, but every
[ __ ] creator is.
He does these day in the lives where
it's his morning routine as a
25-year-old before his job, for his
9-to-5.
Now, I want to highlight this editing
style here. If you watch his video,
he's either moving in every single one
of the shots, dancing, or he's cutting
the shots every single second to 2
seconds. Yeah, I can't cover everything
in here because editing like we have a
uh have literally video guides inside
Content Academy, our paid community that
walk through everything, but they are
literally like Some of them are a couple
like up to an hour long. So, yes, I
can't cover everything, but this is the
basics.
Then, rewatch your video and determine
the emotion. This is [ __ ] elite ball
knowledge. What vibe are you trying to
give viewers?
And then make your music choice around
that. So, maybe this guy that I just
showed you, Jack Stauber in the Life,
he's trying to make his videos hype,
high energy. He's probably going to use
pop songs, fast-moving pop songs, rap
songs. If you're trying to go for the
more aesthetic, calm vibe, do not use
[ __ ] pop or hype songs. It's just
going to be really weird and uncanny.
No, use calm, maybe some lofi, maybe
some instrumentals from movies that are
calm, chill, cuz you want to curate a
vibe with your video's music. And then
lastly, b-roll
is the videos or the footage that you
overlay on top of your talking.
Now, add b-roll only if it helps clarify
something, not just to keep [ __ ]
flashing on the screen, only if it helps
clarify what you are saying. There's
going to be a lot more on editing, but
these are the basics to cut your editing
time down from perhaps multiple hours to
just 60 minutes while doing everything
necessary for a viral video to actually
hit.
And this is the editing system,
what I just showed you guys, that I also
use to grow all of these accounts on
TikTok and Instagram. This account 150,
this account to 280, this account to
500k.
Right? It's that simple.
I really want to emphasize to you that I
content really is not this extremely
intricate thing where you want to
overthink every single thing. There are
a couple of things
in your editing and in your scripting
that are going to help you go viral and
then there's a lot of things that are
going to throw you off and just waste
your time. And my goal with this
presentation is to boil down as much as
possible into simple steps that you can
execute so you stop overthinking and you
just post.
It's simple systems that work. Right?
So, you have to know what simple systems
work and I gave you a couple of just
now.
And you stack on 1% improvements every
single time you post
and you just stay consistent. Okay? Now,
a pro tip as well
with consistency, this is one of the
most difficult things as a creator,
right? It's just
realistically, it's just being able to
show up on a regular basis. That's the
hard part. Okay.
Awesome. I'll give you guys a little pro
tip here. Find people, join a community
if you if you don't have people to keep
you accountable.
Literally,
I am doing a posting challenge with two
of my friends right now, three of my
friends actually. And if one of us
doesn't post, we have to send all three
of the other people $30.
So, that's If I don't post today, well,
I already have cuz I'm I'm consistent as
[ __ ] No, I'm just kidding. I If I don't
post, I have to send $90.
Put stakes on the line. That's a pro
tip.
If you really want to make this a
serious thing, put [ __ ] on the line. In
fact, you don't even need other friends
who post content, it just helps because
they understand the grind and they'll
take it seriously just like you.
But just tell somebody, "Yo, if I don't
post, I will send you this money."
They don't have to do anything. They'll
just be like, "Okay." Be like, "I'm
literally just doing this so I can stay
accountable."
It's the simplest form, but it's helped
me stay consistent as well.
Okay?
Fire.
So, let's recap everything we learned so
far.
So far, we learned how money is made
with UGC. We got big picture the vision
on how to monetize.
And then we learned the simple blueprint
to print viral videos.
And then lastly, we learned how to post
in just 60 minutes per day. All right,
if you found value from this
presentation, I'm doing way more of
these live presentations. So, I'm going
to leave a link to my next live
presentation, which is how to speed run
your first 10K followers on your
personal brand. I'm going to be going
through how I was able to grow four of
my accounts over 100K followers across
TikTok and Instagram, and how you can
build an audience that knows, likes, and
trusts you enough so you can eventually
monetize off of your personal brand.
I'll see you guys in that. the first
link in the description to sign up for
that free live class. I'll see you
there. Peace.