My name is Mino Lee and I've grown four
accounts to over 100,000 followers
across Tik Tok and Instagram. So, in the
next 2 hours, this is quite possibly
going to be the most valuable video on
personal branding you have ever seen
because it is not just tactical advice.
This is going to be a create content
with me where I'm going to be walking
through my exact scripting, filming, and
editing process, screen sharing
everything while you do it along with
me. And the process that I'm showing you
actually created all of these viral
videos which generated this much in
sales for me in the past week. So this
video will be the most interactive guide
you've ever seen to get you into the
maximum creative flow state to create
not just one, not two, not three, but
five viral videos in just 2 hours. So
without further ado, let's start with
scripting and ideulating viral video
ideas on a Google doc. Let's get to it.
And timer starts now. And what I'm going
to do is I'm just going to literally
whip out a Google doc and start [ __ ]
cooking. 10 ideas May 24, 2026. Let's
go. I've done this practice many times
before, which is why you can see all of
this stuff written down, right? And I'm
probably going to be actually like hella
mute during this. I'm going to turn on
some music.
Uh,
damn. No music. That's fine. All right.
I've already lost like 10 seconds or 30
seconds.
just made. Okay. Uh I just
Here
we go.
like this. I don't know about this three
lessons, but what I'm going to do is I'm
just going to skip that and just go on
to the next idea because ideally want to
whip out like five [ __ ] ideas in the
next like 3 minutes. Um,
Cold like brand
profit personal Red
Three tips.
I'm hitting flow state right now. Here
we go. Usually that's in like two, three
ideas in you just start hitting this
[ __ ] flow where you're like, "Oh, I
have permission to make random [ __ ]
ideas. Let me whip out a bunch more."
And I think that permission helps me get
into a good flow of ideas where they
just start flowing eventually. Uh, mind
you, none of these are that crazy box.
No, six, seven.
Also have a couple videos saved that I
wanted to use as inspo. Notice how I'm
doing most of my creative process not
from scratch, but by using real data,
right, on what works. So, right here, I
see these three videos say from this
creator has been popping off recently,
right? A couple other videos. This is
actually Okay, let's see.
Post three times a day.
Oh [ __ ] [ __ ] I just lost 30 seconds.
What the hell? Uh, notice how I just
basically scripted out the outline for
that one.
The only four skills you need to build a
cult like brand. Interesting skills.
People like People seem to like skills.
Build a 1 mill
master.
Only four skills you need to build
throat.
I don't like this one. We're going to
cut that one out. Make it even harder
for ourselves. Uh
inspo method. Inspo method. Let's go.
Let's go. Stop. Stop you. I heard this
guy say I heard this guy say
I heard Horoszi
say
>> well.
No, I don't remember any quotes off the
top of my head. could be useful. But
content creators,
two types of 2026.
Ah, that one didn't really do well.
Paradox of being ambitious but lazy. The
paradox of being ambitious but
amish.
Lazy methods building your personal
brand
perfectionism.
Okay. Yeah, there's a little lesson
there. Fly sleep mindset
100k
eight.
Ah, okay. Okay. Come on. Let's cook.
Here. Eight beliefs you need to
Here are eight beliefs you need to leave
behind.
I
leave behind. Is there a more like
esoteric spiritual wording here? Cuz I
know that'll hit more nichely. Here are
eight beliefs I had to
uh
throw out of at least, you know,
to
to finally reach 100k a month.
Okay, now let's actually go back and
revise the ideas cuz I have 46 seconds.
Oh, I have 3 seconds left. Okay, well,
we did it. We got 10 ideas done. All
right. All right. Okay. Okay. Here we
go. Yeah, we have our 10 ideas. Now,
here's what we're going to do. I really
like the idea of this like forced timer
cuz for me, I love procrastinating. And
whenever there's like more work to be
done, I always just like, h yeah, I'm
just wait.
>> So, we're not going to do that. We're
going to set another three three to
five. You know, don't give yourself too
much time for this part. But basically
now force yourself to revise some of
these ideas because a lot of these are
just not hashed out, which is fine. You
know, you need to sift through the
garbage to get through the gold. Uh so
something I also like to do, uh which
I'll actually just do right now is just
go to Claude and rank these content
hooks/ ideas from most to least viral.
Okay. And while it does that, cuz that's
how I'm going to prioritize what to film
first. Pro freaking hack, right? While
that cooks for me, profitable personal
brand. what I learned from Hamza.
Uh, that's not a hook though. Profitable
difference between a personal brand and
a mediocre personal
and
a what's it like derogatory
is three
is
Oh, persuasion.
Uh,
what are the actual meat of the video?
Uh, what are three things I learned from
Hamza? Uh, treat your audience like a
pixel. Like a metapixel.
The metapixel. Metapixel method. The
just like funky names, you know, people
like funky names. Pattern interrupt
sticks out. Sticks out, you know. Uh
Metapixel method.
Uh
us versus them method,
you know, us versus them method, right?
He gets the whole Jeffrey
verse Adonis.
Uh,
those two.
Uh, okay. What's the last one? What's
the last one? Uh,
what not to do.
for
selfation.
Okay. All right. Three tips. I don't
even remember what the three tips were
going to be for this one. I'll probably
like relegate this one to the bottom. I
don't really like it or I have no
clarity on what how I would actually
execute this. How to full guide to
starting
uh first 30 days, first 60 days, first
90 days, first seven days, first 30
days, first 90 days. Goal just
just [ __ ] JFP. Goal is JFP. Ah, first
90 days. I'm going to finish off this
thought here. Goal is JFP. Goal is 10K
views. soul is 100k views
plus double down on what works. Find the
repeatable outlier. Okay. Yeah, that
works. Okay. It's not the best. But now,
let's see. I'm just going to kill this
timer here. Let's see what Claude cooked
up here. Don't be original as number
one. Don't be original as number one.
Honestly, I'm just going to take what
whatever the freak he said, put it here.
If this is actually what mindset of 100K
month creator Yeah. Yeah. Screw it, you
know? Why not? Why not? Why not? Why
not? We're just gonna let Claude
literally reorder here because sometimes
we need to be told what to film because
sometimes that gives me permission to
film, I guess. Honestly, how do I never
run out of ideas? Wow. Wow. Wow. Wow.
Wow. Wow. Honestly, I like
wholeheartedly agree with this, which is
the crazy part. I don't disagree with
any of these points. Hooks master class.
This is cool. Honestly, I'm I'm actually
pretty surprised. You can also use Mino
AI for this as well. Probably would be
slightly better. Lazy method. Peros
being ambitious but lazy. Yeah. The only
issue here is that I don't have an idea
for this. But we could probably I'm
going actually remove this to the bottom
just cuz I don't remember if I actually
had an idea for this. I don't think I
did. Profitable personal brand. Yep.
Brand master guide. Okay. Awesome.
That's pretty much everything that we
need from here. Now, what we're going to
do is obviously film these videos. Oh
man, this batch filming is going to be a
freaking [ __ ] But but we're going to
figure this out, you know? We're going
to grind this out because, you know,
it's 6:00 p.m. on a Sunday. I just want
to chill. I just want to play video
games. But we're not going to do that
because we have a [ __ ] personal brand
to build. We have viral videos to make.
And I want to make one thing clear
before I start this filming, right? Look
at these videos. Yeah, you might think,
damn, like he gets like, you know, he
got 300k views on this video. This video
was filmed at 900 PM. No, no, 1:00 a.m.
Sorry. It was made at 1:00 a.m. after I
came home from a long ass day of work,
and I was just like, "Ah, dude. I need
to get a video out just for habits
sake." This happened to be my best
performing video. Um, in the past, bro,
probably like, yeah, when was this
posted? March. In the last 60 days, it's
my best performer. Made at night at 1:00
a.m. just because I wanted to get into
the habit of it. So, guys, some of your
best videos will come when you least
expect it. All right, let's jump into
filming. Let's go. All right. Before we
get into the filming section, you might
have struggled a little bit with the
brainstorming. And I know it can be very
daunting at first to take these viral
video concepts that you see on the for
you page and actually translate them
into your own voice into the most viral
possible hooks and scripts. So, I
actually created an AI tool that you can
try out in the first link in the
description for completely free that'll
do the entire thought process for you
that's trained off of thousands of viral
hooks that have already been scraped off
of Tik Tok and Instagram and 300 plus
hours of me coaching directly and all of
my content guides. So, just give me 30
seconds. I'm going to show you guys
exactly how this tool works. So, you can
try it out and you'll get an exclusive
3-day free trial if you use that first
link in the description. So, basically,
let's say I found this info video saved.
All I'm going to do is copy the link to
it, go to Mino AAI, and ask it to simply
recreate the viral video. I'm going to
paste the inspo video URL right there,
and it's going to find the video,
extract it, and watch it and transcribe
the entire thing frame by frame. And
what it's going to be able to do is
break down the entire video. So, first,
it's going to tell me what made the
video go viral. And this is also based
on all of the training that I have ever
said in all of my coaching calls, all of
my YouTube videos talking about what
actually makes videos go viral. So in
this case, if we're being completely
honest, that's a subtle way in the hook
to create intimacy. Nobody is obsessed
with your brand. That's a direct attack
on the viewer's ego, right? And then it
gives me a reusable template. So, this
is how I'm able to save time as a busy
22-year-old business owner to be able to
essentially make all the videos that I
post, and still be able to run my
business, manage my team, and take all
the viral inspiration that I see online
and be able to recreate it in a tenth of
the time using Mino AI. So, if you want
to try a free trial of Mino AI, I'm
going to give an exclusive link in the
first link in the description. So, if
you want to go back and retry the
brainstorming, even if you feel like you
struggled, go ahead, try Amino AAI and
go back and restart the brainstorming.
If you're already done and you feel
confident with the ideas that you have
right now, let's go into the filming.
All right, welcome to the 25minut
filming with me portion. Uh, right now
I'm going to set a 25minut timer which
starts now. And what I'm going to do is
I'm trying to try to batch film somehow
four or three to five videos in the next
uh in the next, you know, 25 minute
session. So that means I literally
cannot allow myself to do more than one
take, which is a beautiful part of this
because now I kind of have to just yap
whatever's on my mind, which kind of
it's this way of like brute forcing
authenticity. So what I'm going to do is
I'm going to start screen recording on
my phone as well. So you can see here I
got my phone and I want to walk you guys
through a couple of things from this uh
from this session. So the first one I'm
going to move this a little bit here is
that notice my setup. You guys might
think, okay, it's just a normal setup.
Watch the difference if I don't have
this light on. Look at the difference in
lighting. It feels kind of amateur. Now
look at that. It's clean. And I also
bought these like $50 LED lights that
can color change, but I made them blue
to add a little bit of ambiance. And
yes, I am staying at a hotel just so I
can film these videos. Yes, I paid an
egregious amount of money. No, you don't
need to do that. Often times, actually,
just filming your bedroom is how I made
some of my most far away. I just happen
to be staying at a hotel right now.
Okay. And I also got these performative
wired earbuds. Guess what, guys? I don't
even use these aren't even connected to
my freaking phone. Now, you can use them
connect to your phone. Like, the mic is
good on these Apple ear pod headphones.
We don't need them. I use my iPhone mic
when I film. Billion. And I'm going to
put this performative white monster to
make myself look like, you know, to
match the vibe of the creator, you know,
because people love content creators and
like sophisticated performative [ __ ]
right? I might split test hoodie on and
hoodie off. Not that it really matters.
I also notice I have a pimple on my
cheek, which is kind of giving me
friction to film, but I don't really
give a [ __ ] So, right now, what we're
going to do before I even start filming,
and I know I'm wasting a bit of time
here, is just do some stretches because
getting my endorphins up is a pretty
huge thing. So, what I'm going to do is
I'm just going to jump up and down. 1 2
3 4 5. Okay. Next, what I'm going to do
is I'm going to set a timer for myself
for about 10 15 seconds and just force
myself to laugh. Ready? Go.
Jeez, that creeped me the [ __ ] out. And
I literally am getting I'm feeling
literally sweaty from doing that. I just
watched Obsession last night, which is a
brilliant movie. But the whole goal with
that is to spark some endorphins. So
hopefully your body literally felt a
little bit uncomfortable. That's the
feeling of you getting your nerves out.
That's good. Okay, now let's actually
start filming. Okay. And what I'm going
to do is I also put this little notepad
in front of me, this journal. Not
because any of these notes are actually
relevant to what I'm filming, but just
because it literally helps make it uh a
little bit more performative and signals
planning. You know what I'm saying?
Okay, I'm going to ignore this camera
now and just go actually get locked into
filming. Let's go. All right. All right.
Here we go. I'm I'm nervous. And the
first video is always [ __ ] you know?
That's just like generally how it is.
That's fine. Fine. That's fine.
I grew three accounts to over 100K
followers by rejecting one principle.
Now, something I like to do also is chug
caffeine just so it literally kills any
ability to overthink.
Incredible. Incredible. Incredible.
Incredible.
Okay, I'm going to hit next and I'm just
going to draft this [ __ ] because I
genuinely do not have time to even
overthink the execution of that. Did I
film it well? Did I not film it well?
Did I sound like a [ __ ] [ __ ] Did I
sound really cringe? I don't care. I
don't care. I don't care. These
efficient filmers don't even they film
all their emotions tied up and then
boom, they're done and they move on to
the next one. Mind that's the mindset of
100k a month creator. Speaking of which,
I need to actually plan out this video.
Let's let's think through the script
here. Belief number one, the
and monetizing. That's going to be in my
bio. So, sign up for that.
Oh, wait. We just finished our third
video and now we have one minute to
spare. So, we're going to get up and
stretch for a little bit. I know I
probably wasted like two minutes of that
timer or time trying to uh you know,
come up with the come up with the right
hooks or explain what I was thinking
through. But my friend's also going to
be here in like a minute or so. So, I'm
literally just going to pick them up
while we do our 10-minute break.
Um,
and yeah, I'm just going to cross off on
my on my dock as well the three ideas
that I already executed on. so I don't
repeat them again. Okay, we're just
going to do this.
All right, and now we have seven ideas
remaining. Okay, and we're going to do
that in our next filming session as the
timer literally is about to run down to
zero. We're going to take a little
10-minute break. You know, do not scroll
because that's going to once again ruin
your focus, [ __ ] up your dopamine
receptors. Do not scroll. If anything,
you can do some breathing exercises
together or just get up, take a walk,
stay active, keep your body active
because if you want to stay in a flow
state while filming, you don't want your
body to literally shut down and go into
a comos state. Another thing, too, is I
don't like to eat during my filming and
deep work blocks because once my body is
starting to digest food, my blood sugar
might rise and crash, which is going to
cause me to become eepy and sleepy,
which is not what you want when you want
to stay locked in, energetic, excited to
film. Okay. So, let's take a 10-minute
break, stay off the screens, and just
try to stretch, move around, and we'll
set that timer now. All right. So, our
our homie Charles just entered, right?
We're in the midst of our uh our
10-minute break session right now. But
yeah, our homie Charles just entered.
>> What's up? You going to be focusing in
the back while I'm filming to make this
on extra hard?
>> Cuz it's cuz I know you guys are
probably thinking, "Oh, bro, I have a
roommate, so I can't film." Well, I'm
going to practice with a roommate here
now.
>> I'm here.
>> And he's he's got a super big [ __ ] so
I'm super intimidated by his BDE, too.
So, I'm kidding. I'm kidding. I'm
kidding. I'm kidding. I'm kidding. I'm
kidding.
>> Yo. Yo.
>> Wait. Actually, that would be kind of
funny. What if I What if I just like
took my shirt off like
Pause, mate. Pause. But yeah, sorry.
You're saying
>> Oh, it wasn't about filming, but um
>> wait, I'll just keep this I'll probably
mute it now just to uh just to like keep
this time lapse going.
What if you're like being an [ __ ]
>> That's like the fried case study.
>> It's actually the front. Okay. Walk it.
Walk in walking. Walking walking.
>> All right, the timer's up.
>> Time to film.
>> Let's go.
>> You thought this was going to be some
calm ah calm a porridor. Now we're
getting hype. Let's get hyped. Let's get
ready. Let's settle back into flow
state. We got 25 minutes left to film
four videos.
Let's do it. All right, let's get hyp.
Let's start our filming session. Let's
get hype. Okay, I turned on some focus
music this time on Brain FM. I'm not
sponsored, but this helps me block out
any overthinking from my brain so I can
just purely focus. I play that on my
computer. Let's go.
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
games alongside the common alongside
obviously the common good of being part
of the community.
That's actually a new record for me,
too. That's actually a new record for me
to to film 10 videos in the span of just
an hour. But we did it. We did it, guys.
And now we're going to move on to the
editing portion, which, you know, we're
just going to have as a minimum viable
editing. I'm going to walk through
exactly how I'm going to edit these
batch filmed videos and how you can do
the same to maximize the viral potential
of your content. But let's take another
5minute break before we jump into that.
All right, let's finish up with our 1h
hour minimum viable editing session.
Now, the reason why I call it minimum
viable editing is because with editing,
it's very easy, especially as a beginner
to content, but also when you're just
trying to build up momentum and your
consistency, to overthink the editing
and almost overdo it to the point where
it actually hurts your video's
performance. So, I want to show you guys
the exact very simple process that I do
with my videos to minimum viably edit
them. And I'm just going to set our
60-minute timer here and get started
with the editing. I'm also going to
screen record this. So,
like so.
And we will get started. So, we're going
to open back the Tik Tok app and just go
back to the first couple drafts. And
we're just going to get started here.
So, we're going to go to this one right
here.
>> Here, the seven limiting beliefs I
>> And what we're going to do first off is
what I call a rough cut. And what I'm
also going to do is I'm going to walk
you guys through my editing thought
process for the first video. And the
rest of them, I'm just going to stay
silent. So then you guys can also edit
in peace, right? But let's start off
with the minimum viable editing process.
Starting with step one, which is the
rough cut. And what I'm going to do is
basically cut out either sentences that
I think are either redundant or
unnecessary to the video, as well as do
the fine cutting of dead space, where
it's like 0.2, 0.3 seconds of dead
space. The seven
are the seven limiting beliefs I had to
grow out of in order to reach 100k a
month as a content creator. Belief
number one, the idea that quality beats
creator. Belief number one, I'm going to
remove the the idea that because I think
that just slows the video down,
especially in the first 10 seconds.
>> The idea number one, the idea that
number one, quality beats quantity.
Quality beats quantity. There's a dead
space there. So, I'm going to press it
and delete quantity.
Hear these seven.
>> Okay, it looks like this clip just got
repeated twice.
>> Quantity. When you're pumping out the
scale of actually running a business
through your social media, you need to
stop thinking about every single content
p social media. You need to stop
thinking about social media.
>> Okay, I'm going to cut out the business
part.
>> Honestly, you need to stop thinking
about every single content piece as this
magical form of art. You have to
understand that you are a production mat
piece as this mal
form of art.
>> Yeah, I'm going to cut that part out
too.
>> It's quantity. You have to understand
that you are a production company at the
end of the day, which means you need to
just pump out a video and then
immediately at the end of the day, which
means honestly got to cut that part out
too and just do this
>> quantity. You need to just quantity. You
need to just pump out a video and then
immediately on to the next without
dwelling on how well that without
dwelling on
>> I'm going to cut out this little breath
hereing
on how well this video is going to do
because that's going to take you out of
the flow state necessary to be
consistently producing
number number two number two
number two the obsession over being
original. I used to genuinely take pride
in my over being original. I used going
to be consistently pumping out content
enough to the point where you can
actually
>> I'm going to cut that part out.
>> Being original
become way three. Number three, I
original.
>> Cut out that dead space.
>> Original. Number three, I had to become
way more introspective. of journaling
and meditation. These were necessary for
me to actually develop the These were
necessary for me to actually
meditation. I'm going to cut this rest
of this clip here too. A lot of times I
just kind of like say an explan
explanatory portion, but from my
experience making and editing these
videos, I've realized that just a lot of
times I overspeak. Even now too,
honestly, like you might be getting
bored of me talking right now and it's
very normal to overspeak in our videos
and that's the goal of the editing
process. Meditation four.
This oneation
four. This one's an obvious one, but
stop scrolling as much because if you're
scrolling and you're over consuming,
you're going to lack the
clear-mindedness necessary to also be
articulate on camera. Number five.
Number five, I camera. Number five, I
had to give up this clinging to this
concept of safety.
If you stop post If you stop, if you
stop post
safety, if you stop posting for 2 weeks
when you have 100,000 followers, guess
what? Followers [ __ ] mean nothing.
You're going to lose all the traction
that you on social media.
>> I got this
>> on social media.
Now you can social media. Now you can
treat social media. Now you can social
media. Now you can treat this as a
Now you can treat this as a bad
interaction that you have on social. Now
you can treat this as a bad thing or you
can treat this as a way to constantly
self-develop to be more comfortable with
risk and boldness.
Comfortable with risk
risk.
Number seven. Number seven. I number
seven. I had to develop a ruthless level
of optimism. People have told me for the
past 3 years, "Yo, are you sure social
media is going to be a long-term
career?" Yet my business has
continuously
be a long-term career. Yet my business
has I'm going to cut out continuously.
>> continuously
business has continued to grow.
Has continued to grow.
>> Take a fat breath here.
>> Grow.
And number.
And number seven, detaching from worldly
outcomes.
Worldly outcomes.
I used be so obsessed with views and
make
I
used to be outcomes.
I used to be so
outcomes. I used to be
I used to be so obsessed with views and
making sure people would see my page and
see, oh, he's a viral creator. Oh, he's
got motion. And once I finally learned
to let go of that slowly.
Mhm. Cut this part
>> slowly
that we're by reminding by
slowly by reminding myself every morning
that dude we're going to [ __ ] die.
None of this [ __ ] matters. All of these
videos are going to be burned to the
ground in a none of this [ __ ] matters.
Burnt anyway. This [ __ ] matters. No
matter matters. No matter how rich,
famous, successful I become in this
lifetime. It's not going to matter once
I'm dead. It's not going to matter.
Matter once I'm
once I'm dead.
So all dead. So all of this [ __ ] is just
fun and games anyways, you know? Don't
worry. We're just here to have all of
this [ __ ] is just fun in games anyways.
Come on. And that's all this is. That
should be the most that
should be the mo that should be the most
that should be
that
>> and that should be the most encouraging
sign to encourage you. And that should
be the most and
>> there we go. about this repetition too.
>> And that should be Anyway, that should
be the most encouraging sign.
That should be the
Anyway, that should be the most
encouraging sign to [ __ ] create
something today. Here are the seven
limiting Here are the seven limiting
belie. And there we go. We've done the
rough cut. We've cut out all the
repetitions and dead space. The second
thing we're going to do is add auto
captions. I'm also just going to make
sure the volume is at 200%. That's just
like a personal preference to make sure
my videos are as audible as possible and
apply
>> in order to reach. Now, we're just going
to hit the captions, auto captions here,
and
let Tik Tok load that for a second.
It's also really late right now. It's
11:40.
It's 11:50 right now, but we're grinding
this out. And that's oftentimes how
content is. It's late at night, but
you're getting the content done. That's
the most important thing.
Okay. Now, we're going to hit style and
do custom. And this is my preferred auto
caption style. But if you're new and you
haven't gone consistently viral and
found that like winning editing style,
just copy mine, honestly. Uh, what
you're going to do is hit this. And now
you have these clean small auto
captions. Like what I like to usually do
as well is split it into uh one line at
a time. I had to grow out of in order to
reach 100k a month as a content creator.
Belief number one, quality beats
quantity. I'm also just going to do
hashtag. You need to just and we're
going to do a couple spelling checks
here.
Um just to make sure that you know all
the captions are actually spelled
properly cuz that's going to take you
out of the flow state necessary to be
consistently producing. Number two,
the obsession over being original.
Number three, yeah, we're just going to
continue this process. I had to become
way more introspective. So, journaling
and meditation.
Number four,
stop scrolling because you're scrolling
your
clear mind. It is necessary to also be
articulate on camera.
Number five. There you go. This clean to
this concept of safety. If you stop
posting
for two weeks,
you have 100,000 follow 2 weeks. When
you have
when you have
[ __ ] mean nothing. You're going to
lose all the traction that you have on
social media. You can treat this or you
can treat this as a way to constantly
self-develop to be more comfortable with
risk.
Number seven,
I had to develop a ruthless level of
optimism. People have told me
for the past 3 years, yo, are you sure
social media is going to be
continue to grow?
that
something today. All right. Awesome. Now
we have these. I'm going also remove the
here are the just seven limiting
beliefs. Honestly, it keeps one line but
keeps it also clear. Okay. And now I'm
just going to make it a little bit
larger and make it a little bit more
centered. And then lastly, now what I'm
going to do is I'm going to add a text.
So the
mindset of a
love creator.
Okay, here we go. So we have that
>> reach 100k
7 limit.
>> Now I'm just going to add little 1 2 3 4
quantity.
I like to sometimes add little midv
video overlays or text just to keep it
engaging throughout.
Number two, the
I'm going to add also a CTA here at 10
seconds in. P.S.
I'm teaching a free live class
how to
in my bio.
And there we go.
how well that's video is going to do
because that's going to take you out of
the flow state necessary to number two.
The Okay, number two, the obsession over
being original.
Originality is a myth.
Originality is a myth has become way
more introspective.
Three, spend way more
alone time. I'm just going to add these
captions here just to help keep it
engaging throughout for this one's
obvious one but
for
digital detoxing
digital detox
number five I had to give up this
number five
the false sense of security.
Okay.
Five. The false sense of security.
Number six.
Yeah, I accidentally said seven here.
Number six,
uh, pessimism
kills growth.
I'm going to add a little subtext here
cuz I think it'll be helpful.
Uh,
you will have slow months.
Get stuck.
But
let's see. You have slow months. Get
stuck. But
I just say this is normal.
>> Number seven.
>> Number seven. Detach.
>> Stop chasing views.
Okay,
here are the seven limiting beliefs I
>> Okay, and there we go. So, we've fully
done it. Now, grow out of in order to
reach 100K as a content creator. Belief
number one, quality beats quantity. We
need to just pump out a and then I'm
going to just add a little caption
semin
how to speedun
your first
followers this week.
tune in.
Okay, here the seven limiting. All
right, so now we have that. And in more
options, this is key actually because
you want to be able to cross post this
onto Instagram. What we're going to do
is just make sure that there's a save to
device, right, which is going to
autosave basically this video in full HD
quality without a watermark to our
camera roll. So, we're just going to
post video and let that cook. So now
>> today's day six,
>> it officially just took 18 minutes, 17
minutes, and we just edited our first
video. So that's how you can edit in
just the span of 15 minutes and still
get a super clean edit that is also, you
know, super uniform and clean for both
Tik Tok and Instagram, right? That is
awesome. Now, we're just going to
immediately go on to Instagram and I'm
going to post this initially as a trial,
right?
And
here these seven limiting beliefs.
person do this comment
dream to tune into my free
on speed running
followers
teaching how you can speedrun
okay And now I'm just going to trial it
and
send it up.
>> The harder you train, the strong. There
we go. We did it. So now I'm just going
to let this actually post.
Going to make sure. We're just going to
refresh it on Tik Tok as well to see if
it actually got posted. Here are these
seven limiting beliefs I had to grow out
of in order to re and sometimes you just
need to see just to make sure it gets
its literal first view to see if it
actually gets posted cuz sometimes
content just randomly gets taken down on
Tik Tok. Genuinely Tik Tok's algorithm
can be really freaking annoying. But
we're also going to let this post two
trial reels. Okay, so we're just going
to let this cook and see. And we're just
going to let this give it a second.
Sometimes Instagram literally takes 10
years and that's fine.
Yeah, sometimes the Instagram literally
takes so long to post. Oh, got some
water.
Okay, I think it should be finished
posting. We're just going to check our
trial rules here.
Okay, seems like it's up now. We're just
going to make sure it's posted onto Tik
Tok.
There we We got our first view,
>> which means it is fully posted.
>> Let's go to posting our next video or
let's go to editing our next video. We
got another 39 minutes here. Let's move
on. But yeah, that's the general gist of
editing. So now I'm just going to let
this overlay play as I get into a deep
editing flow state and let's uh continue
to edit your videos as well. Let's get
into it.
Hey up.
Heat. Heat. N.
Heat. Heat.
Hey,
hey, hey.
Hey, hey, hey.
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
Hey, heat. Hey, heat.
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
All right.
Heat. Hey, Heat.
Heat. Heat.
Hey,
hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey,
Hello.
Hey.
feel.
Doo doo doo doo.
Oh,
hey.
Heat. Heat.
Come on.
Heat.
Heat. Heat.
Hey.
Uh-huh.
Nobody's Bye-bye.
Bye-bye.
Byebye.
Heat. Heat.
All right, so the 1 hour timer has
finished. I'm just going to finish up
this one video real quick. Should
probably take another 5 minutes. All
right, and there we go. We're just
finishing up posting this final video.
And you can see here now we have
up four videos. One, two, three, and
then the last one, four up now on Tik
Tok. And there we go. Now, I will go
ahead and edit the next three videos
probably tomorrow, but it's probably
going to take me another 45 to an hour,
right? So, feel free to do that on your
own time as well. But hopefully this
tutorial was helpful. If you found this
video helpful and you want more direct
help from me, I have a private community
where I coach creators, right? And we've
already helped 60 creators grow to their
first 10,000 followers across Tik Tok
and Instagram on their personal brand.
So, if you want to build a personal
brand that can actually help you
monetize and make a full-time living as
a creator, go to that second link in the
description to apply to join Content
Academy. Other than that, thank you guys
so much for freaking watching. If you
found this helpful, yo, let me know in
the comments which part you found the
most helpful. If you want more videos
like this, please let me know. I thought
this would be a really fun spin on the
study with me concept. I always find
myself watching this kind of like
Pomodoro style video from this guy
Justin Sun on the internet. So, it's a
little bit of an interesting video
style, but if you found this helpful,
let me know. I'd love to do them in the
future, too, where I'm just kind of
going about my actual video process. If
you want to see more videos like this, I
guess you can hit that subscribe button
if you want to, you know, if you want
to. Ah, stop. Okay. Okay. I'll catch you
guys in the next one.