I remember the first time I watched one
of your reels there's a chain there's a
cool shirt here I was like wait this is
the head of Instagram and I'm into it
what is the competition for Tik Tok hurt
us but it hurt them way more where does
Instagram lie on Revenue share creators
are tough to keep happy does like watch
time matter people ask a lot about the
algorithm I didn't anticipate that
answer from you what's one of your
interests gardening and planting food in
my backyard all right cool Tik Tok is is
gone from the US what does that mean for
Instagram
I mean today on the Colin beer show
we're joined by head of Instagram Adam
misseri Adam joined Facebook in 2008 as
a product designer and eventually became
the head of Instagram in 2018 we came up
to the Instagram Offices here in San
Francisco and started our conversation
with Adam about what type of content
performs best on Instagram we also
talked about the race to remain
competitive with Tik Tok and YouTube and
asked Adam about his perspective on
creater monetization and revenue sharing
on Instagram it's a really fun and
eye-opening conversation that covers a
ton of ground I think you guys are going
to really enjoy it and if you're
watching here on YouTube make sure to
subscribe here's our conversation with
head of Instagram Adam
[Music]
masseri Adam welcome to the show thanks
for having me the first thing we wanted
to ask you is you're the head of
Instagram um and we were trying to think
in our head like what what does that job
mean like what does your day-to-day look
like
it's a very strange gig you know in the
same day I might talk to a policy maker
about a very serious safety issue I
might talk about the relative allocation
of CPUs and gpus in
2026 I might then have to record
something explaining a new ranking
update or a new feature that we're
launching and then have a one-on-one
with someone who's really mad at me for
some reason and try to figure out why
and how I can do better and that might
all be before lunch so it's very
schizophrenic how do you get to that
point where you now have this very
varied job but you started as a product
designer with Facebook yeah I'm curious
what does it take to number one grow
with someone like Mark Zuckerberg for so
many years and rise in the ranks
essentially to get to this point I think
it was mostly just because I was
reliable I wasn't very good I just have
a lot of range so I'm a decent at a
strangely large number of things and I
think that has really helped me that
helped me in my transition from product
design into product management where
being more of a generalist I think is
more advantageous and then into being an
executive again it's a very generalist
type role to the what we were talking
about before because of the range so my
career really accelerated when I leaned
into that and was honest about what I
wasn't good at is there an element
though of like being able to develop a
relationship specifically with Mark
Zuckerberg someone that clearly you know
well work closely with with you know to
lead Instagram I would imagine you must
have some ability to like work well
right and to pair well yeah I think you
need I mean for any with any boss to
work for them as long as you I have
worked for Mark you need to have some
level
of not just relationship but trust um
but I do think
that with Mark Mark is very consistent
um he is always going to hold a really
really high bar he's always going to
push you really really hard he's always
going to have very high
expectations um and you can you can kind
of when you've worked with anybody for
long enough start to anticipate sort of
what their feedback is going to be what
they care about and so as long as you
make sure you Embrace that in addition
to embracing whatever you believe in and
how to you want to approach the role you
have to find that balance and I think
with
Mark I we have that balance most of the
time I mean we argue a decent amount we
argued a lot in the early years I
remember um pushing back a lot on a
number of random unimportant design
specifics in like 2009 um probably not
good career
advice I look back at my 26y old hot
head self um but over the time like you
build up that trust and where did some
of that tension come from back then of
like what were you fighting for what was
he fighting for like what what does he
care about and what do you care about
about I mean I think those fights were
probably a little bit less principled I
was probably just being a pain in the
ass he was very results focused and I
was I cared about things I still care
about now but I was I didn't care enough
about other things and I think what he
was doing was pushing me hard on the
things that I didn't care about enough
that I should have cared about do you
feel responsible
for Mark's new
style no but I love it I love when I
started seeing him with the chain I was
like he might be hanging out with Adam a
lot yeah the chain is good oh man the
chain is a whole thing there's so many
stories the whole thing I remember the
first time I watched one of your reels
that's kind of how I came across you for
the first time was one of your own reels
oh yeah yeah I was like wait this is the
head of Instagram I was like wait one of
these is not like the other like
comparing you against the other like
Tech leaders I was like there's a chain
there's a cool shirt here what's
happening I'm a big soccer fan this is
zadan um look I think that for a long
time he embraced not using not wasting
any energy on deciding what to wear
every day so he wor like the same thing
every day for a long time as a lot of
tech execs have done over the years and
over the last couple years he's started
to explore expressing himself and I'm
into it I'm totally into it I think
clothes are fun uh so I'm I'm very
supportive yeah uh and also to get memed
like that with the whole beard thing
what I mean you guys spent a lot of time
on the internet how many memes are
positive about a public figure yeah
totally it's such a rare thing and I
think also just like being a fun part of
the conversation is is so great and
you've been that right I've been Meed
I've never been Meed in a nice way I've
only been MD in the standard way it
could happen there's still time all
right I've given upen today who knows
we'll
see um so obviously so much has changed
since that era I mean I come from the
mypace era I put all my band's music on
MySpace unfortunately it's gone forever
now yeah like I can't access that music
anymore um but we come from that era I
from the the Friendster Myspace era into
into Facebook into Instagram um and
Instagram today is is a very different
place than you know it was obviously
when it first started and what the
internet was like when we first started
being creators the only place to really
post video when we first started in 2011
was uh YouTube and Vimeo those were kind
of the two primary did you guys do a lot
with Vimeo back in the day he uploaded
his first videos yeah I was very uh
invested in Vimeo I felt like this is a
true place for artists and filmm yeah
yeah well that's sort of like the design
aesthetic Vibe kind of thing he he
brought me over to YouTube but I was
he's like I care about the results my my
identity was W he was yeah he was
interested in the results I was wrapped
up in being the artist yeah
unfortunately we also came from the era
where like you know the social network
the movie came out and I think we were
just like this is what we have to do we
have to build a a thing and try and get
it acquired that was like the the
modernization of the American dream was
kind of uh perpetuated by by the story
of Facebook right and I think that being
a young person coming out of college
during that time that was the thing it
was like where are we going to build an
audience and how are we gonna um build
something of scale and you were right
and I I guess we were right Vimeo versus
YouTube we were right on YouTube we made
the right move yeah uh but today
obviously there's there's uh an
unbelievable amount of places to to post
video to build audience um I'm just
curious to to dig into the world of
Instagram today uh and and how much
video has changed oh a lot yeah a lot I
mean I think that when people think of
Instagram and you've known Instagram or
you've been on Instagram for a while you
almost always think of a feed of square
photos maybe hypers saturated you know
just maybe a little bit too airbrushed
or you know Landscapes but if actually
you look how people use Instagram it's
just changed dramatically and I
understand that as we evolve Instagram
forward it can be really frustrating
because people get used to using an app
in one way and if it changes underneath
them that can be
annoying but if you think about if we
had stuck with a feed of square photos
and we didn't have stories and we didn't
have DMS and we didn't have videos or
reels we wouldn't be anywhere near as
relevant as we are today I think the
biggest risk that any platform like ours
faces is that the world as it continues
to change faster and faster gets away
from you and you just become irrelevant
because you can't keep up and if you
push too hard and you change too quickly
that can backfire and we've had that
happen and if but if you don't take
enough risk and you are too attached to
the Past then you're just going to
slowly become irrelevant and that's a
balance and so you are asking about
video video is a huge part of what we do
now it's more than half the amount of
time spent on Instagram as video at this
point in most countries it's not the
only thing we do we try to do it
differently than YouTube and Tik Tok uh
where I think it's a bit more of a
laidback passive experience we try to
create a bit more of a participatory
leanin experience one where you're G to
discover a real and then send it to a
friend and then talk about it with
another friend and um but it's still a
huge part of what we do because it's a
huge there's a huge amount of demand and
at the end of the day we're a business
we have to figure out a way to meet
demand as demand moves around and shifts
actually think that's the biggest
differentiator when we talk about video
on Instagram and even when as creators
when we're producing a video for
Instagram that we know is going to be
distrib on Instagram we look at it as a
unit of conversation right like video on
Instagram is so different because of the
DMS it's huge it is such a different
experience because you're essentially
building something if it's successful
then we see that the shares go up right
and that suggests that its success is
determined by someone watching it and
needing to send it to a friend to
connect and it all happens on one
platform right like the the expectation
on Instagram is that I can create
something and everyone from my niece or
nephew to my parents to uh you know a
Creator right a professional Creator can
watch this and we find over and over
again that that ends up being the mo the
healthiest thing to value in the ranking
models people ask a lot about the
algorithms feel like it's a black box
everyone's always feels like they
deserve more reach than they get and
sometimes that's the case but one of the
most important things to look at if
you're trying to evaluate how your
videos or anything is doing on Instagram
is definitely the sends sends I would
look at sends per reach um so of the
people who saw it how many of them sent
it to a friend um because that tends to
be the content that does the best
because it tends to drive the most value
for the overall Community you see
something that you think what what's one
of your
interests uh lately I've been getting
into like gardening and planting food in
my backyard so all right right cool so
let's say you guys I just harvested some
basil is what I'm saying so my best
friend is a has a huge Green Thumb so
we're going to use him as IND this
example instead of me because I would
not like that thing at all but if you
did a whole if you saw some amazing
basil planting video maybe some sort of
time lapse right and you sent that to my
buddy
hondro that is an interesting moment
because you discovered something that
someone made something creative
something beautiful something
interesting and then you shared it with
a friend in this hypothetical world you
and HRA are also buds of course and then
he he psyched to get it and that you
might actually have a conversation about
gardening basil whatever you like but
then he came back to Instagram and then
he actually probably checked out some
more things and then maybe he saw an
amazing you know soccer highlight and
then he sent that to me and that's the
flywheel um where yes you are
discovering something it's consumption
it's somewhat passive to see a video but
then you send it to a friend you start a
conversation then that helps them
discover more things themselves and they
send it to someone else and that starts
another conversation and that's why
short video for us is so
symbiotic with connecting people with
their friends whereas in you know the
world you come from of long form video
is much less so because if you spend 20
minutes watching or 50 minutes watching
a pod video you probably consuming a lot
less content from Friends sending a lot
less things to friends it's a cool
amazing experience so is going to the
movies and watching a two and a half
hour film um but it is less connected to
and less symbiotic with part of our
reason to be which is to connect people
with friends it's also a huge ask to
send someone like a hourong video right
like that's a crazy ask to to message
someone that but to send someone like a
15-second reel on Instagram totally it's
an easy ask but you also see a lot more
15-second videos in 10 minutes then will
watch long videos so is that the most
important factor then when it comes to
reach shares per Impressions on on
average on average yeah and is that a
stat that like you give to us yeah you
can look at shares and you can look at
reach and then you divide those to we
should make it and I have had this
conversation many times with the team
it's amazing how little influence I feel
like I have on a day-to-day basis that
we should um make more prominent in our
insights tools what matters most so that
we can help people focus on that more
yeah I think you need to dictate that to
us as creators because I think that's
something that YouTube does really well
yeah our YouTube studio app tells us
what matters yes and then we all
optimize for those things tot and we
understand it it's like clickthrough
rate and average view duration and if
we're optimizing for those and driving
high percentage retention then the video
does well couldn't agree more I did a
video recently where I talked about
sends per reach U but I only reached so
many people so we got to get into the
insights because a lot more people yeah
use the insights so what else is
important there in that ranking system
if we have sends per Impressions
essentially when you go down the list I
mean it it'll depend right so likes
matter for sure but I think that those
things can be misleading sometimes
because most people will do one or the
other they'll like or they'll send it's
rare that I'll find something send it
and then also like it and it's not that
I wouldn't have liked it it's I got
distracted by the send I think that
liking is so interesting because it's
like sometimes you don't want to
publicly like commit your name name to
something like I don't want to attach my
name to this video but I think it's
funny uh and sometimes I'll do neither
of those things I won't like it or send
it so does does like watch time matter
or length of time I spend on a on a reel
yeah they definitely matter they matter
a lot less than sense but they matter I
think another thing that's important to
take a look at though is less isn't a
direct engagement rate is what
percentage of your reach was unconnected
versus connected because those are
really two parallel systems that mean so
what percentage of your reach came from
accounts that followed you versus what
percentage of your reach came from
accounts that don't follow you we just
showed your content to them so your your
connected reach should be much more
people are going to on me in the
comments here but it should be more
stable than your unconnected reach right
we try not to get between people and
content from accounts that they follow
so there's you know we don't do
demotions minus one or two exceptions
like misinformation and we basically if
we think you're interested in it we show
it to you but when it comes to
unconnected reach showing you something
in explore or in the reals tab as you're
going through content from accounts you
do not follow there there's a lot of
opportunity and there's a lot of
responsibility
on the opportunity side we should be
able to help you discover things you
didn't even know you loved I mean the
whole promise of the internet is that we
should be celebrating Niche interests I
actually heard you on one of your pods
recently talking about on the crater
business side focusing more on Niche but
we shouldn't all listen to the same top
40 songs we should all be able to
discover oh turns out I'm really into
afro beats or something and you're
really into some specific form of reg I
don't know um the internet should help
us do that and so what I think with
recommendations is that should help with
Niche interests and helping small
creators grow because it should help
people discover accounts that normally
wouldn't get discovered uh and also
there's way more unconnected content
than there's connected content so you
maybe follow I don't know a few hundred
accounts you know maybe few thousand
accounts most of them don't post
something to feed in a given day yeah
right so you know let's say there's a
100 or 200 things you could see in a
given
day there's over
there's hundreds of millions of pieces
of content posted today that are from
accounts you do not follow a few of
those might be really exciting for you
and and is it like if I'm a Creator and
I'm thinking about how my videos surface
on Instagram one is obviously in the
connected feed people who follow me
absolutely the other is going to be on
explore yes and then the other if I'm
making reals is in the essentially theab
in the reals tab yeah right and so in
those three places um
what are are all those factors that we
just talked about sends per reach uh
length essentially average view duration
on a video uh engagement like do those
factors rank equally across those three
Discovery platforms no not quite the
same so in feed we try to heavily
preference content from accounts that
you follow and accounts where you've got
Mutual follows so if you and I follow
each other we're probably friends in
real life so that content will got it
that content we will value more um in a
number of ways one of is like we just
shift more of the weight and the value
model towards things that friends would
do with each other's content like liking
um whereas that matters Less in the
context or something like that might
matter Less in or commenting which would
matter Less in an unconnected content
where if you're commenting on a public
real you know it's just different it's a
different place um that probably matters
Less in unconnected surfaces like
explore or reals uh but in General sends
matters the most I think across the
board and we're trying to share as much
as we can like for a while they were
very different system so maybe your
explore was all about men's fashion and
your real tab was all about gardening
and that doesn't make any sense so we're
trying to make sure we consolidate the
infrastructure this is a bit more
technical so maybe less interesting so
that as so the app behaves more like you
would expect if you are really
interested in something that you would
see it in any recommendation surface I
think it's technical but as professional
creators it matters a lot to us totally
right because the first thing we think
about is how does our content surface in
this environment and then we will make
adjustments accordingly right absolutely
how important are follower counts
because I think a a common sort of
frustration amongst some creators is
okay I've put in this work over a period
of time to gain a level of followers
right and I don't feel like I'm actually
seeing the benefits of that yes right
I'm not feeling the rise from that I'm
not reaching them yeah so how what
advice do you have for those types of
creators and how do followers play into
reach follow account is super important
because you're GNA have a much better
chance of reaching anybody who follows
you than anybody who doesn't follow you
so there's a really strong correlation
between how many followers you have and
how many people you reach that said they
matter less today in a world where there
is more time spent looking at
recommendations than before than they
mattered you know five years ago now you
might say stop leaning into
recommendations like just focus on
followers bring back old Instagram the
issue with that is that the pie is
smaller recommendations are driving more
overall engagement yes that's good for
us as a business uh we're connecting PE
consumers with more content they're
interested in so that's good for
consumers but there's more reach to go
around so it actually does lift average
reach for all creators um but it doesn't
mean that your reach is more volatile
because a larger percentage of your
average reach will be through the
recommendation system like I was looking
at some of your reals plays counts this
morning and there's you know you've got
some that went nuts and some that are
relatively small and some of them went
nuts maybe because they're paid
Partnerships and people paid for it but
some of them were just totally organic
uh I mean just candidly the ray band
meta one was fully organic which like 60
million views this is insane I haven't
gotten anything that's like 30X anything
I've ever done or maybe 10 but um which
is awesome the thing we noticed though
when what any of our reels that you know
hit the the I would say three 4 million
plus Mark which is only a few but the
ones that have it's relatively immediate
that they got they start getting shared
yeah it's it's like within the first
hour if we are getting if there people
are sharing them in their stories at a
high velocity then yeah that's what
we're see and that's a sneaky thing that
I think a lot of people don't realize is
a lot of unconnected reach can come not
in the surfaces we've talked about like
explore or the reals tab but they can
show up in stories or they can show up
in in DMS if you share a real into a
story or you share a real as a DM and
someone watches that then you've got
another impression of play and so
sometimes it can come that way too A lot
of those reals are about uh generative
AI or about the rayan meta about like
future Tech and I think
that you know plays to multiple human
emotions one is like excitement you know
there's like the excitement for the
future isn't this crazy I got to share
it with a friend the other is fear right
like this is terrifying so I have to
share it with a friend yeah um and I
think when you tap
into understanding like triggering an
emotional reaction from someone um and
ideally that emotional reaction is the
desire to connect with someone else um
that's where we've seen the the highest
velocity ofip and this is I'll go into
sort of more my personal intuition as
opposed to based on research but we
don't support feed to feed reshares and
even feed to stoies reshares can only
happen once you can't reshare it again
got it so almost all of what we would
call reshares are
dmms and I think that this is again my
hypothesis this is I don't have rigorous
research to back this up that what you
want to share with one friend or with
the group chat is tends to bias if you
if you biased towards that type of
content tends to be healthier than
something that you want the whole world
to know about um and it's not that you
know we have reposts on threads you know
obviously Facebook has reshares Twitter
has their own version everybody's got
this it's not that things are bad but I
do think they bias more towards like the
whole world needs to know about this
horrible thing that happened or this
Injustice or it's a little bit less
personal it's a little bit less Niche I
most of the reals I sent I would never
post to all my followers I've got a
buddy in London CA we' send each other
ex almost exclusively soccer highlights
from like 45-year-old dads making a shot
on a Sunday leag that they'll never make
again hyper very n the whole world
sounds like it was made just for you
awesome yeah exactly uh whereas you know
with my brother it's like pretty off
color dark standup comedy you know never
would post that to all my followers you
know so with my sister it's more
Furniture Design and architecture so
it's more Niche oriented and I think
it's a little bit less Sensational on
average and I think that helps shift the
tenor of the content that you experience
on Instagram and I'm not saying all the
content people see on Instagram as
positive that is not true any major
social network with hundreds of millions
or billions of users it's going to have
all sorts of negative energy in it but I
think the average energy the average
tenor of the content buys is more
positive on Instagram for a few reasons
and one of them is the content that
rises to the top is the content you
would share with an individual in a
conversation not that you would yell
from a rooftop to the whole world that's
really interesting like that what would
you say is the competitive advantage of
Instagram and real specifically when we
look at like the world of short form
video I look at it as Instagram reals
and Tik Tok and it's not that creators
can't post similar types of videos on
both or the same video on both but what
would you say is you or is Instagram's
sort of superpower when it comes to
Reals in relation to Tik Tok I think
it's more creative freedom obviously Tik
Tok has been leaning into photos and
trying to get into other formats like
stories but they've had a lot less
success there I'm not speaking poorly of
Tik Tok they are phenomenal compe they
do a number of things really well and
there's a few things where I still feel
like we're trying to catch up with them
but in general I think our suite of
tools which by the way sometimes can be
a little intimidating or people get
stressed by how many options there are I
do think gives Critter more freedom to
figure out how they want to realize
their goals and I think that's important
we're also a larger platform worldwide
and so that gives you more potential
reach particularly if your content isn't
uh is Glo is globally applicable which
is hard in video I've actually seen you
guys talk about this too where you know
language is a challenge right if your if
your content requires deep understanding
of what's being said that's tough if
someone doesn't speak the language um so
there's a few things like that um but I
think Tik tok's great I think they do
really great work and they've inspired
us to get a lot better at what we call
exploration based ranking so doing
better ranking for smaller creators and
helping them a chance of breaking out
and just be really really reliably
entertaining like it's like you know
you're going to have a pretty good time
if you open up that out yeah it almost
scares me how good of a time it is yeah
it it it's like uh I'm curious like in
comparison and and maybe this
is if you know the specifics or not but
like how long would it take me on
Instagram to change my for you feed
versus Tik Tok
that on Tik Tok F it's way faster if I
start watching cooking videos the next
time I open Tik Tok I'm in the cooking
world right we're still behind them on
speed there you have to be careful
though cuz sometimes you can be the
opposite problem like explore is still a
little Tippy it's like hey I watch one
cooking video like ease up I don't need
this to be all cooking all the time um
that's not just about speed though
that's about intensity so you might
adapt quickly but not go overboard and
how much cooking in that example you use
they're fa they're very fast um and we
they're very fast in two ways one
understanding your interests more
quickly and adapting and two getting
content that is going to be succeed to
succeed really quickly and that helps
them be culturally relevant we've been
closing the Gap um pretty quickly on
both of those fronts but there's still
room to improve on those areas for us
and then on the the note of language
like we we talk about this all the time
that if you want to a successful short
form piece of content it ideally should
be able to be viewed with the sound off
yes not even any language transcend
language totally I was curious if you
know how many people watch Instagram
with their sound off is that a stat that
you know H I don't have the I don't have
a stat to share but last I checked it's
not about people it's about time so like
what percentage of video Impressions
have sound on or off
um and I think it was like it was
roughly half half it was roughly half I
mean give or take 10% plus or minus but
it was roughly half I think that's a
really important thing for creators to
think about yeah that's why captions are
so important that's why you got to make
sure your captions are visible in the
feed not just in the full screen viewer
one of the classic mistakes is put your
captions and you don't even see them
until you expand the video and then by
then you you probably have S on anyway
but ideally you're like similar to
YouTube where we think a lot about title
thumbnail and packaging the packaging of
a short form piece of content is the
first frame yes and the visual hook
right and so the the first frame and the
visual hook should be able to beod
without language that I think is like
the most important piece of advice I
totally agree but there's also ways to
do it in the in the full video that
aren't necessarily like not using
language like I remember
reading um oh man what was his name
Malcolm gladwell's book I think on
strangers and like not not being able to
trust strangers and there's a whole
section in there I forget why it's even
connected to that idea about the show
Friends and how tons of people around
the world have learned to speak English
watching friends cuz you can basically
know exactly what's happening without
understanding any of the words cuz the
acting is so over the top expressive
interesting I'm not trying to offend any
friends lovers out there I know a couple
people life are like passionate about
friends friends is great but you can
kind of know what's going on because
it's almost like a caricature of a
response um and you can think about that
in the content right so I'm not saying
you have to make giant facial
expressions but just watch your video
and see if someone can get the
without actually understanding every
word and as you'll know and if they can
it's going to have a wider appeal so w
with Instagram being so uh DM focused
what I've also noticed is like my
younger cousins use snap a lot for
messaging which is amazing I I like it's
incredible the um how prominent it is as
a messaging app with young people it's
very strong with young people and I I
was curious just we we talked about Tik
Tok I think about snap and I think about
just how young people are using the
internet today versus when you know this
was the earlier version of social it
felt like the battle was for the user
base is that correct like like trying to
get as many users as possible like what
is
the what what is the the war you're
fighting or the battle you're fighting
today with the other competitors like
what is the competition
for it's for a number of different
things I mean it is at some level for
attention right we are an advertising
based business and that business is
going to be proportional to the amount
of attention that's spent on the
platform got it but it's also for
cultural relevance I I think a lot about
what decisions do we need to make that
don't necessarily grow the pie but I
think will be good for the business over
the long term so I mean one thing that
is controversial is we focus on creators
and we don't focus on Publishers we
don't try to prevent Publishers from
using our platform but we build features
for creators we don't build features for
Publishers I don't have teams that goal
on P any any production that includes
Publishers if I can avoid it I have
team's goal on Creator production can
you define the difference yeah so a
Creator is an individual that creates
original content with some level of
commercial intent that's a I don't mean
necessarily making money it could just
be like sure part of what you do you're
trying to grow because you're trying to
achieve something on the platform um so
Publishers are you know brands
magazines newspapers doesn't have to
just be news um and there's there's
amazing content from Publishers on the
platform but they're not individuals um
they are creating original content and
they definitely have commercial intent
and we focus on creators because we
believe con power is going to continue
to shift from institutions to
individuals across Industries we've seen
this in sports we've seen this in news
we've seen this in music we've seen this
in every vertical but just think about
how
relevant as athletes are right now
relative to the play relative to the
teams that they play for sure and how
different that was 20 30 years ago with
very few exceptions a lot of people's
Allegiance is sometimes primarily to a
player now not to a team that's insane
if you think about sports fans when I
was a kid and so we just think that that
is that shift is going to continue and
we also see that in the data creaters
drive on average more engagement than
publisher does people want to see the
world through the eyes of another
individ idual that they relate to or
that they look up to more than they want
to consume content from a publisher that
they feel is hyper processed and
produced and um designed for them if if
that Trend keeps up uh what does
Instagram have to do to continue to make
creators happy I think a lot about when
uh Kylie Jenner shared that post of
Instagram Instagram again and that was
in relationship to like some pretty good
memes about me that was fun but like if
you know LeBron has more followers than
the Lakers right like if that Trend
continues for creators yes what does
Instagram have to do to keep creators
happy in the next five 10 years creators
are tough to keep happy um but there's a
number of different things that we know
that they care about and we work hard
contrary to popular belief I'm trying to
keep them happy um one is clearly you
know is reach and it's not I do think
reach is a means to an end it's not an
end and of itself and I think too many
people just focus on reach for reach's
sake but you want reach should be
growing over time and ideally relatively
stable that's very hard to deliver on
any platform that guarantees you stable
reach is lying uh that doesn't mean that
platforms aren't working on it and
trying to give you more reach and trying
to figure out how to grow the pie but
pure stability is really it's not
possible even if everyone just did
chronological feeds everywhere but that
matters a lot um I it also Matters How
safe you feel on the platform do you
feel like you can be yourself um or the
part can you share the part of stuff
that you want to share um so that's
about protection it's about dealing with
you know any antagonistic behaviors or
bullying or harassment but safety
matters a lot um Revenue matters a lot
but actually to a very small subset of
creators the vast majority of creators
are very small and they're too small to
monetize in a meaningful way and so yes
they care about monetization they want
to hear about monetization but it's
actually not the thing that they can or
should really focus on because if you
have 2,000 followers it's not really
going to be the thing that you spend
your time on is figuring out how to grow
your following not try to make money
from 2,000 followers um they also care a
lot about being able to connect with and
interact with both the their fans but
also other creators so we try to also
figure out ways to facilitate
connections between creators and
creators and fans actually that's
another thing that we do really
particularly well that we kind of loed
into is with DMS if I just I'm a fan of
you and I follow you and then you figure
who I am and then you you can text me on
Instagram and it goes into my inbox so I
know people in Hollywood who just like
end up making real connections with
people who become lifelong business
partners because they like their stuff
on Instagram and it's not even they're
not even digital Ned creators it's like
a film score or a director um so those
are the things we try to improve and um
obviously um we've got room to improve
across the board as ases everybody I
think it's interesting to hear that uh
revenue is not as important and sure for
for a Creator who maybe has 2,000
followers it's like not something that's
coming their way when we told our
friends that we were coming here who are
primarily YouTube creators that we were
going to be sitting down with you they
were so interested in Revenue I think
for us like we come from this culture of
Revenue share yeah and I know Facebook
does it and I'm curious like where does
Instagram lie yeah Revenue share I'll
talk about Revenue share in a second but
you should also tell me if I'm wrong
that's just the research that we have
suggests what what creators care about I
think for me the the challenge is that I
don't think we can
blanket use the term creators anymore
and I and I think specifically on
Instagram I think it's harder to use
that term I think the term is so broad
that it's challenging to have it
encapsulate everyone in the category
right and and when it comes to Instagram
like you know my parents are on
Instagram they post content on Instagram
and they probably have a thousand or
2000 that we have so many cousins Indian
family so it's like we have so many
cousins we probably have 2,000 followers
on YouTube there's more a divide between
like Creator and consumer line is
Instagram it's way more it's just like
everyone everyone can be considered a
Creator and so there for me if we look
at it as like a a pyramid of like the
emerging Creator you know as the base of
the pyramid the vast majority on
Instagram is going to be an emerging or
aspiring Creator someone who knows how
to make good stuff but they haven't
figured out how it can become their
their full-time income then you have
like the professional Creator group
who's making a living right and then you
have the top tier which is probably like
uh A-list celebrity and and hyper large
scale creators at the top of that if if
we're talking about Creator pyramid
there and the base is not gonna care
about revenue or maybe they care about
it but it's not going to be a factor for
them yet yes but the next Notch and up
care a ton care car to
to I think there's a bit of for me on
Instagram that I've accepted the fact
that the way we monetize is we build an
audience and then we it's a part of our
broader advertising business it's not
something we split with the platform
yeah but we're able to sell you know
native advertising
ourselves Instagram yeah which makes a
ton of sense that's actually last I best
we can tell well north of A5 billion
industry is people doing brand deals off
platform on in and then Distributing
that content on Instagram so and I do I
do totally understand the revenue
matters a ton particularly for large
creators and large creators are
disproportionately important right
because they reach more people um on rev
share because I I want to make sure I'm
not St in the question it's something
that we're working on it's something
that I think is just fundamentally more
difficult with short form video though I
do think shorts is doing decently um but
with long form video Everything is a bit
more straightforward um particularly
attribution so if you watch a 20-minute
video and you see three ads you know
what percentage you want to share and
it's very clear who those who that share
goes to um whereas with short firm video
if you watch 50 videos and you see 15
ads
who gets those dollars um so attribution
is tricky in and of itself but the
bigger problem is that we haven't
figured out a way to do it that isn't
just burning cash um so we are running
tests for what we call bonuses which are
essentially performance-based incentives
so you know we will pay you to create
more content and then people create more
content but then we measure does that
actually increase the revenue for the
app and so that we can actually have
money to share back and we are finding
that it is much easier to make those
programs Roi positive for photos than
for videos and one of the reasons is
photos are higher monetization
efficiency because you you get more add
Impressions because you look at photos
for less time but another is that per
dollar when you pay a Creator to create
something new they will create more
incremental photos and incremental
videos because videos are harder to make
and really interesting
the incremental content they make is
lower quality than the average quality
but that drop is much lower for photos
than for reals so they'll make another
reel but they will only make one and
it's way worse than the Reel that they
would have created otherwise um or the
first reel that they would have created
either way and so we are trying to
figure out okay what can we do about
that how can we get this working because
to me I need that program to make enough
money so that we can pay
creators and have those checks be
credible if I send you guys a $112 check
it's probably going to make you think
worse of us than if we just didn't have
a program and so we're iterating and
we're iterating in Japan and Korea and
the us to try to get these programs on
their video side working so that we can
then scale them up but for us to do that
it's going to need to be it's going to
need to not burn money it's going to
need to be uh get to a place where the
eligibility can be I hope ideally uh
public so you know why you're allowed to
be in the program in the first place and
the checks need to be credible um which
probably comes down to cpms at the end
of the day yeah I think credibility is
the most important because I don't think
you know if we got a $12 check I don't
think I would be I would feel
disrespected or anything like that I
would just want to know how did that
happen yeah but it might discourage oh
it might discourage but if I knew if I
knew there was a clear path towards like
hey this is why it was $12 based off the
viewership you got here's what you can
do to increase it right I may feel
better about the trick though is it's
not just about your viewership it's
about the replacement value so let's say
you made you made 10 reals through the
program and they all got really good
views but if you hadn't made it we would
have had just as much engagement from
him that was in paid for then from an
Instagram business perspective the the
ROI is negative 100% so if we paid you a
th000 bucks making up numbers now for 10
res and the replacement value was Z you
would look at it your reals and be like
they all got 500,000 views and these are
the cpms you owe me X and it's like yes
but from a business perspective if we
hadn't paid you
$1,000 and we would have had we would
have made the exact same amount of
Revenue then then we've actually just
burned $1,000 and so it's yes we should
we should show you why um but My worry
is that let's say I show you why to the
degree I can and let's say I even pay
you more more than 100% M let's say it's
$1,000 and I pay I pay you $1,000 and we
and we only and we only made an
incremental
$900 you know I've lost $900 and you've
got a $100 check and you probably are
going to think that I'm being cheap
because I'm only paying you a 100 bucks
for 10 videos that got half a million
views each so It's Tricky and I'm not
trying to say our job is hard of course
our job is hard and we've got great jobs
and I'm very grateful for them yeah I'm
just saying that the program has to be
sustainable because if it's not if we're
burning cash when things get tight when
the economy goes up and down and AD
dollars go up and down and a lot of our
business is just exposed to
macroeconomics at this point then when
we cut marketing budgets like one of the
things that we're going to cut is a
program that is literally burning money
and I need the program to be stable
right I can't have a program this year
and take it away for everyone and take
it away next year and then bring it back
to year after that's just jerking you
around and you all particularly the
large craters you're a business so how
much money you make matters but so does
the consistency of those dollars so that
you can plan accordingly you know I
think we had it's really interesting
actually I I didn't anticipate that
answer from you I think uh what you just
said makes a ton of sense uh and I think
about when we first started we were
making such Niche content on YouTube
that AdSense and revenue share was
nominal for the first n years of us
being on YouTube and so we learned how
to build a business without Revenue
share and so when even when I think
about Instagram
like I I do think that now the culture
and to look out out the next five 10
years like solving some level of Revenue
share for for video is important or some
level of platform monetization but
largely because of what you just talked
about from a macroeconomic standpoint I
think all creators need to solve if
consistency is important the ads
business is actually not the best
business to be consist it's inherently
volatile it's inherently volatile so
then if you're building a a a business
on top of you know Instagram then
platform monetization would not be the
path for your most consistent check I
think we want to feel valued because we
feel valued by other platforms and I
think
YouTube figuring out the the the shorts
Revenue sharing model in this like large
pool um it feels like a nice step in
that direction I was curious what you
thought about that of like the the model
that they've implemented there I think
it's a I think it's a good model I don't
know if it's working or not sure from a
business perspective because I don't
know maybe they're just subsidizing
their shorts business with their long
form video business or with their search
business because they want to grow in
short form video because I mean Tik Tok
hurt us in 2020 2021 but it hurt them
way more so it's not unre unreasonable
as a business to take a loss in order to
grow market share um and assume that
you're going to figure it out later
which they might be doing um and to be
clear like they are best in class at rev
share but rev share is not the only way
to make money as a Creator whereas Tik
Tok is best in class at discovering
small craters and helping them pop but
it's not Best in Class at rep share it's
not Best in Class in stability of reach
in fact that ability to pop is sort of
inversely correlated with stability of
reach because it's more volatile by
definition and so I think they're doing
I think they're doing good work I think
I know a lot of people who work there
who just do good stuff I don't know if
they're subsidizing it or if they're
just better at it than we are or what or
what's going on but also YouTube
isn't Google or alphabet's main business
search is their main business and
whenever you are in an adjacent business
like I'm sure they care about their p&amp;l
and I think you guys interviewed Neil
before but it's not the same pressure uh
like whereas Instagram yes Facebook and
Instagram
our like sister apps like we're both
driving most of the revenue for the
company in order to subsidize all the
other longer term bets that we're making
so one thing is Facebook video we have
friends who their number one yeah
Revenue Source people underappreciate it
is Facebook instream ads yeah it's huge
it's a huge source of Revenue and a lot
of that is because they're posting you
know relatively longer form content 3 to
six maybe 10 minute videos on Facebook
and the content's engaging and I'm
surprised always when we meet a Creator
who's like yeah I make most of my money
from Facebook Facebook is much bigger
than Instagram worldwide if you just
look at Raw minutes per day or raw hours
per day I do think though it's a
different app in a number of ways they
don't have DMS in it um we have a much
stronger position and a lot more on in a
lot of countries not all countries
around friends sharing products like
stories not just DMS and I just think I
think of like connecting friends is an
adjacent thing to Short from video and
short from video is an adjacent thing to
Long Fromm video but long firm video and
connecting friends aren't adjacent and
it pains me to because I love podcasts
uh watching them listening to them doing
them um I actually did a couple
interviews with creators over the last
couple weeks and it pains me sometimes
that long form content just doesn't have
a real great home on Instagram but if
our core thing is about connecting
people over creativity I can't get
enamored with the longform video
business and then lose our core identity
people think and they give us criticism
and it's fair sometimes that sometimes
we lose our way or forget who we are but
the reason why I am not interested in
pursuing long form video in a meaningful
way is because I don't want to erode our
our it's not even our business like our
our heart like our core reason to exist
I do think a a piece of short form
vertical content right now is one of the
highest margin branded content pieces in
a Creator business like we've
experienced it right like when we do a
short form vertical video
campaign typically the ad dollars are
there right there's there's more ad
dollars that have shifted towards short
form vertical video now the piece of
content can also be posted across
platform uh different platforms and it's
easier to make than a long form YouTube
video and so in this moment right now
the short form vertical video branded
content business is probably the highest
margin video business for creators that
obviously is dependent on your size and
scale but I think in in large part that
is the highest margin business right now
as a Creator I believe that you did a
video on uh pod recently I forgot what
the name of the Creator was but they
starting to charge and they got a big
backlash they wanted to they they put a
lot of their content
yes and so you were talking
about this sort of
space I think there are things that long
form is better at and I think there are
things that are short form are better at
but from an advertiser's perspective I
think it depends on what the
advertiser's outcome is right so just
think about branded content in general
even in the podcast world right you've
got one extreme which is basically
direct response
advertising ag1 subscriptions where they
take a cut of the subscription and then
you get the other end which is like much
more sort of like almost like you're
playing in like the B2B space like
acquired you know and they're getting
each deal that those guys get is a big
deal for them they spend a lot of time
nurturing those deals they have a few
deals but those deals are pretty solid
and they almost all of those guys who
sign up stick with them um and then
there's a whole range of things in
between so if you're trying to reach a
small Niche audience and have a really
deep stable connection you know I think
acquired long form type stuff whether
it's podcasts or otherwise maybe YouTube
videos is probably better creating a
deeper richer more enduring long-term
connection for sure yeah if you're
trying to do like um you know Dr maybe
it doesn't matter because you just want
to get that that one conversion or maybe
you're trying to do brand awareness and
there there it's really about just
getting a larger type of funnel so it's
not about the niche it's just like you
want to reach as many people as possible
to let them know about toothpaste or
whatever it is that you're selling
something that has really a broad
addressable market and so as a Creator
yes you should think about your costs a
lot and how much does it take and cost
you to make a photo versus a short form
video versus a long form video but as
you think about your Advertiser deals
that you work with and if you are
privileged enough to be able to be picky
you should understand what kind of
business they are and what they're
trying to get out um what they're trying
to get out of advertising and how much
your content or the Deep different types
of content you could create align with
those Advertiser
interests and I think that's a level of
sophistication that's hard if you spend
all of your time just trying to figure
out how to make something that pops uh
which I which I get which I totally get
I think you have to spend have had spent
some time in your life which we did
fortunately sitting in those rooms with
advertisers and understanding and
empathizing with their position yeah and
I think once you can understand that you
can understand how they fit into your
world one of the things that we think
from our side because this is obviously
you know a multi-sided Marketplace so
primarily two-sided and then we're a
platform is in the world of branded
content if that's the primary way that
creators make money on Instagram one of
the interesting things it's just there's
no measurement there's like so little
measurement people don't advertisers
don't necessarily know what they're
going to get yes you can be like go to
momentus
elements.com Adam and like hopefully we
can like do the attribution that way but
for the most part there's very little
measurement um in that world my take is
that larger names tend to get overpaid
and smaller names get underpaid because
the advertisers advertisers spend more
based on intuition because they don't
have numbers to go off of that's a
distortion in the market that scares me
because I feel like any Distortion will
inevitably get corrected at some point
and we'll probably get blamed for it and
so I want to figure out how we can help
that the whole industry move forward
that's one of the reasons why I like
partner ads so much is not because
they're a potential Revenue stream for
us though they are but because they
allow branded content to have proper
measurement and if we do that if more of
this industry or more of the Branded
content ecosystem is measured my
hypothesis is that you will see dollars
shift from the largest creators to more
Niche creators you might sell more of
whatever you're trying to sell by
reaching 100 small creators than running
one big check for the same amount of
Total Money to one big Creator but right
now you would never do that because it's
impossible to manage can we help that
through measurement through connections
through the Creator Marketplace is I
think something that we're still trying
to crack could you explain partner ads
Yeah so basically way a partner ad works
is you do what you would normally do so
you would like who's one of your oh we
we talked about Canon before so let's
say Canon was like we want you to make
some content uh we want to do some ads
for you uh with with you for our cameras
you would make the creative and then you
would make it so that they could use
your creative as an ad to people who
don't even follow you yep and it just
basically allows you to own the creative
the content is attributed to your
account but it can get distributed
through our ad system and so it gets all
of the measurement of our ad system and
all that infrastructure um which helps
advertisers understand demand understand
demographics understand
conversions um because the bread and
butter of our advertising business is
not brand advertising though that's a
good amount of money it's direct
response advertising where measurement
is everything uh and then Canon will
know all right I wrote These Guys a
check like what did I get for it and
like that could be scary yeah yeah or
that could be amazing because if you are
if if if they realize that they paid you
I'm making up random numbers now
$110,000 but they made
35 you know that's then you're worth
more than you're getting paid got to
increase our rate yeah but then but you
would never know unless we do this so I
love I I actually love that about
Instagram because it makes the
advertising more native to the platform
right like the advertising is Creator
oftentimes it's creators in sponsored
post which is great because then it's
like native advertising to the platform
I actually think that's where YouTube is
behind right now and I don't think it's
the platform's fault I actually think
it's the probably the industry at the
moment where they're running TV spots on
YouTube where if you were running ads on
YouTube with YouTube creators in the
pre-roll that felt more native I
actually think there'd be more effective
ads yeah um and I think those are those
are really effective on Instagram I do
think the more measurable advertising
gets the less it values General kind of
brand lift and association with creators
that's true but I think that's mostly
true because brand lift is harder to
measure it's it's you can't measure it
really but there's like a I guess you
can through like surveys and you just
need a lot of scale to be able to do it
without the air bars being so Bonkers
that it's not even worth doing yeah um
but to be clear I mean there's a lot of
AD dollars right now on brand marketing
with very little measurement I mean just
think about how TV works yeah uh I mean
there's measurement it's not no
measurement but it's not have you ever
met someone who's a neelon house no no I
have not never met I've never gotten
that phone call I've never gotten the
call I'd think I'd be a great neelon man
would
terrible actually have one question on
paid partnership when when we click like
paid partnership yeah or branded content
but that the advertiser doesn't boost
the content use it as sponsorship does
anything happen in the ranking system to
our content nothing no no we don't I
mean it would be really problematic if
that decreased your reach because then
we'd have people avoiding marking things
as paid and by the way in some countries
it's law like you can get in real
trouble in Germany for instance for
getting paid and not marking something
as paid so much so that a lot of people
in Germany creators Mark things that as
paid that aren't paid worried that
there's like there might be some maybe
they got a gift like a year ago and it's
gonna get they're gonna get in trouble
they do hashtag ad on all this yeah yeah
yeah I'm curious you mentioned smaller
creators what are some sort of metrics
or talking points that smaller creators
could use to convince advertisers and
maybe it's you know agencies who are
using this information but how does that
smaller Creator get that deal I think
it's probably about being more clear
about
who your audience is and why that
audience is disproportionately valuable
to that Advertiser so you know let's use
I don't I don't love the example of
supplements because there's so many
Shady actors in that world but it's an
easier example like if you only have a
few thousand followers but they're
really passionate and they're all about
like biohacking and health stuff then
like they are way more valuable to a
thorn supplement um Advertiser than the
average person and so you shouldn't just
care as The Advertiser about the number
you should care about how much How
likely in this case this hypothetical
example those followers are to want to
buy your product um so it's about
understanding your Niche and why that
Niche is disproportionately valuable to
that Advertiser is probably the most
straightforward way do you do you care
if a Creator is considered an Instagram
Creator in the same way that I think you
know YouTube creators just have a brand
to them right that's a YouTube Creator
or a Tik to or a Tik tocker like you
guys are YouTubers yeah we're YouTubers
right like I know I wanted to say it a
lot at some point but like do you care
about like creators being considered
Instagram creators I care about our
cultural relevance and both to the
general population and to creators I
think that I don't think that we should
ever do anything to discourage YouTubers
or Tik tokers who are primarily on those
platforms from being successful that
would be
literally just bad for our business um
but I do care that there is a critical
mass of crators that have an affinity
for and a loyalty to our platform which
is one of the reasons why I care so much
about small creators in general I think
it's way more practical to help a new
generation of creators grow on your
platform and therefore have some more
affinity and loyalty to your platform
than it is to pull someone who's had 15
years of success on YouTube and get them
to switch their primary that's just
swimming Upstream
um that's another reason why I think
small crators are super important and
why we' trying to do more and more to
benefit
them um but I think if we are only a
secondary platform for most crators
that's probably a bad place to be in
best case we can best we can tell we are
a larger we're the largest platform for
creators so there's the most creators
active on our platform but obviously
we've talked about a couple things where
other platforms are better um but I do
but the sentiment is not quite as high
um so
people well probably hearing this as a
crater and if you're upset about your
reach you're probably going to think the
sentiment is really bad that is true
there is definitely a group of people
who are really upset about reach uh it
doesn't come it isn't like the over
doesn't overwhelm sentiment for the
entire population um it's in some sense
a very loud and I'm not trying to throw
any shade here but a very loud minority
that we're trying to figure out how to
address and we need to do better by but
actually the average sentiment around
Instagram for the average Creator is
quite high but it's not quite as high in
certain countries as some of the
competition and I I'd like to close that
Gap yeah I feel like um I'm curious like
how do you get that next crop of
creators excited about Instagram I think
they have to have find you have to they
have to find success on the platform
yeah but they also have to maintain that
success so more small creators will find
some success on Tik Tok than any other
platform but often it's like a flash in
the pan and then it goes away and that's
not really helpful because you haven't
built anything sustainable um whereas on
Instagram and on YouTube it's harder to
break in I think we aren't as good at
valuing small smaller creators it's
harder from a technical reason you've
got less data but uh so it's a little
bit harder to break in so we're trying
to find the right balance make it
possible for new talent to break out and
and grow
while not losing so much
not getting not not having reach become
so volatile that your follower account
doesn't matter and people say it doesn't
matter on Instagram but it really
matters in a way that it doesn't matter
nearly as much on some of the other apps
I think that's a challenge that creators
have with short form content no matter
where it is is building brand right if
you're making long form content it is
difficult but if someone chooses to
spend 20 minutes with you they will
remember you tomorrow there are times
when with short form content because you
can consume so much in such a short
amount of time that you may not actually
remember the Creator you just saw even
if you loved what you just saw right it
feels like it served the purpose of
entertainment for you like that lean
back experience I don't know if I agree
so yes if you were going to compare
someone who watched one 15-second video
end to end and one 15 video 15minute
video sorry 15 minute video end to end
so clearly you're going to have more
memory more affiliation with the with
the um 15 minute video I don't know that
means that on average the average sord
creator has a harder time building a
brand because the average short fir
Video Creator can make many more videos
for the in the same amount of time for
the same amount of
money um so you might mean you get more
at bats I think it's what makes it
harder to stand out on the first for as
first impression are surrounded yeah
yeah I will say though like I I think
about and Colin and I talk about this
like every platform needs model citizens
right because the younger crop that
comes in they need to see what success
looks like totally YouTube is you know
with YouTube we have the Mr Beast the
Ryan Tran the Michelle car and right now
when I think about Instagram and I think
about a short form Creator who has stood
out quite a bit I think about Haley yeah
uh Haley Bailey she produces so much
content unbelievable the amount of
content on every platform out of this
world she's not like exclusive To Us by
any searches imag yeah that is an
incredible feat truly but to put out
that much I think she is extremely
recognizable and what Colin's mentioning
of like building a brand on the platform
she's built an Inc I think about Keith
Lee as well who really long F reviews
you know love these niches which is
amazing uh and I do think that there are
some you know what I would consider
model citizens emerging they're not
necessarily exclusive to the platform or
uh but I'm curious if you have that
feeling if you have that sense of like
that's something that Instagram needs to
inspire the younger crop I think we need
that I think you need models to have
other or success stories for the newer
creators to look up to we do see that
more creators have us as our primary PL
as our primary platform than any other
platform and all the off platform
surveys we do so you're more likely if
you're a Creator to say um Instagram is
my primary than any other platform but
also at the same time every time we
measure the number of creators that use
multiple platforms goes up because the
Creator Community is getting more Savvy
you don't want to have all of your risk
in one basket um so I do think that that
is a hard position to maintain long term
but it is a um there is a certain amount
of cache and cultural relevance that
comes with Instagram that we have to
fight to maintain um because I think
that's also can easily um fall so it
does matter it does matter that you have
success stories to prove that it can you
can realize your aspirations on the
platform because if you can't see
anybody that you can relate to who
succeeded on the platform you're not
going to believe that you can
the some of the early success stories on
Instagram from when I remember us
building our career were a lot of the
like meme accounts or the aggregator
accounts yeah and I know you recently
made an announcement around originality
and a commitment to originality I was
wondering if you could explain that
controversial G to get a lot of heat
from the aggregators coming up so I do
want to separate memes and um
aggregators sure because you can be an
original Meme creator there a lot of
great meme creators out
there so the idea behind originality is
that we should make sure that more value
if we can flows to the original creators
that make something then those who find
that content and then um repackage it
and aggregate it from other original
content creators and that if we don't do
that we will just erode more and more
trust with the original content creator
Community which will be bad for us over
the long run it'll manifest as negative
sentiment people leaving the platform
maybe they stay on the platform but
they're quick to um criticize us nobody
defends us and I think reputation
matters um even though it might actually
not be beneficial it might be beneficial
but it might not probably won't be
beneficial to the business in the short
run so this is a classic challenge in
running a business of short-term
long-term trade-offs are you willing to
eat a long a short-term hit because you
think you're going to be in a better
place longterm even if you might not
ever be able to measure it because what
you're in this case you're doing is
you're reducing the risk of a negative
outcome and so if it doesn't happen you
never knew that it would have um so what
we work on is meas defining originality
and there's different buckets there's
original there's mixed original so if I
take your video and then I like do a
green screen on top and I talk about it
that's mixed original and then there's
unoriginal or and mixed unoriginal so I
just like take someone else's and i'
post it can we get good at classifying
that content and can we um figure out
how to
responsibly privilege the original
content and I don't think we want to
boost I don't like boosts like if you
just boost something it's bad because
it's just tends to be opaque it's a
little bit like no one knows what's
happening behind the curtain and it
doesn't feel very transparent so what
we're trying to do is in some sense
riskier is not recommend content from
aggregators so if you follow an
aggregator because you love the and
there are a lot of amazing aggregators
out there great you'll see their content
in your feed if we think you're
interested in it we're not going to do
anything to get between you and that
content if you're not seeing it it's
because we could be wrong but we think
something else is more interesting to
you that you
follow but if we show you content from
an aggregator from an account you don't
follow then that's much more on us and
so I actually said this before there's
more opportunity and there's more
responsibility um so if we if you see
something Shady from like a friend of
yours that's like on your shady friend
if we show you something Shady from a
random person that's really on us uh so
there's more count there's more risk and
more accountability but there's also
more opportunity I think it is
reasonable for us to say we're not going
to amplify we're not going to recommend
content from aggregators um but we are
going to recommend content from creators
because we are invested in creators over
the next five or 10 years so let's just
say like practical example is a sports
highlight aggregator posts a high school
dunk but the original creator of that
video yes was one of that uh basketball
player's friends who was filming it yes
they filmed it it got reposted on a on a
big Sports account yes so is the
suggestion there that instead of showing
it from the sports account it would show
it from the original post that is one
thing we do we call that direct replace
okay so if we can find the original then
we just swap it out um which is pretty
nuts so it's almost as like a reshare
like would it still look like it's from
the aggregator
no I was saying it would be the original
video in your feed again this is in a
recommendation it would be weird if it
was just in the connected context you're
just looking at stuff that we think you
think are going to be interesting in the
reals tab this aggregator found this
amazing dunk if we know if we can find
the original post of that dunk we're
just going to swap it out and show you
the original because in the feed yeah
yeah got it you know and how do you find
that is that like the content ID system
similar to YouTube yeah very similar so
in in our experience with Content ID and
like original
content specifically whether it's
YouTube Instagram Tik Tok most of our
content is cut in a different way than
we would cut it it's it's meaningfully
transformed yeah um so it doesn't get
picked up in a in a Content ID system
right it's a clip of us sitting with Mr
Beast but there's Now new b-roll on top
of it so that's not gonna get picked up
right the most viewed Colin and Samir
videos on the internet are not made by
us yeah yeah right by other people and
for us in in where we are in business
I'm completely fine with that that is
more visibility for us the internet is
better at cutting clips from our videos
than we are there will be clips from
this of you that are cut by other people
right that are just
crowdsourced um you know and I I don't
really have a problem with that I think
that's okay um and I it's it's hard to
find the original Source when and we
can't always find it mostly it will be
transformed in some way shape or form
yes right but that's why we can't just
rely on Direct replace so direct replace
only gets us so far what we look at is
what percentage of recommendations so
what percentage of photos and videos
that you're seeing from accounts you do
not follow are original or unoriginal
and we want we want to grow the
percentage that is original there will
always be recommendations that are
unoriginal because we're never going to
be perfect and that's I want to be clear
like at our skills it's not possible
doing the direct replace or that swap
only gets you so far um because maybe
the original was posted on YouTube or
was posted on Tik Tok talk we then we
can't know who's is the original um so
what we look at is does this account
tend to post original content or does
this piece of content look like an
original piece of content so you look at
things like how similar is this video to
the last n videos that this account has
posted aggregators tend to have much
more variance my stuff my grid is boring
as hell you just it's just my mug over
and over and over again right so it's
not that hard for a classifier to tell
that my account is Po in original
content uh or that any given video on my
account is probably original if it's me
again um sorry if you follow me um
whereas if it's an aggregator there's a
lot more variance and so it's much more
likely that the classifier will predict
that this thing is unoriginal and if it
does we're not going to demote it from
anybody who follow to anybody from
anybody who follows you but we're not
going to recommend it proactively to
someone who doesn't follow you and so we
do this at the content and the actor
level and we want to let you know so if
we think you're a Content aggregator we
want to let you know that and we'll put
that in account status so you can see
okay you're non- recommendable not
because you post anything problematic
but because you're an aggregator and
we're not recommending aggregators and
and that way you can do something about
it maybe you need to you need to do more
of your own spin on things add your
b-roll add your commentary add your I
mean look if you take my photo and you
make it into a meme of me with some
really mean mean comment on on the top
that is original yeah wow whether or not
I like it you may have just asked for
that with that video I get it anyway you
should see my DMs it's a thing so
another thing that we're seeing
specifically this week uh is Instagram
tagging and classifying content as made
with AI yes and that is uh you know
something that I noticed a week ago and
I was like huh that's strange I this
photo does not look like it was made
with AI but maybe it's maybe they did
some fill on Photoshop and and posted it
on here there probably something really
light like that is that how that works
like and how does it it's just the
metadata on the on the image so we're
trying to lean on the on industry
standards here so there's going to be
more and more content that is generated
with AI over time and is going to be
more and more difficult to identify it
there is no way we're going to be able
to programmatically identify everything
that is posted on Instagram as that was
that did use AI as having used AI long
term so I want to be clear like the goal
here is wouldn't we know for us to be
transparent so that people can make
educated decisions about what to believe
and not by the way it might have no
relevance because if it's just a funny
video then it's a or funny picture
doesn't really matter if it's made with
AI or not necessarily so we're trying to
lean on industry standards here and so
there is a Adobe has I forget what the
name of the metadata property or
attribute is but they Mark files that
used AI in Photoshop as having used Ai
and then we pick that up and we mark it
and um some of the other apps are doing
the same thing um what's happening is
people are doing benign things in
Photoshop that are technically using AI
it might not even be generative fill it
might be like I don't know maybe their
stamp tool uses AI you know you know
because AI is just a core technology
doesn't mean totally fabricated image
and so it's getting marked because
they're being conservative in what
they're marking in the file and then
we're just respecting the files mark
saying hey AI was used to make this and
then it's possible that the creator
doesn't even know that it was Ai and the
tool that they used so we have to figure
this out because clearly this is
frustrating and not the ideal experience
um and I'm not sure where we're going to
land because it's this isn't just an
Instagram Ora issue it's an industry
issue and I think if we do our own thing
and everyone does their own thing then
and you don't have an industry standard
I think the whole internet is less well
off um but we have figure rap ing
problem I would say with the election
it's has to be so trusted in the event
that something gets posted without that
made with AI but it is in some way
altered and it just wasn't picked up
then you're in a real situation where
people are believing something but
that's also going to happen like right
now if you make an image you know with a
number of different of these uh
diffusion models and it doesn't Mark and
a lot of them don't mark it in the in
the metadata like we don't have a way to
tell we can build classifiers to trust
try to detect it looking at the typical
types of artifacts you might see but
that is an arms race and we will never
have full coverage I want to be super
clear there will be content on all
platforms that is made by Ai and is not
marked as AI because the platform wasn't
able to detect it because the person who
made it specifically tried to avoid that
and that just means that yes I think we
should do our part to detect what we can
to label what we can but people also
just have to be Discerning readers or
consumers because
this isn't an Instagram thing this is an
internet thing you're going to have to
assume that it's possible that someone
made something um using these
technologies that was by the way
possible before gender of AI it's just
way more possible now yeah it's way
easier now I think what makes it harder
on Instagram is that Instagram is this
wide array of content where I can open
Instagram and see that you know one of
my friends from high school is having a
baby and then I can immediately go into
like geopolitical issues and then
immediately go into watching a creator
that I like and I think the context
switching in my brain of what's truth
and not truth or real and not real is
harder in a platform where I'm
consuming such a wide variety of what's
serious what's entertainment what's
comedy no I agree with that I mean the
cognitive load in a platform where the
content has more variation and not just
substance but like topic and how you
should approach it you know how I should
approach a video of my my brother posts
of his two-year-old girl is very
different than how I should approach
like a news clip from a uh you know I
don't know about the election or about a
war um so yes I I totally agree those
can happen in a matter of you know
seconds they could be adj they could be
adj less than a second yeah yeah W with
that in mind do you have any thoughts
around you know like I guess the impact
on Mental Health the impact on you know
a young Generation Um and how much they
should or shouldn't be using the
platform I think parents know best for
each kid I'm a I'm a dad I have three
boys but they're to Young use Instagram
they're 86 and4 and I think that
platforms like Instagram can bring an
immense amount of value H to anybody in
including kids uh or teens I should say
but they can also be problematic um just
like anything can I think that looking
at too many unrealistic images in a
magazine when I was a kid is also can be
problematic but it can also be inspiring
it depends on who I am and also where I
am in that moment maybe the same
magazine or the same platform or
Instagram in this case could be really
great for me today and could be really
problematic for me tonight um based on
where I am emotionally right now so the
thing that we try to do is one make sure
that we focus as much as we can on
addressing parents concerns we get a lot
of scrutiny and a lot of incoming
compliance requirements and we engage a
lot with policy makers and we're going
to do our best to comply with local laws
and make sure we're taking feedback from
policy makers but I care more about what
parents think and what um child experts
think and so we primarily try to P
prioritize our work uh based on those
interests and then to build tools to
empower them right so one of the things
that we have built and that we're
actually doubling down on right now is
tools to help parents shape the
experience into what they think is best
for their kid um so maybe they want to
have blackout periods where I don't want
my kid using Instagram in the E week
weekday evenings because it's homework
time or I want to give my kid an hour
limit um you know how can we help them
shape that experience um without giving
the teen a really strong incentive just
to lie to their parents and to us
because you could always pretend you're
older than you are or have a second
account that you don't tell your parents
about so it's a kind of a a really
difficult balance because if what we
build for parents is to
restrictive teens are Savvy they'll just
work around it so we have to figure out
how to do it in a way that can address
parents needs
without pushing teens so far that
they're just gonna lie I'm curious on
that note the the law that Rona santis
passed in Florida when he passed that I
remember like watching the news and
Comedians and commentators and people
saying like wow I'm on the far left and
I can't believe I agree with like
something Ronda santis said in Florida
which is that like you have to be above
the age of 14 before you can use social
media you need your parents permission
uh at age 14 and 15 and I was wondering
like is that even realistic like is that
something
that can be done I mean we can build it
teens can lie we will build it I mean
we're looking to comply I do think the
situation in the states is complicated
because now states are doing their own
thing and the more variance there is the
harder it is for any platform to comply
and actually execute well and so you're
going to have more and more mistakes and
more and more things s to the cracks I
think it would be good for there to be
parental consent I think though that has
to be an industrywide thing um it can't
just apply to one platform or another I
think it would be good for it to be the
same for all 50 states I think we'll
just make a lot less mistakes um I also
think it would go way better if we get
support from Apple and Google on the
operating systems it is much easier for
me I mean I've got three kids they've
got three iPads each one have has one
it's much easier for me to tell the iPad
that this kid is born in 2016 this kid
is born in 2017 this kid is born in 2020
when I first said it up then for every
app to try and figure out how to do Age
collection age verification and age
prediction on its own and right now I
can ask my phone as an app developer
where is this person in the world right
now to 10 feet can I to listen to their
microphone to turn their camera on but I
can't ask for permission for to know
what their birthday is and that's crazy
and so if we could do that and if you
could do not just Age collection but
also parental control at the operating
system or the App Store level you would
have way less
mistakes I don't know if that's ever
going to happen so we have to do
everything we can to predict age well to
build good parental controls to balance
these different equities that are
intention and we will and I think we do
really well but not as well as we can
we're going to have to get better and
better and better uh but right now I'm
worried that the industry as a whole is
not headed in a direction where you're
not going to have too much slipped
through the cracks
yeah I I want to talk to you about the
future I feel like you you know you
obviously uh H have been on the ground
here and involved with with um Facebook
and and Instagram I think you'd have a
good perspective on where things go in
the future two questions for you about
the future the first has to do with um
Tik Tok if in a year from now
Tik Tok is is gone from the US what does
that mean for
Instagram I mean I can't talk too much
about this one in general I worry about
a world where more and more platforms
are banned in more and more countries
and countries and governments use that
stick as a way to push their own agendas
the vast majority of our business is
outside of the US uh so it would I think
drive more attention not only to
Instagram but to YouTube and other
platforms but it is a step in a more and
more fragmented internet which I think
is probably bad um uh overall now to be
clear it could maybe get sold and you
know there's other paths here I don't
want to guess about what's going to
happen and so without speaking to the
specific band and Tik Tok here in the US
I do worry about a more and more
fragmented
internet I'm curious what you think and
I don't even know how much you can say
but like what is next for social media
in General on this wave because uh there
there's been all of these markers right
of like all right we have Vine we have
really short video uh we have long form
video we have stories we have all these
different fine was just too a little too
early way too early we have all these
different markers of like oh here's a
new instrument we can use even text
right with Twitter and threads it's like
here's a new instrument where we can
communicate yeah what are we on the
precipice of I mean there's going to be
a bunch of different things and I don't
pretend to have a crystal ball I do
think that
I mean the the
current Paradigm shifts I think will
continue for the foreseeable future so
for at least five more years right so
more and more sharing is going to shift
from feed based formats to messaging
based formats um you know You' mentioned
Snapchat before Snapchat is not a
stories product yes they have stories
the vast majority of sharing at Snapchat
is in messages there are way more photos
and messages shared on Instagram in a
given day than posted to stories and
there are way more photos and videos
posted to stories and posted to feed yet
people think of us as a feed app so
you're going to see that continue to
shift um and I think that's interesting
for a number of different reasons I do
think video has not um fully saturated
yet I think you're going to see mobile
video continue to grow probably
primarily driven by short fir video but
what you're really seeing I think is
mobile video Eating into TV's market
share um so we talk a lot about Snapchat
Instagram Tik Tok but the truth is like
we all exist in a much broader ecosystem
in the US the average family watches 5
hours of TV in Western Europe it's three
and India I think it's three or four so
I think you're going to see video
continue to grow so that's kind of a a
Tailwind for digital creators like
yourself I do think you're going to see
um I don't know
how or I don't know exactly what it'll
look like but if you think about every
five years ago there seems to be some
big shift in
how people share that manifests as some
combination of a new format or a new
channel so um you know moving to moving
away from SMS or you know reals and Tik
Tok or before that stories which was
pioneered by snap I think originally
invented by caca um I think we'll
probably see one of those in the next
five years it's probably facilitated by
all of this generative AI I think that a
lot of the stuff that we're looking at
now in that space
will be a little bit cringeworthy in
five years because it's so new but
that's kind of what happens and what's
really exciting about our new technology
is people are just trying things
out and I think we'll also see more and
more this is more further out I don't
know how the social networks are going
to evolve in a world where you've got
more and more sort of ambient not
ambient awareness but more and more time
is going to shift to this format right
like right now we've got the ray B metas
which obviously you know about which by
the way I've been doing really well um
and I think the sleeper feature on those
they're showing up like socially too
like for me as I go out and like people
bring them out and I'm like oh that's
cool like you're enjoying this
experience and sending me videos and
photos after the sneaky feature about
this I think is the speakers in the mic
yeah I do think people are sleeping on
this I wore them for a full day uh the
first time I tried them yeah and by the
end of the day my honest thought uh
because I was skeptical I was like I was
around for Google Glass oh yeah Snapchat
spectacles like all the above but uh
after wearing these for a day my first
thought was these could potentially
replace my iPhone down the line a long
time from in a long time but but it was
the first glimpse of like oh this
product I got really used to just
communicating out loud which felt a
little funny because I was just walking
around talking yeah um but the video
quality is incredible the um audio
quality is incredible and the
perspective is very unique yeah so like
I think these are yeah the mic is also
sneaky good because it's in the nose
Bridge so it's closer to your mouth so
it ends up being better with maybe less
expensive Hardware than like a fancy ear
Ear Pod because it's physically closer
to your mouth so I mean I liked I mean I
don't think Marquez was the first one to
talk about it this way but I kind of
liked his framing when he did that video
about how all of these virtual reality
headsets are trying to come at the
future from this One Direction with this
you know large piece of hardware on your
face but it does everything
and then these are trying to come at it
from the other end which is like all
right they don't there's no screen right
so we can't show you an image you can't
see a
notification but you know there's going
to be more Reliance on voice there's
going to be obviously llms are really
making more audio and Voice driven
interfaces much more practical and much
more human um coming at it from the
other side and so where is it going to
meet in the middle but it's like a lot
of physics challenges right you know
batteries are hard to make small you
know so like how do you have a screen
that you can see through these are like
wild interesting challenges taking
swings in this sector obviously we saw
it with Humane yeah like oh yeah yeah
just like taking swings of like maybe
this is how a wearable works because
like the concept of a screen like this
plus something like that may be kind of
interesting yeah um so that I could then
engage with a screen but who knows where
this goes in the next couple years but I
do find this to be one of the most
compelling pieces of Technology I've
engaged with the thing that's going to
be really interesting to me is I think
in 3 to seven years you're going to see
things that
are for lack of a better analogy halfway
between that and like a quest or a
Vision Pro sure they're not going to be
as slick and you're not going to be as
comfortable wearing them but they're
going to do more of the things and
that'll be interesting because the early
adopters will kind of like dictate that
period but then in like another 3 to 5
years when you can get to something that
feels As Natural to wear as that and
even that's still too heavy um that does
more of what a quest does then things I
get get really interesting and what is
Instagram in that moment right because
if our core jobs are to connect people
around creativity so it's to connect
with friends and connect with your
interests but we come from a visual
Heritage and the primary interface is
actually voice what is it what do we how
do we evolve um if we talked a lot about
cultural relevancy of Instagram if
Instagram in 5 years loses its relevance
what do you think went
wrong we
probably just moved too slow when people
ask me what my biggest concerns are they
almost always lad up to this idea of the
world evolving faster than we can keep
up so you know as you hire more and more
people there's more overhead you move
more slowly as there's more and more
scrutiny there's more and more sort of
risk mitigation functions and processes
you move more slowly as you get more
heavily regulated you move more slowly
um as you become if you become short if
you become too short-term focus on
short-term Revenue you move more slowly
you hold on to the past so it's almost
always the reason why I'm worried about
the thing is I think the world is going
to change faster and faster we've seen
that for all of of human history the
particularly in technology the rate of
innovation has just been increasing and
I think the most likely thing for any
platform of our scale is that eventually
we will just move slower than the world
and the world will move away and we'll
be left in the dust uh and
so what that looks like is harder to
predict but I think if it happens I put
a lot of money on that's why it
happens well Adam I know we have to get
you out of here I know I got to do my H
review you got to go yeah you got to get
to a meeting um thanks so much for
hanging out such a blast it was really
fun I'm I'm I like I like had seen some
of your content before but I went real
deep over the last two days and I'm now
like a genuine fan oh great so you have
now you've got one more fan you can talk
to your advertisers about amazing well
thank you for coming on the show thanks
for having me and if you guys have more
questions just DM Adam I guess you might
as I geter on Monday I go into those DMs
I go in the request folder and I try to
answer a couple every I do like that you
do amas every Friday every Friday I have
I don't know when I'm going to do it
today actually if you do have a question
you can ask me a question for sure for
sure actually now that I follow you on
Instagram if you ask a question it'll
bubble up to the top of my AMA so you're
more likely to get answer well we'll ask
a question now although we did just ask
a lot yeah we just asked do I need to
pay for metav
verified realizing we didn't touch that
but that's all right I'll ask you an AMA
for the next time for the next time all
right all right thanks guys thanks Adam
[Music]