three of the top priorities for us are
it's just not an important thing for for
reach I got a lot of hate for this why
am I not getting the views I feel I
deserve does Instagram Shadow ban I'm
sure a bunch of people are
just steaming hearing me say it really
disappointed in myself when you ask that
question yeah I'm s I'm sorry for asking
it can be hard my DMs and my comments
can be pretty dark yeah I can imagine I
should double check before I answer cuz
we're being recorded we want to be the
best platform for
creators hello and welcome to today's
episode of build your tribe I'm your
host Brock Johnson but I'm not going to
bore you with a long Preamble because
you didn't come here to listen to me
talk you clicked on this episode to hear
directly from the head of Instagram
himself I do want to say that I feel so
honored and humbled to represent all of
us content creators and small business
owners in this conversation I hope you
learned something and I hope you walk
away feeling a little bit more at peace
with growing on Instagram without
further Ado here is my full interview
with of Instagram Adam
[Music]
moseri you might be the most visible
head of a social media app that I can
think of and so at least in terms of
showing up putting your neck on the line
posting content addressing concerns what
led to that
decision uh I don't know if I'm the most
maybe the there might be more famous
ones there definitely more famous ones
but in terms of Po on the platform up
showing up putting yourself out there so
I used to work on Facebook for a long
time I worked on the Facebook app for
almost 10 years and I
remember maybe about this might have be
10 10 years ago now MH there's more and
more as we're getting really big there's
more and more concerns and questions and
scrutiny and my take was that the
conversations were clearly going to
happen about fa Facebook and social
media more Broad with or without us and
it would make more sense to be part of
the conversations than not even if it
would be sometimes difficult or a lot of
work or sometimes really unpleasant I
spent a lot of time on Twitter back in
the day talking to journalists and some
of our most uh Avid critics but I just
thought it would be better to be part of
it than not so I kind of built up
that that that habit or that sort of
part of my job and so then when I
transitioned over to Instagram it just
made sense to keep doing it uh and then
over the years I've tried to focus more
and more on not trying to reach
everybody most people don't care what I
have to say um but for people who are
using
Instagram uh to make a living or as like
or as a Creator I wanted to make sure
that I was speaking to them so um and it
was a lot it was a lot you know it's a
lot of fun at times it can be hard it
can be hard it my DMs and my comments
can be pretty dark yeah I can imagine
but in general um I just think it's good
to be out there speaking of those
creators and the people who want to make
money on the platform what are your
biggest goals or priorities for them in
2025 I mean there's a lot of stuff going
on right now I mean we want to be the
best platform for creators and in some
ways um I think you could make that case
uh in other ways we're behind but there
are a lot of creators on Instagram
probably more than any other platform so
if you look at how many people we think
are creators are on the platform that
looks like a bigger number than YouTube
channels or you know um most other
platforms but you know you never know
for sure and we know that there's a lot
of competition and we know that there's
a lot of scrutiny and a lot of um
concerns about our platform from the
Creator Community as there are about all
platforms and so what we're trying to do
is better
understand the broad group's needs and
then meet those needs the things that
matter most as far as we can tell and
you should tell me because you probably
would know better than I I certainly
Reach people always want more reach um
and so figuring out but it's not just
about how much reach it's about
stability which is very hard I think any
platform that guarantees you stable
reach is probably Ling uh but certainly
there's more and less stable uh but
there are other things too like I really
want us to do more as a priority um on
helping small creators break out which
is actually from a engineering
perspective a bit more difficult um I
want us to do more to reward original
creators and identifying who's creating
original content is also an interesting
trick I want us to do to be um better at
Trends it takes still too long for
things to pop on Instagram yeah um so
this those are maybe
of maybe three of the top priorities for
us are um valuing original content
helping smaller
creators break and also having Trends um
just happen quickly H makes sense in
terms of helping smaller creators
something a lot of people have noticed
recently is the pie chart of where their
reach is coming from is really increased
in terms of uh the disconnected or the
unconnected reach as you call it the the
reach from non-followers yeah so I'm
curious what motivated that change
trying to grow the pie yeah so basically
the if you look at how people share on
Instagram creators aside for a second
there are more photos and videos not
including text shared in DMS than there
are in stories every day and there are
way more photos and videos shared into
stories than into feed every day so yes
feed is for average folk to share photos
or videos that they're really proud of
but it's it's a very small percentage of
average folk who actually post a feed
Post in a given day um whereas for
creators it's much higher so it's
becoming much more of a uh public domain
whereas stories and DMS are much more
about where your friends are though
obviously creators are in all of those
places in different ways but because the
amount of content being shared into feed
was decreasing for a long time um we've
needed to figure out a way to that meant
that the amount of time people were
spending in feed was decreasing and so
that was a negative feedback loop
because there's less time being spent
there's less reach to go around there's
less people like and comment less then
people post less and then there's less
content to see so then people spend less
time and they like and comment less and
it was going in a circle so
recommendations was really just an um
the only viable way to maintain feed as
an important Place gotcha and it is the
most important place for creators to
post stor are awesome but your average
crator reaches way more people in feed
mhm and so recommendations was a way to
from a just aure brass tax business
perspective maintain feed and Grow Feed
as an important part of Instagram and we
try to do so in a way where it would
help
people discover creators and other
accounts that they would love but might
not even knew
existed um and so you've seen that play
out and you've seen I made it I pushed
really hard to make sure people could
see the difference between their
connected and unconnected reach MH um
because they should know where it's
coming from and what to optimize for you
know might be different or how to think
about it might be different so it was a
it was a business need and then a user
need um and we tried to that's what
we're always trying to do is figure out
something that's not only good for
creators but also good for average folk
and also good for Instagram and then you
know at the overlap is where the good
stuff happens people are always freaking
out over algorithm changes and updating
there's this new algorithm you answered
recently on one of your Friday ask me
anything which are awesome um you said
that you're constantly tweaking and
working on the algorithm but oftentimes
in small ways that we might not even
notice is that a daily thing that it's
being tweaked and work on worked on
gotcha small changes go out every day
gotcha uh it's very rare that there's a
massive change and how we do something
it's much more common that we're just
trying to get a little bit better one
day at a time gotcha um if you see a
huge swing in what's going on it
probably isn't there was a huge change
in how we rank content it's probably
more there was a huge change in the
world gotcha it might be you know
Mother's Day everybody's posting
pictures of their moms tell talking
about how much they love them that's
actually content for you to compete with
as a Creator um or there's seasonality
you know like if you have predominantly
young people who follow you and schools
out you know you see time spent on
social media is going to grow um
holidays same thing um if if people are
off work you know they're going to spend
more time online so if there's a big
swing in a given day um it's probably
more likely the world
changed um but
also the thing think one piece of advice
I give a lot that I don't know I'm good
at giving is don't overreact to any one
post because something might have been
weird that day look for the patterns so
for for these types of posts how do they
do for this other type of post how do
they do and then you know double down on
what works and maybe rethink what
doesn't um talking about messaging which
I know you believe is a central part of
the platform and I would agree that it's
one of the real strong suits that
Instagram has over other platforms um
there's been a lot of mixed messaging no
pun intended around DMS recently and
specifically DM automation uh so I'd
love if you could clear the air about
automation through approved Partners
obviously um and whether that's allowed
on Instagram or you know specifically
the whole uh if you comment this word
you'll receive this automated message oh
interesting so I think it depends so we
certainly we have an API it's it's
allowed um but sometimes there are some
providers that are doing Shady things so
like one thing is like don't ever give
anybody your password if anybody's
asking you for your password
like that's not probably like a trusted
partner yeah but actually most accounts
that are compromised so that are self-c
compromised last time I checked um so
that happens a lot um so we do want to
support this part of the ecosystem uh we
know it's important uh but make sure you
are working with someone who's reputable
uh it's possible sometimes we mistakenly
catch good actors when we're trying to
catch Bad actors I'm sure that happens
um but yes there there are apis there
are tools that are supported and allowed
gotcha okay um in terms of SEO on
Instagram um it seems like you guys are
really working to improve the
discoverability of profiles and posts um
can you talk more about the future of
how Instagram might work as as a search
engine showing us what we're looking for
and having Instagram results pop up when
we are searching for things so I mean
two different sides one yes we're trying
to do better at helping
at having content from creators on
Instagram surface in search results for
you know Google and other Searchers
providers um because I just think that's
a win-win for everybody so we're
starting to try to figure out what the
opportunities are there that team has
been doing has been lean and mean and
mighty for a long time um but they're
doing some good work um but we're also
starting to invest more in search on
Instagram um because there's so much
amazing content and quite frankly what
we call content search search as opposed
to searching for an account actually
searching for some type of content it's
not very good on Instagram uh and that's
not a knock on that team that team has
been really small for a very long time
so we've strengthened that team recently
and I'm pretty excited about some of the
ideas um that will hopefully and
improvements that are going to go out
over the
next well next few months and few years
um it's a long road um but I do think
that could also be really good one for
people who are looking for things you
can imagine whatever you use Instagram
for it' be great to be able to find that
more easily but also for creators
because it should allow content to
resurface so that you don't kind of get
all the value in those first 24 48
Hours um but we'll see gotcha one thing
one of those little features that might
be that something that that team worked
on that I noticed recently was at the
top of the comments section there was a
recommended search yeah um can you tell
me more about that feature and what
determines what that recommended search
is so we're working on it actually the
latest version is not out yet um but
what we're looking at is both the the
contents so the the real or the carousel
or the photo but what we also need to
look at is the comments below okay
because sometimes and that's not out yet
but I think that's coming out sometimes
where the real interesting context is is
not in the piece of not in the video
that someone uploaded but in the context
around it which is is almost always in
the comments and so what we're trying to
do is you know surface that more easily
um and then you can go and find out more
so if you saw I don't
know Walton gogins face and SE uh not
Severance um White Lotus this week was
like a big meme yeah you could maybe you
see that maybe you haven't maybe you
don't watch the show and there's a
picture or a real of that and you'd be
like why why do this guy looks so
confused yeah uh but in the comments you
might find you know the context between
this crazy Sam Rockwell sort of
monologue in this Barn in a hotel in
Bangkok or whatever it was and then that
might be it might this the pro The
Prompt might be something like you know
I don't know you know White Lotus
episode 7 or whatever it was and so then
it would give you context and then if
you clicked on that you might get a
whole bunch of other content that put it
in context gotcha uh our hope is to
sort of create a little bit of fun and
Delight by connecting the dots right
because the real might be funny on its
own or the meme the comments might be
good to read if you've got time you may
or may not search for it but if we can
connect the dots all of a sudden you
know maybe one plus one plus one can
equal four instead of three gotcha um so
I know you said comments are coming soon
right now it's primarily looking at the
content itself so does that mean the
caption the spoken audio the actual like
analyzing of what is in the video all of
that all of those things are considered
but this the technology we're using to
actually understand those things is
going to get much better over the next
couple months so um so the way this
works for any provider is you know this
is to another platforms too is you don't
actually you basically take key frames
from the video so you might look at 16
or 128 or even as many as you know I
think I think YouTube is probably more
like up to like 512 different frames
from the video to try to understand that
what happened you also will transcribe
the audio into text um and then try to
un use that and extract any
understanding from that um comments um
coming soon if not already out and then
from all of that you try to come up with
a uh a search that might be interesting
and we try and if we don't come up with
anything we think that's interesting we
just don't show you the prompt sure um
so what you'll see is those prompts will
get more they'll happen more often as we
get better at understanding content um
and context and then and we're more
confident in the recommendation makes
sense I think it's very helpful for
creators to know that it's everything
it's all of those things yeah yeah uh to
be aware of yeah and it's going to be
like right now it's disproportionately
looking at the caption relative to the
video relative to the audio relative to
the comments in that order but that's
going to change because as we get better
to understanding all the pieces we'll
integrate them um so definitely just
assume we're trying to understand the
full context um because that's that's
where we're going that's what we're
working on gotcha you've talked about
kind of the three metrics that are best
or that you would recommend focusing on
the most for increasing reach what do
you tell people when they ask you what
focus on shares yeah because I think
shares at least algorithmically speaking
of course they're helpful but it's a
sending a post to another human so even
if the algorithm was optimized for saves
a share would still be the way to reach
another human being yeah that's how I
think about it but speaking of this
conversation of shares of course human
to human all shares are not equal if I
send a post to my wife that's one
additional viewer if I share it to my
story that might be hundreds or
thousands of extra viewers
algorithmically speaking are all shares
created equally or are different shares
weighted more heavily oh that's a really
good question I
I I think they're valued relatively
equally um
because it's true that like if you send
a message to one person there's less
views than if you send it to your
stories and maybe thousands of people
are going to see your story MH um but
they might have seen your other stories
that day anyway and your wife might out
have open Instagram that day and when
you send her a message her phone's going
to Bing and she's going to open it up
most likely hopefully I don't know yeah
um and but also because if you just
think about it from a from
a from the perspective of the of the
person receiving it like it's kind of
more meaningful if you send me something
you're like I think you'd be really
interested in this that is a lot more
meaningful than I thought everyone might
want to know this thing in addition to
all the other things I thought they all
should know today yeah yeah um so we
look more it sends gotcha um and then
the third metric if you will has to do
with the time the amount of time people
are spending with the content yeah I
want first of all clarification it's
watch time so the amount of seconds that
people are spending with that piece of
content not necessarily watch rate watch
be correct watch rate being the percent
that you watch yeah the percentage of
completion we look at both um but we we
try not to we look at both because if
you watch something all the way to the
end that's a good sign but we definitely
don't want to just you know penalize
things because they're longer okay and
so you know if you watch 20 seconds of a
21 second video and 20 seconds of a you
know 10 minute video like it's not like
those two things are equal um so we do
look at both okay um but it what matters
more is just the over amount of time
watch we're not trying to optimize for
time this is a common misconception is I
was like oh these platforms they just
want you to spend more time they're just
trying to optimize for time
time that is that is not quite the case
for us I think if you look at you know
Netflix from what I can tell they
optimize for time YouTube time Tik Tok
time plus some other things around
originality and and and breaking
content
um we are a place to be to to be
entertained to entertain yourself to
find stuff that to explore your
interests but we're also a place to
conect with your friends and if we just
optimize for time what would happen is
you would you could just you would just
show longer and longer and more and more
videos but then for every five minute
video you watch that's maybe 50 things
you didn't see from other other people
including your friends so we're much
more in the like short video focus it
doesn't mean there's a perfect length
for video but one of the reasons why you
know the the primary flows only allow
for up to three minutes it's like we are
you know a place where we want you to
easily explore a bunch of interests send
a couple things to a friend maybe talk
to your friends about them and short
video is way
more uh like close to that friend
Connection use case than long video
because long video becomes much less
participatory and much more I'm just
gonna sit back and watch right Y which
is awesome it's not a bad thing but
that's not our thing mhm I don't think
you can really have a lean back
experience that's also one where you
talk to your friends you know you kind
of have to pick two of the three you can
either be long form and short form or
short form and friends it's really hard
to be long form and Friends makes sense
um speaking of hashtags while we're on
the topic of algorithm and increasing
reach um I know there's been a lot of
changes with hashtags over the last few
years I believe you can no longer follow
hashtags the recent section of hashtags
is no longer a thing um and I know
you've said a few times now that I got a
lot of hate for this I'm sure yeah I
know you do um uh is that hashtags are
no longer a primary way to increase your
reach on Instagram they don't
significantly increase your reach on
Instagram gotcha contr to popular belief
yeah um it's just not an important thing
for for reach um so I don't know I I can
say that all I want
people I mean I like hashtags there's
nothing again hashtags we moved away
from following hashtags because it
wasn't
really being used that much and just
recommendations in general were kind of
handling that uh we moved away from the
recent tab which I know people really
like because it just was uh a safety and
a Spam it was getting abused by Bad
actors I would imagine yeah it's just
much harder to to to um to manage the
safety risks and the spam risks because
you can just if it's just determin I
know everyone's just like just do go cry
deterministic recent hashtag recent feed
but for hashtag specifically if you just
do that it's really easy just to
like post a thousand bad things that
don't quite violate our community
guidelines but almost do and just take
over that page and so it just became
like not worth it um whereas if you
allow us to rank we can then filter out
things that are problematic or spammy or
repetitive or unoriginal um and we don't
have that ability if it's just a Chrono
thing um and it just was getting abused
too much um so I get it I'm sure a bunch
of people are
just steaming hearing me say it um but
that was I want to be honest uh I'd
rather tell people why and have them
disagree then just like yeah pretend it
wasn't an intentional decision is there
a day where hashtags are removed from
Instagram completely I don't think so um
I think there's a probably a couple
interesting ways we could evolve it um
we'll see where search goes over the
next year or two but there's no plan or
just remove them gotcha staying on the
topic of hashtags there are some banned
hashtags hashtags you can't use what
happens if you use one unknowingly on
one of your posts will that affect the
post will that affect your account will
that be a Content
violation it's not a Content violation
and basically what will happen is it
just won't turn into a link got uh and
so we basic so you know we try to make
sure we're not encouraging people to
discover unsafe content right so you
know anything related to self harm for
instance or uh that's the kind of thing
that we would just basically block the
tag um it's not a strike uh I don't know
if it would affect your distribution or
not I should double check before I
answer because we're being recorded um I
don't think it would but I would I'd
like to double check that um but mostly
the main thing is like we just don't
want to make that a link you didn't know
maybe you didn't mean it sometimes they
actually seem like benign names because
a lot of people try to work around these
systems by using codes for these
different things um and so you might
bump into one of these terms by a
mistake gotcha um speaking of you know
banned things and obviously there are
certain like self harm related or curse
words that might be um frowned upon
let's call it um Are there specific
words or phrases that the algorithm can
detect in our content um and then
downrank us or our content because of it
it's not quite that direct okay so
there's not like a list of words that
you're not allowed to use and then
you're going to get down ranked um but
we do have things like um you know we
have you mean there's two there's two
sets of rules at a high level there's
what we call Our Community standards
which is like what can and cannot be on
the site you know you not allowed to
post you're not allowed to like
celebrate violence you're not allowed to
you know post nudity you're not allowed
to you know post a series of things but
then there's also our recommendation
guidelines which is content that we feel
comfortable or not comfortable
recommending and the reason we have
those is even though it's complicated is
because if you're seeing something from
someone you
follow then if you find it offensive
that's on the person you follow right if
you just post something offensive and I
follow you it's like that's on you yeah
and it was and it was your decision
follow me exactly so we don't we try not
to get between people and people they
follow um there are I think at this
point zero
safety um like zero of these like
recommendation implementations for
connected content we do not downrank
content from people you follow because
we think it might be offensive okay
ever um but if we just show you a post
for some Rando you've never heard of and
it's really offensive yeah that's not
really on that random person it's more
on us okay uh so we have more
responsibility there so we take more uh
precautions there and so it's possible
if you write really aggressive content
there might be nothing wrong with that
maybe you are advocating for a cause and
you're mad and you have a right to be
that's okay um but it might get caught
up in oh this isn't harassment but it's
borderline it's aggressive and we won't
recommend it so it's possible that sound
like this is specific words but if you
are posting something and it's getting
close to MH one of our
rules um it's it it will be less likely
to be recommended nud is another example
if you post something that is
like like borderline nudity but not
actual nudity so we will not take it
down because you are you know exactly
where that line is and you're not
Crossing it you're going right up to
that line um the chances are you're not
going to have that content recommended
because we're going to see that as
probably not appropriate for to
recommend to people who haven't decided
to follow you but we will not get
between you and your followers gotcha
okay I do feel like the account status
area in settings is very helpful um
being able to check and see is my
content recommendable am I in good
standing um I'm curious though are there
ever times where people are not
recommendable or not able to have this
disconnected reach and yet it doesn't
show up in the account status so
basically this is what people would say
does Instagram Shadow ban yeah
if there are there are very few okay um
there are there are a couple real edge
cases for the most gnarly potential harm
you can think of okay where we might
want to be careful not to let someone
know that we are like looking into
something um but those are the minority
cases so our hope is to put all of it in
there um everything at the account level
right it's possible that one piece of
content might get caught up but your
account is fine so that won't be in
there um but at the account level we try
to have everything be in there the only
exceptions I can think of are for the
darkest of dark which I hope nobody
watching here feels like they could
possibly fall into that category yeah
that makes sense that makes sense and I
what I also often tell people is a ban
is a ban all social media has their
guidelines and they have the right to
downrank your content or not recommend
your content but it's not a shadow ban
especially in Instagram's case when
they're telling you yeah the word Shadow
is not involved because it's in the
light you're telling them yeah and
that's the thing that I try to explain
and I'm not always that good at it but
um I want people to know it's in our
interest for people to know if you know
what the rules are and if you know what
the content is that we're trying to
reward then you're going to probably
make more content like that and that's
good for you and for us it's not in our
interest to like in the shadows like
make decisions and and you know now look
sometimes we make mistakes um most of
those mistakes I hope are reflected in
account status so you can go there you
can see if content is taken down you can
appeal you can see if you've got any
recommendation issues you can appeal or
remove those pieces of content uh but I
want people to know because I think it's
in our interest for people to know um
sometimes things are
broken um but usually usually not
usually um it's a been us going on
gotcha uh recently in one of your ask me
anything Fridays you answered a question
I thought made a lot of sense around uh
taking a break and essentially if you
take a long break and say eight months
without any posts on Instagram and then
you come back the algorithm doesn't have
much data that it's been recently
trained on and so it's very likely that
that new post won't perform all that
great yeah that's true I don't like that
that's the case so I'd love us to figure
out a way to do it I just want us to be
honest about the fact that that's the
case do you have any idea is it like a
sliding scale and that the longer time
you spend off the less recent data there
is or is that the once it hits 3 weeks
then it's no longer considered recent
data it's it's between the two so
basically I think if you I don't think
there's a big difference if you take off
three months or four months okay I think
once you get to about a month part I
should I'll double check on exactly how
long we retain some of these signals for
it's not that we have no signals right
like if I follow you and you post again
we've got some signals on my interest
than you but we've got more signals on
my interest than other people because
you've been off for a month or two um
but it kind of I think you probably
realized most of that unfortunate loss
in that first month or two um but it's
definitely not by Design gotcha it's a
it's a byproduct of how we build things
and that doesn't mean I'm happy about it
um it's something I'd like us to figure
out how to address I think there's
probably other things that are more
important to address um like getting
better at recency and originality and
some of these other Concepts um but it's
it is I've experienced it like I've gone
off for a month
you know I don't know I went a recharge
I had a kid and I came back and I was
like oh yeah I gotta work my way back
yeah yeah um in terms of consumption and
like the interaction component if I'm a
Creator and I create about this one
Niche topic uh rock climbing but I only
consume content or primarily consume
content relating to a completely
different topic like cake baking do
those two things affect each other at
all do they interact with each other or
not necessarily not necessarily okay
that'd be kind of cool
actually um we don't really
use I'm trying to think even in inferred
I can't certainly know not explicitly
but maybe not even inferred we don't use
your consumption patterns as a signal of
how interesting your content is for the
people who are interested in your
content makes sense um we do look at
things uh like you know are there groups
of people who have interest and interact
a lot Etc so there there might be some
way it seeps in but if you if you only
post about rock climbing and you only
like watching bacon videos that's great
like we got there's there's nothing
wrong with that what about activity
specifically around the time of posting
so I have a post I'm going to make it
10:00 a.m. and so from 9:45 till 10:00
a.m. I'm active and I'm responding to
stories and I'm engaging and then I make
the post and I'm staying active does the
algorithm reward me for that activity
not directly indirectly it could happen
right CU if you're on there a bunch and
you're messaging people and replying to
comments or whatever they might see that
and they might then tap on your profile
and then interact with that content uh
and so indirectly it could help but the
way the ranking system works is it
doesn't know that that's why that's
happening got it's just like oh if this
thing is getting more engagement it's
more engaging it's going to do better
and if you're active in a way that is
getting people to engage more with your
content then yes that would help but
it's not try something that we're trying
to reward I don't want people to feel
like they got to get on there yeah I
schedule posts all the time same um I
schedule mine for early because I we're
here on the West Coast so a lot of my
followers in the US and I want to get my
posts out before the California's awake
and before like New York is really into
their day yeah um and I'm not up at 5:00
a well actually I'm offing up at 5m.
because I got little kids but I'm not on
I'm not on my I'm not on Instagram at
5:00 a.m. when I scheduled these posts
yeah I I used to be the same way living
in California wanting to post so the
East Coasters could enjoy it and yeah
this was before I scheduled and I'd wake
up and make the post and oh my God a
stressful way to wake up before we
schedu post I said alarms like 4:30 I
get up like my wife like what I'm like I
gotta post this gotta post a real um I
want to shift gears into some new
features some things that are upcoming
maybe plans for 2025 uh first I want to
talk about live is there any
new exciting features anything that you
can share about changes coming to live
in 2025 no I wish I had something for
you on that I feel really disappointed
in myself when you ask that question I'm
s I'm sorry for asking no it's okay I
just you know with the rise of
popularity of live on other platforms
live shopping I was wondering if
Instagram was working on anything like
that nothing major that I can think of
okay um another new feature I've you've
mentioned this a few times um Blends I'm
psyched about blend I knew you were
gonna be psyched about this question so
tell me more about Blends and kind of
how it's going to operate supposedly so
the way it works is you can start a
blend with a friend
in uh a thread so if you and I message
uh there'll be a little blend icon at
the top and we can start a blend and
it's just a feed of reals that you or I
or both of us might be interested in
okay and as you as you scroll through it
it'll show you who it's for oh so you
can be like ah you know you know this
one this one was like for Adam you have
to opt into it so because it's it's it's
personal right you see my very intimate
oh yeah yeah yeah you get a you get a
look into the wild weird weird world of
your friends interests yeah um and then
you can you know and the the default
action if you if you sort of reply is to
send the message so you're talking about
it um and so it's pretty fun actually uh
I don't know if it's for everyone uh um
you can also do it in group chats too
not just oneon-one chats um but look I
want us to be a place where you
connect you know over your interests
we're not the best place to sit and just
watch TV or video and if I'm running
late I'm not going to DM you on
Instagram I'm probably going to Whatsapp
you or hit you up on iMessage or
something uh but I think we can be the
best place to connect with the people
you care about about the things you care
about to me this sits right at the heart
of that in a really kind of cool way
yeah it um you know I know that the the
adoption of people using the friends
feed and the the following feed might
not have been as wild at least from what
I hear people still are unaware that
that even exists yeah um so is the hope
that because this is in DMS a place
where people are spending more of their
time already that it will be a more
heavily adopted features at the hope at
least to some degree yeah but it's
really not about I'll be pretty excited
about it if it's not something that
drives a lot of
incremental engagement for the whole
platform but if it's a if it's like a
really meaningful thing for a minority
of people who just really love it gotcha
because I feel
like not everything is about growing the
pie growing the pie is good you know if
there's more people spending more time
on Instagram you know that that is
helpful for us as a business that is
helpful for creators because there's
more reach to go around um
but if you only grow by just doing
things that you can get anywhere else
you get the
same movie clips and like old sports
highlights and all this commoditized
content that you can get anywhere else
then it's yeah you might grow engagement
but you
are you're
less it's easier to leave Instagram in
the future whereas if there's content
that you can only find on Instagram or
experiences you can only have an
Instagram that might not make us more
money that might not mean that any
average crator reach goes up but it
might just like deepen someone's
appreciation for the
experience I think that's pretty rat so
um this one I'm actually there's
multiple ways this could work out that
I'd be pretty happy with good um
speaking of growing the pie and
increasing average reach um I was
reading a study that um at least
according to this one study average
reach for reals carousels feed images
and stories were all significantly down
last year compared to the year prior is
I'm curious why is that why and I know
this is the number one question I
receive number one question I'm sure you
receive is why am I not getting the
views I feel I deserve yeah I mean I
wish I had a great answer that would
satisfy people who aren't getting as
much reach as they feel like they
deserve in general reach is going up for
some people and down for other people
it's much more of a blend the thing
that's hard is that though overall
there's more reach to go around this
year than last year um there's also more
people on Instagram and so there's more
competition and so like if if there're
in the if there are 10% if there's 10%
more content because either you know
because there's 10% more people and
they're all posting the same amount a
day as a year ago that doesn't mean
there's 10% more things consumed yeah
there's probably one or two% more things
consumed okay so that means that there's
more there can be more
competition in practice there are people
growing and there are people shrinking
and there's people who are roughly flat
there's also people who turn out right
you don't get the reach you deserve for
long enough you move on yeah uh and
there's new people all the time who
either have signed up for a while but
now just starting to post or they just
sign up in the first place so there's
also a decent amount of sort of churn uh
for lack of a better word um so I want
to get someone's content to every single
person who's really interested in it
because if we can do that the person who
sees a video or photo will be happy the
creator of the video be happy and then
we'll be happy because both of those
people will be happy and they'll be
using Instagram more um are we perfect
at ranking absolutely not um but we're
getting better all the time um so I it
is the thing I try to really explain to
people is it is in our interest to get
someone's content to every person who's
really interested interested in it and
if we're failing to do so that's bad for
our business yeah people think that we
suppress reach to get people to buy ads
it doesn't make any sense it's easy to
get people other people to buy that
wouldn't be a sustainable business model
no no it would just be no one would be
there and it just wouldn't work like we
have over 10 million advertisers around
the world on on meta advertising and
like we have we've got that's okay
that's that's a different challenge
there's weaknesses and strengths there
but we are more than happy to grow
engagement with one group of people and
then sell ads to a different group of
people against that same attention makes
sense essentially boils down to supply
demand so there's an oftentimes an
increase in the supply of maybe the
number of people posting the frequency
of their posting but the demand hasn't
necessarily risen at the same pace is
that what you would say yeah for a bunch
of reasons right so for a while the
amount of time people were spending on
smartphones was growing every year
that's roughly flat in a lot of
countries like the US now I it's not
like there for a while a lot of people
like I mean think about how many people
you know well maybe this is a little bit
longer than five years ago but 10 years
ago but you know 10 years ago not
everybody had a smartphone now everybody
has a smartphone you know we're buying
them less often or you know five years
ago maybe not everyone had fast internet
access and now most everyone has fast
internet access and so the amount that's
on the demand side right because the
amount of people who are interested in
watching stuff isn't growing as um as
fast as the amount of people who are
interested in reaching people makes
sense um and look I would love it if it
was yeah that would be great um so the
thing that I'm more focused on is how
can I make sure that the right value is
ACR to the right people like so I still
think we're getting better but I still
think aggregators as great as they are
and they I'm not anti- agregator they
get disproportionate amount of value
relative to what they create if you
compare them to original content
creators yeah um that doesn't mean they
they aren't valuable right if you go
around and you Source awesome stuff and
you bu able to reach about that that's
cool but ideally the person who came up
with the thing and made the thing gets
more views than the person who found
your thing Y and so we're trying to do
more and more to find the original
content creator when we can and swap
that person into that spot um so but
there's still room to improve there last
few questions if Tik Tok goes away
what's your advice for Tik Tok creators
migrating to
Instagram I mean if Tik Tok goes away
that' be a big deal I I would say look
more and more creators are across
multiple platforms I think that's just
smart I try to lean into that like I I
feel
like it's good to not have all your eggs
in one basket it's my job to make sure
Instagram is as compelling a platform as
possible but it's a great basket yeah
exactly or a great egg but you can have
a couple other eggs that's cool
um when you're joining Instagram I think
that I mean there's some things that are
the same and there's some things that
are different for any platform Tik Tok
Instagram YouTube Facebook the most
important thing is to be really clear
eyed about what you're trying to
accomplish um and then make sure that
the work you do aligns with that sure
reach is great but for what end are you
trying to get brand deals are you trying
to evangelize a cause are you trying to
sell
mugs like what are you doing and then
okay you've got that goal in mind you
then need to find the overlap between
content that is going to help you
achieve that
goal and content that is g to be
compelling because if it achieves that
goal and it's not compelling no one's
going to see it and if it's compelling
and it doesn't achieve that goal why are
you doing it and then the third is that
it's true to you so that's true of all
the platforms for Instagram specifically
if you're new to Instagram or you
haven't been using it as much much I
think it's important to understand that
it's not just
about um short form video that's a huge
part of what we do it's a lot of the
time it's maybe probably more than half
the time spent on the platform at this
point um but there's a lot of other
things too that can kind of be really
interesting um you can do stories that
show behind the scenes of how you make
your reals you can create a channel and
really create a deep relationship with
your most passionate followers and
message them directly you know there's
and the coolest stuff happens when
people connect the dots between these
things you know they tease their video
that's going to come out on Sunday and
their stories on Friday or I met a
Creator once that unfollowed everybody
and then ref followed a bunch of people
every month with a different Focus so
you know one one month it was about
climate change one month it was about
you know women's education and I was
like okay that's really cool you should
make a video on the first the month
explaining why and then point them to
that these are the kind of things where
it gets really fun so I would I would
don't feel like you have to do
everything but it' be good to understand
all the pieces so you can see if there's
anything that aligns with your interests
I often say that the diversity of ways
you can approach Instagram is really its
biggest strength in that you have
stories and reals and photos and
carousels and all these different ways
you can create and engage with the
platform yeah and and you got to figure
out the ones that are good for you
because doing all of them might be too
much yeah that's okay yeah um last
question besides Blends what feature is
coming in the pipeline that you're most
excited about or that can make the
biggest
difference maybe for creators or I don't
know if I can say I don't any I'm
already like sharing with I'm probably
gon to get a little grief for how much I
I H it rhymes with it Creator
specifically rhymes with uh for creators
specifically I don't know um I feel
there like a new thing I can I can I can
tease but I will say this I am very
excited about the long-term potential
around partner ads partner ads allow you
to create content as a Creator and then
have you know you can do this deal
offline that's fine with a brand and
then they can ask for um the permission
to use your creative for their own ads
and run ads to our ad system um and you
have to approve that as a Creator and
you can make that deal however you want
to make that deal the reason I really
like it might be a little
bit academic but I think it matters is
that in general brained content there's
no measurement right so you don't know
as an Advertiser I I paid I paid you
five grand to post this thing that I get
anything from it our ad system has a lot
of
measurement which means that how much
you are actually helping the advertiser
is going to be much better Quantified MH
and that is I think going be really good
for the small creators because when an
Advertiser doesn't have measurement they
don't really know M they go on their gut
they go with the big name that they know
or they like yeah um and so I think and
sorry if you're a big crator out there I
think the biggest creators are probably
overpaid and the smallest and the small
even not just the smallest and the and
everybody else particularly the small
crators are underpaid absolutely and so
and this is growing a lot on um on
Instagram the partner hat system and so
if we can grow that more I think we can
help shift more dollars from the biggest
craters to the little ones I think
that's pretty cool because the whole
promise of Instagram and really the
internet is to help you discover your
Niche interests allow anyone to be
successful uh and then there's other
things we can build on top of that
around the Creator Marketplace and
helping Brands find the creators that
can help them and help creators vet the
right Brands and make sure they're
reputable so there's a lot more work to
do there uh some people know about it
it's grown really fast but we don't you
don't hear about it a lot so I think
that would be the one that I would be
the most excited about awesome Adam
thank you so much thanks for having me
this was a blast yeah I appreciate you
cheers again I want to say thank you so
much for listening today I would not be
here and I would not have been able to
make this interview happen if it wasn't
for supporters like you I want to ask
you to subscribe to this podcast where
we release episodes every sing week
about the latest trends tips and
strategies across the various social
medias and I do want to let you know
that next week I'm going to be posting a
followup to today's interview where I'm
going to break down my thoughts and my
responses to his answers to the
questions but if this is the last video
of mine that you ever watch and the last
time you ever hear my voice I want to
say one last time thank you so much for
being here and as always happy
networking