Yeah, so fun.
I'm glad we had this.
Microphone luckily look where
So Adam
What about
the algorithm?
Oh my god. Where are you from
originally?
Uh Sicily.
Oh nice.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah. I love Sicily.
Sicily is really nice.
Yeah. The food was unbelievable.
I couldn't believe the food.
It's true. The food is amazing.
The little The little The sweets.
Disaster.
This is the real interview.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
The backstage.
Yeah, you got to tell me where to eat
and tell me the restaurant. I mean
Granita, you have to try granita. It's a
sort of ice cream but yes, but with
fruit. Like
Yeah, yeah.
crazy tasty amazing the taste
Ciao Adam. I'm very happy to be here
with you. Welcome to Milano.
Thank you so much for having me. Excited
to be here.
Do you like Italy?
I love Italy. I try We spend a week or
two here every year with the family so
it's really fun for us.
So have you already taken some cool
pictures to post on Instagram?
Yeah, maybe. I don't know if they're
cool or not but I just spent a week in
Rome with my family and they just flew
back yesterday and now I'm here for work
for another week.
But do you know any Italian idioms like
Mamma Mia, Buonasera?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Buongiorno. So show me your Italian.
I can't speak it all. You give me
something to say I'll try and say it but
I definitely definitely mostly I my I'll
I'll tell sometimes here with my kids
I'll yell at them in Italian tell them
like you know, to
Come on, let's go or go to the table or
you know, come on and just like
So like that kind of thing.
And you have you have to know that here
in Italy we also love to speak with our
hands.
Always.
Like this. Yes, this is our signature
move. Do you know what it means?
Well, it means different things in
different places.
Yes. So here it means what are you
talking about?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Um my dad was raised in Israel. Uh
but if you go back far enough, Egypt and
before that Italy. And so they do a lot
of this. But they use this more to be
like yeah, what are you talking about?
But also um like enough. Like wait, like
you know, they'll say like in Hebrew
like
What?
And it mean like uh stop, enough, like
what's your problem? You mean that kind
of a thing.
No, in Italy here it's much funnier like
Yeah.
What are you talking about? If you do
this here, everyone will understand you
probably.
Exactly. Yeah, well I will try to keep
my hands on my on my on my legs.
Okay. But should I call you Adam or Mr.
Instagram? What do you prefer?
just Adam, please. Please, I much prefer
Adam.
But do you like Mr. Instagram as a
nickname?
That sounds It sounds It sounds too
formal.
I think that um
I mean look, Instagram is this wild
thing, but there's there's
thousands of people who work there now
and billions of people who use it. And
so I see my role as just trying to
support it as best I can.
And I'm really excited about my new role
as a meta ambassador.
We appreciate your help.
Especially as a mother to help people
use Instagram in a better way, which is
basically what you are doing every day.
So how do you help people all over with
the world use Instagram in a
good way, in a healthy way?
I think it I mean there's different
ways. I mean what I try to do outside of
my normal job, which is to try and set
goals and build the team and set the
strategy or support the strategy, is I
also try to do a lot of this type of
thing where I explain what we're doing,
why we're doing, what's coming up next,
how the world is changing.
I try to do it for average users and I
try to do it for parents. I try to do it
for creators who use Instagram to make a
living.
Um I feel like the more transparent we
can be and the more effectively I can
explain and the better. Um and that has
costs. It takes time. There's a lot of
you can imagine my comments and my DMs
aren't always the most friendly.
Um but it's I think an important part of
the job.
Of course. And when I was preparing this
interview, I thought wow, leading
Instagram today is like being the
president of a huge country.
No, no.
You have so many responsibilities.
There is a lot of responsibility for
sure. I think um it You want to You want
to balance two things. You want to
embrace the responsibility and the
scale,
but also
stay humble and understand your role and
what is appropriate and what is not.
Mhm.
Cuz on one hand it's billions of people.
It's an It's a like an a huge platform.
People explore interests and make a
living and do their jobs.
On the other hand, you know, it's
something that a lot of people spend
tens of minutes a day on. And it's just
one small part of a much bigger
Mhm.
of their life. And so you try to keep
both
ideas in your head at the same time.
That's true. But what's a typical day
like for you?
I was joking about this earlier cuz
someone um it is I mean if I'm home on a
normal day, it's a lot of meetings.
I spend a lot of time in meetings with
spreadsheets and emails. It is not
fun or sexy or It's like a you know
a lot of data, a lot of meetings,
Uh-huh.
a lot of reviews, documents,
presentations.
But then I go and I do I go out and I
travel a fair bit for work and so it
might be I mean with some creators, do
some interviews. I might meet with some
policy makers. Um I might
um you know, I might meet a head of
state, you know, um I might get a bunch
of feedback from a bunch of users or go
to a research session.
Uh and then might all happen in the same
day. So it's very different things from
minute to minute or hour to hour I
should say.
Mhm.
Um but then I go back and I I to
meetings and spreadsheets.
So, meetings, basically.
Always.
I try to carve out some time in the
morning to think.
Uh-huh.
Cuz I feel like I mean, I'm sure I'm
curious how you think about this, but
life is moving so quickly, you can get
caught up in the day-to-day, whatever is
crazy happening today or tomorrow or
this week.
And it's hard to find time to reflect.
But often your best ideas, your your
best opinions come in when you have a
little bit of space to stop and think.
Mhm, it's true.
try to schedule time to stop and think
sometimes, but I'm not always good at
it.
For me, normally is
before going to the bed. Like there, I
have a lot of ideas. I don't know why.
Yeah, yeah.
But probably it's because my daughter is
sleeping.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. You have a little
window when after the kid goes
You start to think about something, then
I fall asleep immediately.
My head is so scrambled after fighting
my three boys to go to bed for an hour
that if I have half an hour afterwards,
I'm usually a bit of a mess. So, I try
after they go to school, before I start
meetings, I try to have a window.
And how much time do you spend on your
phone?
A couple hours a day, probably. I look
sometimes. I can check now if you want.
Yeah, all right.
I'll check also.
Okay, okay, we'll see.
Let's see.
Where did I put it?
And I want to see also how much time do
you spend on your Instagram.
Oh, yeah, we'll see. Well, I have I have
a couple versions of Instagram, so it's
not going to be fair.
Okay.
Cuz I'm always testing the new ones.
I have to say I'm really proud of my
numbers.
What do you Oh, let's hear. Let's hear.
You got to share. You can't just say
that.
No, no, no. I have just 2 hours 26
minutes, which is like perfect.
Yeah.
And 15 minutes in Instagram.
This is not showing Something's not It's
not showing
to go on the app.
in the wrong one. Hold on.
Like No, you have to do like this. Look.
Oh, you Oh, you do it there.
Yeah.
I like the
An hour and a half today.
But I got to I got to switch devices.
Hold on.
An hour and a half.
Today.
Ah, okay.
Okay, last week
What? 3 hours and 58 minutes.
Ah, wow.
Um,
you've got
You can't see Instagram cuz it's all the
different versions at the bottom.
Uh,
Facebook WhatsApp is my primary texting.
Mhm.
Chess.
Chess? How do you like to play chess?
I I mean well, I'm trying to learn. I
don't play chess.
I play chess. I'm really, really good.
I'm not.
Really?
Uh, I'm learning well, because I started
playing cuz my 9-year-old, Nico, started
playing and I would play and
you know, then, you know,
he started beating me.
And so, I was like, uh-oh. So, now I'm
trying to learn because I can't I got to
learn more so I can teach him.
Uh, and so, I've been trying to take
lessons.
I'm getting better, but I'm not I'm not
My My 9-year-old is much better than me.
And what's your relationship like with
your community? Because before you were
saying to me that you receive a lot of
comments.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Like also a lot of DMs. So, how do you
decide which ones to reply to?
Oh, yeah. I mean, that's tricky. So, I
try to go every I have a lot of to-do
lists. And And they have a lot of
recurring tasks. And one of them is to
check my DMs every week.
Mhm.
Not my normal DMs. I check those every
day, but the requests folder. And I just
go through
maybe 10 or 20.
Uh-huh.
Just And I don't might not respond to
anybody. It's helpful for me to get a
bit of a sense for how people are
feeling.
Are people excited right now? Are they
mad? If they're mad, why are they mad?
What are they mad about? And if
someone's being reasonable, I'll reply.
If they have a question I can give an
answer.
Spontaneously.
Yeah, yeah. And that always freaks them
out.
But if they're just yelling, then I just
I just don't reply.
Because when I started working for the
zone, I received a lot of criticism
because, you know, like we were trying
to do something new in the world of
football, soccer.
Yeah, I know. Football is football most
of the world. You can call it football
here.
And people were upset just because, you
know, like sometimes people don't like
change.
Yeah.
So, I know innovation is a big part of
your job. So, you must face a lot of
backlash, right?
Yeah, I mean, that is
the world is changing more and more
quickly. And so, if we want Instagram to
stay relevant, we have to change with
it. Otherwise, if we were just Imagine
if Instagram was just square photos.
Mhm.
No video, no stories, no DMs, just one
feed square photos. We probably wouldn't
be here talking today.
So, we need to evolve.
At the same time, when we do change
Instagram, if you spend half an hour or
an hour on Instagram every day,
and I come and I rearrange it,
Mhm.
it's just going to make you mad. Cuz you
had your Think of it as your desk, where
you organized your photos and you wrote
your letters every day, and then I just
changed it all. I didn't ask you.
Uh-huh.
Maybe I said, "Why?" Maybe it is better,
maybe it's not, but you don't care.
You're just like, "Why did you mess with
my desk?"
Mhm.
That's how I think how people feel
Yeah.
about Instagram.
That's true.
So, we have to balance those things.
But I would rather
I lean more into change,
uh and occasionally have to slow down,
than not change enough and be cuz I
think if you don't change enough, you're
going to become irrelevant. Especially
as the world changes more and more
quickly. So,
that's the conscious decision, but I'm
I understand and I accept that it's
going to come with a fair amount of
criticism and negative comments and DMs.
But the very first thing about you on
your Instagram bio is that you are a
father of three boys.
Yes.
How old are they?
Uh Nico is nine, Blaze is seven, and
Elio is about to be five.
And how do they use technology? Also,
with chess?
Chess. Well, they play chess Mostly
Mostly we play on a board.
Um
they they use um so, what do they do? Uh
on flights, they're allowed to iPads and
they watch they mostly watch,
you know, movies and TV shows.
Uh, and then on the weekends
they're allowed time but they have to
earn their time.
Uh-huh.
So I used to have it where you had an
hour and if you if you misbehaved, you
lost 10 minutes.
Uh-huh.
But that really didn't work. They got
more and more mad and they misbehaved
more.
Uh-huh.
And so I switched it, my wife and I, and
we decided no, it's better to be
positive and rewards oriented.
Mhm.
Then and so we now say like, you know,
if you don't fight and you do your
homework, like you're in 10 minutes and
every day you're in 10 more minutes. And
then you get to your hour whatever it is
and then they can spend it and they they
just my 9-year-old loves Minecraft.
Mhm.
My 7-year-old likes playing um,
sillier games. They play mostly games.
Mhm.
But they have to earn their time. And
then you have to have set boundaries.
Of course.
That's the key. That's the hardest thing
though, right?
Yeah. Yeah.
Is how do you say no when they're mad?
not easy for me to set boundaries. But
I'm trying. I'm starting, you know, to
do it.
Yeah.
Because she's uh, young. She's just
She's too little for it, yeah.
Yes. When you're in love.
Yeah, yeah. She'll yeah.
I I
But are you a united front with your
wife always when you set boundaries with
your kids?
We try to be.
It works sometimes.
Sometimes I feel like she changes her
mind and I'm like, no.
Like we agreed.
Um, sure I do the same.
Uh,
we sit and we talk about it. So we have
to
we like I actually think this is
important for any couple with kids is to
agree on on what is going to be allowed
and not allowed for your kids in terms
of technology use.
And then
um,
and then to stick to it. And if you want
to change it, that's okay. But that has
to be another conversation. You can't
just on the fly when you're mad or when
things are hard to say, ah, whatever,
just give them another hour.
Cuz I think that's how uh, things start
to get much more difficult to manage.
And I think as a father,
uh being a father of twins is also your
decision as the head of Instagram. So,
there is something you think about now
that you would have never considered
before becoming a dad?
I don't know if there's something I
would never have considered, but it
certainly weighs on me, right? As my
kids get older and they get closer to
being old enough to use social media, it
be it's one thing to understand the
risks of social media and phones and the
internet to 13, 14, 15-year-olds. It's
another thing to think about it in the
context of your child. You know, Nico, 4
years he'll be old enough.
You know,
do I think he's ready? No.
Uh will he be ready at 13? Maybe.
Uh
another thing that became very clear to
me is I mean, you only have one so if
you ever have more, you'll see this.
They they're so different. They're so
different. And so, when Nico versus his
brothers are going to be ready is
probably going to be different. I can
imagine one who's more mature gets
access to a phone or gets a phone
earlier and one who's less mature, maybe
I wait another year or two, right? Um
every child is different.
Platforms need to do what they can to
keep all children safe,
but parents ultimately know what's best
for their children cuz they know their
children. And I think I probably am
going to make different decisions for
different children. I don't think I
would have thought that
uh before being a dad.
And as a dad, have you ever had a
conversation or a special moment with
your kids that influenced a decision
about the platform's future?
Or they are too young maybe now?
Probably they're too young. They ask
about it. They don't really know cuz
they don't use it, but they've heard of
it.
They know it's an app, you know, they
it's but they're like, "What's an app?"
I was like, "Well, you know, you know
when you play a game on your iPad,
that's an app." They're like, "You make
a game?" I was like, "No." They don't
So,
they kind of get it,
but no major things yet. They're
Um I don't even know what it is. I think
they think I think they think it's cool
cuz they've heard it's cool,
but I don't really know what it is.
So, how do you hope Instagram will be by
the time they are teenagers and they
will understand what it is Instagram?
Um
4 years, it's going to change a lot
probably. My hope is that it helps them
safely explore their interests
and connect with their friends about
their interests.
I cuz I think young people, particularly
teens, they're trying to figure out who
they are, what do they love, what do
they want to be?
And I think Instagram at that young an
age is
probably best for that. Particularly
when we do well with different types of
educational content, right? So, my
middle one loves football, soccer. So,
you know, I sometimes save videos of
soccer drills. And then I'll share them
with him later. You know, my older one
loves Minecraft and chess, right? You
know, my youngest one
uh everything. So, we'll see. It might
get more specific later.
And so, I would hope that they can
connect with their friends who share
those interests on the platform. How
will it be different in 4 years than or
6 years or 8 years than today?
Um but I think that'll be
the thing that is valuable to them as
teenagers.
So, speaking about teenagers, I'm really
happy to talk about the new teenager
account because I've already spoken
about it on my podcast and also we did
an amazing event here in Milano.
It was great.
Yes, it was great. Do you know why?
Because was such a beautiful moment we
can because we had the chance to speak
not just with the creators, but also
with their parents.
Yeah.
So, it was really really nice. What
inspired this idea?
It was a long time in the making. We've
launched a lot of different tools to
help keep teens safe on Instagram over
the years.
Block, restrict,
private by default, reachability
settings, lots of different things. But,
parents are busy and they can't keep
track of every new feature that we
build. And so, the idea to start was to
try and
uh take all of those safety features and
organize them into one
simple-to-understand
feature. Or um
And then, when we did it, we also
decided, "Okay, let's audit all of the
features that exist and let's look for
opportunities to make them more
consistent, to make them stronger, where
are there things that we can do more
of?" And then, so we did that, too.
And then,
that So, it started out as just a
collection and then a bunch of
improvements. And so, like some projects
do, it snowballed and got bigger and
bigger.
And so, then we tried to make sure we
organized it as best we could in a way
that was going to be as
to do two things. One is to be a set of
automatic controls so that teens
and parents didn't have to really worry
about the settings, but to also empower
parents who had the time and interest to
go shape the experience into what's
particularly good for their teen, for
their child.
So, do you think teenager account can
help bridge the generation gap between
teenagers and parents?
I'm hoping. It's tough, though, right?
Cuz if you if you make the teen accounts
too restrictive, then teens will
try to work around them. They'll lie
about their age, they'll have a second
account that they don't tell you about,
or a different phone, or they use the
web instead of their phone.
Teenagers are very savvy. They're going
to figure out ways around it.
Uh but, they also they want to be safe.
They don't want to be bullied online.
They don't want to have negative
experiences on Instagram.
Um so, you have to find the right
balance. Is it protected enough that
they're safe and that they feel good
about it, but not so restrictive that
they're just going to go try and work
around it? Um and I'm hoping that if you
can do that,
they'll use it and they'll talk to their
parents about it, and the parents have
something to talk to their kids about,
or an entry to that conversation.
Mhm.
You should talk to your children about
how to use Instagram, how to use social
media, how to use your phone. What's
safe, what's not, what what are your
boundaries?
Mhm.
Uh that needs to be a conversation and
an agreement up front.
So, do you think Instagram can truly
become a space that supports the
well-being of the new generations?
That's what we aspire to do. I But I
want to also be honest that, you know,
we know that there's 2 billion people on
the platform, there are risks that come
with being on any platform of that size
and being on the internet.
Um but I want us to be the safest
platform out there, and I want to be one
that not only empowers
teens, but also empowers parents to make
the best decisions for their teens.
Mhm.
Is there something you have done at work
that you hope one day your kids will be
proud of?
Ooh.
I don't know.
Maybe teen accounts. I don't know. Maybe
that'll be a long time in the future.
They're not proud of anything I do right
now.
Aw, that is not true.
No, no, they don't They're just They're
just They're more interested in their,
you know,
having fun, football, Minecraft, that
kind of thing.
Uh
Easy stuff.
Pokémon cards. They love Pokémon cards.
Aw, okay.
It's wild.
Yeah.
They collect, they argue, they fight,
they negotiate, they
They negotiate also.
Yeah, they fight about them. I I now
collect
Uh-huh.
so that when they disagree, I can be a
third party in a trade, and I can be I
can make peace.
Are you having fun?
No.
With them?
No. I try I try. But you have to meet
them where they are. Like your your your
kids are going to be your kids, they're
not you. They're not going to have your
interests.
Mhm.
And so you have to try and adopt some of
theirs.
Mhm.
Uh so that cuz if I ask them, "How was
your day?" They don't answer. "Fine."
But if I ask them about
what Pokémon card they traded, or about
a football match, or about you know,
Minecraft, they'll they open up.
Mhm.
And so I try to meet them where they
are.
I need to take some notes
Well, you just you just started to speak
I assume.
Yeah, yeah.
Yes.
And I want to speak also about this
mysterious, almost mythical war that
everyone talks about, the algorithm.
The algorithm.
The algorithms. So,
how it works and what it is. Please
explain.
Yeah, there are So, there are many
different algorithms, but usually what
we're talking about is ranking.
Um algorithm just means a set of steps
to organize. So, it could even be just,
you know, it could not be AI or machine
learning. It could be very simple, but
generally what people mean is they mean
ranking on Instagram and other
platforms.
Uh
now, what we're trying to do is make the
most of your time.
Maybe you spend half an hour a day on
Instagram, and maybe you see 100 things.
But you follow maybe 200 people or near
there's thousands of things you could
see from them. Uh
there's billions of things uploaded
online every day that you might be
interested in. So, we try to go and find
the things that are you're the most
interested in and then surface them
first. And how recent something is is
one indication of how interested you
might be, but it's not the only one. So,
it's not strictly chronological.
I know this is contentious. I know there
are some people who are just like, "Just
put everything in chronological order."
But when we do it, we see that Instagram
is less interesting.
People use Instagram less.
Which means there's less reach to go
around for every creators. So, the
average account gets less reach, less
followers, and the average user is less
happy about Instagram if you ask them.
They use it less, but even if you say,
"How much do you like Instagram?" they
say less and less and less over time.
So, we try to
we rank to try to make Instagram
interesting, to grow the overall pie.
It's good for our business, it's good
for creators, it's good for users.
But to also give people tools so that
they can shape the experience. And you
know, the ability to override the
algorithm, to pin your favorites to the
top, to go to specific feeds or search.
Um, and it's a constant work in
progress. People think we make big
changes.
We almost never do. Uh, what we make is
lots of little changes every day and it
slowly changes over time. So if you see
a huge change in your reach on a
Tuesday, we didn't make a big change.
Something else happened in the world.
Um, but we do change every day and those
changes add up slowly but surely over
time.
How many fake stories have you heard
about it? And what's the funniest one?
Just the funniest one.
There's usually these there's both the
superstitions. They're like, okay, like
if I
What are the superstitions I've heard
that have been kind of funny? It's
always random.
Like superstition like what?
Well, it's like, yeah, like I know like
if I don't look at the likes or comments
for the first 15 minutes, it does
better.
Not that.
Oh, yeah. Definitely heard that.
Is this true?
No.
Oh, okay.
This is crazy.
But it's always like that. Cuz people
they have an experience and something
worked and they assume it's because of
something they did and it might not The
content might have been better or maybe
there's less competition that day.
Uh-huh.
Or maybe what they did was more relevant
that day cuz something in the world was
happening that was related to what they
said.
Mhm.
Um,
but yeah, people always they they come
up with all sorts of I try to every week
on my Instagram and my stories,
I answer about 10 questions.
Ah.
Uh, and I try to and a lot of them are
about the algorithm. I call it uh,
asking anything or AMA.
Mhm.
Uh, and I do it I've been doing it for
maybe 6 years now.
Oh, really?
And I still get questions about the
algorithm every week.
It's not easy to understand.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
It takes time. But speaking about funny
things,
um,
how people react when they realize that
they are face to face with with the head
of Instagram?
Most people don't recognize me.
Yes.
Sometimes they do, but usually they
don't.
They don't.
They get But sometimes you see I mean, I
don't know. You probably are much more
recognizable here in Italy than I am in
the States.
Yes, in Italy, probably. Yes.
But you know when someone sees you and
they talk to you normally and then they
realize halfway through and and they do
the thing?
That does happen sometimes.
And what's your relationship like with
the celebrities? Because I bet you
receive a lot of requests also from from
them. If you want to share one with me,
I promise I won't tell anyone. Just
between me, you, a few friends here.
That's
A few cameras.
A few cameras. A few Instagram stories.
Um I mean, I get to meet one of the
biggest perks of my job is I get to meet
a lot of amazing people in a lot of
different industries and a lot of
different parts of the world.
Um
I get a lot of feedback from from public
figures, the same way I get a lot of
feedback from users.
Um I try always to find the signal. So,
what's the best
um you know,
what's the best idea? What's the What's
the most important complaint? What's the
realest thing?
Mhm.
Um
uh But I also try to learn. I actually
find
um Sometimes I end up in conversations,
they want to know, "How do I get more
reach? How do I evolve? How do I grow?
How do I grow my followers?" And I try
to give them the best answers I can. But
I also try to learn about their
industries. How does your world work?
How does football work? How does fashion
work? How does
news work? How does entertainment work?
For me, it's really fun and exciting to
understand these different industries,
the businesses, the people, the
personalities.
Mhm.
Um and then to hopefully take some of
those ideas back and hopefully feed them
back into our team and our strategy and
what we can build. But also just for me,
cuz it's fun
to get to be in this role where I get to
travel the world and learn from people
and try to
get a little taste of different
cultures, whether it's the food or the
language or the culture or the art.
Thank you so much, Adam.
Yeah, thank you for having me.
But, to wrap it up, I want to take a
selfie, the perfect selfie. What do you
think? Yes, the
Oh, yeah, you're probably better at
selfies than me, no?
Really? No.
I think so.
No.
Okay, we'll try.
I have selfie stick arms. I have a long
arm.
I know, I don't have that. Let's do it
like this.
Okay.
But, let's end with your signature move.
Thank you, Adam.
Thank you so much.
Yeah, it was so fun. I'm glad we had
this.
Microphone, luckily. Look, we're
So, Adam,
what about
the algorithm?
Oh my god. Where are you from
originally?
Uh Sicily.
Oh, nice.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah. I love Sicily.
Sicily, it's really nice.
Yeah, the food was unbelievable.
I couldn't believe the food.
It's true. The food is a
It's a little It's a little bit sweet.
That's true.
This is the real interview.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
The backstage.
Yeah, you got to tell me where to eat in
Palermo.
Granita, you have to try granita. It's a
sort of ice cream, but yes, but with
fruits. Like
Yeah, yeah.
It's crazy tasty, amazing. The taste is
wow.