What is up and welcome back to working
hard. Today is a very big one. I am
speaking to categorically one of the
most influential people in social media
across the globe, Adam Miseri, the head
of Instagram and threads. It's safe to
say that Adam has helped shape the way
that billions of us communicate, share,
and create online every single day. And
I actually don't think it's an
overstatement to say that every single
guest that has been on this podcast has
in some shape or form used Instagram to
build their success or creatively share
what's going on in their daily lives.
Over his 20 year career, Adam has risen
through the ranks at Meta. And now in
the top job, he is at the heart of the
cultural conversation about creativity,
connection, and content. This episode is
for anyone who's ever used Instagram for
anything or wants to use it for anything
to build anything. Anyone who wants to
rise through the ranks in tech or a
corporate role or learn how to harness
their creativity.
[Music]
Adam Miseri, head of Instagram. Are you
currently more working hard or hardly
working? Currently, I would say working
hard, but I aspire to be hardly working.
I'm constantly trying to balance the
job, which is, you know, an amazing job,
but demands a lot of time, and then
being a dad. Um, and if I get if I do
decent at both of those things and I get
a decent night's sleep, that's about as
much as I can ask for in a day. Yeah, I
think that's I think that's fair enough.
I think that, you know, I I ask a lot of
people that question and it's often the
case that we're all aspiring for this
hardly working always feel like it's a
little bit out of reach, but at the same
time, we're trying to grapple with this
balance. Yeah. I had this idea about uh
almost 10 years ago now that I'd really
push hard for 10 years. I'd have kids,
they'd be little, I'd work really hard,
and then I would switch into a job that
was maybe less intense. And now that I'm
10 years in, I'm thinking I might have
underestimated how long, probably more
like 20 or 30. Um, just cuz, you know,
my kids are 9, seven, and almost five.
And it's not much easier than it was,
you know, 8 years ago. So, and the job
uh is certainly not relaxing. So, I
think maybe I underestimated the push.
So, let's start there with working hard.
What does a typical dayto-day look like
for the head of Instagram and threads?
There's sort of two types of days. One
is if I'm in California, I'm in San
Francisco, you know, I go to the office,
I get up, I'm I'm in charge of breakfast
for the boys, got three every day. Uh
yeah, pretty much. Um we have like a
whole schedule so they we don't have to
fight about it. Like you know, Monday is
what actually is? Monday's eggs and
bagels. Tuesday's banana bread.
Wednesday is waffles. Thursday's
breakfast tacos. Friday's cereal, I
think. Um, so I'm in charge of
breakfast. Get some time in with the
boys in the morning. If I'm lucky, I get
a workout in and then I go to the
office. And then it's just a lot of
meetings. It's not glamorous. A lot of
spreadsheets, presentations, emails,
data, and meetings. Yeah. Yeah. And then
I go home I try to get home and have
dinner with the boys and then maybe have
an hour to hang out with my wife before
I go to bed. But then the other version
of the day is something like this week
and last week and in three weeks and in
four weeks where it's just sort of
almost chaos. I'm traveling like you
know I came in from Milan last night. I
go to Paris this evening. You know do
five, six, seven, maybe eight things in
a day, meet some creators, maybe some
policy meetings, maybe do an interview
or two. Um, and it's just a whirlwind.
Yeah. Uh, and that's like that is very
different every day. And then I'll go
back to emails and spreadsheets and
dashboards. And so when you're having
more of this kind of whirlwind time and
you don't have your normal routine, what
are your non-negotiables that keep you
feeling balanced and focused and like
having a little bit of home and routine
in when there's almost no routine? I
should have some non-negotiables
actually you ask. I don't know that I
have many. I I try and the one thing is
maybe it's not a non-negotiable. The one
thing I do do is I try just to to eat
the local cuisine. I feel like it's
always nice, even if it's not, you know,
for work, but even if it is with for
work, like go to a place that I might go
to if I lived in that city because I
like to get it's so hard because you get
it's fun and amazing to meet all these
people, but you also want to get a sense
for the local culture. And I think food
is often great way to do that. Uh, so I
ask for that, but I don't I wouldn't
quite call it a non I should have some
non-negotiables. What are your
non-negotiables?
I think my non-negotiables, especially
when traveling and working at the same
time. So, there's a lot going on and
you're kind of I I always really
struggle with keeping up to date with
the team back home and trying to make
sure I'm constantly checking in and
constantly making sure, you know, I'm
helping there whilst also being present
in the place I'm in, which I find pretty
difficult. I think my non-negotiables in
that way probably a little bit boring,
but I try and make sure that I have
scheduled blocks of whether it's an
email block or an approvals block to
just make sure that I know within that
day that I can be present because I know
that do you know what in 2 hours I do
have an approvals block. So anything
that's coming into my phone now I can
leave it. It's going to be worked
through. And I think to me that gives me
a lot of head space because rather than
it being headsp space where I'm just
thinking, do you know what? It's all
fine, my head space is more about
knowing that I'm definitely going to be
able to get something done. And that for
me is very um it helps me to kind of
stay present. Yeah. So that I'm not
constantly thinking about all of the
things that I'm not doing. I do that at
home. I don't do that on the road. I
should I I jam through emails on the car
between meetings. Like actually on the
way here, I just went through probably
like 20 or 30 tried to make sure no one
was blocked on anything. Yeah. So, I'll
try to ask you that idea. When you're
doing your emails, is it something that
you try and get back to them throughout
the day or do you do it specifically in
blocks? Because I'm a big blocks person.
I feel like if I give myself permission
to go back to emails at every moment
during the day, obviously, if there's
any urgent one, then I'll go back to it.
But if I give myself permission to do
that, then I'm never quite present in
the meeting I'm in or the, you know,
whatever it might be. I do both, which
is messy, but I'm always afraid that I'm
well, one is I try to push as many
decisions down into the team as
possible. I'd rather the team make 10
decisions without me and I disagree with
one then, you know, make three decisions
with me over the same period of time. I
don't want to become a bottleneck for
progress. Uh so, but I am also so that's
sort of like a fear of mine. And so I do
check during the day and not like during
in the middle of meetings but you know
you know when I have you know a commute
because I'm always worried that I don't
want anyone to be sitting and waiting
around uh because I need a decision or
guidance from me. But I try not to make
that many decisions. I actually now have
a counter. This is a new weird Adam
thing um in my office where I count
every decision I make in a week and I
try to keep that number as low as
possible. That doesn't mean I don't get
a lot of questions or asks. I just try
to delegate them as much as possible and
um be like here's what I would do, but
this is actually Ashley's call or Max's
call or Jenny's call. Um so I I'm trying
to empower my team as much as possible.
I find that so useful. I think one of
the things that I've really struggled
with over the past few years as my teams
have got bigger. I'm 10 years into being
a founder and I still don't think I've
nailed the kind of delegation and
decision aspect part of it. I really
struggle between whether something would
be negligent of me not to be the person
making the decision versus taking away
someone's autonomy and also building a
crutch versus actually helping the team.
If you take some more time and you
explain how you think about a space or
what you value or what the strategy
might want might be uh you might it
takes longer than just making the call
but maybe they'll be able to make the
next five calls without you and that'll
actually save you time. Right. Right.
So, you know, teach a man to fish or
give him a fish kind of idea. So, you've
been in tech for approximately 20 years.
Yeah. What originally drew you to that
world? I was living in New York. I was
going to NYU. Um I My parents were
helping with tuition and I had a bunch
of credits from high school. I took a
bunch of college classes, but I needed
to make money for food and for rent in
New York City. Uh this was in, you know,
2001 to 2005. And so, I just started
doing freelance work. Of course, it was
bartending and waiting tables, but I
started doing freelance design work and
we found some of the better jobs were
doing web site design. So, I started I
taught myself to program and I was sort
of learning to design at school and so I
was just I freelancing and then I
started a small design firm. I started
working with a guy named Sydney Blank, a
really wonderful man who was 10 years my
senior. I was 19. He was 29 and his gray
hair added an air of credibility to the
whole operation. Um, but it was just,
you know, my rent was due on the 15th of
the month, it was 1,300 bucks. I'd look
at my bank account, there'd be $150 and
I'd be like, I got 14 days, you know,
and I need to make 1150 and eat. So, uh,
that's kind of where I started. Um, and
then that grew. I moved out west, opened
up an office, and then I had a bunch of
friends start in companies like
Facebook, and eventually they convinced
me to join. And do you think because I
guess then you were almost starting as a
founder before you went into a more
corporate background. Yeah. Do you think
that gave you a more intense kind of
learning process that you were able to
bring into the corporate world? So much
learning. Facebook was 400 people maybe
when I joined in 2008 and it was by far
the largest place I'd ever worked. You
know 20 times as big as the last startup
I was at which was a tech startup which
was maybe 20 by the time I left. Um but
I learned a lot um from from the design
years from the running the small agency
uh or consultancy really um you know
learning how to talk about money
learning how to advocate for selfworth
learning how to negotiate contracts
learning how to communicate ideas to
clients learning how to
um communicate
about the creative process and create
structure around something that is
fundamentally
ephemeral or sort of hard to pin down.
Um, you know, learning how to work hard,
uh, learning how to be accountable, you
know, having employees at 19 or 20 and
feeling responsible, you know, you know,
I had one or two on visas and I was
like, if I mess this up, they have to go
home. Like, that's crazy. Mhm. Um I
remember we our first year as a proper
company, we paid out a bonus, Sydney and
I um to we only had like probably two or
three employees and you know we had a
little extra money in the bank from the
in the corporation. So we paid it out as
bonuses to ourselves and everybody else
and we didn't realize that New York City
had a nine 9% city tax. So we had
completely miscalculated and we had all
of a sudden like we needed to ask for
the the money back. We couldn't do that
to our employees. So we gave all of our
money back and then forego I think
salary for a little bit because we like
we can't give someone a bonus and then
take it back. But like learning which
then taught you about thinking ahead and
making mistakes and taking
accountability. So so many so many
lessons that I really deeply appreciate
despite how wildly chaotic and stressful
those early years were. Yeah,
absolutely. And did you have big
aspirations for leadership at the
beginning of your career? I didn't
really think about the long term. Uh, I
was trying to just pay rent. I loved
design. I loved building things. We did
graphic design, branding work,
exhibitions for museums, websites,
kiosks at exhibits. Sometimes you go to
an exhibit and there's like a a computer
program you work with. I used to build
those. Um, but no, I was not thinking
about the long term. What skills would
you say then you think have contributed
most to your career progression
considering it wasn't necessarily
something that you were looking at and
being like okay I want to be the top of
a company like Meta. Yeah. Um I'm not
great at anything. Uh what really helped
me was I have a lot of range. I can do a
lot of things reasonably well.
Um, and that really helps because I as a
designer at Facebook in the early years
before it was meta, I was middle of the
pack, but I worked really hard and, you
know, I communicated well and I kind of
worked my way up. But my career really
took off when I switched over to what we
call PM, which is product management,
sort of coordinating all the all of the
different teams. And that really catered
to my strength. And it's not actually
what I would want if I I romanticize the
the specialist, the amazing machine
learning engineer or product designer or
anything like carpenter or watch maker,
you know, uh fashion designer, the
person who does one thing better than
anybody. I think that's the coolest, but
it's just not me. And when I switched to
focus on a role that was more about a
generalist profile, um about doing a lot
of things, um that's when my career took
off. Yeah, that's so interesting because
I do think that I mean we've spoken on
this podcast before about how you become
more and more generalist as you move up,
especially a corporate career. Um, but
understanding how to be generalist and
also how to be a good manager and also
how to understand other people's roles
is is difficult. It's something that you
don't necessarily always have the right
learning to do at each stage where
you're pushed to the next stage of your
career. So what really strikes me in
what you've said is actually what helped
you a lot was an awareness of what you
were good at and what you weren't
necessarily strong at but I got lucky. I
think that's a really good thing for
people to do. You want to understand
what do you love doing? What are you
good at? And where is there good work to
do? You know if you're a large company,
what's valuable to the company? If
you're starting something, what is there
demand for in the world? But it has to
be at the intersection of those things.
M I got lucky because I had a I had a a
really talented boss um who has done a
bunch of good big things since named
Brett Taylor. He was even the co-CEO of
Salesforce for a while after he left. Um
but when he left there was a big vacuum.
So I sort of just declared myself a PM
because there was this project that
needed a PM and there was no one to do
it. You can't do that anymore at Meta.
You can't just be like I'm a PM now.
Like you have to like apply and do go
interviews and all those things. Um, but
I did it out of need, but it happened to
be a better fit. But I think people who
are more intentional,
um, can make a lot more progress by
being, okay, being honest about what
you're good at, honest about what you
love and what matters to you, and
realistic about what matters from a
business perspective to the company or
to the market can really help. Um, but I
I I I would be lying if I said I had
that foresight and that self-awareness
that when did I make that switch? I was
probably 29. Yeah. I do think though
that that yes, absolutely there's always
an aspect of right place, right time.
But at the same time, what you're
describing is making sure that in each
situation you make opportunity out of
it. You can make your own luck if you
know it doesn't mean there's no
guarantees but you can definitely be if
you if you're self-aware and you've got
hustle and you're a quick learner you
can do anything over time. So I don't
mean to be at all dismissing that idea.
I'm just I don't want to claim that I
had that foresight at 29 because I
didn't. So maybe the thing to do is to
make sure you're constantly taking every
opportunity and putting yourself into
situations because you don't know which
is the one that's going to take you to
the next level. Yeah. I mean, I think on
some cadence, not every week because
that's probably just exhausting. Think
about, you know, like, okay, if you're
at a large company or if you're I'll do
large company and a startup differently.
If you're at a large company, okay, what
what do you want? Like, what are your
aspirations? What matters to you? Maybe
it's what you learn, maybe it's the
impact you have in the world, maybe it's
who you work with, maybe it's how much
money you make. Just be honest. And then
that's an articulation of what you care
about. And then if you're at a large
company, what does the company care
about? And then make sure you shape your
role to be at the intersection of both.
Um because if you love it and it's
aligned with your strengths, but the
company doesn't care about it, that's
not going to work. And if the company
loves it or cares about it and it has
nothing to do with your aspirations or
your values, you're going to just burn
out. And so you got to be at that
intersection. And managers, by the way,
should be always making sure their
people are at that working at that
overlap. Um uh if you're doing your own
thing, it's the same idea, but instead
of what matters to the company, it's
like what matters to the world or in the
world. Where is their demand? Where is
their business to be had? Where is there
something that should exist that
doesn't? Right? Um and doing that on
some regular cadence, I think, is really
healthy and much easier said than done.
Knowing what you care about is not
something most people do. You ask I ask
a lot of people what what matters to you
most? And it's hard for them to answer
truthfully and concisely. They'll list
like seven things that all matter to
them. Yeah. Uh, it's, you know, if
you're lucky, it'll just occur to you in
the shower one morning. But most of us
have to work at it. Um, talk to friends
that care about it. Write out to
organize your thoughts. I like to
pretend say what matters to me most is
who I work with. And then does that feel
honest or does that feel disingenuous?
You know, just like role play almost. We
all have our own tactics, but figuring
that out is really important. Yeah. And
you've worked with Mark Zuckerberg at
Meta for seven years. Since 2008. Since
2008. So, what would you say makes a
good leader at such a big company
for at Meta or for Mark or both? Either.
I mean, I think the styles of leaders
that do well at Meta vary a lot. Um,
there's a lot of different styles at the
senior most management team. The at meta
specifically, I think if there's there's
a few things that are kind of
consistent. I think strong communication
skills is really important. I think
really um structured thinking and
analytical thinking is really important.
Uh and being quick on your feet is
actually really important because it's
pretty chaotic. Uh but we have different
strengths. Some are much stronger
organizational leaders. Some are much
stronger strategically. Some are more
strategic around business versus product
versus design. Uh there's a different
range. Some are extroverts. Some are
introverts. Some are loud. Some are
quiet. Some have changed. Uh but those
are probably the themes. But that's
because the company
values speed, values focus, values
impact. And so being able to understand
what matters, communicate it
effectively, and will progress into
existence are just going to be
disproportionately important than at
other companies. Not that they're not
important at other companies. Whereas a
different company will have a different
set of values, a different set of
different environment and maybe
different types of people
will sort of last the longest and get to
the most senior levels. Yeah. So really
being able to get clear on what the
company values are as well so that other
people can execute in that direction. I
think so. Yeah. Now if you're a leader
or you aspire to be a leader, I think
it's it's
about being intentional about your what
kind of leader you want to be, right?
There are leaders who are
um very visionary and strategic and
directive. There are vision there are
leaders who are very thoughtful and
insightful but lead from behind and are
more introverted and less alpha. There
are leaders who are really supportive
and really lean into this idea of taking
care of their people. There are leaders
who spend no time or energy on that.
Right? And there's different merits to
all of these different leadership
styles. And the truth is, if you're in
one of these roles, you do need to move
in and out of these different styles
depending on what the company and the
team needs. But it's good to be
thoughtful about what's your style and
why or what's your what are your styles
and why and then when are you acting in
which capacity. Yeah. And for someone
who's listening to this who might not
yet be head of Instagram, but they
might, you know, be in their first
leadership role, so their first
managerial role, for example, what would
you recommend to them in terms of
actually really honing that skill?
Because I think a lot of, you know, a
lot of workplaces have great training
schemes, a lot of workplaces don't.
Yeah. And I think that that's one of the
issues that we've talked about a lot on
this podcast is how do you actually
progress your career whilst also making
sure you're building the appropriate
skills to perform and ensure your team
is performing as well so that you can
progress in the direction you want to.
What would you recommend to people in
that position who want to hone those
skills but maybe don't necessarily have
the right training? I think I mean a
couple different things maybe a little
bit separate from leadership skills but
the sort of the standard mistakes
first-time managers make uh one is under
delegation right so we talked about this
a little before but like a lot of really
talented people get into their first
management job and they just try to do
everything themselves and you can do
that but you're going to be less
effective than if you manage to get your
team to be to grow your team's abilities
over time which is related to another
one which is often First-time managers
are hesitant to hire or mentor people up
um who are going to be as strong or
close to as strong or even stronger than
them. Classic mistake. I love having
people work for me who are way smarter
than me and better than me at things.
It's the best because then I can learn
from them. Um, and I've managed so many
people through this transition and they
like I don't know if we really need the
senior person and then they I'm like
just try it and then if they land that
person like every time a month later
they're like this is amazing. I run
ideas by her, she gives me advice, she
drags me along. It's like another
standard mistake. Uh, and the third
mistake I that comes to mind when I
think about first-time managers is
trying to manage everyone the same way.
Um there's this idea of fairness in
management, but the truth is
everyone's needs are different and if
you're going to get the most out of your
people, you need to understand their
specific needs. There are consistencies
like the overlap I talked about before.
So what is what matters to the company,
what matter understand what matters to
the individual. The answer to those
things will be different, but do that
for each person. But some people need to
be challenged. Some people need to be
need more support. Some people need
really direct, frank feedback and
they're comfortable taking that in
public. For other people, that'll
completely blow back uh or blow up in
your face. You have to understand the
individual's needs and then manage to
those needs. Um so for first- time
managers, I would say like look out for
those because I just it's seven out of
eight make all three of those mistakes.
Yeah. Um at least for some period of
time. And then as you get more senior,
then it's about thinking a little bit
about what kind of leader do you want to
be? What's your style? Um
and whatever it is, it's okay. Like you
can but you but you have to be honest
about what your wants are and what your
strengths are. Yeah. Um because if it's
not if it's not aligned with one of
those, it's not going to work. And I
want to move on to speaking about
Instagram and how to grow on there for
people who want to. Um, so I personally
have been on Instagram from the very
beginning. I appreciate your business.
Prior to even videos. I remember um the
15-second videos coming along
transforming my career. Personally, I
will say it was a People forget
Instagram was a feed of square photos,
no stories, no videos, no DMs, no
rectangles. Um, and we get a lot of
flack for evolving Instagram forward.
And I understand that. It's annoying
when things change, especially if you
use them. And I take it as a sign of a
good sign that people are invested in
our product. Um, but if we didn't
evolve, we wouldn't be having this
conversation. Yeah, absolutely. And in
my time, I guess on Instagram, I feel
like I've felt every algorithm change,
every feature change, every kind of
really having businesses on there and
being a creator on there. It's been
really important for me to be very close
to that and work out what that means to
the business every single time. But I
want to know from you what it is like
going through so many iterations of a
business because I can imagine you're
making changes almost daily. Um it's
pretty wild. I mean every year gets a
little bit crazier. I mean look I would
say it depends on the type of work. So
like one thing people ask a lot about is
how ranking works about the algorithm.
They call it the algorithm. There's many
many algorithms but how does ranking
work fundamentally? Uh and so but the
way we work on that is very iterative.
We make small ch tiny changes every day.
Um very rarely if ever do you see major
changes. So some people will say like oh
something clearly changed last week. My
reach went way down. It's like that
actually almost never happened. It could
be that your account got flagged and you
could see that in account status and
undo that. Um but it wasn't some major
ranking change. Could be that something
happened in the world. Maybe it was you
know champions of the game and there's a
lot more competition with your
followers. Um but so but managing that
is much more about long-term what's the
goal what's the best measurement for the
goal make sure that the metric isn't the
goal but it's a proxy for it that the
incentives are and the guardrails are
clear and that team can iterate for it
so supporting that work is totally
different than building a new product
right like we're working on an app
called edits right now for video editing
and to support that team it's not about
metrics or guard rails or you know GPUs
or revenue new budgets. It's about
making space for creativity. It's about
understanding how we might
differentiate. It's about the art of
knowing when to let push the team to
keep exploring new ideas and then when
to switch to push the idea the team to
start to focus on less and less of ideas
and double down on the ones that are the
strongest. Uh it's about giving them
space. Um so again what the work demands
is very different based on the type of
work and over time the more teams you
manage of more types you start to build
your own sense of those patterns those
archetypes uh and then you manage each
of those teams based on what's going to
get the most out of the people and the
best results. Yeah. And there's
obviously an extraordinary amount of
creativity on Instagram. I think I've
seen some Instagram feeds that should be
like in a gallery. Yeah. Yeah. Um and
that obviously means, especially when
we're talking about all of these
different iterations of Instagram that
have happened over the past kind of 15
or so years,
there's a huge breadth of different
creativity. There's kind of this
off-the- cuff posting or whatever it
might be. And there's also, I'm sure,
you know, things that someone spent 100
days creating in order to get up on
Instagram. Are you kind of able to keep
all of those creators in mind when
building new features and when releasing
new parts of the app? We try to. It's
challenging. I mean, one of the things
that I worry about is that people are
sometimes are often too precious about
what they share. We're here to support
creativity, but we want to support what
we internally call everyday creativity.
Right? it is. If you can if you have an
amazing idea or you can take an amazing
photo or shoot an amazing video in 20
seconds, you should feel comfortable
posting it. That's great. For other
people, they post once a month and
that's all that they need and that works
for them, too. And that's great, too. We
want to support all creatives, not just
ones who spend a 100 days on one post.
Um, so we try to develop different
products, right? So, um, and people
spend more time making a real that's 2
minutes long than they do posting a
photo into stories than they do sending
something in DMs as a even an image.
Actually, one thing people forget is
they don't even realize is there's way
forget texts. There's way more photos
and videos posted in DMs every day than
there are to stories. And there are way
more photos and videos posted into
stories than into feed. But when you ask
most people to think of Instagram, they
think of feed. Uh, but it's not the most
important surface in terms of where
people share and it's not the most
people actually consume content. It's
third or fourth. That's very interesting
and I can imagine that's incredibly
interesting when you're looking at how
you actually build the app itself and
understanding how how people are
genuinely using it dayto-day. like yes
they're consuming the feed but actually
if you're understanding that they're
more consuming messages more or they're
consuming stories more or whatever I can
imagine that's young people spend more
time in DMs they spend more time in
stories they spend more time in the real
tab than they do in feed that's very
interesting and you do a lot of building
in public and I speak to a lot of
founders on this podcast who are doing
exactly that they're building in public
they're they're using social media to be
able to share the journey and show the
kind of good, the bad, and the ugly. You
do a lot of ask me anything every every
Friday. And and what spurred you to do
that? Cuz that's not a classic kind of
more I don't know, you don't expect that
from a huge organization.
I mean, I used to manage newsfeed on the
Facebook app and there was a lot of
conversations about how ranking worked
given how big Facebook was and how
influential it was around the world. And
my take back then was the these
conversations are going to happen with
or without us. And so we might as well
participate, provide context, and
basically the idea is to explain what
we're doing and why we're doing it.
Maybe humanize us a little bit because a
lot of people didn't even think anyone
worked at Facebook back in the day. Um
that it was just Mark just like coding
away, I guess, on his laptop. And so I
started doing that in the Facebook days.
And then when I moved over to Instagram,
it just seemed natural to continue doing
so. Um, and I just think in a world
where we're going to be under this much
scrutiny and there's going to be this
many people who use our app and this
many people who rely on our app to do
what they do for a living or to at least
amplify what they do for a living, I
just think the conversations are going
to happen. And so my hope is to for for
the rest of us or for the rest of
everyone um to just if you're interested
to explain what we do and how we do it.
The other benefit though for me is
because we care so much about creators
because power is continuing to shift to
individuals from institutions across all
these industries around the world. It's
very helpful for me to experience what
it's like to be a creator on the
platform. Trying to create content that
breaks through, trying to manage my
comments and my DMs, trying to load
things when they don't load properly.
it's really helpful for me to build some
empathy and then to better manage the
team because nobody on the team has
millions of followers or almost nobody.
Um, and so it's it's very helpful for
me. It's funny because I well my latest
company I'm currently building an AI
talent agency for creators and the one
place that I've been almost avoiding
building in public despite the fact that
I've built every other of my companies
in public has been Instagram because I'm
almost worried
about the creators seeing what we're
currently building and what might work
and what what might not work and
actually might not make sense for you to
do it then but actually that's one of
the things that I've realized recently
has been a mistake in journey and
actually, you know, I'm I'm going to
start making sure I'm having a lot more
of those conversations because a lot of
the things I think we built that didn't
work for the creators. We probably could
have found out a lot sooner if we were
building in public and were getting that
kind of direct and constant feedback
loop. I think that's great. I think one
of the things though is we almost have
to build in public now because when we
run a test, you know, there might be 10
million people in the test, so it's
going to get covered somewhere by
somebody. Um, but if you're gonna build
in public, whether you're big or small,
you need to go in eyes wide open and you
need to make sure you have a thick skin.
It's good to get the feedback. Um, but
there's going to be more noise than
feedback invariably. Unfortunately,
that's just how the world works. And
it's our job to sift through all of that
and find the signal and ignore the
noise. And you know, if you see my DMs
or my comments, they can get pretty
gnarly and pretty angry. Um, but I need
to sort of accept that. but still go
through it because I do find gems in
there consistently every week. Yeah. Um
but you need to know what you're getting
into and you need to make sure you have
a thick skin because there's a lot of
critics out there. And so I just think
it's just important to be conscious of
that as you get involved. And for anyone
trying to build their Instagram or maybe
their business's
Instagram, is there a optimal amount of
times to be posting? because I have seen
all sorts of theories out there on kind
of how many times you should be posting
stories a day. Yeah, there isn't. Um,
there are a couple things to consider. I
mean, one of them is just so it's like
same thing about managing people. It's
similar for creators and using
Instagram. The question again with this
idea of like a ven diagram. So, what are
your goals? Like, okay, you want to grow
and get reach, but to what end? Are you
trying to sell a product? Are you trying
to build a brand? Are you trying to
evangelize a cause? Are you, you know,
what are you trying to build a
community? what are you trying to do? So
then you have to identify that goal and
then you also have to figure out what is
a creative strategy or a content
strategy that's actually going to
resonate that's going to do well. Uh yes
by understanding ranking but more by
understanding what people are interested
in because ranking is just a proxy for
people's interests. Um and then you got
to just try things and find things at
that overlap. Um, and so I think that
that's kind of where it starts, which is
you need to you need to sort of identify
that overlap. All questions like optimal
time to post, you view through that
lens.
Um, so it might be that you are a museum
curator and you're trying to drive
ticket sales and you probably should
post a bunch when there's a new exhibit
coming out in order to build up some
demand, but it doesn't make sense to
post a bunch all the time. And so maybe
it's maybe the answer to that question
changes. Maybe you're, you know, one of
these creators that does incredibly well
and posts one thing a month. Um, for a
lot of people it's more valuable to post
more often because it gives you more
shots on goals, so to speak. I mean, you
know, we're here in a soccer, sorry, a
football arena.
Um, but the thing there I'd be careful
about is burnout because let's say it is
optimal from a reach perspective to post
two things a day or three things a day
or four things a day. But if that's not
aligned with your goals because you
can't keep that up, don't do it. You
have to come up with a different thing
that is, you know, both good for
engagement but also aligned with you
your goals and your constraints. Um so
it's not a really satisfying answer um
because everyone has to kind of find
their own journey. For me I have found
that um more important than frequency is
having patterns or series. So I don't
have to think about what am I going to
do. I just know on Fridays they do an
ask me anything on stories. I try to
post at least one video a week about
either a new feature or an explainer or
what I call a hidden gem. So a cool
thing you might not know about. And I,
you know, if I have time, two or three,
but I do at least one a week. Um, and
then if I'm on the road, I just post
stories all day long. Right. That way I
don't have to think about it. And then
if I have a new idea, I'll try it and
maybe that'll become a series or maybe
it'll go away. Yeah. And what I really
like about what you've just said is
essentially the optimal cadence of
posting is the one that you can be
consistent with and the one that allows
you to do the rest of your job because a
lot of people have different parts of
their job aside from social. to maximize
my reach. I should probably post a reel
at least once a day. I cannot do that.
Actually, doesn't even take me that time
much time to create a reel, but my life
is so hectic right now. Not just the
job, but also the kids that I just can't
do that. So, I don't I post one, two,
maybe if I'm lucky, three times a week
because that's what I can that's what I
can sustain over the long run. You've
just launched edits. How do you see that
being able to help people create content
and grow their brand? The hope with
edits is that it will be a tool that
allows people who create videos today to
create more videos and better videos,
but also one that allows people who
might not have created before start to
create. It's not for a power editor who
uses a desktop and Adobe Premiere and
two monitors to edit their videos. And
it's not for someone who just posts
pictures of their kids or, you know, I
know videos of, you know, where it's
just stand still. There's no editing
need that needs to be done. It's for
those that middle and there's tens of
millions of people in that middle. Um,
and the hope is that it will not only
I'll be a video editor, but it'll
actually help with the entire creative
process from finding inspiration to
keeping track of your ideas to yes,
editing the video and hopefully doing
some pretty fun exciting things with AI
in order to make more interesting and
wonderful uh, story tell stories to
actually seeing how the video does and
looking for patterns in your insights.
that sort of entire creative journey.
Now, we'll see. Um, and you know, this
is just the beginning and it's going to
take time, but that's the aspiration and
it's one that I'm very very excited
about. Which creators do you think are
really killing it at the moment on the
app? Ooh. I just I love how there are so
many different types of creators that do
well and have completely different
strategies, you know? So,
uh, like on one end of the spectrum,
there's like, you know, Haley Bailey who
does this comedy, she's based out of New
York City. She posts five times a day
reals, but she also posts five videos on
every other platform she uses. That is
an insane amount of content production.
She is prolific. I do not encourage
everyone to try to aspire to that amount
of production, but for her, it's just
natural. And then on the other end of
this spectrum, there's Rick Rubin, who
only has one thing on his profile at a
time. And when he posts another one,
which might be once every week or two,
he deletes the last one. Uh, and it's
just kind of his zen take on
creativity that Fortnite. Um, and so
that's kind of the fun bit is seeing
people find things, ways to be creative,
to express themselves, but that are
really aligned with their identities,
their values, their stories. Um, so for
me, that's always kind of fun to see. U,
for me, my my Instagram is a lot of, you
know, design content. So, I'm really
into architecture and furniture. It's a
lot of um you know, there's men's
fashion. There's a lot of football,
which we call soccer in the States. Um
some basketball and some watches. Um but
for everyone, it's different. So, if I
named the creators in those markets, it
would just be probably completely
uninteresting to somebody else. And what
do you think entrepreneurs are getting
wrong and getting right on Instagram at
the moment?
I think too often entrepreneurs and
business owners and creators are focused
uh too much on reach. And to be clear,
I'm not saying reach doesn't matter. Of
course, it matters. If you post and no
one sees it, then what's the point of
posting? But again, the question is
reach to what end? Um if you can get
great reach, but you're trying to sell
shoes and none of your reach is actually
helping you send any shoes, then there's
no point to it. Uh, and I think that is
that's a that's a common problem is you
get overfocused on ranking in the
algorithm and how to get more likes or
how to get more views or more reach and
you lose sight of why you're there in
the first place. It's better to have a
smaller following and reach less people
but have them actually in my weird
example effectively sell your shoes than
to reach more people and sell no sell
none. That particularly delights me is
when people come up with creative ways
to connect the dots between the
different things that we build. I' I've
met people who follow a different group
of accounts every month based on a
theme. They're focused on causes. So,
you know, maybe maybe it's climate this
month, maybe it's women education next
month, maybe it's something else. Um,
but so that's a cool thing. That's a
hack. But what they should also do, and
I've seen people do this, is create a
video explaining that. So now you've got
a real that explains what you're doing,
and you've got your following list,
which actually points people in the
direction. And you've sort of you have
a, you know, one plus one equals three
kind of thing. And so if you can think
about how can you use realels and
stories and who you follow and your grid
and your DMs or your channel. Um you
can't be not everyone can be using all
of these tools. So I'm not trying to say
that. But if there's creative ways to um
amplify your stories by using two or
three and having them interact, I think
that's always particularly exciting. And
what would you say generally for
creators is the most important metric to
track on Instagram? So the the measure
of how I mean reach is probably the the
output that matters. But if you're
trying to understand why your reach is
what it is, the things to look at most
are likes per reach. So you know if a
thousand people saw it, how many liked
it, sends per reach, and if you're
posting a video, watch time, average
watch time. Those three matter the most.
Okay. For reals. Mhm. What about posts
in general? And for posts obviously uh
you watch time isn't relevant if it's a
photo. But likes per reach and sends per
reach. For stories, you know, obviously
you can't do there's different things
you can interact with. For channels,
it's different. But for the main posts,
those are the three things that matter
most. And I'm personally obsessed with
productivity and making sure that I I'm
getting that. I really give off that. So
I give intense. I should introduce you
to my OCD palace later on my phone. I'll
just show you how I keep all my notes
and all my to-dos. Well, I show you my
productivity method, which is a
step-by-step process for good to-do
lists. But um Oh, yes. I love this.
Yeah, it's a it's um it's a really good
one if I do say so myself. But I wanted
to know your productivity
non-negotiables. So, if you sat down and
you know you have an obscene amount of
work to get through, what are your kind
of non-negotiables or what is your
process in really tackling that to-do
list? So, I have a running to-do list
that's organized and I I always mark
things. There's a small subset that of
things that absolutely have to get done
today. And I try to be really intense
about not putting too many things marked
as it has to get done today that don't
actually have to get done today because
at the end of the at, you know, at the
end of the day, uh, inevitably something
comes up. you know, we'll have a press
cycle or a kid will fall at school and I
have to pick them up early and my day
will get blown up. So, I have to have a
short list of what needs to get done at
any given in any given day so that when
when my time gets compressed, I know
where to focus first. Um, that I think
is as much about peace of mind as it is
actually about prioritization. Yeah, I
completely agree with that. My big thing
is that I think that we often have this
big to-do list that feels more
terrifying than it is because it's not
weighted in terms of importance or time.
Like I'm I categorize my to-do list by
time. I have three different sections by
time. Um yeah, I find it gets everything
done so much quicker. But that's that's
exactly the thing is if you have a spare
five minutes and you look at your to-do
list, you're probably going to get
nothing done because of the paradox of
choice and you're kind of thinking there
are all these things. Whereas if you
have it separated into things that take
under five minutes, you're going to be
able to get through them super quickly.
So it's like this illusion of just being
able to skim things down and work out
which are the priorities. Yeah. As long
as we're nerding out on productivity.
I've met someone who does this thing I
wish I could do. I think my list is too
long. Who doesn't do to-do lists as like
a list? He puts it in the calendar for
the amount of time he thinks it's going
to take. Yes. And so he if you give him
another thing to do, he's like he'll
look at his calendar and he'll be like,
"All right, I can I can do that. That's
going to take about an hour. I'll do it
on I'll do it tomorrow from 11 to 12."
Yeah. Um but if it's not if he doesn't
have a window and it's going to take an
hour until next week, he's like, "You're
not going to get it till next week." And
so it's he's he actually and he's built
up a lot of good intuition over the
years about how long all these different
tasks take. My to-do list is so long. I
don't know how my calendar and I have so
many meetings that my calendar is
already a little bit triggering just to
look at. So, I'm not sure I could do
that. Yeah. But I love that idea. So,
mine's a combo of those two things. I
have the to-do list split into three,
which is under five minutes, 5 to 30
minutes, and 30 minutes plus. And then I
write out my fixed commitments for the
day. So, all my meetings or when I'm
going to the gym or whatever it might
be. And then I slot them in
specifically. They're already in time.
You do? Yeah. So, I take I've already,
you know, I've flagged my
non-negotiables. The beginning of a long
relationship of productivity hacks being
DM'd to each other. Oh. Fantastic.
Honestly, I would love absolutely
nothing more. Um, and I Yeah, I'm just
obsessed with it. I feel like I when you
talk about being obsessed with
productivity, I think people think that
you want to be working all the time
rather than the fact that you want to be
working for less time. So, that is why
you need to do it effectively. Anyway, I
feel like we could talk about this for a
long time. Just to finish, I feel like I
have found
the real common ground here. Um, just to
finish, I would love to know what the
best piece of advice is that you've ever
been given. Oh man, I know big one.
I've been given a I've been lucky. I've
been getting a lot of good advice.
Um, in the early years, my my mother
started ran an architecture firm for the
longest time. And so when I started a
design firm in New York when I was young
in uni, uh, one amazing piece of advice
she gave me was always talk about the
money openly and early. And I got me
very comfortable talking about money.
And I think a lot of people struggle
with that. And that's not only relevant
if you're a business owner. I mean a a
report. I work at a big company. It's
actually sorry, I'm trying to say it's
both. So if you had at if you're running
a company and you're especially if it's
in service being like, "Hey, we build
websites." The the smallest job we've
ever done was, you know, 5,000 pounds.
So if that's too high for you, you know,
that's totally okay, but this isn't
going to work. I just want you to know
that upfront and being comfortable
saying that upfront and saving people
some time and giving a sense of um you
know what their expectations should be.
It's also about being confident in your
self-worth. Similarly, if you're working
at a large company, being able to self-
advocate, right? So, being able to say,
"Hey, this is what matters to me. I care
about compensation and here's why.
Here's what I think is fair." Be okay
with not necessarily getting what you
ask for, but you're going to get more if
you ask for it. And so this comfort with
being talking about money which is
almost like a dirty subject for a lot of
people I think served me really well in
the early years um in the middle years
and I don't I can't think of the latest
I think I mean my first manager at
Facebook was a woman uh maybe she was my
second name Rebecca Cox really intense
really talented designer and I thought I
was like doing great like I said I was I
was a little overconfident in my 20s and
she's like, "You need to focus." Which
is a very simple thing to say, but in my
20s, I was like working around the
clock. I thought I was crushing it, but
the work wasn't great. And it wasn't
great cuz I was doing too many things.
Uh, and I and that sort of idea of do
less things and do them better, I think,
is one that is almost always valuable to
consider at least. And so, she really
pushed me and humbled me a little bit.
She's like, "You're unfocused. You're
all over the place." I was never used to
hearing that because I never had a boss
before. Um, so I don't know. I could go
on and on, but those those two jump out
to me from my mom and from Rebecca.
Well, thank you so much. You have been
fantastic. Thank you for all of the help
on how to use Instagram and also just
the general I feel like people will
learn a lot from your corporate
experience and your career. So, thank
you so much. Thanks for having me. I
don't usually get to talk about
management and organizational leadership
and that's just these are my obsessions.
This is just me trying to get some
advice consultant. No, it's great. It's
great. I I mean I would love to more. I
don't know if anyone usually cares. So,
I'm excited. Amazing. Well, let's do it.
Cheers.
[Music]