Hi, Adam Meri. Hi. Thank you so much for
taking the time. Welcome to the channel.
Thank you for having me. I'm excited to
be here. We've got loads of topics to
see together. You're 42 years old.
You're the head of one of the biggest
social networks in the world. It's of
course Instagram. Instagram has between
2 and 2.5 billion active users. That's
what I looked up online. That's about
like a quarter to a third of the world's
population, which is kind of impressive.
Um, I'm of course one of them. um as a
content creator, as a journalist, also
as just someone spending some time
online. And so today I have lots of
questions for you. We'll talk about your
job, talk about meta, talk about content
creation. uh also talk some you know
sensitive topics which I feel are
important about misinformation, online
harassment, mental health, AI all those
topics and see how you view those
questions as a head of uh of Instagram
to yeah see and and try and understand
what happens um behind Instagram. So
thank you so much again for a lot to
cover. I'm excited. We'll try and cover
I hope it'll be good. I'm sure it'll be
interesting. Um so to start with um
you've worked at Facebook and Meta for
almost 20 years. Quite a few years now.
Yeah. I started 17 years old. Yeah.
Yeah. I was 2008 I started as a designer
like a just a entry-level product
designer. I was 25 years old. Okay. And
then you did so many things at Meta. And
since 2018 you've been the head of
Instagram. Uh what does that mean? Uh
what exactly do you do and what don't
you do as a head of Instagram? It's a
great question because because Meta owns
a couple different apps, there is stuff
that is shared and this the stuff that
is what we would say federated. So
ultimately I'm responsible for the app
and most of the teams that work on the
app report directly to me particularly
if you work 100% on Instagram. So I
manage an engineering team, a design
team, a research team, an analytics
team, uh a product management team and
some others. Um, but then there are
other teams that we lean on a lot. Um,
you know, there is one infrastructure
team that supports all of the apps.
There's one ads team that supports all
of the apps. There's one safety team
that supports all of the apps. And so I
will I will have infrastructure ads and
safety teams as well, but they are sort
of Exactly. Um and then I'm also
responsible for supporting um
partnerships, policy, legal, marketing,
communications,
uh what we think of as the business
functions as well. So I try to think of
the app from end to end and um hire the
best people I can and help guide them
forward um but support them ultimately
um as opposed to necessarily direct
them.
Instagram started as a photo app uh
quite a while ago. Feed of only square
photos. Only square photos. Um and today
it's clearly way more than that. So how
would you describe Instagram today? And
for example, how would you uh say it's
different from Facebook or other
platforms that may exist today?
So a lot of what we've done has changed
and Instagram has become more
complicated over the years. I think it's
a little too complicated if I'm honest,
but working on ways of simplifying, but
the heart of what we do has stayed the
same. We've always looked to connect
people over creativity, right? Be a
place where creative people like you can
express themselves and then the rest of
us can not only enjoy that content, but
talk to our friends about that content.
How we do that has changed. you know,
we've added DMs or messages, we've added
stories, we've added reels, um, notes
over time, but the core needs that those
products or those features are meeting
stay the same. Uh, and I think that'll
continue to be the case where I think
the product will change in the next 5 or
10 years, but those needs I think will
stay the same. But you also but you also
asked how we you should go too but if
you want me to answer um how differs. Um
we are I think more focused on a subset
of groups like young people and creators
and Facebook and we have I think a
broader range of tools to hopefully
enable more flexibility to creatives
than things like YouTube or Tik Tok
which are more specialized just on
video. M and so I was asking myself like
how you define a social network like
Instagram would you say today it's the
format but at the same time you see that
like of course format are changing you
know evolving like very fast is it like
this goal you just defined here like
what's the main thing you say would stay
like all through the years is it this
goal you just talked about this question
of for Instagram yeah but for a social
network it could be broader so I think
of a social network as a place where
people can connect with content and
friends and the content is generated
by creat well public accounts and
private accounts. So user generated
content connecting with content and
friends. So you know you might have
platforms that are much more focused on
a specific format like clubhouse and
audio. You might have uh networks that
are much more focused on a type of
content like at least LinkedIn started
focused primarily on professional
content. They've actually expanded a lot
since then. Um, usually we all start
with a specialization and then we
broaden, you know, um, and that that and
then we and then we and then we compete.
And we've seen it with other platforms,
of course, we've seen, you know, Tik Tok
trying to do long videos and even us
like we we've been trying to post like
some 10-minute long videos on on Tik Tok
and now they're working sometimes better
than like short form and we're like,
"Oh, that's that's weird." Um, YouTube,
of course, is trying to do short videos.
Spotify is trying to do video, too. Um,
what about Instagram? Like, how do you
navigate through all of those changes?
Yeah, it's it's wild. So, there's a lot
of ways to think about it. Um, I'm
making space here. It's a podcast. I
don't know if anyone's going to like be
able to see this. Um, the way I think
about it, um, or at least one way to
think about it is there are three
different types of
experiences. Um, and you can't do all
three. Well, I think you can connect
with friends. That's one type of
experience. There's short form video,
that's another. And then there's long
form video, which is another. You can
do, I think, really good work around
connecting with friends and short form
video in the same app. And you can do
really good work around short form video
and long form video in the same app. I
don't think you can do connecting with
friends and long form video in the same
app really well. Because if I watch a
video for 10, 20, 30 minutes, that's a
lot of messages to friends, commenting
on friends, seeing friends photos and
videos that you did not do. Whereas with
short form video, what happens is you
watch a lot of them and you send some to
your friends in a DM and then it starts
a conversation and that brings them back
into Instagram and then they see some
and that send it to another friend. So
those things are symbiotic in a way long
form video is not. YouTube has always
been very focused on maximizing the
amount of time spent on the platform.
Tik Tok actually similarly, which is why
I believe they're leaning more into long
form video. We don't go our teams on
time spent. Time spent is I think a nice
measure of how relevant we are in the
world, but it's not our primary goal
because if we do that, we would go all
long form video and we would lose that
friend part, which I think is really at
the heart of our identity. And I don't
think we can lose that. But at the same
time, you could think that like and Tik
Tok does it quite well today that like
um on even Instagram on wheels like
having lots of short form content would
make you stay on the app and so sure for
sure form video can definitely drive
time spent. I think one of the reasons
Tik Tok has struggled even though they
have had some success on more friend
type content is because they focus also
a lot on longer video and on time. So
that's why I think some of their stories
products haven't done as well. They've
done better with messaging because I
think short form video is good there,
but you know they made their friends tab
the a be real app tab for a while and
that didn't really work. They've had a
bunch of different fits and starts and I
think that's partly because their
primary goal is overall time and that
really is in a lot of tension with
seeing content from friends, messaging
friends, commenting on friends content
and connecting with friends and all the
other ways you can do. Yeah, totally
makes sense because we can we can also
see like YouTube for example, they've
integrated some shorts. It's working
quite well today. I mean, I see it on at
least on my accounts, but they also
tried to do like a sort of a social
network thing with like friends and
stuff and that didn't work. I don't I
don't even know if it's still there
today, but like at least they tried and
Yeah. They had stories for years and it
didn't work and they had messaging for I
think six years and they unlaunched it a
few years ago. Yeah. So, it tends to
show Yeah. long form as you're saying is
maybe not compatible with this sort of
friends. They're just more intention.
Interesting. Um and also we've seen
especially like in Asia or in China um
the building of like what sometimes
people call super apps. So like WeChat
for example. Yeah. WeChat basically for
those who don't know like you can
message, search, pay, shop, do like
order, you know, cab like do so many
things with one app. Pay your rent. Pay
your rent.
Bank people keep a budget. Uh they have
a they have a decent float actually. We
chat and some of these other major apps
and like if you're over there like you
need this app to basically like do most
of the things today which is kind of
impressive. We've seen like Elon Musk
with X for example trying to I mean
that's what he says like build a super
app by integrating you know messaging so
the whole social media thing video
payments uh AI now which is very strong
too over there um is that like a goal
for Instagram too or for Meta to have a
sort of a super app not explicitly I
think there's value in them but I also
think what works in China doesn't
necessarily work outside of China and we
see that in a lot of different ways so
one Small example live video if you look
at any of the Chinese networks it is an
immense percentage of time spent on them
uh something like 20%. Whereas on all of
the apps that we can tell outside of
China it's less than 1%. Uh there's just
something different going on in China. I
think it has to do probably with how the
media works around censorship around,
you know, freedom of speech and that you
can't get some of that type of content
on TV the way you can on um some of the
super apps the way you can in in France
and Europe and the US and a lot of the
rest of Asia. And so there's just some
big differences. And even when you look
at countries that are obviously
different, I want to be sensitive here,
but culturally approximate in a lot of
consumer behaviors to China like
Indonesia, you just see these huge
differences. So now look, I think Elon
is taking X in a new direction. Um, I
think it's interesting. We'll see if
he's successful or not. But for us, I
think that opens up some opportunities.
I'm happy to compete with X on video
with Instagram and then to compete with
X on perspectives and conversations and
debates with culturally relevant
creators with Threads because I think
threads is better at that than Instagram
and I think we'll be better at that than
X over time. And what's also interesting
is to see that we've um seen like more
and more you know social media or even
like formats arrive in the past few
years but also like be adopted by the be
like the users in a in an increasingly
like fast way like Instagram in a few
years at least in France like managed to
get like millions of followers but also
like short form you know reels or like
formats you know today like if you go in
the subway like you'll see everyone
watching those formats and it's the same
for like other type of content um this
idea that like things are going faster
and faster that like adoption of like
new formats is you know evolving in a
sort of a fast way. How do you see this
this question today and how does it
impact your work today? It just creates
even more urgency and
uh and makes agility and speed even more
important and but look this is a long
trend is that technology is advancing
faster and faster. If you look at what I
would call like the dominant forms or
the primary forms of communicative media
or technology over time, their reigns of
of being the primary sort of have
shortened, you know. So
uh let's go like go if you go back a h
100red years you know I think
that film was actually big before the
radio and that lasted many decades and
then radio was really important but it
kind of became the primary thing in
maybe the 20s and that only lasted until
that lasted the 50s or 60s and then TV
became important and then that lasted
for a couple decades and then the
internet and websites became important
and that lasted for maybe two decades
and then apps became important and then
you that's lasted for less time. And so
you're seeing these 10 years of these
primary ways that we entertain ourselves
or consume information or connect with
friends, they they their their reigns as
sort of the the champion or the lead is
shortening over time as technology
evolves more and more quickly. And so
for us, the question is how do you
evolve? Because I know it's annoying and
frustrating when Instagram changes. It
feels like I came in and rearranged your
desk where you talked to your friends
and wrote your, you know, letters or
organized your photos. But if we didn't,
we would become irrelevant. If we were a
feed of square photos and we didn't have
recommendations, we didn't have stories,
we didn't have videos or reals, we
didn't have DMs, we wouldn't be talking
today. You'd be talking to somebody else
who worked on a different app. And
so, we need to be careful. We need not
to move too quickly. I don't want to
break anything, but we I would rather
take more risk and move forward more
quickly than the alternative because
that's usually how big apps become
irrelevant.
So interesting. Yeah. So yeah, it means
trying out new stuff very often and
seeing what works. And it means trying
out new things. It means being willing
to adopt and copy competitors when they
show that they can meet that same need
better. Don't copy everything. only
things that are aligned with your reason
to be. It also means planning, you know,
so we have so many things happening this
year. We have, you know, the the
political environment is changing
drastically. You know, tariffs, yes,
tariffs, no, who knows? We have uh a
potential Tik Tok ban in the US. We
have, you know, this massive thing cards
that are going to get flipped over and
one I don't know what's going to be on
the other side, but it'll have I know
it's going to have a big effect on
Instagram. And so I make sure that I
have my teams try to look around corners
and plan for different outcomes so that
we can be quick to adapt when we do see
what's on the other side of each card.
Yeah. And we'll be talking about quite a
few of those changes um especially like
in terms of AI and like how AI for
example may change some some stuff. Um
so as you said Instagram is part of Meta
which is owned by Mark Zuckerberg. um a
few months ago he made a big shift in
his messaging. He said that was in an
interview in a quote the masculine
energy I think is good and obviously
society has plenty of that but I think
corporate culture is really trying to
get away from it. Um I think having a
culture that celebrates the aggression a
bit more has its own merits that are
really positive and he said also like he
wants to bring back free speech to the
platforms. Um, all those questions
raised concerns among a lot of users.
Um, what should people expect from
Instagram this year after this shift,
you know, in the d in the direction for
for the group? Yeah. So, I do want to
tease things apart. So, there was the
masculine energy comment which was one
comment in a three-hour podcast, which I
don't think was connected to the broader
shifts happening to the network. Um, I
think it was a little bit taken out of
context, but I understand why there was
such a strong negative reaction to it.
But I do think the more substantial
changes were the changes we announced in
early January around trying to focus on
making less mistakes and enabling more
speech. Uh, and look, we we have we are
global platform and what is accepted and
expected varies from country to country.
you know what seems like m maybe here in
France you'd look at one of our policies
and compared to the US and you would
think we're being too conservative um or
um but if you were in Iran you'd
probably think we're being wildly too
liberal the
definition the definition of free speech
depends uh if you're in the US or if
you're in France there's not at all the
same way of seeing and also even just
the the idea of the value of free speech
free speech is a like a core tenant of
our ex our identity as as as you know
Americans it's you know the first part
you know amendment in the constitution
so it's like a whereas like you talk
about the right to free expression in
Europe it does not resonate in the same
way at all but I do think we can all
agree that there are different equities
that we need to balance we need you know
safety is one privacy is another uh
those things can be intention and speech
is another And those things can be
intention. Nobody here in Europe likes
it when we take their content down if
they don't think it really does violate
our community guidelines. And so we're
always trying to balance those equities.
The changes in January weren't related
to masculine energy. They were related
more to how we try and balance those
equities. So the big thing that was the
theme across all of them was we want to
make less mistakes. There are billions
of things uploaded to the platforms a
day. you know, millions of things
reported, if not more. If we make a
mistake on 1% or 10%, that means like
even just 1% actually, that means that
there's hundreds of thousands and
millions and tens of millions over time
of content that we take down that we
should not have. And I just think we
were making too many mistakes. And so
we've tried to make some changes to the
policies, yes, but to how we enforce the
policies, how much we rely on reports
versus algorithms,
um, and things like that to try and
minimize the number of mistakes and be
public about it. Cuz every 3 months we
post, uh, a report of all the content
takedowns we have, how many are there,
how many were proactive, how many were
reactive, how has that trended over
time, and what we're going to add now is
and how many mistakes did we make
because that is another key part of the
equation. and Meta talked about the idea
of ending a sort of a medialed
factecking by maybe replacing it with a
system where basically the community can
like yeah like check content and like
see what's true, what's not and like add
basically I mean I would understand it
like uh X does today. Um is that
something so you're willing to do on
Instagram and do you have an idea on
like how this will work? Yeah, we we've
started to roll it out. still early, but
the idea is to instead of rely on third
party fact checkers who have there's
pros and cons to working with those
organizations
um to work with the community at large
and it doesn't mean anybody can add a
com community note to anything but you
allow anybody to propose one or trusted
users to propose one and then other
users vote on them and then where
there's broad consensus then resurface
it. I actually was very involved in
building the third-party fact-checking
program back in 2017 and 18 because I
was Oh, that was a long time. Okay.
Yeah. I was working on newsfeed off for
the Facebook app. This was in the wake
of President Trump's first election and
there's a lot of concerns particularly
in the US about fake news. Um, and I,
you know, we were trying to do the best
work we could, but honestly, I don't
think it ended up being nearly as
successful as we wanted. Third party
fact checkers are limited in how much
content that they can do because there's
only so many of these organizations and
we have to pay them to do it. there are
biases and their selection even if they
always give an honest answer is if it's
true or not what they picked to actually
approve is um we saw a lot of biases and
it was just fundamentally much more
difficult to scale whereas I feel like
the community notes approach which all
credit to Twitter they pioneered um is I
think a more scalable one and so we're
pursuing it um now time will tell if we
can be successful or not but the idea is
not
to ignore the issue. The idea is to
quite the opposite, address the issue
with a more scalable solution cuz I mean
on a personal level that's just like how
I see it. But I love the idea of like
community factecking because I feel like
I prefer like this concept from like
having a company or like a government
saying like that's true or that's not
true. So the general idea I feel like
it's something that's ideally would work
very well and would be very interesting.
The only concern I have and I see it on
X today is that um often you get some
content that where the community notes
uh they tend to get on the on the
content like way too late. Yeah.
basically like a few days or a few hours
after like the content has been
published and so this you know you can
have a fake news with like millions of
views and it's only like after a while
that this content is is really notice
but yeah also since Elon Musk took over
X and reduced content moderation. The
spread of false information has grown
significantly. This has raised major
concerns for democracy and many
organizations have the same fears about
Meta if it decides to take a similar
approach. It's a real concern. It's
actually more of a concern with third
party fact checkers because they are
there's less of them and and um there
are organizations that are tend they
just tend to be much slower than the
community. But it's still an issue with
community notes, right? I want to make
sure I'm not pretending otherwise. You
if you do not move quickly, then by the
time you get involved, it might not be
even helpful to add the community note
because all the views have already
happened. Yeah. Because like people will
start to fact check something if it get
views. So it's often way later. And so
just to understand how you see this
today. Um so of course we've talked
about this problem of like um being like
reactive like and and yeah speed
regarding this. Um but how do you view
like a platform like Instagram today
regarding like fake news and everything?
Does that mean that like if something
like there's uh fake news like something
that's completely false will it be like
deleted or will it be able to stay on
the platform but with like something
saying that this content is not true or
the latter it would the idea is to not
censor people for saying things that
aren't true but provide context um
because you know I could say the sky is
green and it' be weird for me to for the
platform to take that down but it's not
so you should know that you know when
you see
Generally, we want to empower people to
make educated decisions about what to
trust and what not to. Um, and I mean,
look, we'll probably talk about AI in a
bit, but we're moving to a world where
you're going to be able to create an
image or a video of anything you want.
Uh, and it'll look real. And so, as you
try to evaluate
um the the veracity of a piece of
content, you're going to have to
consider not just what you're looking
at, but who said it more and more. So I
also think community notes aside, we
need to do more and are starting to do
more to give people context about who's
posting. I want to protect pseudonymity.
I don't want to make everybody put their
real names everywhere. There's a bunch
of downsides to that. But are they is
their account verified? Like do they do
we at least know who they are? They've
they is how long has the account been
around? What country is the account
based in to allow you to make a decision
on whether or not to trust something or
not? because you're going to need to
consider much more in the future who's
saying something um than you have in the
past relative to what's being said.
Okay. Yeah. And so how do you think do
you think AI how does that how does AI
change this? It's the fact that you get
more and more content that can be
produced that can be fake and sometimes
it's obvious like if it's like something
you see that's fake and it's like even
like in a yeah it's going to be like a
humoristic thing. How do you see those
contents on your platform today? And
what's the biggest issue or goal for you
to manage those? So, I actually think
there's a lot of exciting opportunities
with AI generated content. Um, I think
that it should enable a bunch of people
to be more creative. It should enable
creatives to produce more and better
content because it's usually not make
something from nothing. It's usually
part of your workflow. So, you know, you
can it's not even necessarily like
glamorous, but you know, you you're
making a reel there seven clips. You can
make all the color line up so it looks
like they're all on the same day cuz you
know, you're facing the light, you're
away from the light. You could add a hat
that you forgot to have or a prop, that
kind of thing. Um, but there are risks
too obviously. Um, I think a couple
different things. One, we want to make
sure anything that's made with AI is
labeled as such. So, you know, if you
use any of our tools to make it, it's
labeled and there's an ability to add a
label if it's not. We cannot detect
everything that was made with AI from
everybody because that's a bit of a an
arms race that is impossible to win. Uh,
we can do some work there though. Um,
and then we can provide more context
about who's saying it so that you can
make decisions about what to trust and
what not to trust. But Instagram aside,
like you will be able to make a video
where you could just take a photo of me,
a video of you saying whatever you want
and then have it look like me in my
voice, but it's you saying it even if
you said it in a different language and
then you could post it and you could
make me look as bad as you wanted.
That's going to be able to happen. But
is it from you? Why might you say that?
Are you based in France? You know, did
you did you schedule did you sign up for
Instagram a week ago? These are the
things that are going to be important
for people to evaluate whether or not
they should trust that this is
authentic. And I I see it I mean I've
seen it on some social media uh with
like some people taking my voice taking
basically the format of like my videos
and just changing what I'm saying to
like so sometimes it's like funny stuff
and like obviously you understand that
like it's just AI generated but
sometimes people use it to like spread
like fake news or like some stuff and
you're like oh that's scary because even
myself I see it. That's what we were
saying earlier. I see this content when
it has already like hundreds of
thousands or millions of views and I'm
like, "Oh, that's too late for me to do
anything because the content is just
getting anyway." So, yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
It's tough. It's tough, but it's the
world we're moving into. But I would
like to know if I see it, is it is it a
verified account or not? You know, if
it's your name and it's verified or if
it's, you know, but if it's not your
name and and or it's not verified, that
changes things. Um, is it based in
somewhere in Eastern Europe or in you
know Russia or somewhere where there's
like we know that there's more negative
content that comes from not all of it
but a lot of fake content comes
disproportionately comes from those
parts of the world um things like that
signals of trusted patterns of like way
of and is there a way for meta today to
instantly understand if a content is AI
generated it's too difficult to not
perfectly uh there are ways to detect
But it's the the technology to our
conversation before is changing so
quickly um that we we do not know for
sure if everything that is created is
created with AR or not. Cuz by the way,
a lot of times it's a hybrid, right? You
we've used Photoshop for years to like
touch things up. It might not even be
airbrushing. It might just be like
getting rid of spots from, you know,
photographs back in the day. A lot of
those tools can and do use machine
learning and AI. uh to make sure you can
use the stamp tool so you can get rid of
you know your pimple when and you take a
piece from here and put it there. Um, so
just saying is this manipulated in any
way is is our and by the way again we we
always talk about AI as if it's push a
button get a piece of content I think
that is a thing but the much more common
thing is it's used to edit in a longer
creative process whether that's a
positive creative process like telling a
story or a more you know malicious
process like trying to spread a piece of
fake news. Yeah. And if we take and then
we'll move on to another topic but like
if we take I mean the worst case
scenario we we could imagine for like
any social network social network which
is a group whether it's like a political
group or anything a group who like uses
AI to produce a massive amount of
content uh spreading whether it's fake
news or anything but like publishing
like hundreds and hundreds of like uh
fake news for example in this type of
situation
What would be uh Instagram Instagram's
role in that? Yeah. What would Instagram
do? So that risk predates AI, right? Cuz
now what you have is, you know, a
content farm and what we call
coordinated inauthentic behavior. So um
CIA is what we call it internally. And
so what we're looking for there is
patterns. Are there things that are
happening that look like it's some sort
of collusion or organized effort to
spread? It might not even be
misinformation. It might just be
propaganda. You know, we saw this with R
coming out of Russia a bunch, you know,
particularly four, five, six, seven,
eight years ago. Um, and so there we're
looking at what are the IP addresses.
What does the network of connections
look like? Um, how are they using it?
They're very sophisticated. Uh, just
like spammers where they pretend to be
people. They adopt those patterns. They
don't post at local late night times if
they're pretending to be in Texas, even
if they're not. Uh they post, you know,
a few times a week, not every second of
the day. They become friends with each
other. They post things that are not
about the propaganda or the
misinformation in addition to the actual
um sort of agenda content. Uh but we're
getting more sophisticated. We work with
governments around the world to try to
identify them. Uh we have a whole
investigations operation and set of
teams. uh when we identify it, we don't
always remove it right away because
usually it's useful to take one account
and then branch out and figure out
everything everybody else they seem to
be working with and then we take the
whole network down at once. Okay. And so
you might take it down if you see that
it's a sort of an organized automatic.
Okay. Yeah. If it's coordinated and
authentic behavior, we take the whole
network down. Um we might not take the
first account down that we find cuz we
want to make sure we leverage that and
don't let them know that we're on to
them until we find all of the
connections and then we'll take the
whole thing down. Did you differentiate
like one guy just saying something
that's not true with like an organized
way of spreading we're not the truth
police. We're not going to go and take
down content that you say that's false.
But if you're using our platform to try
and have a coordinated attack on uh on a
government or on democracy or on
propaganda that is 100% if we find it we
take it down and that's the whole
network and it's fully done. It's not a
piece of content done. That's the
accounts are all blocked. the IP
addresses are all blocked. We try to
make sure we handle because that's
that's that's election interference
usually. That's that's pretty serious
thing. That's a serious thing. Yeah.
Another updates and important thing that
happened after the interview. Meta has
now launched its AI assistant called the
Meta AI on a large scale. This launch
sparked in Europe strong reactions with
many voices calling to block the use of
users personal data. So, we've already
talked about this on our other formats,
but we'll go into more details soon to
explain the whole debate. Uh, we'll talk
about like content creation and like all
of this and the algorithm. I have quite
a few questions in a few in a few
minutes. But just I had another uh topic
I wanted to talk to talk with you. Um,
another sensitive topic about mental
health uh on social media. You had a a
US study published in March 2025 that
showed that 40% of young people being
treated for depression or suicidal
thoughts also have problematic use of
social media, not only Instagram but
like social media in a broader sense. Um
also in 2021 um internal meta documents
revealed by the Wall Street Journal
showed the company knew about some risks
for for teens. Uh so that was like in
2021. um in 2025 uh almost four years
later, what have you done uh as a group
to fix those uh those issues? So, I want
to be clear with some of the issues that
we're talking about, things like, you
know, well-being or even things like,
you know, bullying. There's
no 100% fixing them, right? These things
are human, right? Teens and kids, they
harass and they bully each other. That's
going to that's as old as time. Now,
does that mean we should just accept it?
No, of course not. We have a bunch of
responsibilities. Um, but I want to make
sure that I'm honest with two and a half
billion people on the platform or
whatever it might be, not everyone's
going to check their baggage at the door
and only bring their positive self to
the platform. And so, our job is to
minimize the bad and maximize the good.
Now depending on the issue you're
talking about um whether it's
problematic use which we define as using
a product more than you really feel good
about or bullying or negative social
comparison you know there's different
things that we have tried to do uh to
minimize the risk and to minimize any
sort of downsides. Um, for teens
specifically though, which matters most
cuz our youth matters most. Um, the big
thing is that we took all of the tools
that we've built over the years, audited
them all, looked for inconsistencies,
but also opportunities to go further and
improve and put them into a package we
call teen accounts, which is actually
rolled out here uh and worldwide at this
point. Yeah. Saw some ads a few a few
weeks ago. Yeah. Yeah. Well, we want
people to know about it.
And what teen accounts are are a really
comprehensive
uh set of automatic protections for
teens to try and keep them safe and give
parents some peace of mind. It's about
who they you know uh they're private by
default. So who you can post to, who can
interact with them, right? So only
people that they're connected to or you
know pe adults they don't know can't
even message them at all. What content
they see. We don't send notifications in
the evening. remind them to maybe try
something else once they hit an hour for
the day, even if it's not all in one go.
Um, and parents, if they want, can go
and change those settings, but the
defaults, because we know a lot of
parents are busy, are very careful and
safe. And if the teen and if they're
specifically under 16, so if they're 13,
14, or 15, and they want to change those
settings, they need to get their parents
approval or permission to do so. Um, now
this isn't entirely new. Some of those
features have existed for years or many
years, but some are also new. U but the
idea is to just try to make sure that
there is a
clear, safe, age appropriate experience
for those under 18. And I know you have
kids. I don't have some yet. I don't
have kids yet. But like I guess it's a
question like all parents ask themselves
like how we should deal with social
media for our kids. Like should we give
them accounts at what age? uh like
should we look at what they're doing?
Should you have an access to the account
or like should you just leave them doing
what they want to do? Like more on a
personal level, how do you see this
question? How did you do it yourself? I
have three. Uh they're not old enough to
use social media. You have to be 13 to
use Instagram and they're are nine,
seven, and about to be five. Um they use
tablets and you know to watch movies on
planes and increasingly play video
games. But look, I I think there are
some things that are universally true,
but there's a lot that is specific to
the child. So, yes, you can't use
Instagram until you're 13. Uh, and I'm
excited about my kids using a safe
version version of Instagram when
they're 13, where they can explore their
interests and connect with their friends
over their interests. But are they all
going to be ready at 13? I don't know. I
can imagine a world where one of the
more mature ones at 13, I'd feel very
comfortable. and one of the less mature,
more wild ones, I might want to wait
until they're 14 or 15. Um, because
ultimately, I think every child is
different and a parent knows best what's
appropriate for their child. Uh, and
that has to be uh, well, it doesn't have
to be, but it should be a parent's
decision and it should also be a
conversation because I actually think
what matters a little bit more about
whether or not you give them access to
it or not is uh, do you give them good
information so they can make good
choices and do you set clear boundaries
and stick to them and I think those are
hard. Uh, so our responsibility as a
platform is to make sure that things are
safe even if a parent does that. But I
strongly encourage parents to consider
those two things and we try to find ways
to support them in doing that by
building tools for them, educational
materials for them and outreach to them
like the marketing you saw. Yeah.
Because especially I feel like there's a
sort of a group pressure you know when I
was in high school that was like a time
you know you had Facebook, you had
Instagram but it was not as big as
today. Um, I remember like Snapchat for
example was a big thing and uh high
school I I was old enough but like in in
like before that you had some you know
this sort of group pressure of like oh
you're not on Facebook or like oh you
should be on Facebook and like I can
imagine like discussions with like
parents who are like you know they're
like no you won't have Facebook today
and at the time kids would be like yeah
but everyone has it I'm not the I'm the
only one not having that's what makes it
the hardest is your kid comes and they
tell you everybody else has an iPad
everybody else has plays Minecraft.
Everybody else uses Instagram. Why can't
I? And one, they may not be be telling
you the truth. My kids lie to me all the
time. Um, but it makes it much more
difficult as a parent um to say no. But
I think I mean I say this my family, my
boys all the time. All they're all boys.
Um I'm like different family, different
rules. Um and that's hard. I know. Um
but it's I feel like it's my job as a
dad. And coming back to those some of
those issues and questions. Um, one
thing we've heard a lot about is all the
questions about like anxiety and like
body image issues like how do you see
yourself by looking at others on social
media? Um, especially like uh among
younger people but not only um how do
you see this question as a head of of
Instagram and how especially you know
we've talked about AI, we've talked
about those things. We know that like it
can help like change a face or like just
make it perfect uh in a way. um how do
you navigate through this question? And
just to add some context here, back in
2021, the Wall Street Journal revealed
that Meta knew through its own internal
research that Instagram could harm young
people's self-image and mental health.
One internal study showed that one in
three teenage girls who already had body
image issues said that Instagram made
them feel worse. If you follow the
channel, you know that we covered this
story several times. That one's a m one
of the trickiest. Um, so there what
we're really talking about is social
comparison, comparing yourself to
others. And by the way, there's two
types. There's negative social
comparison and positive social
comparison. If I look up to a role model
and I emulate their good behavior, that
is positive social comparison. Um, but
if I am looking at an unrealistic, you
know, definition of beauty and I feel
bad about myself, that's a negative
social comparison. And there's nothing
more human than comparing yourself to
other people. And so, both are going to
happen offline and online. But there,
it's very difficult for us to know when
it's healthy and when it's not. I'll
give you an example. I've had a number
of friends who have really struggled to
become pregnant. Um, I got one friend in
particular that I'm thinking of right
now. uh lost a number of pregnancies uh
to miscarriages. So for her, and I
talked to her about this using
Instagram, when she saw someone else
post pictures of their new beautiful
baby child and how excited they were and
the nursery and the clothes, etc., it
was incredibly triggering and upsetting
for her. It was negative social
comparison. Now, for you looking at that
same photo, it might not be problematic.
Probably wasn't problematic at all. For
me, it wasn't. And for the platform,
there's no way to know.
So there that's one of the reasons why
it's particularly tricky. Um so we've
tried to build some tools. I think the
most powerful is a bit of a um a big uh
tool that I don't recommend everybody
use, but if you end up in a negative
place, she my friend ended up in this
place where she had followed a bunch of
baby accounts and then lost the
pregnancy and her whole explore page was
all baby related content. So, she's in a
really bad spot now because we think
she's all into it and it's the worst
thing for her. You can do a full
Instagram recommendations reset. So, we
basically forget everything we know
about your interests and we start from
scratch. And so, you know, if she if she
used that tool, which this was years
ago, so it didn't exist yet, her her
explore would have been as if she had
just signed up for Instagram. It would
have had no baby content most likely.
Um, now if you or I use it right now,
it's going to make your Instagram much
worse. I'm not sure what you're into,
but we wouldn't know either if we if you
did that. And so it would just be very
generic um broad interests. Yeah. Cuz I
guess I mean the fact of being like like
looking at something that makes you feel
not good. It has always existed like you
know reading a newspaper like watching
television like you could have a content
that be like oh that's triggering
something with me that's not good
because I'm feeling this or that way.
But I guess the main difference is that
now with social media, you've got this
algorithm thing that means that if you
watch them something, even if it doesn't
make you feel good, you might get
another one, another one. And so I guess
that's if you interact with it
specifically. Yeah. So this is the
tension between what we I would call
first order and second order
preferences, right? So I might really
like looking at these sad videos of like
wounded
puppies getting rescued or something
like that. So I might always watch them,
but it's fundamentally making me sad.
But Instagram doesn't know it's making
me feel sad. It just sees that I'm
watching them, so it's showing me more.
So that's when things like the reset is
important. You can also say that you're
not interested in things. Yeah. You got
to think like interested or not
interested on each and actually
um
uh hidden gem maybe is in explore. If
you mark something as not interested,
you can long press to do that. Uh or
long press and go to the dot dot dot on
Android. It'll ask you if you want to do
others and you can do batch. So, you can
just select as many as you want in your
explore. Like just select like I don't
want this this this. I don't want any of
these, right? Um uh and that will also
help particularly if you don't want to
do a full reset. Uh but you're just like
I'm getting you think I'm interested in
I don't know pets and I'm not, you know,
you can just select all the pets you see
and hit no and hopefully we can figure
it out quickly. Interesting. So I feel
like that also I mean of course
Instagram and social media have all
those issues to like like get on but
like what I'm also understanding is the
fact that it's also a question of like
um awareness and like education like for
everyone to get to understand like how
social media works, how uh your content
is being pushed and like in what ways
you can sort of trigger the thing to
make a change in a way or another. Yeah.
And so I want to make sure that you
don't have to know about all of these
tools and these tricks and that the
experience for most everyone is not only
safe but positive and brings value to
your life. Um but I also know that it's
not you're never going to you know bat a
thousand to use an American expression
around baseball. And so you need to
build tools like this and then raise
awareness about those tools so that when
people inevitably end up in some
negative situations that there is some
way to get out of it. And so I want to
talk now about the algorithm itself.
It's always like the big question
everyone ask themselves. Um sometimes
there like questions sometimes some
myths around how they work. Lots of I
can't imagine. If I tap my heels three
times and I don't look at the likes for
the first 10 minutes, then everything
goes, the video will just work very
well. Um, so in 2025, what makes a post
work well on Instagram? What are like
the main, you know, factors, the main
thing that make a content work on
Instagram? So if you if you are I mean
in terms of what you're actually
creating it obviously depends on the
creator and the audience but in terms of
if you want to
evaluate what how well your content is
doing. The thing to look at to that sort
of gives you the best sense of if it did
well is its reach but the but that
doesn't tell you why right that's not
that useful. It's like oh I know it did
badly. I knew it did badly like thank
you for telling me that. Um so if you
want to understand why uh the three most
important things are uh sends per reach
or send rate. So basically take the
total number of sends and divide it by
the total reach, likes per reach, same
idea, and then average watch time if
it's a video. And so basically it
doesn't matter necessarily if it got 10,
50, or 5,000 sends. It matters more if
you know if we got 10 out of 20. 10 out
of 20 is way better than 5,000 out of a
million. Yeah. Um and that'll give you a
sense for why this was a sendable
um photo. This was a likable uh
carousel. This was a video that people
watched a lot. So the the average watch
time um those things are going to there
are other things that matter. Saves
matter. Comments matter. Do you tap on
the profile? Do you follow the profile
when you get there? But those three
matter the most. And I mean so those are
like questions maybe not everyone ask
themselves but as a content creator or
even like as a media it's some questions
you may have does like those things you
just talked about sends per view also
per reach. um you'd say it's more
important than um the format itself
because like for a while we were hearing
like oh now Instagram is a video
platform so you have to do reals and
stuff and sometimes and at the same time
we're doing other stuff too. How do you
see this question of formats? Is it
Yeah, they they intersect, right? So, it
turns out that reels tend to be more
engaging because there's sound on and
there's moving image. You kind of get
sucked in. You're more likely to like,
you're more likely to send it to a
friend. Uh, so they interact. Now,
that's not true for all reels. I can
create a really boring reel that'll
underperform an amazing photo that you
take. That's so it's not these aren't
universally true, but they are averages.
On average, reals are going to get more
engagement because they are more
engaging. We've tried to one be honest
about that. Two, help photos and
carousels be more engaging by adding
things like music. Um, by the way, music
can really help your reach cuz it just
catches your attention. Um, which is
kind of a great thing if you're trying
to get more reach. Oh, those are it's
really two things. Yeah. Um, and then
you should figure out what works for
you. Cuz as a creator, the most
important thing isn't what's going to
get you the most reach. Uh, reach of
course matters, but to what end? Are you
trying to build a brand? Are you trying
to sell me medin? Are you trying to
evangelize a cause? Are you trying to
pull together a community? Right? What's
the reach is a means to one of those
ends or different. And then so when you
come up with your content strategy, it
needs to align with that goal. It needs
to also do well on Instagram. So, be
engaging. And you also need to be able
to sustain it over time. It needs to be
realistic because if it's not one of
those things, you're going to fail. If
it's not aligned with your goal, and
yeah, it gets a ton of reach, but what's
the point? But if it's if it's aligned
with your goal and nobody interacts with
it, no one's going to see it, what's the
point? And if it's something that you
cannot do, it's you want to create 10
videos a day, you know, post every hour
of the day and you just can't do that. I
can't do that. Most nobody can do that.
um then then you're going to burn out.
And so it's hard, I know, but you need
to find a creative strategy that is at
the intersection of those three ideas.
And by the way, what works this year
might not work next year cuz people's
interests change. Uh so you, you know,
I've evolved. I've tried many different
things. I did a series of podcast
interviews and they just did terribly.
So I stopped doing that. This one will
work very well. No, no, no, no. I mean,
I was interviewing you. You are a much
better interviewer than me. No, no, see.
Yeah. You're just trying stuff. Yeah.
And like Instagram is a is a special
platform because you've talked about it
as a platform where you get friends and
like people connecting together, but
it's also a platform where you get some
media, some content creators,
celebrities. I guess like it's a is it
like for you like sometimes weird things
you get like on the same platform both
things and sometimes not the same. I
think it's but I think it's the magic of
it. So on one hand, yes. Broadly
speaking, I'll oversimplify. friend
content and public content can be
intention, right? Um, you know, if
you're watching a video about the news,
you're not actually talking to a friend,
but I don't think we're the best at
texting friends. You know, WhatsApp is
if I'm late, I'm going to text you on
WhatsApp. I'm not going to DM you uh for
like meeting today. And I don't think
we're the best at pure, you know,
leanback cons uh information
consumption. If you if I want to watch a
an hour long video, it's Netflix is
going to be even better than you
probably YouTube or Tik Tok. Um, but
what I think we do remarkably well and I
think we have an opportunity to be the
best at is connect with your friends
about your interests. I talk to people I
know in real life and some I've met
online about creators, about fashion,
about architecture, about uh football,
you know, you know, that's where it's
really special. We're like, yeah, I can
see the highlight from the Saka goal
last night. I'm an Arsenal fan. Sorry, I
know I'm here. That's good for you. You
got good good. Yeah, we're playing you
guys in two weeks. Um and but I'm
talking about that with the other Goonas
I know. That's kind of what's that's
kind of where our sweet spot is. Yeah.
So, it does make sense for you to get
both and I see how it would work this
way. Um, I've got one last question. Uh,
which is like kind of a broad question,
but how do you see, you know, Instagram
for the next few years? Do you have any
plan for like a long-term sort of like
five or 10 years or is it something that
goes, you know, evolves so rapidly that
you're like, oh no, two years away from
that is already kind of a long distance.
Two years is long distance for us. Um,
it's worth noting that right now in the
United States, there's an important
trial involving Meta. The American tech
giant is being accused of
anti-competitive practices, especially
for its acquisitions of Instagram and
WhatsApp. If the Federal Trade
Commission wins the case, Meta could be
forced to break up and sell some of its
platforms. So this trial hadn't started
yet at the time of the interview, but
it's an important topic that we'll be
talking about, so I just wanted to
mention it today. I mean, over the next
few years, I don't anticipate any major
changes, right? We we we're launching
the edits app, which I'm really excited
about. I think you'll see us lean more
into creative tools, and to AI for
creative tools. One idea I'm really
excited about that hopefully is coming
later this year is video editing. So,
not deep fakes that can make you make
something, say something, but um take,
you know, anybody editing a real should
be able to select any clip they want or
the whole reel and then ask for any
special effect that they want. Um, you
know, make the lighting match or add the
prop or make me wear a suit or whatever
it is to be able to story tell. But
longer term, five, 10 years, I think it
gets much harder to predict because for
a long time now, the primary way we
consume information is on these little
glowing rectangles. I don't know how how
many centimeters is 6 in. It's like, you
know, 14, 15. Um, and I think that will
change. I don't think phones are going
away. I think they'll be part of our
lives for the foreseeable future. But I
think some of our information
consumption is going to shift to
something that looks more like this. And
you're seeing this right now with two
ends of the spectrum. The simplest with
the Rayban Metas, which by the way,
we're selling millions of them. And
they're they've got AI, they've got a
camera, but they also have a microphone
and a speaker. They're great for phone
calls, podcasts. I use that for all the
time. Um, but they don't have a screen
and they have limited capabilities,
limited battery. And then on the other
end of the spectrum, you know, we've got
these Orion glasses that we don't make
and sell because they would cost€ 10,000
euros each, which would be ridiculous,
but they're a research project where you
can literally you have a screen built
in, but they look like these glasses and
I can control the operating system with
my hands. Um, and that's kind of a wild
thing. Those are going to come together
and when they do, they're going to be a
lot of people who use them. Is that in 5
years? Is that in 10 years? Is that in
15 years? cuz it needs to not only work
but be light and comfortable and
fashionable and cheap. I don't know. But
what does Instagram mean if part of
Instagram is connecting with friends?
And a lot of way people talk is with
glasses is an is a question I don't have
an answer to yet. That's interesting
because you sometimes get like even when
I do interviews about my work with my
team, people like, "Oh, so where do you
see yourself in 10 years?" And I'm like,
"I don't Oh, and the thing is like if
social media like if platforms like you
don't know where where you'll be in 10
years, there's no way for me to know
either because of course we're
publishing uh on those on those
platforms. Adam, thank you so much for
taking the time. This was such a
pleasure. I really appreciate it. Thank
you so much. I mean, we covered like a
wide range of topics and I hope like
yeah, it'll be interesting for people
who yeah follow this. It would be great.
So yeah, thank you so much for for
taking the time and thank you for
following this uh this interview. Uh you
can of course subscribe if it's not the
case to see the other the other
interviews. You can also follow us of
course on Instagram. Uh we get we do
quite quite a lot of things today too.
And so yeah, we'll see you soon. Thank
you again so much Adam for taking the
time. Cheers. Thank you.
[Music]