Hey everybody. Hi. What's up? I'm Praa.
Thank you so much for watching Mostly
Sane. Anytime you kind of get one of
these opportunities where you're like,
"Hey, Praa, do you want to sit down with
Adam and talk to him?" And you're going
to be like, "Oh my god, yes." He's the
one person you want to go to with every
question you would ever have about
Instagram, which is an app that you've
been obsessed with for a decade now. And
then you sit down with him and then
suddenly you're like, "What do you ask
someone like Adam about Instagram?" You
know, it's one of those. First of all,
I'm going to say hi. Hi. Welcome. Thanks
for having me. I know we've barely had
you here any times so far, but have we
been nice to you? Yeah, it's been great.
It's been great. I've been to India a
number of times, but not not in about 6
years. So, it's been a while. Oh, a lot
has changed in 6 years, especially
online because I think the whole geo
revolution kind of took over and then
India became this mad mad place of the
price was for the data, one of the
lowest costs of data in the world and
then we've just seen an explosive growth
of Instagram over the last and it's
available everywhere. Every time I
travel outside of India, I'm so grateful
for the network services that we have
back home because you could go to like
the smallest towns and villages and
you'll have all bars there. Yeah. And
then sometimes I'm just getting out of
the subway like Yeah. But six, seven
years ago was not like that. It was not
like that. A lot has changed. So I want
to ask you how does it look to you right
now when you're sitting with access to
literally look at everything across
markets. How does India look to
Instagram right now? Uh it's our largest
market at this point. And if you look at
the number of people who use Instagram,
the overall amount of time spent on
Instagram, it's just been amazing. And
so, um, it has gone from like an
important market to one of our very most
important markets really, really
quickly. I also realized that because I
started creating content in 2015. Thank
you.
Hey, we were just posting pictures
there. It's okay. That's all you could
do back then. Yeah. But um, I remember a
very significant shift happening. So I
would have friends who were working in
like marketing firms and agencies and
places where these influencer marketing
budgets would be made right and I
remember in the beginning they were like
praa we're working with like 4% dude
like 4% of our entire budget is going to
go for this so like can you do it for
like cheaper or can we try to do a
parter with you I remember these were
conversations and now
not too many years later the
conversations have actually gone up to
like 80% of our budget is now just
digital or like all of it is just now
digital. So with the influx of money
that has come in, it's also not just the
consumers that have gone up, but also
the creators that have gone up.
Absolutely. Like the consumption that's
happening at this point, especially on a
platform like Instagram, is crazy. So as
someone who is working with something
that's changing so quickly, how do you
manage this? How do you map these
changes? I mean I think the thing for us
that's really important is that we are
always open to evolving and evolving
quickly because you know Instagram has
always been about connecting you with
your friends and uh inspiring or
empowering creative people but how
people connect with friends how they
create how they entertain themselves has
changed a lot and the biggest risk for
us is that the world changes faster than
we can adapt and we just slowly become
irrelevant. Uh so you know at times
sometimes we change things too quickly
and we get you know yelled at for it and
rightly so. Um but in general I think
it's it is super important for us to
lean into that because the alternative
is to just um become irrelevant. And
it's so for a lack of a better term
creepy. I'll tell you why. I listen to a
lot of audio books. Okay. Okay. And I
always listen to them on 2x speed. Yeah.
I'm always like okay get to the point. I
literally have I can only handle 1.5. 2x
makes me nervous. Really? Yeah, it
depends on the reader though. Some
people read faster, some people read
slower. Yeah, but like audio books are
sometimes just really slow. Audio is
usually the same. The books are usually
slow. The podcasters are fine. Yeah. I
also watch my content on 1.5x all the
time because I love binge watching stuff
and if I don't watch it on 1.5x, I don't
get to consume enough. Do you use reals
at 2x? Yeah. So I want to tell you which
is why I was over the moon
when I found out that I can watch brand
new. Yes. And I didn't know. Yeah. Okay.
Because there was no like announcement
that was made. No. Just quiet. Yeah.
There was a real that came up saying hey
did you know that if you long press
above the heart Yeah. Yeah. And I tried
doing that and I have never been
happier. So thank you so much for giving
into my obsession. All right. All right.
even more where so something like that
which is such a minute detail in a
consumer's behavior how do you map like
this or is it just intuitive for you uh
I mean it's a mixture of things we talk
to a lot of people who use the product
um we look at you know you know the data
so how are they using it but we just
talk to the people in person and do
research we travel around the world
doing so uh we get lots of inbound
feedback I get a lot in my DMs by
request oh yeah they're a little a
little Hey, Adam, here's a suggestion.
Yeah. Yeah. My birthday. It's my
birthday. All I want is a blue check
mark. And you know, it's one of my most
common DMs. Does it work? No. Just
checking for a frame. Yeah. Yeah.
Exactly. So, you know, you you get a ton
of feedback and the trick is how do you
sift through it all and find the signal
amongst the noise and then try to make
things better every every week. You
know, I I was so tempted to message
Instagram about this because while I am
doom scrolling,
there's this whole thing right now
saying, "Wait for part two." And then if
it's a page that I'm not following, I
have to go to that page and then keep
scrolling to find part two. So, I wanted
to check, can we not have like a search
bar? Oh, yeah. No, we should make search
easier. search needs to work at the
Instagram level first really well and
then we can make it work better on this
sort of specific yeah like specific
profiles where I could just go to reels
and search part two of this candle
making they might have like 19 part twos
I mean we're always going to hack the
algorithm in some way or the other but I
just I just feel like no we should do
profile search for sure right it'll just
feed more into it's more just useful
it's just like you you when you want to
find that thing then you can't remember
it was and it happened to be like 30
posts ago it's is annoying. Yeah. Okay.
Okay. Good. Okay, that said there. So, I
didn't have to slide into DMs for Okay,
cool. Thank you very much. Now, as a
creator myself, my two biggest platforms
are YouTube and Instagram. That's where
I earn my money from. That's how I pay
my bills. That's where I go to form my
content and I happen to be in a position
where I love doing my job because these
two platforms are so dynamic constantly
and work so well with creators.
Especially in a country like India where
we have a very quick ascend when it
comes to the number of people joining
the platform as creators. Is there
something you want newer people joining
today to know as creators? I don't know
if this is specific to newer creators,
but if you're just getting into it, I
think even if you or if you've been
doing it for a while, I think one of the
most important things is to make sure
you're intentional about finding the
overlap between what's going to work on
the platform, but what is also aligned
with your goals. I think if you create
content that does really well, but it's
not aligned with your goals, then why
are you doing it? And if it's aligned
with your goals and it doesn't resonate
with an audience, then it's not going to
reach anyone. And so, again, why are you
doing it? So, you need to find a content
strategy that does both. Cuz reach is
great, but reach is a means to an end,
right? Are you trying to uh get brand
deals? Are you trying to sell a specific
product? Are you trying to evangelize a
cause? Are you trying to mobilize a
community or create a community? You
know, depending on what you're trying to
do. Yeah. Have the objective clear.
Yeah. Make So, be very clear about
putting pen to paper on your objective
and then explore different and try
different ways of creating content that
will align with that objective. but will
also hopefully resonate with an
audience. I like that you say that
because I always find that a lot of
people kind of start creation thinking
that we'll figure it out on the way
because that's how I have done it. But
the more I create, the more I realize
that there has to be some kind of a
direction that you have in mind when
you're going forward with it because
only then can you use the platform to
its fullest potential. Exactly. And and
it's not that what you do won't change.
Of course it will. But that goal
hopefully will stay the same at least
for you know periods of long periods of
time. Yeah. Now there's so much that
comes with Instagram, right? Like you
download Instagram and then there's the
feed where you have the posts, then you
have the reals, then you have the notes,
then you have your stories, then you
have threads. What do you recommend? Is
everything working in tandem a good way
for your profile to move forward? You
don't have to use everything as a
creator. If um they you can um different
tools are good for different things.
stories is a really great way to show
behind the scenes, bit more authentic, a
bit more frequent. Uh whereas, you know,
broadcast channels are a great way to
reach your most passionate following.
You're going to reach less people, but
they're going to go directly to your in
their inbox. So, it just depends on what
you're trying on those goals. Got it.
But one of the things you have to think
about too, and this I think of as being
aligned with your goals, but you could
frame it as being sustainable, is you
have to pick a strategy that you can
keep doing. If you think the best
strategy is to post a real every day, 10
stories a day, a broadcast channel
update and like a feed post and you just
can't produce that much content, then
it's not the best strategy. It's not
sustainable. So, pick the ones that
prioritize. Pick the ones that are most
aligned with your goals and then don't
do the other ones. That's okay. Got it.
Also, there is so much shift that
happens in consumption, right? Like I
remember a very clear shift happening in
2020 when we were actually sat down and
told, "Okay, you're going to have to now
concise your 8 minute YouTube videos
into 15-second reels." And that was the
most daunting thing for us as creators.
I remember fighting it for so long to
actually huge change. I actually started
enjoying it. And now I'm in a place
where as much as I want to write and
produce long form content, I really do
enjoy short form.
But as a creator, I feel like I also
need to be prepared for this wave to
take another term where U-turn where you
never know if long form just comes back.
Is there a way that creators can kind of
find a balance between predicting this
but also not preempting it? I I think
it's tough because I don't think any of
us really know where the world's going
to go in 5 or 10 years, but I do think
that there are some broad trends. um
some of them. I mean, I do think we're
we're still going to see short form
video continue to grow. Um it's also
expanding off of phones and onto tablets
and TVs and the rest of that. Connected
TV is becoming more and more important.
But I think what's really going to be
interesting is in 10 years when we
don't, yes, we still have phones, but we
spend a lot of other time using other
devices that probably look more like
these. Um then like a lot's going to
change. Speaking of in 10 years, how is
Instagram working with AI? What are
consumers, creators to look forward to?
I'm there's a lot of stuff, but what I'm
most excited about is AI as a tool for
creators to be able to tell their
stories and more people be able to tell
more stories and better stories
efficiently. Efficiently, but some some
of it might just be a little bit as
straightforward as um translations. It's
like if you don't speak the language of
a country, that doesn't mean they're not
interested in your content. So, if we
could help translate videos, sound like
you, look like you, but have it actually
be in a local language that could help
creators reach a broader audience in
markets that weren't accessible before.
Uh, so even some more straightforward
features like that could be really,
really exciting. You know, one of my
favorite quotes around AI is, I need AI
to do my dishes and laundry so I can do
art. I don't need AI to do my art so I
have to do dishes and laundry. And I
think that's such a beautiful way of
looking at this new tool that comes with
so many kind of uncertainties. Yeah. And
concerns. So what and concerns? What is
the lens that you sitting at the
position that you are at where you have
the power to kind of mold and shape it
into what you want your consumers to
use? How do you look at that when it
comes to what's coming for us? Well, I
think for us at Instagram, there's
really two sides to it, right? There's
what tools do we want to create? you
know, translating videos, helping
creators do any visual effects that they
want on any video that they want. But
then there's also all the AI tools that
aren't going to that are inevitably
going to be used to create content that
then comes into Instagram, but they
weren't created on Instagram. I think
the key thing for me is that content
that is generated by AI is labeled as
such. So, you know, whether or not um it
AI was used to create it. doesn't mean
you should trust it or shouldn't trust
it, but it should be a piece of
information that you consider. Um, and
so how do we create tools to label stuff
appropriately? Uh, and then when we're
making tools, our first party tools, how
do we empower creatives? Because that's
really what Instagram's all about is
trying to empower creative people to
tell their stories. Love that. So many
of us who started off I mean for me I
remember one of my I wouldn't say
fondest memories but one of my first
memories of using Instagram was I was so
obsessed with the filters and everything
that all the crazy borders. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. 2012 12 no 11. Yeah. Yeah.
2011 where I remember that my goal was
that I want to click and upload a
picture in every class. I was in college
at that time. Every class while I'm in
class. I I was that hooked to it. And
this one time I got caught and then the
teacher wasn't very happy with it or
whatever. But that became my thing where
I was like ooh like it's lame now that
you think about it. But in my hair was
very cool when I was in college. But I
was like every class I attend I'm going
to upload a picture from there. Um I
started off like that. Now when I scroll
down my feed, I see where I started,
where I've reached in the past 10 years.
A lot of us did that. A lot of us
started with just like, oh, look at what
I'm eating for breakfast. And now it's
way beyond that. So how does Instagram
as a platform look at this journey that
creators like me have from just posting
to actually becoming businesses where
now it's a model that like I said helps
us pay our bills. It's a brand that we
kind of build. It has given me
opportunities that I have lost count of
and I'm very aware of that for so for
something as lucrative as that. How does
Instagram look at creators doing this? I
mean, we want to we want to support
that, right? I think the the more that
we can help creators reach an audience
and tell their stories uh in ways that
allow them to make a living or
supplement their living. Um I think for
us the better, right? So you know
whether we you know we've tried a lot of
things around um paying creators
directly around facilitating deals with
brands and direct response advertisers
from creating products that allow fans
to pay creators through things like
subscriptions and digital gifts. Um that
we we want to make sure that the
economic side of the creator ecosystem
is strong uh so that the creative side
can be strong because uh there's only so
much you can do if it's just a side
hobby or it's only something you do
while you're in school. Yeah. Also, I'm
very excited to know is there anything
that India as a market has done that has
been new or different? Because I I
always feel like we're a very different
bunch of people. Yeah, it's definitely
it's definitely different. Has has
anything just really peaked where you
you're always sitting on your reports
and they're like, "Huh, how was this
working in India?" It was something like
that. Not that crazy, but in general, um
I mean, there's a lot of people use it.
They use it more. They're much more
videoheavy and they message a lot more
too. Uh just kind of like more creative,
more expressive,
uh more passionate. Okay. So, good.
Yeah. Yeah. All right. No, but we're
very happy and we wanted to tell you
that thank you so much for doing this.
Thank you so much for sitting down and
answering questions that I had for you.
Uh but it's one of my favorite places to
create. We appreciate everything. I've
been doing that for so long and I've had
great partners who work here who have
helped me through so much. Um, not just
that but just the crossber
collaborations just going above and
beyond organic reach or just seeing the
potential of what any piece of content
can do on Instagram is mindblowing and
very very motivating for a creator like
me. So, thank you so much for giving us
a product that actually works. Thank you
so much. The creative energy from people
like you is what makes Instagram work.
We're very happy to be here. But thank
you, Adam. This was fun. Thanks so much
for doing this. Um, and yeah, I think
that's it. If you like this video,
please follow on Instagram @ mostly sane
and subscribe to my YouTube channel.
Bye-bye.