Feeling good?
&gt;&gt; Yeah. You?
&gt;&gt; I think so.
&gt;&gt; Hey, what's up, people of the internet?
Welcome back to a bonus episode of the
Waveform Podcast. In this episode, I'm
going to be sitting down and
interviewing one-on-one the CEO of
Instagram, Adam Seri. This is a really
interesting interview. I'm coming at it
from the perspective of a creator. I
upload to a bunch of different
platforms, which I'm totally transparent
about. You guys know me as a YouTuber,
but I also make shorts and I make
Instagram content and then also Tik Tok
stuff here and there. And so I do have a
lot of thoughts on each individual
platform. And I thought it would be
interesting to ask him some of my
questions about how Instagram has come
to be what it is today, where it came
from, where they're going into the
future, and pay careful attention to the
way he answers the same question both at
the beginning of the interview about
what Instagram is and at the end of the
interview because it's a different
answer. And I think it's really
interesting to see the framing and the
way we talk about the platform. And yes,
we talk about paying creators, too. So
stay tuned for all of that. Without any
further ado, here's your bonus episode
interviewing the CEO of Instagram, Adam.
&gt;&gt; All right, Adam, thanks for joining me.
&gt;&gt; Thanks for having me.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I appreciate the time. Okay, so
you're the CEO of Instagram and and I'm
a creator. I I work on a bunch of
different platforms. I know what I think
Instagram is, but it'll be cool hearing
your own words. What is Instagram today?
&gt;&gt; So, it's changed a lot. Um I for for
better or for worse, I got a lot of
feedback and I think that's
fundamentally a good thing. Um, but at
the heart of what we do has always been
to try to bring people together over
creativity. You know, we started out by
making it so that anybody with an idea
could make a photo that they were having
that they were confident sharing with
those pretty intense filters and
borders.
&gt;&gt; Remember them?
&gt;&gt; Yeah. No, it's pretty pretty pretty
opinionated in retrospect.
&gt;&gt; Um, but how people connect with their
friends has changed. How they
communicate has changed. How they
entertain themselves has changed. And so
we've had to evolve. Um, but at the
heart has always been these two ideas of
connecting with the people you care
about over your interests.
&gt;&gt; Connecting with the people you care
about. I mean, it's a social network
obviously, but it it has both
chronological and algorithmic ways of
sharing stuff with you, sharing stuff
between people. Um, and there's a lot of
features that have been added on top
over the years, which is why I wonder
how you think about how to add a new
feature to Instagram. You probably get
tons of suggestions and ideas about
things to add, things not to add. Yes.
&gt;&gt; If things are removed, exactly. What's
your filter like? How do you decide
like, okay, we were just photos this
many years ago. Now it's all these
things. How do you decide what to add to
Instagram?
&gt;&gt; I think if it's it has to be connected
to, you know, creativity or connecting
people. Um, but then it also has to be
something that is going to be cared
about or we think used by enough people
that it'll matter because obviously the
app is getting more and more
complicated. I think we need to do more
to actually simplify things and collapse
some of the patterns into less patterns.
Um, but we also have to evolve. The
biggest risk of any platform of our
scale is that the world changes and we
failed to adapt and we slowly become
irrelevant. People think of Instagram as
a feed of square photos with those
borders.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; You know, but if you look at the last 10
years, you know, if we didn't have
stories, if we didn't have DMs, if we
didn't have reals,
&gt;&gt; we wouldn't be talking today. uh we
wouldn't be an important enough platform
to really be a platform that you focused
on. And so we've had to figure out how
to evolve um and try to stay true to
those principles and then try to also
keep the app simple. Sometimes we do
better or worse at one or the other.
&gt;&gt; Sounds like a balancing act because I
mean keeping it simple is on one end of
the spectrum and keeping up with all the
competition and all the evolving things
happening in the world is another.
&gt;&gt; Yes.
&gt;&gt; Are you leaning towards one end or the
other? I mean you have a lot of
competition now.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I make videos on five platforms
that accept video uploads. Like how do
you think about
&gt;&gt; more and more creat? Yeah. And I used to
never do that but you know that's a
slightly different language that I speak
to each of those audiences.
&gt;&gt; Different audiences.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; So depending on the year we'll focus
more on building new things or
simplifying. But in general my bias is
going to be to make sure that we are
taking risks. I think that what happens
a lot with large companies is they
slowly go down hitting their goals the
whole way down. And I would much rather
look back at 5 10 years of working on
the app and have a couple examples of
where we pushed too hard or went too
fast and it kind of um we got some
blowback for it then the alternative
which I see is primarily like you never
upset anybody but you also didn't evolve
fast enough and you just matter a lot
less.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So, I'm going to bias and I think
we as a culture at Instagram bias
towards trying to take some bigger bets
and trying to take on some risk and
sometimes they will pan out and
sometimes they will be painful.
&gt;&gt; Fair enough. I I definitely feel like
that applies in a lot of different
genres. It applies as a creator. If I
just do the same thing over and over,
I'll be happy because I'm achieving the
goal of doing the same thing, but I'll
probably get left behind. And in other
product categories, that's the same
thing. Like you can make the same
product over and over but then your
competition will pass you.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; U but when you think about those risks
you know there are some that you decide
not to take obviously and there are some
that you decide are worth the challenge
of like p pushing yourself forward.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Is there some sort of filter you run
through to decide like okay this would
be cool but I don't think it's the right
direction for Instagram.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. There's a couple different things.
One thing I talk about a lot internally
with my team is like it it it needs to
matter. And for for something to matter,
it either has to be like novel and
interesting or it has to actually like
meaningfully move the app forward or the
business forward. If it's a small
change, but it's not interesting, it's
not novel and it's not going to really
change how people use the app, then it's
probably just noise. Uh it also has to
be connected to what we do. Like I like
we're going to for instance, you know,
I'm sure we'll talk about AI today.
We're going to try to figure out in what
ways AI can help empower creators,
empower creatives, connect people as
opposed to all the other things that AI
can also do. So it has to be connected
to our mission and our reason to exist.
Um, but you also have to decide how many
like so like I'll give you an example
that's maybe a little bit less obvious
from the outside. Usually we're talking
about how many you know we're talking
more about how many new features to
build. But when you're one of the most
important things about Instagram is how
ranking works. Mhm.
&gt;&gt; And there's a couple, you could call
them bets that we are making that don't
maximize the amount of time people spend
on Instagram or revenue we make or
engagement that we have. So we focus a
lot for instance on originality. Making
sure that we try and drive as much
traffic or distribution to the original
content creator versus an aggregator.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; That actually leaves engagement and
revenue on the table. But the bet is
over time you will build more of a
rapport with the creative community and
that that'll benefit in some indirect
way over years.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Timeliness. Similarly, if you want to be
culturally relevant, things need to
break quickly. But sometimes you're
going to drive more engagement by
showing something that was really funny
that's 5 days old.
&gt;&gt; Yep.
&gt;&gt; So, how many of those bets can you take
on at once is another thing that we have
to juggle.
&gt;&gt; Interesting. And I think what a lot of
people also wonder is how much of that
comes from meta. Obviously, you're a
part of Meta, but to some degree
independent. How much of this comes from
Meta's goals and Meta's decision-making
in budgets versus like what Instagram
independently thinks that they should be
doing?
&gt;&gt; It's a balance uh depending on the year,
but in general, there are a few ways in
which we try to make sure we're
supporting the broader company. We also
try to make sure that we're leveraging
all of the good work and technology from
the people across the company. So we
build on their infra build on meta's
infrastructure. It's meta's ad system.
We use meta's safety technologies. Um
but then try to also carve out our own
space right we're more focused on
creative expression particularly visual
creative you know threads which we also
work on is more focused on ideas and
perspectives. Um Facebook is more of a
social marketplace for all things. So we
try to make sure that we are cognizant
of the rest of the company when they
when there are ways for us to contribute
back that we do but that we don't lose
sight of um what our own identity is.
&gt;&gt; So in 2022,
&gt;&gt; okay,
&gt;&gt; I tweeted about how there should be an
iPad app for Instagram.
&gt;&gt; And you may remember this because you
replied to this.
&gt;&gt; I do remember
&gt;&gt; and I I remember reading that reply. I
don't know if I have it exactly in front
of me, but it was clearly not a priority
at the time. There was not
&gt;&gt; um there is one now.
&gt;&gt; There is
&gt;&gt; what changed?
&gt;&gt; So I mean a couple different things. One
is in general we always wanted to build
one but it wasn't the next most valuable
thing we thought we could do with our
time. Two is I think that we saw an
opportunity to try and lean into where
we think Instagram is going over time.
So, you know, more and more of Instagram
time spent is watching short videos,
watching realels.
&gt;&gt; Um, people it's they're actually some
they're actually pretty social. People
send reels to their friends all the time
and start conversations.
&gt;&gt; That's where the iPad app starts now.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So, the idea was in a world where
messaging and reals are driving our
growth, how could we reorient the app
more around those concepts? And then if
you look at how people consume video,
it's usually they consume video less
times per day than other things, but for
longer each time. So less sessions a
day, longer duration per session.
&gt;&gt; Okay?
&gt;&gt; And that's also the shape of tablet
usage. People use tablets less times per
day, but longer per time than their
phone, for instance. So, we thought it
would also be an interesting opportunity
to try a real's first version of the app
um without all of the challenges that
come along with moving people from one
version of the experience to another.
&gt;&gt; I I kind of wonder if that was it
because you they've tested a real first
version of the app in some other places,
but this was a new version of the app.
So, it's not like people on the iPad are
switching from feed to reals.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Um,
&gt;&gt; they're switching from if you had it
like the tiny little mobile phone
version.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Um, and it's interesting also
that, you know, I was asking for an app
for an iPad and I I wonder how much you
listen to user feedback about what they
hope to see in Instagram or what they
wish would come back from old Instagram
or whatever it is. As a creator, I deal
with this all the time. I have to have a
filter for like, okay, I know people
will always want the old thing, but I
have to have a balance of moving forward
as well, like you talked about. Do you
listen to or factor in a lot of user
like like verbal feedback like Adam
bring back this Adam stop doing this?
Are you listening to that at all?
&gt;&gt; For sure. I mean I get into my comments.
I get into my DMs. I get into that
requests folder on a weekly basis
&gt;&gt; and I try to find the signal uh and try
to not get overly focused on the noise.
&gt;&gt; But I also try to understand what's the
root thing someone's asking for. Um, so
sometimes you're asking for a specific
feature, but there's like a thing that
Instagram isn't as good at that it used
to be, you know, at a lower level and
then where I can where we can meet that
need in some other way without inventing
yet a new thing or going backwards, we
try and do that. But I do think it's
also just true that what works changes.
I mean, actually curious for you
&gt;&gt; um cuz I've even experienced this on cuz
I actually post on Instagram, you know,
so I get a little bit of um empathy for
what it's like to try to be successful
on the platform.
&gt;&gt; Okay.
&gt;&gt; Uh I actually had my my followers start
to decline like a year and a half ago
and I was like, "Okay, I got to rethink
&gt;&gt; the investigation."
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Yeah. But so for you like have you
found that certain things sure people
are asking for you know the version from
a couple years ago but have you found
that certain constructs or series you do
stopped working and you needed to
reinvent them?
&gt;&gt; I think in the past a little bit more. I
think now the priority for me has been
to abandon something before it trickles
out and dies. Yeah.
&gt;&gt; So we have series that we do. We have
like almost recurring videos every year.
You know, I'm going to unbox the new
iPhone and review the new iPhone.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; At some point, eventually, we're going
to move on from that type of video, and
I want to be ahead of that rather than
behind it.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Like a TV show getting out before
it gets
&gt;&gt; before you get cancelled for not having,
you know, the things people looking
forward to. But it is interesting. And I
also think yeah there's some amount of
noise where you know I I hear people in
the comments asking for certain things
but I have to sort of interpret read
between the lines and understand what
they really want is something more
fundamental.
&gt;&gt; Um what's the new Instagram iPad app
now? What's the new most commonly asked
for feature that is simply not a
priority right now?
&gt;&gt; Oo that's a really good question. So the
most requests I get aren't for new
features. They're like verify me.
&gt;&gt; Uh it's my birthday is my favorite
version of that. It's my birthday. All I
want for my birthday is a blue check
mark.
&gt;&gt; Interesting.
&gt;&gt; I get that a lot.
&gt;&gt; Uh a lot of people who disagree with
content decisions. If some content was
taken down and they feel like they're
censored, we want to make sure that we u
provide feed um recourse there. What's a
feature that's asked for for that that's
not a priority right now?
&gt;&gt; I know a lot of I see a lot of people
saying prioritize photos again.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; And I just feel like obviously that's
where Instagram came from.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; But it may feel feel like it's going
backwards. There's a lot of photos first
creators who feel like they're being
left behind by focusing on reals a lot.
&gt;&gt; But we've tried, particularly with
carousels and being able to add music to
photos and music to carousels to give
people who don't want to make reals a
way to still create content that's going
to be engaging. We're not trying to push
video because we have some interest in
video. Actually, video in a lot of ways
is not great for our business.
&gt;&gt; If you watch one video, um, you probably
could have seen a few different photos.
So the number of ads you're going to see
per hour is going to go down. So we call
that monetization efficiency. But the so
the reason why we're leaning to video is
not because it's, you know, we have some
like thing for video. It's because
that's what's driving engagement. That's
what's driving pulling people away from
Instagram to other video platforms. And
if we want to stay relevant, we need to
do that. So the question with photos is
not everyone's going to be able to make
videos. Making videos isn't easy. You
probably know that better than anyone.
How can we make well how can we make
making videos easier but also how can we
make photos more engaging so that they
can compete in a video first world. Um
but most of the features are like much
smaller. They're like just weird broken
things that drive me nuts. Like if I add
you to a collection, we can have shared
collections now and you know it goes
into the DMs every time I save
something. I can't retroactively add
more people you know to that collection.
There's lots of little things like that
that drive me nuts.
&gt;&gt; Sure. Um, and so I'm constantly trying
to get those things.
&gt;&gt; So that was the big whale. Now it's just
&gt;&gt; that was the big whale. I mean, there's
other ones like, you know, people people
ask to go back to chrono feed. We have a
chrono feed. You can get there. We're
not going to make it the default.
&gt;&gt; Uh, so maybe that's maybe the most
requested, but that's actually a very
loud but relatively small percentage of
people.
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
&gt;&gt; Um, but that one is I do get a lot too.
Um, but that one I think we've sort of
found the balance there. But people ask
for more power. They ask for a lot of
power features. Like I want to be able
to not see any photos from my high
school friends above their kids. And
it's like, okay.
&gt;&gt; Well, it's interesting you say that
because there's this new feature that
you've started talking about that I just
got access to 25 minutes ago.
&gt;&gt; Oh, really?
&gt;&gt; I haven't really fully dived in yet, but
I would love to hear you explain it
because giving users control is a very
risky thing to do. It
&gt;&gt; and many don't even pretend to want to
do it.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Uh, but there's a new feature
where you'll be able there's no name
yet. You tune your algorithm
essentially.
&gt;&gt; Explain what it is first of all and then
why you figured this was something you
wanted to try to do.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So this was a meme on threads
about two years ago almost now called
dear algorithm and people just wrote
these letters
&gt;&gt; asking for things that were very sort of
bespoke like that example from before
&gt;&gt; and it was but it's clear that you know
people want more control over the
experience and I think that makes sense
and a world where more and more of not I
mean look what the the primary people
actually share on Instagram is not even
through feed or stories it's through DMs
so the connecting side is really healthy
on the on and direct messages. But in
terms of what they consume, more and
more of it is recommendations, content
from accounts that you do not yet
follow, particularly reals. And so in
that world where following still
matters, but matters less than it used
to. How can we give you more control
over the experience? And so we took a
look at that that meme and then we took
a look at some of the new um
opportunities that some of um some new
technologies and AI allow and we created
a way for you to actually see what we
think that you're interested in.
&gt;&gt; I saw that I got that far.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, you got that far.
&gt;&gt; So I got I hit the button and I saw the
eight or nine top topics that it thinks
I'm interested in.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, it's not comprehensive. It's the
top ones. Okay, that's funny cuz the
number one one is like the model name of
a car that I've been looking at for
years, which makes perfect sense. Uh, so
I shouldn't be shocked that it knows
that about me, but it is funny that it's
gotten that just from how essentially
how I've engaged with content that's
been recommended to me.
&gt;&gt; Yes.
&gt;&gt; Okay.
&gt;&gt; And then you can add topics cuz maybe
you're into something that we don't know
you're into.
&gt;&gt; And then you can um add things that you
would not like to see. Um, so you could
just be like, I'm not interested in
American football or I'm not interested
in politics or whatever it happens to
be.
&gt;&gt; Um, the thing that it doesn't support
yet that I'm really excited about is the
ability to see something that we think
you're into and for you to override us.
So, for instance, you could be like, you
know, I don't know, maybe maybe you were
all into
um March Madness and then your team lost
in the first round and you're just like,
I really don't want to be pummeled with
March Madness for the next four weeks.
&gt;&gt; So, you can pop it out. Um there's lots
of examples like that where we might
misinterpret
um a signal as that you're interested in
and it might be more that it's like
upsetting you or that it was interesting
to you a week ago but isn't now
&gt;&gt; or I was hate watching it and I really
just wish it would stop showing up so I
could stop hate watching.
&gt;&gt; Hate watching is a thing. Uh this isn't
hate watching but I have a friend who um
got stuck in this place where she saw
was constantly getting like videos of
like animals in like tough situations.
It's like kind of sad and like rescues
and like sometimes you don't know if
they get rescued or not.
&gt;&gt; It's kind of sad.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; And she but she couldn't help.
&gt;&gt; And so
&gt;&gt; like doom scrolling.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Yeah. So
&gt;&gt; um I actually for her um this because
this was a couple years ago. I was like
look we can you can just do a full
reset. I I don't recommend it but
&gt;&gt; for everybody because it's a big deal
but you can just be like forget
everything hard reset.
&gt;&gt; That's a button like an algorithmic
forget I said anything type button.
&gt;&gt; Yeah that exists.
&gt;&gt; Okay. Um, but this might be a nicer way
to do that because maybe she doesn't
want to have an Instagram that is much
less interesting. She just wants to get
rid of pets.
&gt;&gt; Interesting. What What is the riskiest
thing about this? Because I I I imagine
I mean there's Tik Tok. They've never
even pretended to want I mean I guess at
the beginning when I sign up they're
like give us your basic interest and
that's kind of the end of that.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; YouTube there's categories I can click
on, but my algorithm is just doing its
thing and I can feel it shifting when I
watch a little bit more podcast stuff or
when I watch a little bit more car
review stuff. What is the risky thing in
your head about giving users these
controls over their recommended stuff?
&gt;&gt; Two big things. One, we might mess up,
right? So, like we won't deliver. You'll
not get as much of the thing you ask for
or you'll say you don't want something
and you'll still get it at which point
you're going to rightfully point your
finger at us and that will happen,
right? We're not we do make mistakes um
particularly at scale. And the other is
that it'll be um less efficient uh at
you know driving engagement and driving
the business, right? Like showing you
what you ask for might mean you use
Instagram less than showing you what you
tend to interact with more.
&gt;&gt; Um or it might be there's a bunch of
ways in which it can get more more or
just spending time on making sure that's
working is an opportunity cost and we
could have we could spend that time
elsewhere making Instagram better in
some other way. Uh so those are very
real but I think we're going to a world
where this is possible at a level of
execution that it wasn't before
particularly because on the back end if
you look at how ranking has evolved over
the last five or plus years a lot of the
most advanced techniques have become
less and less human interpretable. So
we're like we're looking at these things
where we take videos and we map them
into this space that we call an
embedding and all these things are these
giant vectors and we can't even describe
why these seven videos are near each
other
&gt;&gt; just happen to be because of behavior.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. But then it turns out with some of
these new models we can be like oh
that's you know in your case you know a
specific type of car. Uh and make and so
we can so that allows us to do things
like not be like hey are you into sports
but you can be like no I'm into you know
I'm an Arsenal fan I want to I want to
see like the invincibles on re
highlights you know vintage you know you
know goals and we can go out and try and
get that for you.
&gt;&gt; Interesting. And also I wanted to ask if
you'd ever heard of this extremely
discreet theory about crustaceian
evolution. No. But
&gt;&gt; have you heard about how uh how it seems
like there's a bunch of crustaceations
are all evolving into lobsters or crabs
specifically because it seems to be the
ideal form. It's
&gt;&gt; the ideal form
&gt;&gt; for living under, you know, super high
pressure cold water.
&gt;&gt; No, but I'm into this.
&gt;&gt; So, it's interesting because I like
analogies and I like to take that and
look at it in other lenses.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; And sometimes it feels like products do
that. Yes. where they're all competing
with each other and trying to get better
and they're eventually just becoming the
same thing
&gt;&gt; whether or not it's the ideal thing
&gt;&gt; is there a possibility that social
networks are doing this where you are
running Instagram and in order to
compete as I've heard you say
&gt;&gt; uh you're adopting you know people are
obviously engaging with videos reals
things like that so we're going to do
more of that
&gt;&gt; maybe potentially losing the core of the
photos and the things that came
beforehand that brought people to
Instagram
&gt;&gt; is Is it possible that the competition
is all sort of getting at the same thing
in a way?
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I think you can make that argument
for sure. You we're all sort of
regressing to the mean. I mean, I think
so in some ways like we're trying to do
certain things differently. So, we're
trying to do reels differently by making
them more social, more friendly. You
know, things like that friends feed
inside of the reals tab where you can
see what your friends have interacted
with, leaning more in re-shares, etc.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. But it but it's also true that if
you take a big step back and you look at
all of social media, not only have the
apps become more and more similar, the
rate of convergence has increased.
&gt;&gt; So you look at you know uh like when did
each app introduce ranking and there was
like many years between like the first
app and the last app.
&gt;&gt; When did each app introduce stories?
There was a few years. I mean it was
popularized by Snapchat. It was invented
by cacao stories in Korea. Um but then
like every you know Pinterest even
YouTube x
everywhere. Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Uh and that was faster. When did we all
start leaning into mobile first video?
You know Tik Tok style, real style,
YouTube short style that happened faster
um recommendations faster. So I think
that the competition is fierce and as a
result there is a very real pressure to
borrow and steal ideas from the
competition that works. But you also
have to figure out how do you also stay
true to your own identity and how do you
differentiate because if we're all the
same
&gt;&gt; then you can just switch apps and it
doesn't cost you anything. And I guess
is there a pressure to well there is a
pressure to evolve the feature into your
own thing but do you feel like leaving
behind some of the core things like
chronological feed or just a ton of
photos everywhere. Do you feel like
there's a risk to that or is it just
sort of smaller numbers to the point
where it doesn't have to matter as much?
&gt;&gt; So there's definitely a risk. My hope is
that
the core ideas are the same if the how
is different. So, you're still
connecting with friends, you're still
exploring your interests, you're still
expressing your creativity if you want
to, but how is changing. Uh, but yeah,
there's definitely risk and there will
always be people who are going to be
upset and who going to want us to move
back. And look, I feel that way too
sometimes. But I think the alternative
is to just to become irrelevant because
I don't think you can just not evolve
and hope to continue to grow or even
maintain your scale. I think you're
going to see people we we do we see
people when we don't evolve fast enough
leave us for the competition. I'll give
you an example. We look all the time.
Pick a team, the ranking team, the video
creation team, whatever.
&gt;&gt; We look at two things. We look at the
top line. How is the trend doing? Are
people, you know, sharing more on
Instagram? And then we look at a back
test. So all the changes we make in a in
the six-month window, we will hold out
or not launch to 1% of people. And so
you can see what is the value that the
team is creating and then you can also
see what the overlying app trend is. So
I'll make up numbers. Let's say we
increased how much people are sharing
photos and videos by 5%. But the overall
amount of photos according to the back
test, but the overall photos and videos
shared on Instagram per person per day
was totally flat. That means there's a
5% headwind. That means if you don't do
anything, you're losing 5% every six
months.
um we see that across um a lot of
different key metrics which is just a
signal of either people moving on or
more likely just the competition getting
stronger. Uh and so if we don't evolve,
you're just going to see us shrink and
then that spirals. If there's less
people using Instagram, there's less
reach to go around. Creators start
leaving, less people then use Instagram,
there's less reach to go around still
and you're in a negative feedback cycle.
&gt;&gt; Interesting. The bottom line for the
company matters, of course. Obviously,
you want you want to keep the core
values of the of the product, but also
you need to still be a business
&gt;&gt; for sure.
&gt;&gt; How do creators make money on Instagram
today?
&gt;&gt; Primarily through um branded content
deals and also increasingly through what
we call partner ads. But there's at a
high level three ways to make money
&gt;&gt; uh on all platforms. You can either get
paid by a brand or a company, you can
get paid by the platform directly.
&gt;&gt; YouTube is best at that. Or you can get
paid by your fans, users. And we have
things like subscriptions and tipping,
&gt;&gt; but they're smaller scale.
&gt;&gt; One thing that's interesting in terms of
getting paid by companies, historically,
it's been primarily brands doing branded
advertising,
&gt;&gt; and that's great, but there's a lot of
money in advertising that isn't brand
dollars. It's what we call direct
response. So trying to sell a specific
chair or watch or whatever.
&gt;&gt; Yep. What partner ads do is allow
creators to create content and then opt
in to letting brands use that creative
as ads, which then benefits from the
entire measurement system of our ads
system, which is very good for direct
response advertisers, which then
increases the pool of dollars for
potential dollars for creators to make
by allowing them not only to do
off-platform
brand deals with big brand awareness
campaigns, but also deals with direct
response, which is a which is a massive
actually the majority of our business.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I'm interested in the breakdown of
that cuz I think when I first started as
a creator actually when I first started
none of them were really a thing.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; But uh especially on YouTube for example
uh made lots of videos made no money and
then the first version of this was
revenue sharing with the platform.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; And the first checks were extremely
small but it was just the easiest bottom
way to get like a foot in the door to
start to see some revenue from the work
that you do.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. And then it felt like you
graduated to the point where you were
able to work with a brand on something.
&gt;&gt; Uh what is the breakdown like on
Instagram? Is there is it mostly uh
people working with outside companies
and then putting their stuff on
Instagram?
&gt;&gt; Yeah, so Facebook has a meaningful
revshare business. Instagram doesn't
we've been working on it for years now
and we haven't been able to make it
sustainable and I can go into the
details there.
&gt;&gt; Sure.
&gt;&gt; On what I think sustainable looks like.
It just has to break even. We can't just
be burning money like you said. we are a
business.
&gt;&gt; Um, but the vast majority le, you know,
it's easily north of $10 billion a year,
probably a lot more. This is a couple
years old at that data point. Um, is
through offplatform deals that creators
make directly between them and brands
and then they use in they use their
reach on Instagram um to monetize that
way. And now what we've seen is we've
been able to scale up partner ads, these
direct response ads to a really
meaningful scale. Um, which we hope is
just increasing the overall pie. We
still have subscriptions. We still have
tipping. We're still working on what we
call um bonuses or performance-based
payouts, the sort of rev share. Um, but
they are much smaller in scale.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So, how do you how do you grow
that revshare piece? cuz I think a lot
of creators think about that and would
love it to be more but as as you say
it's not as sustainable. What are the
what are the major things keeping it
from being sustainable?
&gt;&gt; So there's three things I think that the
pl that the program needs to be to make
sense um to scale up. One is the it just
needs to not burn money. Um
&gt;&gt; so what the theory here is that you pay
creators they create more content then
you have more advertising and then you
can make back what you pay creators. um
I don't need to make money off this if
it's even close to break even or break
even. That seems like a great thing to
do.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Two, the criteria for being eligible
needs to be transparent. It can't be
some algorithm and you're in and I'm not
and we have no idea why.
&gt;&gt; It has to be like, all right, you need
to hit might be
&gt;&gt; might not be like automatic. It might be
like you need to average a million views
a week or whatever it is, but there
needs to be some transparent
eligibility.
&gt;&gt; There should be a page that explains it.
&gt;&gt; Exactly. But we need to get the program
to be break even without using
algorithmic ways of identifying creators
so that you can just actually explain
why you are are not eligible. And then
three, the checks just can't be
embarrassing. Like if I sent you a $4
check, you'd be like, "Thanks, but now
I'm kind of offended." Um, that doesn't
have to be that high. It just has to be
something that's like, "I don't want to
be sending a bunch of creators pennies."
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Um, I just think that'll that'll just be
a bad look.
&gt;&gt; It's interesting you say that. I I heard
you say that on Colin and Samir and I
actually disagree. I think
&gt;&gt; you'd rather get pennies.
&gt;&gt; I would rather get pennies and I it's
not really me specifically, but I think
as budding creators because again it's
it's hard to go off platform and get
good at brand deal and manage the inbox
and negotiate and do all that.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. And so to just have like a base
way of of having like splitting revenue
with the platform, even if my first
YouTube check was $1.74, like that was
motivating in a way for me to see, okay,
if I can scale my reach, if I can focus
my efforts on certain things, then I
know that I can increase what I'm
making.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; And obviously, it's not going to be a
full-time massive chunk of the business
for every creator. But I think I'd
rather get $4 than $0 if I know that
there's a reason I can move it to $10.
&gt;&gt; I might be overreacting to angry
DMs I get from people who are in the
program who who are like, "You make X
billion dollars a year. You sent me a
check for $9."
&gt;&gt; Yeah. It's maybe because it's hard to
explain exactly how you arrive at the
number cuz I know on YouTube Yeah. you
can very easily determine what ad came
from what video and how it's associated
with the uploader. Maybe that's harder
on Instagram, so it's harder to explain
to
&gt;&gt; attribution is tougher. Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; But I look if I'm over I would love to
drop one of the question to make it more
possible.
&gt;&gt; Um that's not the gate right now. Um the
first two are um but um you know we
might get there. Maybe we'll get there
in some countries and not other
countries. But um I could very well be
over rotated on that piece of feedback.
I'm always trying, like we said, how do
you step through the signal and the
noise?
&gt;&gt; There's a lot of strong opinions about
what we do, particularly from people who
rely on us. And I get that. And so I'm
always trying to figure out um when am I
just being
when am I really focused on what's best
overall and when am I might be
overreacting to not being not maybe
liking getting yelled at? And this might
be an example of the latter.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I just I when again the arc on
other social networks especially with
YouTube that I came up on so that's why
I reference that a lot is like when I
was first starting sure the $1 check
didn't meaningfully make a difference to
me but it was motivating and then
eventually it was the biggest part of
the business and then when I was able to
get the skills to go out and sell to
others who wanted to like work with me
on ads and manage the inbox and all
that.
&gt;&gt; Yeah,
&gt;&gt; that became the next biggest chunk and
then the revenue share with the platform
became secondary. Yeah.
&gt;&gt; And it's also it's always going to
fluctuate. Like I don't think any smart
business depends entirely on the revenue
share of the platform.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; But it does represent motivation and a
nice like bar to continue to see if it
goes up or down. You can kind of
associate that with the performance of
the entire channel. So I feel like it is
&gt;&gt; uh something that most I think you're
getting a vocal minority being very
angry, but I think most people would be
happier to see something than nothing.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I mean, it it it's a compelling
argument. So, you're giving me something
legitimate to think about.
&gt;&gt; Uh, which I I think it would not be
surprising to me if I was overreacting
to a vocal minority. I'm always trying
not to.
&gt;&gt; Um, but it's hard. Uh, and so just
pattern matching in general, the kinds
of mistakes we make, that's a common
pattern. So, you're probably right. Fair
enough.
[Music]
Support for this episode comes from Masa
Chips. You know, sometimes the best
snacks are the ones that have felt like
they've been around forever. Simple,
straightforward, they're done right.
That's exactly what Masa Chips are
aiming to do with their delicious
tortilla chips made the traditional way.
Masa makes their chips with just three
ingredients. Organic Nyximalized scorn,
Redmond sea salt, and 100% grass-fed
beef tallow. And the result is a chip
that's sturdier, crunchier, and more
flavorful than the big brand bags you're
used to.
So, one superpower these chips have is
since they're so sturdy and crunchy, the
amount of guac you can pick up in one
singular scoop is kind of like out of
this world. That's like four times the
amount of guac versus chip ratio I have
in my hand right now. And they come in a
bunch of great flavors. You know,
there's the obvious white, blue,
traditional. They also have an habanero
flavor that's fantastic. And what
surprised me the most was this churro
flavor, kind of like a dessert tortilla
chip. Can't get enough of it. But Masa's
mission goes even further. They only
source their beef tallad domestically
and are focused on creating their
products with sustainable practices. So
if you're ready to try the most
delicious tortilla chip you've ever had,
which are sustainably produced, go to
masachips.com/wwayform
and use code waveform for 25% off your
first order. Link in the description.
&gt;&gt; How often do Instagram ads get you to
buy stuff?
Um,
more often now than they used to.
&gt;&gt; They do. They get you.
&gt;&gt; They get me.
&gt;&gt; I always thought like I I never get got
by my own ads. Obviously.
&gt;&gt; They still get you.
&gt;&gt; They get me sometimes. Well, cuz
sometimes it's something I didn't know
about. It's like very tough. I mean,
it's perfect. It's like I'm a dad. I'm
in my 40s. I live in San Francisco. I
like gadgets. So, they're like, you
know, they're like growing like they go
after me with the things that it they're
pretty good. I mean, what do I like? Uh,
what have they got me with? Uh, coffee
gear. I really like
&gt;&gt; coffee gear. That's a popular one.
&gt;&gt; I really like coffee. I make I'm got
deep into pourover for a couple years. I
got deep into espresso for a couple
years. So, you know, a little tiny
coffee grind vacuum that's perfectly
designed to like fit into your setup.
&gt;&gt; They say just the right thing with just
the right pictures.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I know. I was like, "Ah."
&gt;&gt; Um,
&gt;&gt; my wife always jokes. Um, she I we we
once a year usually have an argument
about whether or not Instagram is
listening to your microphone. Um, she's
sometimes doubts my position on that.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Um,
&gt;&gt; it seems like the ads get really good
sometimes and have to defend that.
&gt;&gt; They do. They do.
&gt;&gt; Just for the record,
&gt;&gt; they are not. We're not Oh, for a couple
reasons. Okay, hold on. Yeah, I should
be careful.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Um, so, uh, you might have been
looking for it online, uh, because we do
work with advertisers who send us data
about what people were looking on their
website, uh, who they want to target
those people. So, you might be looking
for, like we were talking about, a
camera lens and then get that lens.
&gt;&gt; Yep.
&gt;&gt; Um, you might have been talking about it
with a friend and they might have been
looking at it online.
&gt;&gt; That's the one that seems to be the
creepiest but is actually real.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. where that person's getting ads
for it, that person bought it, I talked
to them about it. And is it proximity or
is it just like my relationship with
&gt;&gt; it's more it's it'll most likely happen
if you two are similar on paper. So it's
like
&gt;&gt; two guys, you know, in tech roughly the
same age. It's like that kind of thing.
Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Um,
and then sometimes it's just people
don't realize they actually saw the ad
and cuz you scroll by them and sometimes
that registers subconsciously and then
you're talking about that area. That's
kind of how advertising works.
&gt;&gt; Um, those are the three main. But here's
the other thing. No one believes me, but
the other thing is if we were if we were
listening to your mic, your battery
would drain real fast.
&gt;&gt; Sure.
&gt;&gt; The if the phone was remotely competent,
you'd be seeing the little light saying
that the thing was on. Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Um and it would just be a gross
violation of privacy
&gt;&gt; most importantly.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So like
&gt;&gt; we don't um but I do have this
conversation once in a while.
&gt;&gt; Funny.
&gt;&gt; Uh okay. So what is the future of
Instagram look like? Cuz uh there is
this evolution happening in social
networks and obviously you've seen ev
the Instagram of old to what it is
today. What is Instagram in and I love
asking you this because CEOs hate
talking about future products but I'm
going to ask you anyway. What is
Instagram in 5 years, 10 years? Is it
very different?
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Is it still keeping the core of what it
is now?
&gt;&gt; So, I think there's a period of time
that's more clear and there's a period
of time where it gets a lot less clear.
That's always true. The further on the
future, the less
&gt;&gt; granularity you have, but there's a
little bit of like a um like a a
threshold. So, over the next couple
years, I think the biggest thing that's
going to really change our business is
going to be AI.
I think you're going to see a lot of
great things where you're going to see
more creators can create more content.
Uh so you can create more content or
better content if you're already a
creator or people who didn't have the
ability to make content can make
compelling content who couldn't used to
before.
&gt;&gt; Um but there's also lots of concerns,
right? There's also, you know, deep
fakes. How do you know what to trust?
How do you know that something was
actually captured with a camera? You
won't be able to. So there's
opportunities and challenges that come
along with more and more content that is
created with AI. We too often talk about
AI as binary. It's either synthetic or
real content. And the truth is
&gt;&gt; AI assisted in the middle.
&gt;&gt; It's going to be mostly that is my
guess. Um uh so so I think that's going
to change what content you see on
Instagram, who you follow on Instagram,
who you even talk to on Instagram. These
things are going to change and there's
going to be a lot in the blurry middle.
We focus mostly on the extremes. Go back
to the way of old or don't talk to like
the unsupervised AI bot. But I think
most of it's going to be in between
those two.
&gt;&gt; Where things get much more fuzzy is when
the form factor changes. Um we obviously
have been very public about the fact
that we believe that eventually phones
will still be part of our lives but not
nearly as dominant. Um, one example of
how it could turn out is how, you know,
desktop and laptops have turned out,
which is, you know, you have more than
one probably. Um, uh, you know, it's
still an important part of your life. My
computer's important part of my life,
but it's not the most important in a
world where, you know, wearables, but
particularly glasses, I think, get
better and better more in, you know, the
five to 10 years. And obviously we we've
talked about this publicly with
um Met Ben Displays and with um Orion.
Um I think that that makes it much less
clear what Instagram is.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Cuz there's certain things that
naturally flow like most of what you do
in terms of connecting with Franc's
message. You can imagine that.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Um you can capture photos, but then what
does a consumption experience look like?
&gt;&gt; Yeah. in in a glasses first world is I
mean I've got a couple
educated guesses but I think it's going
to evolve a lot.
&gt;&gt; Does any of it worry you? Cuz I made a
reference at the end I got to see the
metaray band displays and I made a
reference at the end of my video to like
you know there is an Instagram app on
those glasses and there is a actual real
possibility that I could be talking to
someone wearing the glasses and they
could just be scrolling through
Instagram. Yeah.
&gt;&gt; And not paying attention to me. Looking
through glass at me.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. That's pretty close to that Wall-E
meme. Like that's extremely
&gt;&gt; with the slurpies,
&gt;&gt; the people. Yeah. So like
&gt;&gt; is that I mean it's it's possible now
that could actually happen. What do you
think about that?
&gt;&gt; I'm a worrier by nature. So I worry
about all of the things. Um there's like
how can it get misused? How it could be
bad for people. There's also how it
could be bad for the business, how it
could be bad for us. I mean the thing
that we've maybe talked about a little
bit less publicly uh in the context of
AI and new technology is like yes it's
changing what our apps are and what
people do on their app on our apps. It's
also massively changing how we build our
apps. We we're trying to wrestle with it
even internally as well. So I think it's
important for us to be honest about the
risks and the downsides and then try to
do what we can to maximize the upsides
and minimize those downsides. So yeah, I
worry about it. Um, I've got kids. Um,
what what is their life going to be? I
mean, so when I was 13, I'm 42. I was
born 83. When I was 13, it's mid90s.
This is like AOL dial up 2400 BPS early
internet. Yeah. Like
on the phone.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So, look at my parents had no idea
what I was doing online. Um, and I think
one of the risks for me as a dad, my
kids are too young to use social media,
but they're nine, seven, and five.
they're going to come up as a lot of
this tech comes up
&gt;&gt; and if it's going to be hard for me to
even understand possibly um what the
risks are if I'm not proactively leaning
in. So yeah, I I I think about I'm
excited about all the positive
opportunities and I am concerned about
all of the risks and I
&gt;&gt; I try to think about both.
&gt;&gt; It's an interesting position because as
a social network with now it's three
billion monthly active users. There's
three billion. It's like a hard number
to wrap my head around.
&gt;&gt; You become kind of like fabric of
society type big like decisions that you
make to get people to use Instagram more
get humanity to be on their phones more.
Like that's the type of repercussions
that come with what's happening at
Instagram, you know, which is
interesting. So I
&gt;&gt; I actually wonder what you think of
you've seen these AI creators like
creators on Instagram that are entirely
AI.
&gt;&gt; Well, yeah. Well, there's two kinds.
&gt;&gt; Well, right. And I'm I'm talking about
the ones that are are completely
independently AI,
&gt;&gt; but not just independent AI. It's a
persona. It's a person who right there's
also like if AI who's like fully
synthetic content, but they're creating
these dreams,
&gt;&gt; random all types of stuff. Yeah. I mean,
there's like a creator with a name and a
face and it's AI and they make tons of
stuff for no effort.
&gt;&gt; I figure that's good for Instagram in
theory because it's very efficient. It's
a creator that doesn't demand a ton of
revenue, but like creates tons of
engaging content. Yeah. But on the other
side, as a as a human creator, yeah,
it's horrible. I hate seeing that.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; What do you think when you see AI
creator doing what human creators do?
&gt;&gt; Um,
both. So, I mean, so on one hand,
I think that in a world where anybody
can like make any type of video with
like, I don't know, $150 worth of AI
credits, whether it's personifying a
person that doesn't exist or anything
else. Um, like what do we have left as
creatives? And I think it's really our
taste and our understanding of culture
and our own creativity. And so I I'm in
some ways
um bullish on that those ideas that
creatives will always have taste, have
creativity and have a position on
culture. And therefore whether or not
the content was created with AI, without
AI, or entirely with AI, they will be
telling stories, pushing boundaries,
driving culture, and that'll be good.
Um, but I also worry about, and it's
also great if there's people who, you
know, maybe you just were never
comfortable in front of a camera and now
you can do it. But then I also worry
about deep fakes. I worry about just an
explosion of competition.
&gt;&gt; If there's 10 100 times as much content,
there's no way there's going to be 10 or
100 times more engagement. So, the
average reach is going to go down.
&gt;&gt; We'll probably get blamed for that. Um,
what does that mean for people who,
yes, it's great who people who couldn't
create content before can now create
content, but for people who aren't don't
have access to or aren't technical
enough to leverage this technology, how
to make sure that they still have a
voice.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; So, uh, my mind pingpongs between the
exciting opportunities and the scary
risks.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Does it make sense to create rules
around it? like you want to enable
obviously you want to raise the floor
and make it more accessible for people
to create but I don't I don't think this
is me being biased as a human creator I
don't think we want Instagram to be full
of AI only creators and there are some
that are getting tons of engagement very
successful profiles
&gt;&gt; but I I don't love the world where
Instagram is full of that
&gt;&gt; is it up to the rules of Instagram to
prevent that from happening or if they
just make good enough stuff is that's
just the way it's going to be
&gt;&gt; it could be I mean I have a really hard
time imagining
it getting to a place where like that's
all that there is because I just don't
see how that content is going to cover
enough culturally relevant content.
&gt;&gt; You're very you believe in humanity a
lot.
&gt;&gt; I think people are interesting and like
and look AI will be interesting
&gt;&gt; um over time but right now like there's
a reason I mean
&gt;&gt; on one hand like it's unbelievable what
some of this tech can do. Um, like you
know, for instance, I was living in the
UK for a while. One common thing for
banks to do is voice signatures to like
sign in. Like you should definitely not
do that anymore.
&gt;&gt; Way too easy to fake.
&gt;&gt; As someone who has thousands of hours of
my voice in high definition on the
internet,
&gt;&gt; don't do that.
&gt;&gt; Don't do that.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Um, on the other hand, like I haven't
found a funny AI yet.
I haven't found an AI that has um
said something that I thought was like
on the bleeding edge of what's
interesting in culture right now. Um and
that will happen. Um but I think that's
further away. I think right now
&gt;&gt; people particularly creatives
um bring something to the table that AI
does not. Even though AI can completely
with particularly with direction
fabricate something that didn't exist.
Yeah, I think to an extent some of it is
interesting now because it's AI, which
may be why some of it is blowing up, but
I think the other reason so many people
call it slop is because it kind of just
appeals to the lowest common
denominator. We're we're sitting here
thinking, okay, we've never seen
anything really interesting or creative
or funny. I've never really thought that
hard about something AI,
&gt;&gt; but at the very lowest level of just
like basic humor, basic interesting
imagery,
&gt;&gt; they're making that stuff now. Yeah.
&gt;&gt; So that's
&gt;&gt; but the thing about that from an
Instagram business perspective is that
it's not it's it's not that valuable. So
like for it's too commoditized. You'll
be able to find that anywhere.
&gt;&gt; So for us, sure it might be nice for
some of the content on Instagram to be
content that you could find elsewhere
and drive some engagement, but it's
fundamentally not differentiated. It's
not defensible. It leaves us exposed. If
we become all content that you can find
anywhere else, then it's very easy for
you to leave us.
&gt;&gt; Um whereas if there's content that is
more unique or differentiated, then I
think that it's much more valuable
beyond the amount of engagement it might
drive or how amount of revenue it might
drive. That's one of the reasons why we
focus on creators. The creators do post
across multiple platforms more and more
so, but it is fundamentally more
differentiated than like sports
highlights or AI slot for instance.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So, I mean, yeah, sounds like
there's at least some incentive for
Instagram to keep humans on the site
happy and lots of great stuff.
&gt;&gt; I mean, look, there's different there
are different forces in different
directions at play. Um, it's just like
most big questions, not black and white.
Um, not simple.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Well, I guess then I have one more
question for you.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Which is the same question from the
beginning. M
&gt;&gt; you know Instagram 3 billion monthly
active users reels upcoming AI you know
maybe leaving some features behind
evolving forward what what is Instagram
right now 2025
&gt;&gt; Ooh right now um it depends a lot on the
country but I'm not going to use that as
a copout but it is wildly different by
country
&gt;&gt; I believe that
&gt;&gt; um in so maybe you know we're here in
the US so maybe in in the US I think
that
we are there's some strengths and
there's some weaknesses. I think on the
strength side, you know, I think we are
still the de facto home for most
creators. They use multiple platforms.
YouTube is better at long form video.
They're better at revshare. Tik Tok is
better at breaking new talent and
helping people get discovered.
&gt;&gt; But we are a more complete suite of
tools for you to not just tell your
stories, but engage with your audience,
etc. So that's why if you look at how
many creators are on Instagram, it seems
like they're more than any other
platform. Um, we are trying to continue
to stay culturally relevant by investing
in originality and timeliness. Um, but
there's real risk that the competition
will execute better than us. Um, and
I don't want to be in charge of
Instagram when we drop from being like a
tier one app in terms of cultural
relevance to a tier two.
&gt;&gt; And that to me that feels kind of
existential. Um, I want us to be the
best platform for creatives, the best
form for people to talk to their friends
about their interests. In some ways I
can point to numbers that suggest that
we're the first and other ways I can
point to numbers suggest that we're the
second or the third. Um, and so we're, I
think, at this really intense,
possibly pivotal moment where the world
is changing faster than ever. The
competition's fiercer than ever, and
we're trying to navigate that and
somehow also stay simple and stay true
to our identity.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Well, sounds like you're a busy
man, so I'll let you go.
&gt;&gt; Adam, thanks for the time. Such a
pleasure. Appreciate it. Hopefully us
again.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, it'll be a blast.