I was trying to figure out where you
were going with that. I was like, "Wow,
he's really asking his salary?"
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; Oh, yeah.
I'm sure that's public. I'm a
shareholder. I can find [laughter] that
out right now. Oh, man.
&gt;&gt; Please. All right. Let me call my RAPID
ROBINHOOD BROKER.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
[singing and music]
[music and singing]
[music]
[singing]
&gt;&gt; MASA AND OREN, WELCOME back to the Good
Guys podcast. We are sitting here with
the president of Instagram, Adam
Mosseri. Hi. Thanks for having me.
&gt;&gt; Thanks for doing this. Wow, look at
this, Ben. Can you believe these stats?
It's fantastic. And we've been chatting
with Adam for the last 10 minutes, and
let me tell you, he is much funnier than
I expected. So, this episode is going to
be an absolute hoot. We are seven boys.
We've seven boys between the three of
us, okay? Parents over here. Good guys.
Adam's another good guy, and just
happens to run
a platform that is incredibly important
to the livelihoods of all of us. So,
thank you very much, Adam. Yeah, but can
you just allow the
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; I don't know my guy.
&gt;&gt; just allow the algorithm to reach a few
more people,
&gt;&gt; Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Well, I'm sure we'll talk about the
algorithm. What if the algorithm kept,
like, you know how the Coca-Cola recipe
is in like a cave in Atlanta? Yeah.
Like, it's [clears throat] kept
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; Like, there's only one person who has
the recipe, and it's like maybe one of
the Coke family. Where is the algorithm
held?
So,
to [laughter] start, we talk a lot about
Honestly, I I used to try to
reframe questions like that, cuz there
isn't one algorithm. There's lots of
things we do to try to understand how
interested you are in certain topics,
what certain content's about, match you
with your interests, etc.
But, at this point, I think everyone
just what they mean when they say the
algorithm is is the sum of all of those
things, and I've stopped trying to um
fight that framing. I just don't want
people to feel like the algorithm is
some entity that has its own agency that
I we hide behind. Like, we are
responsible for the decisions we make
and what we build, and that affects what
people see. So, I want to make sure we
own that. Um, but to answer your
question, for ranking and relevance and
algorithms, it is code on servers in
data centers all over the world. Um,
lots of copies of the same code. And is
it changing all the time? Every day. Um,
people often think that something major
has changed in the algorithm, and they
uh use that to explain why their reach
might have gone way up or way down. But,
the truth is, we almost never make major
changes to it. We constantly make small
changes to try to improve it over time.
Oh, that is You are I feel so seen.
That's me on the group chat with a bunch
of other influencers. Like, when I'm
having [laughter] a real [__] week, I
go, "They changed it, bro."
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Just throw me under the bus.
I'm shadow banned.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, yeah. What are you talking about?
Shadow [laughter] banning, yeah. They're
not highlighting funny right now, bro.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Funny does
Funny [laughter] does well. Funny is one
of the best verticals. I
All the data I've seen suggests funny is
funny is still good, but it is tough.
&gt;&gt; have you been at Instagram, Adam?
I joined Instagram in the spring of '18.
I was hired to run what's called their
product management team by Kevin and
Mikey, the founders.
Um, they had already been at the
company, um, what was then called
Facebook, now called Meta, for about 6
and 1/2 years at the time, maybe 6
years. But, I was at Facebook for 10
years before that. So, 2008, right? Is
that when you started? I 08, I started.
I was a designer. Uh, we were just a
website. The The iPhone, I think, had
just come out, but we didn't have an
iPhone app.
And, you know, it was fun. It wasn't It
wasn't a bunch of kids in a college
dorm. It was You know, we had a couple
hundred people and an HR department.
There were some adults around, but we
were pretty young and trying to figure
it out on the fly. Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh.
Are you represented in Social Network?
Is that Is that the question here?
&gt;&gt; think I don't think so, no. But, you
tell you tell people. You go, "See that
extra back there on the laptop?" That's
me. That's [laughter] me. The kid with
the Jewfro in the back.
That's cool.
&gt;&gt; I wanted to see it. I remember wanted to
see it. We all went to see it.
&gt;&gt; We got Facebook stock, right? Did we get
Facebook stock?
&gt;&gt; it. Yeah, yeah, yeah. The way
compensation is up in all tech companies
is
stock and salary. Um, and that's all We
We do that because we think it's good
for the employees to have an incentive
for the business to do well, not just
for them to do well as individuals.
&gt;&gt; We tried to offer Olivia stock in Good
Guys. She said, "No."
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; Pay me that cash.
&gt;&gt; I would like to see the runway.
Olivia, we'll offer you 25% of the
company or two grand in cash.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; Two grand. She's like,
"I'll take a gift certificate to
McDonald's." [laughter]
Juice bar Juice
Equinox or something.
&gt;&gt; But, you were saying, so you as a
company went to go watch Social Network?
&gt;&gt; We did. We all went together. Wow, what
was that like? With With Mark? Yeah,
yeah, yeah. Uh, it was surreal. Um, it
was interesting cuz it's you can't help
but get distracted by what's accurate
and what's inaccurate. It's almost, you
know, if you've read a book and then
watch the movie, and then you kind of
get distracted by where it deviates and
where it lines up. It was almost like
that. Right. But, like, at that time,
you came on after like Eduardo had left
the company and Sean Parker was gone,
the whole thing. Yeah, Sean was not at
the company. I But, you know, we There
were some interactions back then, I
think, with him. But, no, it was just
after that phase. Wow. Yeah. What a
time. How exciting. Yeah, I mean, it was
It was very exciting and humbling at the
same time. When did you get on
Instagram, Ben? Probably like 2013.
Uh, I I was going to I was going to ask
this. So, I posted memes forever. That
was like my original Boy With No Job and
Girl With No Job were memes, and then we
pivoted over time as the platform
evolved, and memes sort of went away,
and video
uh started to take hold. But, it's
funny, even to this day, if I were to
post a meme, it would reach
four times the amount of people than a
video. Is there a way to let I know the
algorithm, you can't like talk to it. Is
there a way to train the algorithm to
let them know that you no longer post
that type of content, even a decade
later? No, but it's not always the case
that memes do better than videos. It
depends on the
on the person and the content. I
actually do think we should try to get
to a place where you can actually talk
to the algorithm, and I can talk about
that more if you'd like. Yeah. But, um,
but most of the ranking system work is
not actually thinking much about you and
your history. It's mostly oriented
around consumers. It's like, "Okay,
here's a piece of content. Who might be
interested in it? Let's go and find out
as many people as possible who we think
could be interested in it, whether or
not they follow you or not."
There are things that are producer-side
oriented, but for the most part,
it's
nothing happens when you post right
away. What happens is then all the
people who then log in and follow you,
open up Instagram later, and then we go
and look at that post and everything
else that was posted, and then try to
figure what they might be interested in.
It's not like a piece of mail that gets
sent. It's almost like a DVD added to a
DVD collection, and then the next person
who comes into the store, it's an option
for Is there like a a checkpoint type
thing in the sense of So, I post
something, right? Do certain things Do
you need to hit certain milestones
quickly for then it for it to be widely
broadcast? That's a great question. So,
there are two sides to how ranking works
for organic content. So, not ads. We're
just talking about when you post on
Instagram as a creator or as just an
average folk.
There's one side, which is for the
accounts that follow you. So, everyone
who's followed you, and they we're
trying to find as many of them as
possible who are interested in your post
and to show them that content. So, when
they open up Instagram, we look at that
post and all the other posts they could
see, and we rank them based on
relevance.
Half of the people who follow you might
not even use Instagram anymore or not be
on Instagram on that day. Maybe another
half of those don't scroll far enough,
so you're never going to reach most of
your followers, even though we all would
love to reach all of them. Um, but
that's that there's that system
where there's no sort of gate or minimum
thing or threshold that you sort of have
to cross necessarily.
Then, there's the unconnected side. So,
we try to go out and find people who
don't follow you who might love and be
interested in your content.
And the way that works is kind of like
an audition system. So, we try to make
sure every piece of content gets that's
public, that's trying to reach a lot of
people, gets a minimum number of views.
And And then, if it So, we have we set
aside a little bit of
what we call impressions or views to try
things out like that. And then, if it
does really well, then we get it we
broadcast that piece of content to more
unconnected accounts. If it does well
again, it gets it graduates again. So,
it's almost like a competition
where it can keep can keep if it does
better than everything else, continue to
get promoted and promoted and promoted,
which is how you can see content from
very small accounts go very viral
sometimes. Right.
Yeah, it's interesting, right, Ben? Cuz
like, I I'll find In general, I have
like the metrics for my channel, like
milestones where I'll see if something
did about 60,000 views in the first 10
minutes, I go, "This one's going to go."
Yeah, yeah, yeah. And that's not I go,
"You know what, babe? DoorDash."
&gt;&gt; Yeah. You know, like you know you
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; Let's treat ourselves to caviar tonight.
Yeah, it's going to be We can pay and we
won't do pick up, we'll do delivery. You
know, we'll do the charges. But then if
I see it like teetering at 15, you know,
20,000, I go, "This one I just know it's
not going to make it." Yeah, so that's
that's often true that early on you can
get a sense for how something's going to
do. But what matters is not really the
number of views. It's the interaction
rates. So, of all the people who saw it,
how many people liked it? Right.
&gt;&gt; Of all the people who saw it, how many
people sent it to a friend? And what
you're getting a sense for in those
first, you know, in that first hour is
what that rate is cuz you you're like,
"All right, 60,000 views, it's doing
better than the average thing I did."
For the But what's really happening
behind the scenes is maybe your average
post has like a 5% like rate had a 6%
like rate or 1% comment rate, so one out
of 100 people commented on it, this one
had 1.1.
That's actually a big delta. It doesn't
sound like it, but it is. Yeah. Uh and
you're seeing that start to get picked
up in the ranking system.
Well, it's best.
&gt;&gt; overreact to the first hour though.
Here's one more thing.
The comments we're trying to make sure
they're as
civil as possible. People on the
internet are not always as civil as we
would like.
I strongly ask anybody who struggles
with mean comments sometimes to just
give it a minute before you get in there
cuz
the people who post comments the
quickest
are the craziest. And if you just wait
an hour or two, normal people tend to
sort of drown out the wild. And so, just
give it a minute. Don't don't get on
there in the comments in those first
hour. I feel like that's the that's not
the best. And will some of those will
the filter catch some of those within
the first hour? Yeah, but there's things
that are not allowed, which will get
caught, but then there's things that are
allowed, but they're just mean. Oh,
yeah. We're aware. Yeah, and then normal
and nice comments will just push those
mean comments way down over time. But
there's a correlation between how
quickly you comment and
how
tough you can be as a commenter, turns
out. I have a gift for finding the mean.
Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Oh, yeah.
&gt;&gt; Don't look for it. Don't get I Well, you
should check out my comments.
Oh, yeah.
Interesting. Yeah, what are your
comments like?
So,
uh there's a couple.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; There's a lot of mad about reach. Okay.
Give me back Chrono feed.
Um
it's my birthday. All I want for my
birthday is a blue checkmark. Mhm.
&gt;&gt; Um
people being upset about having some
piece of content uh taken down or feel
like they're shadowbanned or someone
they care about has.
But look, that's part of the job. Um
you're
going to if you're responsible for a
platform that so many people use and
rely on when things don't go their way,
even if it's a small percentage of
people, it's a lot of
it's a lot of people.
&gt;&gt; Billion, two billion? Three. Three.
There's only seven billion people in the
world. Three billion people a month
using Instagram.
&gt;&gt; It's it's unbelievable.
&gt;&gt; We just crossed that. Yeah. It's
unbelievable. Yeah, I don't know how to
run that up.
&gt;&gt; how big Instagram is. It's so crazy.
This episode of the Good Guys podcast is
brought to you by our friends at
Element. Folks, Element helps anyone
stay hydrated without the sugar and
other dodgy ingredients found in popular
electrolyte and sports drinks.
Electrolyte deficiency or imbalance can
cause headaches, cramps, fatigue, brain
fog, and weakness. Don't I know. I love
drinking water. I drink honestly like
200 million gallons a day. I drink too
much water. By the way, if you drink too
much water, you could die. So, be very,
very careful. That has nothing to do
with Element. That's just me giving you
a tip. Don't drink too much water. That
said, I'm also not fearmongering around
water. I'm just saying drink the proper
amount of water. How about we drink What
was that recommendation? Eight cups a
day? I think it was eight cups a day. If
you drink eight cups of water a day and
you have no electrolytes, you are not
going to not have that headache, cramp,
fatigue, brain fog, weakness. You know
why? Because you're missing the salt.
You're missing the magnesium. You're
missing all of the good stuff that comes
in a proper electrolyte sports drink mix
such as Element. And Element is a zero
sugar electrolyte drink mix and
sparkling electrolyte water born from
the growing body of research revealing
that optimal health outcomes occur at
sodium levels two to three times the
government recommendations. What are
you, nuts, government? Stop telling me
to drink eight glasses of water a day
without any electrolytes. And please
stop telling me the wrong sodium levels
to be taking. What are you, nuts? Each
stick pack delivers a meaningful dose of
electrolytes, free of sugar, thank God,
artificial colors, or other dodgy
ingredients. Element is formulated for
anyone on a mission to restore health
through hydration and is perfectly
suited for athletes, folks who are
fasting, or those following keto,
season, low carb, whole food, or paleo
diets. Folks, you've got to try Element.
If you haven't tried it yet, honestly,
you are missing out on the greatest
hydration of your life. I'm telling you,
Element is it. And right now Element is
offering a free sample pack with any
purchase. That's eight single serving
packets free with any Element order.
It's a great way to try all eight
flavors or share Element with a friend.
Get yours at drinklmn.com/goodguys.
This deal is available through our link.
You must go to drinklmn.com/goodguys.
This deal is only available through our
link. drinklmn.com/goodguys.
This episode of the Good Guys podcast is
brought to you by our friends at Chewy.
Folks, when I think about the holidays,
all I think about are my moments with my
beautiful pet. The ones that make the
season bright. That's why I'm joining
Chewy Claus who's out here making pets'
wishes come true. From November 4th to
December 24th, share your pet's wish at
chewy.com/chewyclaus.
It could become real and help others,
too. Each wish triggers a donation of
five meals to shelters and rescues
across the country. Submit through the
Chewy app and they'll double the
donation. A wish for a pet really is the
wish that keeps on giving. Friends, you
can send pets' wishes to
chewy.com/chewyclaus
and it might just come true. And your
wish spreads the joy because each wish
means five meals get donated to pets in
need. Send your pet's wish through the
Chewy app and they will double their
donation to shelters and rescues across
the country. Shelters and rescues can
join in on the joy by submitting their
own wish list to Chewy Claus. Their
community can find their wish list and
donate items directly to them. Chewy
Claus is spreading joy with your wish.
Folks, Chewy is already the best place
for you to get all of your pet
essentials. But now Chewy Claus, we're
doing good things for pets. We're
donating meals. They're cause-driven
organization. Chewy is fantastic. Each
pet deserves a wish come true, don't
they? Send your pet's wish to
chewy.com/chewyclaus
and it might become a reality. Plus,
your wish means Chewy will donate five
meals to pets in need. You want to
donate meals to pets in need, don't you?
chewy.com/chewyclaus.
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; The translate tool that's now I think it
was Is it new? I use it a lot.
&gt;&gt; I was excited about Like and I I like it
a lot and I I have noticed so all of my
like 3 years ago I pivoted hard into
cooking. All of my content now is recipe
reels. They're doing better than really
any content I've ever posted over the
last decade aside from memes. So, I
clearly found my niche. But I think that
the translate is is making the reach
even higher.
&gt;&gt; It is. Obviously, that would be it would
become relevant to people outside of the
US, so it makes sense. But would you
recommend always turning that on? Like
are you guys prioritizing that or just
naturally will feed into more circles
because people are understanding what
you're saying? Exactly. It's the latter.
So, it will help with reach more and
more over time cuz we're still getting
we're still new to this. So, for those
of you who don't know, when you post a
reel on Instagram, you can have it
translated automatically
into the the four languages that we
support are English, Spanish,
Portuguese, and Hindi. Which by the way
cover up cover the majority of users. Um
cuz India and Brazil are massive massive
countries for us. And then obviously
Spanish is spoken in a lot of countries
around
&gt;&gt; Told you, Josh. India. India, Josh.
&gt;&gt; our biggest country.
I know. I I You should look at my DMs.
Yeah. It's almost primarily Delhi. Yeah.
But the whole the whole idea is that
there's a world of content out there
that you might be interested in, but you
might not know how to speak the
language. Right. And so, if I can
explain how Instagram works and it can
just show up as me in my voice with
looking like my lips are saying words in
Hindi, all of a sudden I can reach an
audience in India who speaks Hindi and
doesn't speak English. Right. Which by
the way is only about half of India cuz
in there's maybe 26 official Indic
languages at this point. There's many,
many more that are actually spoken on
the ground. So,
um the whole idea here is to help
creatives reach
audiences and find fans across language
barriers.
Wow.
What what's uh what what's the Instagram
perks looking like? Is there any
Instagram PJ? What are we talking about?
Like you got to be places. The Yeah.
You're not flying [laughter] spirit.
Come on.
I'm a United guy. Uh United Yeah, when
the PJ's broken.
&gt;&gt; We don't have We don't have one. I'm a
Mark Mark I'm sure has a plane, but uh
the rest of us uh do not. Which is good,
I think.
Uh no, the perks are I mean like I said,
it's a wonderful place to work. They
take really good care of us.
I we I laughed when you first said perks
cuz I think of the team they love swag.
They love like is swag swag swag swag.
Um and I'm like, "Why? Why do you want
another shirt with like a logo
[laughter] on it?" Like
But they just can't doesn't matter
doesn't matter who you are, people love
a free T-shirt and they love a free mug.
One of your great employees who I've
known for 20 years, Justin Anthony. Yes.
One of the greats.
&gt;&gt; He and I started our careers together.
He was like a talent executive at
Nickelodeon when I was 14. Yeah. And
he's always championing me, and when he
moved over to Instagram, it just felt
natural. And so, he had like a summit
for creators years ago
and brought us up to the headquarters
and was like, "Come over. Come see." I
mean, was the Facebook headquarters
created by the people who did Disney or
Downtown Disney, or is that a myth? No,
no, it wasn't. It was the
Did you go to the campus that was right
on the Like it's by the sort of like
salt flats by the near kind of a water
body body of water? Maybe. I mean, it
had everything.
&gt;&gt; What year was it? This was probably
2018, 2019.
&gt;&gt; yeah. So, it would have been classic
campus, yeah. No, that's um that was
like an old Sun uh headquarters. It was
like an old Silicon Valley company
headquarters. It was sick. Like ice
cream shop, unbelievable, like five
different places to eat food, but the
best part was he took me and the other
influencers, and let's be honest, we
love free stuff. He said, "Come to the
Come to the company store." I got a
Patagonia.
I said, "I can have this?" He goes,
"Whatever [laughter] you want, Josh." I
said, "This is Patagonia. This is
high-end material." And it's got a nice
and it had the Facebook patch right at
the bottom. So,
&gt;&gt; It's very tasteful.
&gt;&gt; just like on your on your chest. Just
Yeah. [laughter]
&gt;&gt; the book. Too much, yeah.
That's good. That's good. Uh
It's It's not quite as Disneyland as it
used to be. I think once we you know,
through the pandemic and then 2022 and
the market contraction, we've started to
try to be much more judicious in our
expenses. Um so, it's not quite the
the um the wildness that it was. Uh
which I think is also good, but it's
still a wonderful place to work. I'm not
trying to complain at all. I was just
going to say, speaking of working for
Instagram, I think it's the perfect
time.
Uh I worked in media for a decade before
doing what I'm doing, and I actually
DM'd I looked back. I DM'd the Instagram
account. I'll read it to you.
I DM'd the Instagram account in 2019.
What'd you say?
&gt;&gt; wrote,
"Hey, long shot, but I saw a job at
Instagram that I was incredibly
intrigued by. I was wondering if you
could possibly connect me with someone
in recruiting to talk about it." Did it
just go on red? Did they Did it just
ghost you?
No one ever read it. No one
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; ever read it.
Uh
&gt;&gt; And let me tell you, this was This was
very talented, Ben.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Formerly at Vayner Media. Very ex- very
excited to work at Instagram. And thank
god it didn't happen cuz my my life
turned out great. But I wanted to work
at Instagram so badly. Does Instagram
check its DMs?
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; I check my DMs, but I don't check that
Instagram. I'm pretty sure someone does,
um but there's a lot. There's almost 700
million people follow that account. So,
it's There's a There's more DMs, I
think, than people can get to. Um I do I
go into my request folder every week.
Yeah.
&gt;&gt; I think it's good uh to get a sense for
what
is on people's minds, what's frustrating
people lately. I always respond to a
handful, which usually freaks them out.
Um
and [laughter]
Of course. Sometimes I find like
important people in there that I didn't
even know like for that it had messaged
me. I like missed it. And so, I'm trying
to get better at that. Oh, I um I've
been recently people will I'm I'm kind
of on an anti-Cameo kick cuz I don't
know. I don't want to pay them a vague
for my likeness. But, you know,
shout-out Cameo. But so now, if people
DM me, I will um I'll just answer them
and I'll do the request. Like if they
ask for a birthday shout-out, I'll be
like, "You don't have to pay me. I'm
just happy to do it." Cuz this way I can
do one every couple days and feel feel
good about it. This one girl You tell me
if this is nuts.
She's very nice. "Hello, Josh. My best
friend, we love you. Blah, blah, blah."
She's like, "Will you wish her a"
&gt;&gt; not sound like my DMs.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; No one has ever been like, "Hello, Adam.
I love you. So happy you're doing such
&gt;&gt; Okay.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
There's only a kitchen. There's also a
&gt;&gt; There's also the side of it where they
call us fat, vicious pigs
&gt;&gt; Okay. All right. All right. Tell us how
Tell us how much they hate Jews. There's
that side of it, too. I get [laughter]
plenty of that. I get plenty of that,
too. Yeah. Yeah. You got to love it.
I
But uh and so, she says, "Can you give
me a birthday video for my friend?" And
the friend's name is C L E I L A. C L E
I
L A? Yeah. This is a smart guy. So,
let's see. Let's see. Cleal Cleala?
Clelia.
Okay. I write her back, "Sure. How do
you pronounce her name? How do you just
write that name? With due respect, a
beautiful name,
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; but you you don't just write Is it Is it
a beautiful name?
&gt;&gt; If there's a silent C, you you know, you
lead with that, you know?
&gt;&gt; It's a silence? No.
Oh, it's Leila? No.
&gt;&gt; I I asked her. So, then she she sent me
a voice message. You say it like Clelia.
Oh, that would never No one's getting
that. No. So, I I sent a video and I
told her friend what was up. Clelia,
what's up? It's Josh Peck. How are you?
Don't look at this pimple right here.
What can you do? Just wanted to wish you
happy birthday.
Uh your best friend, Louisa, asked me to
do this. So, thank her and also tell
your friend she wrote me your name and
it's beautiful. Not, you know,
semi-exotic. [clears throat]
I had never heard it before. And she was
like, "Oh, just can you wish my friend
Clelia a happy birthday?" And I wrote
her back. I was like, "Can you tell me
how to pronounce it?" Cuz this could
have been happy birthday Clelia or happy
birthday
Clelia. [laughter]
Like it just would have been I'm not a
smart man. But you're a smart person and
you're a wonderful [laughter] person,
and I hope you have a wonderful
birthday.
You're You're You're nuts and I love the
way that you code-switch. Hello, it's
Josh.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; Hello, how are you? Hello, how are you
doing?
&gt;&gt; Hello Hello, Clelia. It's Josh
[laughter] here. I'm
I know. I hate my voice. But you know
what I'm saying? I really aired out the
baggage for her friend, Louisa. But
shout-out. I think it's great cuz if you
get one that's that long, it's it's it's
more it's more there's [laughter] more
goodness in it.
&gt;&gt; It's committed. Do you all
&gt;&gt; No one has ever asked me to wish one of
their friends a happy birthday.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; But you're open to it. Oh, I would
definitely do Hearts and minds.
You know? You're open to it.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; Is there an Is there
You know, obviously Mark is in his
Zuckerberg he's in his
oversize shirt era.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; Are there moments where you could be
like, "Are you going to wear the chain
on the outside, Mark?" Can you have that
shorthand?
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; I mean, I think it's good. I think it's
good for him to lean into his own style
and figure out how he wants to express
himself. I've definitely had a chain out
at times, so I can't be throwing shade
at that. All right.
But I don't know. I just feel like for a
long time, it was a very focused
uniform. It was like, you know, jeans
and Adidas sandals and a gray T-shirt.
So, I'm I'm glad he's exploring a little
bit more on the fashion side. I I love
it. I think it humanizes him. Like for
so long, you were like, "Who is this
guy?" And like the second that he
started doing that, you were like, "Oh.
Oh, he's he's him.
He's him with the tees and the It's like
He's a real guy.
&gt;&gt; You got to be you.
You You show If you're showing up
online, in you know, obviously you want
to be thoughtful about how you show up.
But if you're inauthentic, people can
sniff it out, and people [clears throat]
hate that. And so, you have to find
something authentic to tap into, and
then if people like it, great. If they
don't, that's also okay. But if you're
trying to hide something or pretend to
be something you're not, I think people
can smell that. And so, I'm I'm just
like, "Look, you know, you be you.
Whatever Whatever you're into."
I think it's good to figure out how to
find a piece of that that you feel like
comfortable sharing if you're trying to
share online in the first place. I I
feel comfortable asking this now that
it's technically also an American
company, but like is there ever a fear
that like maybe there's like a spy from
TikTok or like there's like someone from
another social media company who's
trying to like I'm sure all of that
happens. That definitely happens. You
think so? Oh, yeah. I'm sure there are
companies that have people go I'm sure
there's I mean, I'm sure even
governments have done it or tried to do
it at times. I think we try to take
security really seriously, which is why
we, you know, lock down access to data
in a bunch of different ways. We track
everything. We try to be really, really
careful. But at our scale, that's
inevitable. Really?
&gt;&gt; Yeah, it's wild. So, you got a couple
spies out there, huh? I'm not saying
there
You don't think there's a little rat
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; I'm not
I'm saying Spying goes two ways. No, I'm
just saying that we are honest about the
risks and we try to reduce the chances
of anything bad happening.
Wow, so interesting.
That's amazing. I would I would be a
terrible spy. Imagine me just like
undercover at TikTok working for
Instagram. They'd catch me day of. Um
Adam, what's next for Instagram? Like
what is Like Like is there like
something enormous on the horizon or is
there like a a new North Star? Like
I just feel like you guys are so great
at pivoting with the times and always
sort of find like figuring out what's
next. Like what is next?
&gt;&gt; There's a lot going on right now. I
think
the
Well, I want to acknowledge up front
that I know it's frustrating when
Instagram changes. Cuz you feel like
it's yours or you got used to it or you
got good at it, and all of a sudden it
feels like we pulled the rug out from
under you.
The flip side is if we didn't evolve,
then we would be irrelevant. There's no
way I would be you'd ask me to be here
today or I'd be here today if we didn't
have stories or Reels or recommendations
or DMs. If we were just a feed of square
photos with filters, we would have kind
of fallen by the wayside.
The thing So, we always try to evolve,
but stay true to our core identity of,
you know, connecting people over
creativity.
But, the thing that I'm personally
really excited about right now is if a
big part of what we do is help people
explore their interests, get connected
to creatives in whatever they're into,
and then talk about them with their
friends.
I think a really interesting question is
how can you more actively shape that?
You know, we talked about talking to the
algorithm before. So, actually just this
week we started to test out this
sort of tune your algorithm feature. We
It was inspired by a meme on Threads 2
years ago, which was called Dear Algo.
So, all these people were just writing
to the algorithm, like, "Please stop
showing me friends of my high school
friends' kids." You know, like, stuff
like that.
Um
stuff that we not might not actually be
able to deliver on.
Um but, we were
with some of this new technology,
particularly around AI, there are
opportunities now where we can
both make the algorithm more
human-understandable
and malleable. So, with this one What
we're starting with is what we So, it's
simple. You can add things You can see
what we think you're interested in.
And then you can add things that we may
have missed, and you can remove things
if we're wrong about things. Or, you can
just even say I don't actually want to
see anything about whatever it is. Maybe
you're just like, "I you know, I quit
American football. I just don't want to
see anything about football." You can
actually just do that. Sure. And it's
pretty fun to actually go and look and
see what we think you're into, and then
go make some corrections. And then once
you do, right now it's just in Reels.
When you're scrolling through Reels,
well, if we showed you something that
you asked for, let's say you asked for
parenting advice. It would literally say
with the little, you know, tag parenting
advice. So, you can see that you're
getting it cuz you asked for it. Right.
&gt;&gt; And so, this idea of shaping your
algorithm is something I'm very excited
about, and it's really only possible at
scale
over the last year or so. Um so, we're
just starting to test this with a very
small percentage of people in the US to
start. Um but, I'm hoping to get that
out over the next couple months.
And is it true, like, I've heard
something to the effect of I think I
think Tyler Cowen was talking about this
on the Rick Rubin podcast. You know, I
listen to what economists I'm
well-rounded.
And [laughter] then I graduated high
school. Um but, Rick Rubin's got some
long pods. Long pods.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, he's he's a he's an interesting,
brilliant cat. He's smart. He's very
smart. And
&gt;&gt; [clears throat]
&gt;&gt; they were saying how originally, you
know, the big tech companies were trying
to especially social media companies
were acquiring these AI engineers in
compensation packages that looked like
10, 15 million dollars, right? But, now
they were saying like, "It's getting to
a point where of this small group of
like true AI cutting-edge engineers,
these guys are like making
hundreds of millions of dollars." Like,
the offers have become so insane because
someone high up at these companies can
go, you know, "If this person can give
us such an edge on the AI of it all,
like, yeah. Like, let's just do it.
Like, it's it makes sense." Like, is
that where we're getting with AI? It's
just such an extreme
um field of of upside?
Yes and no. So, most of what you read
about in terms of the offers are greatly
exaggerated, but it still is a lot of
money. So, I don't want to pretend like
it's not.
I think that some of these foundation
models and cutting-edge models work
model work is
there's really a small group of people
who's
really good at it. And so, there's an
immense amount of competition to hire
that talent, which is what's driving up
the cost of, you know, hiring these
people. Um but, it is pretty wild
because it's
some of these techniques are decades
old, but a lot of it are just brand new
and novel, and everyone's kind of
learning on the fly. So, a lot of this
talent
um and then there's not a lot of it
overall, is also like really young. Um
these are young engineers who
&gt;&gt; Yeah. A lot of them are in their 20s.
&gt;&gt; Wow.
Um they're
&gt;&gt; Are IVs still like Ivy kids, Ivy League
kids, or maybe not? Uh maybe not. I
mean, some of them it's it's people
it's not something you can go learn in
school. So, because it's so new, it's a
bunch of techniques and technologies
that are evolving very quickly. So, it's
people who are very quick learners, who
are willing who who actively experiment.
It's a much more scrappy
type of engineer or researcher, really,
than what we, you know, most of the
Valley has
historically hired, which are much more
like, "This is the right way to build a
database that serves this many millions
of people over this many data, you know,
this many data centers."
Where there's like a right way to do it.
You could write a PhD about it. This is
not that. Um there are PhDs about the
research, for sure, who work in the
research area, but the people who are
building the applied stuff,
it's a small group of people, they're
very young, and they're very
um
scrappy. Um it's it's kind of wild to
see them do the what they do.
Wow. Well, Ben Ben's lost to ChatGPT.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. We We we've I We've lost, Ben.
&gt;&gt; used I I haven't used Google in a year.
I mean, it's just it's literally I have
not used Google in a year. I have a
question, it's ChatGPT for sure. He's
all ChatGPT.
&gt;&gt; I I love chat.
This episode of the Good Guys podcast is
brought to you by our friends at Signos.
Folks, did you know that 73.6%
of US adults are classified as
overweight or obese? It's not mean, it's
the truth. 88% of Americans are
classified as metabolically unhealthy.
Global diabetes diagnoses are projected
to reach 1.3 billion by 2050. I'm not
here to scare you, I'm here to talk to
you about Signos. When you eat carbs,
your blood sugar rises. Your body
releases insulin to shuttle that sugar
into your cells for energy. But, if
you're insulin resistant, the sugar
doesn't get used properly. It lingers in
your bloodstream. That's when weight
gain, fatigue, and long-term health
risks start to build. And most
importantly for me, brain fog. That's
why when I eat a bagel on the podcast,
all of a sudden, I can't see straight.
That's because my blood sugar is out of
whack. And you How did I learn that,
folks? How did I learn that? Because of
Signos. Signos packages an AI-powered
platform for deciphering unique
metabolisms with a continuous glucose
monitor or biosensor, which enables
users to see how food choices, timing,
activity, stress, and even sleep affect
their bodies in real time. You get to
learn what foods actually cause your
blood sugar spikes. So, you can uh avoid
them, or maybe eat them at a time where
you don't have an incredibly important
meeting or incredibly important podcast
where you need to be incredibly sharp,
okay? You get in-the-moment alerts when
your glucose is rising, plus
personalized suggestions like taking a
quick walk. You understand the
difference between physical hunger and
stress eating. And most importantly, you
feel more energized throughout the day
and sleep better at night after taking
the insights that you get from Signos
and transferring them to your daily
life. So, folks, if this sounds like
something that could interest you,
Signos took the guesswork out of
managing my weight and gave me
personalized insights into how my body
works, and I'm sure they can do the same
for you. With an AI-powered app and
biosensor, Signos helped me build
healthier habits and stick to them.
Right now, Signos has an exclusive offer
for our listeners. If you go to signos,
signos.com,
you get $10 off select plans with code
good guys. That's signos.com code good
guys for $10 off select plans today.
This episode of the Good Guys podcast is
brought to you by our friends at
Function. Folks, I chose Function
because it's the only health platform
that gives me data most people never get
and the insights to start doing
something about it. Inside Function, you
get access to test over 100 biomarkers,
from hormones to toxins to markers of
heart health, inflammation, and stress.
For an additional fee, you can also
access MRI and chest CT scans, all
tracked in one secure place over time.
It's in your 360° view to better see
what's happening in your body. That's
why top health leaders such as Dr. Mark
Hyman, Dr. Andrew Huberman, Dr. Jeremy
London, Dr. Benjamin Salfer are all
behind Function. Folks, if I'm behind
Function, you got to take a look at
this, okay? Because lab visits fast and
convenient at over 2,000 locations
across the US. It's just $4.99 a year.
That's $1.37 a day for advanced health
insights. You literally spend $4.99 on
something so much sillier than your
health. You should absolutely consider
this. All results are tracked over time
in one secure place. So, you see how
your health evolves. Insights come from
top doctors based on your unique
results. And folks, if you tried to do
this on your own, I know what you're
thinking. $4.99, Ben. I can do that on
my own. You can't. It would cost you 10
grand. What are you, nuts? Do it through
Function. I'm telling you, folks, do it
through Function. And Function doesn't
push supplements or pharmaceuticals.
It's just powerful, unbiased data
designed to help you own your health.
So, folks, are you ready to sign up for
Function? Of course, you are, because
it's absolutely fantastic. I love it. I
got my biomarkers checked. I found out
what I was deficient in. You're going to
find out what you're deficient in, too.
You're going to optimize. You're going
to supplement. You're going to become
the best version of yourself.
Learn more and join using our link.
Function is in your 360° view to see
what's happening in your body. And the
first 1,000 people get a $100 credit
towards their membership. Visit
functionhealth.com/goodguys
or use gift code good guys 100 at sign
up to own your health. That's
functionhealth.com/goodguys.
Rings? Like, or Is it called the ring or
Instagram rings?
&gt;&gt; Rings. Just rings.
&gt;&gt; The award show? Rings, rings, rings.
Josh, you've heard of rings? No, what is
this? Another award I'm not nominated
for?
Yeah, ring Well, we need to find out how
we get nominated for rings.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; Oh.
Really? Rings Rings is the Emmys of
Instagram. They are awarding creators.
They have a format. And we were nowhere
to be found.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; We get it. Give it to I show speed. What
did he say?
He's so talented. [laughter]
Something like that. Something like
that. Oh, man. Oh, god. When is that? Uh
so, we just did our first
&gt;&gt; It happened. It happened. I didn't even
get [laughter] an invite. It happened.
No, we lost. It's over. We lost.
&gt;&gt; small.
The idea was to try to recognize
creatives from different countries and
in different verticals. And do something
small to start. I don't think you can go
out of the gate if you want this to
matter long term and try to blow it out
of the water. You got to like build it
up and earn that credibility over time.
So, we'll see how it goes.
But, we had about 13 12 or 13 judges
who nominated people plus a bunch that
we pulled just from Instagram and then
they voted and then we had 25 winners.
We just had a dinner in New York about a
week or two ago.
And we gave them an actual ring
designed by this amazingly talented
designer named Grace Wales Bonner out of
London.
Actually, she got hired to be the
creative director for Hermes men like
the next week.
And we also gave him a couple kind of
fun little things in Instagram. So,
they can they get the they get a
their story ring is a different style,
you know, a ring. They can make their
profile any color they want. So, if you
stumble upon one of these profiles and
it's just green or wild yellow that
they're they're one of the winners. And
there's one or two more things going to
come out for them over the next couple
months. But, just try to give some of
the most interesting creatives and
smaller ones
their flowers. Some of the judges were
pretty big names, but we tried to find
up-and-coming talent on the on the on
the creative side.
That's cool. That Super cool. Yeah, I
like the small I like you awarding
smaller creatives cuz pretty much
whatever Ben and I are sending back and
forth it other than the New York City
mayoral race Ben [laughter]
and I sending like these people have 40
followers, but we'll be like this is
maybe some of the great comedy.
&gt;&gt; That's the best stuff. When you can find
a small creator who just crushes, that's
I think that's the good stuff. Oh, yeah.
And news anchor fuck-ups Josh, have you
seen these recently? The news anchor
fuck-ups.
&gt;&gt; Shepard Smith
The woman reading Latits, have you seen
that one? It's the she's trying to
pronounce a town.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; Oh, no. And she just goes Latits and
they're like it's Letits.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; I just saw a reel this morning. It was
just mispronunciations of news anchors
in a row just getting progressively
worse worse and worse. Oh, yeah.
&gt;&gt; The only one I can remember was this guy
read manslaughter as man's laughter.
Oh, that's good. So good.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; They're so good. All of them? All of
them. All of them are so funny.
Oh, man.
&gt;&gt; Man's laughter.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; What um can we can I put you on the
spot?
&gt;&gt; Please. Can we know the president of
Instagram screen time? Oh, yeah.
Yeah, sure. Hold on. Where's my screen?
I I was trying to figure out where you
were going with that. I was like, "Wow,
he's really asking his salary?"
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; I'm sure that's public. I'm a
shareholder. I can find that out right
now. Oh, my.
&gt;&gt; Please. All right.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; Where is it? Where's screen time? Did
they move screen time in the new one?
Here it is. Got it. Okay. So,
average this week 4 hours and 19 minutes
a day.
&gt;&gt; [snorts]
&gt;&gt; Stop it. What the hell? You're the
president of the biggest social media
company in the world and I'm double on
my phone. Yeah, well,
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
That's why he's the president. He uses
your phone.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; It doesn't maybe is this No, I think
that's I mean that's what it says. I
didn't This phone is new. So, I don't
have Sundays. So, maybe it dragged the
average down, but I think it does it
properly.
&gt;&gt; Can that be? And how much time on
Instagram? Well,
it won't it puts all of the because they
have the dev builds for all the meta
apps. It puts them all together. So, I
can't really see that. Plus, I spend a
lot of time on my desktop on it. So, it
probably underestimates it. Wow, I'm not
a big Instagram desktop guy. I'm not Is
it What's that experience like? I for me
it's work cuz I'm using it to like I
like I said, I like to go in the
requests folder. So, I'll go in there
when I'm working if I'm between
meetings, I'll go there and I'll just go
through a bunch of requests and send a
bunch of replies. And what does a day
look like for you? Like an average day
as the president of Instagram? It's very
uh
it's a very strange job. So, it could be
it just I mean, there's a there's How do
I explain this?
There's a few modes of operation.
There's one like what a typical day
looks like. So, a typical day would be
go to the office, you know, obviously
wake up
wake up the kid well, they wake me up,
feed them breakfast, then get them out
of the house. We talked about the kids
stuff before maybe before the book was
recording. But, the the first 90 minutes
is 100% about these three boys who don't
listen to me. Ah, Dad, I want cereal.
I'm the president of Instagram.
[laughter]
Can you get the Lucky Charms? Come on,
Dad. Why [laughter] wait?
That was good.
I love how Adam Waheed keeps coming up
with this.
He's [laughter]
a sweetie.
He's weird. YEAH, GOOD.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; GRACIE ANN, THE [laughter] BIG WINNER.
OH, my god. He has nightmares about Adam
Waheed waking up in the middle of the
night.
Shut [laughter] up.
Okay, so a typical day is just a bunch
of meetings and then a bunch of
spreadsheets and emails. Like I'll meet
with my my staff, the people who work
for me directly. I'll do a couple
product reviews of teams who are working
on things like maybe a team is working
on like a new safety feature. Like you
know, we have like team who worked on
teen accounts which launched last year.
So, I'll meet with them and go over
their road map.
I'll go represent Instagram within Meta
at other meetings. So, maybe there's a
leadership meeting across the execs from
all the family all the app leads to talk
about something.
A one-on-one with someone. It's very
schizophrenic. It could be from safety
to a new creative feature to meeting a
creator to having a one-on-one to you
know, I don't know whatever else comes
up.
But, then that's one mode of operation.
And then the other mode is
everything gets flipped on its head.
Like I'll be on the road. So, you know,
I you know, I'll go to India and I'll
meet with a bunch of creators, do we'll
host an event, I'll do a meeting with a
minister or a policy maker. I'll do some
press, you know, and then I'll get on a
plane to go to New York and it'll be a
completely different 3 days, you know.
So, it can be and that's very like
everything is different for between 2
and 10 days and then I go back to my
normal routine. And do you get like um
do you get briefed in the morning? Like
does your team go like, "Here's what
happened in the last 24 hours on
Instagram?" Or here Oh, no, that sounds
nice. No, I I have a bunch of dashboards
[laughter] that I look at. So, in the
morning I will almost always
start by
getting a sense of you know, my inbox.
So, you know, I get a lot of emails. And
then I'll take a look at what's what how
the platform is doing. So, I'll look at
all right like how you know, are people
using it you know, more or less? Are
they sharing more or less? You know,
what does it look How does it How do the
trends look in different countries? Is
there something unexpected going on to
just to ground myself in the data.
And what what happens when like you get
a call that Kanye's popping off, right?
On on Instagram. I'm sure people are
going to love three Jews talking about
Kanye. Um but like you know, What could
go wrong?
&gt;&gt; It's a part
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; It's a part of
he just came to mind, but like someone
with a massive amount of followers is
starting to go is be slightly erratic.
What does that chain of command look
like? What what actions take are taken?
So, if someone so,
even if you're Kanye, if you're
anybody who's a big account, if you're
violating the community standards and
the content doesn't isn't allowed on
Instagram, it'll get taken down.
Um so, that's not really much of a
conversation. If someone is like pushing
the boundaries or starting to get a
little you know, it looks like they
might be going in a weird place or
something's off,
it's it's the partnerships team that
will handle it. So, they'll like try to
talk to them and they'll be like, "Hey,
just
so you know, like this is what is
allowed. This is what's not allowed."
Like try to make sure that they have
good information so they can make
informed decisions about what to do or
not do on the platform. And then but
ultimately, they get
um we have to try and do our best to
balance both speech which we believe in
deeply and we think is super important,
but also safety which matters a ton.
But, it must also be it you know, when
you're going to lock someone out of
their account that's a super public
person, I'm sure there's there's a big
conversation right of how close to the
edge are they getting? Yeah, yeah. We'll
try to just make sure we don't make any
mistakes. So, if it's someone if it's a
major account, we'll just try to make
sure cuz we make a I mean, there's
millions of things reported every day if
not more. So,
there's systems that try to do this at
scale. There's both classifiers and
technology but also tens of thousands of
people who look at content and make
decisions. They're content moderators.
But, if it's a major account, we'll just
try to really make sure that we don't
make a mistake. We'll double triple
check it. Make sure someone senior looks
at it and is like, "No, this is or this
is not violating." Right.
Good to know. It's more costly to make
mistakes with big accounts. So, we try
to invest more to make sure we make less
mistakes. But, we want to make less
mistakes everywhere.
It's not good for us ever to make a
mistake.
I mean, you think about someone like who
is the number one person? Ronaldo? On
Instagram? By followers?
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
Um it might be. I think it might be. I
mean, actually I think the Instagram
account might be the biggest is the
biggest, but that's not really fair. So,
Ronaldo's one of the biggest. Why is
that not fair? Just cuz it it might not
get as much engagement as someone with
less followers? No, it's just it is On
Instagram, you expect people to go find
and search for Instagram. I think it's
just I'm I'm surprised that you guys
didn't pull a YouTube
on like what Oh yeah, yeah, or no, or
Tom. When on on the Apple on the Apple
product
you got Yeah, like you got the Nano and
that stupid YouTube album was on it.
Like I'm surprised
&gt;&gt; in your phone into your car for like 5
years.
Yes, it would play that stupid Yeah, it
was bad. It would play.
Like I'm surprised that when you I'm
surprised that when you download
Instagram you're not automatic like I'm
surprised Instagram doesn't have 3
billion followers.
&gt;&gt; No, I think it's good for us to to I
mean look it would be
it wouldn't be crazy. People have done
it, but I think it's good for us to
experience what it's like to actually
try to use the platform. And that that
builds empathy but also just
understanding of what's working what's
not. There's not that many people who
work at Instagram who have large
followings. There's maybe like two or
three of us. So actually I find bugs all
the time that the team doesn't find cuz
they don't have the same experience cuz
they don't have
thousands of people messaging them angry
things, you know, so they like their DMs
just look very different. The request
folder loads just fine for them. And I'm
like this is slow as hell. Like we got
to fix this. Can you ever reply with a
little sass?
Just a little. I think [laughter] about
it all time.
I think about it all the time. I I have
recently.
&gt;&gt; Really? What Give me a good example.
Clelia Clelia was a little sass.
&gt;&gt; Not a little. That was cute.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; I am I work with a a foundation called
Feed the Streets in LA. Mhm. We're a
very small grassroots and we do four
feeds a week on Skid Row, MacArthur
Park, just helping the homeless.
&gt;&gt; I mean that's like where they need it
most. Yeah, and it's great and it's just
a group of us. And so when I'm there I
always will try to post something cuz I
have 17 million followers. Like
can't hurt. Yeah. And also we don't have
a social media team.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. And someone wrote me something to
the effect of like feeding the homeless
and posting it on your social media,
what a loser.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; And I was like
This will not stand.
Someone said something on the internet
somewhere I disagree with. I must
engage. I was like brother. So I wrote
him back. I said, "Hi." I was [laughter]
like
"So glad you discovered Feed the Streets
on social media as many of our
volunteers have because of posts like
this."
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; "I said, please feel free to join us
anytime." And I ended it with "I'm there
every week.
Come find me, dog." Oh man.
I didn't write "Come find me, dog." but
you know, it was inferred.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; No, I don't think that I don't think I
don't think it's
I don't think it would go well for me to
to get sassy. So I think I should just
keep it straight.
It's always a temptation for a little
sass.
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; This episode of the Good Guys podcast is
brought to you by our friends at Warby
Parker. Folks, I love Warby Parker. I
love Warby Parker. I love Warby Parker.
I wear Warby Parker. When you see me in
those green shades, I'm wearing Warby
Parker. Because Warby Parker is
convenient. Because Warby Parker has
wonderful customer service. Because
Warby Parker is the right cost for a
premium product. I walked into a Warby
Parker Manhattan. I needed new glasses.
I said to myself, you know, I don't want
to pay too much for a pair of glasses,
but I really want great glasses. And I
want them right now. And I walked into a
Warby Parker. I picked out what I
wanted. I picked out those gorgeous
green frames. I had a lovely person help
me out. And I paid like literally $100.
It was unparalleled how much cheaper
Warby Parker was than any of the
competitors that I have ever tried. And
the best part is, folks, they have an
eye doctor on site. So if you don't want
to go to the eye doctor, wait for them
to write a prescription, send it over to
you, walk into a Warby Parker, you can
do it literally right there. I did it
right there. They also fit me for
contacts. They fit me for contacts at
the Warby Parker. And I can buy my
contacts through Warby Parker. Warby
Parker is this one-stop shop. Let me
tell you, they are absolutely fantastic.
There is no other option. If you are
looking for glasses, if you are looking
for contacts, the quality uncompromised.
It's so unbelievably easy with their
stores and online. And they're
unbelievably affordable. I literally it
was $95.
$95?
That is just so perfectly priced.
I couldn't recommend Warby Parker more.
So folks, Warby Parker has over 300
locations to help you find your next
pair of glasses. You can head over to
warbyparker.com/goodguys
right now to try on any pair virtually.
Look at this tech. How cool are they?
That's warbyparker.com/goodguys.
warbyparker.com/goodguys
today.
&gt;&gt; [music]
&gt;&gt; I have a I have a very random question.
With 3 billion users, do you guys ever
think about incubating products? Like
obviously like you guys are the
marketplace for
advertising. You have creators
advertising, you have creators launching
their own brands. Like you you could
obviously have the greatest VC
incubation arm of CG products of all
time. Like is that ever is that ever a
thought?
Not really. I mean we've talked about
it. I think in general we would rather
be a marketing platform for the people
who are going to be better at building
products than us to market and find
audiences for those products.
I think in general it's an it's a it's a
very fortunate opportunity for us to be
a platform. It doesn't come without its
responsibilities. There's a lot of
responsibility for it, but it's it's
nice to
not have to deal with
producing much hardware outside of the
data centers. It's nice not to
have to produce a ton of content outside
of our own channels. It's I think
platform is just a remarkably
amazing business. Now look at as a
company we do get into other industries,
right? You know, we make
hardware with you know, the sort of
smart glasses and the AR glasses and
we've done obviously virtual reality
headsets. Patagonia jackets.
&gt;&gt; Patagonia jackets, yeah.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; I saw that one that you were wearing
together.
Um but for [clears throat] Instagram I
think we're we like to try to
we like to try to keep it focused. I
feel like Instagram is too complicated
as it is.
In general I'm trying to figure out ways
for us to do less things and do them
better. And so I think focus is really a
major part of the ethos that Kevin and
Mike
really started the company and the group
with. And so I want to make sure we stay
true to that. But it has to be so hard
to stay that focused, right? Like I
again, this is why I I should never be
the president of Instagram. But with 3
billion users like you could take out
Uber tomorrow. Like you can just you can
just build Uber. Like the hardest thing
is acquiring 3 billion people. Like it's
it's
mind-blowing to me. Like
&gt;&gt; It's it's an immense amount of reach and
opportunity, but I also think we often
underestimate what it takes to do
something well.
Um
and so I still I still feel like we
don't do most of what we should do as
well as we should. I'm constantly
feeling like
we should be doing better. I'm
constantly feeling like I should be
doing better. Maybe that's just my you
know,
my my my character trait or flaw.
Um but I would watch I'd much rather
get to best in class across the key
things first before expanding to
something else if I could.
This is you one of our last two
questions. This is you know, this is
asked during all presidential elections
and you're a president.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; So we're going to Definitely not a
president, but but let's do it.
What keeps you up at night? Oh my god,
all I do is worry.
About Instagram.
&gt;&gt; About Instagram.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; I swear to you I mean just how many
times how many things do you want? Like
what could go like what's the call you
fear? A server went down? Like Adam
Waheed moves to TikTok? [laughter]
Still going back to Adam.
Um
I think most of my concerns
ladder up to us
I think failing to adapt as the world
changes around us.
So you know, we're a big company. Um the
team is big. The team is thousands of
people. The company's you know, tens of
thousands of people.
In usually what happens when you're in a
position like we are is that not it's
not that competition isn't a risk.
Sorry, it's not that competition isn't a
risk. Competition is a risk. What what
really happens is competition adapts to
the world as it changes faster than you
do. So whether it is
you know, minimizing the bad so
addressing safety concerns and keeping
people safe on the platform or it's
maximizing the good leaning into
whatever the new trend is on how people
entertain themselves or connect with
friends.
You know, you if you don't move quickly
someone else will. And you might move
slower because
you're too risk-averse or you're too
worried about, you know, revenue this
quarter or you are not connected with
what the trends are that are happening
or there's too much regulatory burden or
there's too much in-fighting and
or complacency. Like it almost always
ladders up to failing to adapt. And so I
[clears throat] worry most of my fears
are about
us missing things that are important
either opportunities to maximize the
good or minimize the bad.
And then that really adding up over time
and getting the better of us. Yeah. You
need to be more like that, Ben.
You need to think that way.
&gt;&gt; You're the president of this spot. I
think you're doing great.
&gt;&gt; He is.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; Thank you. I'm so lucky to have him. But
he's like a real businessman.
I'm the actor kind of. The talent? What
do you call it? Yes, the talent.
Just double clicking on that for 1
second. I just as you have three kids,
Josh has three kids, I have a baby boy.
Are we spoke about this in the last
podcast. Like when are we going to allow
our kids to even have phones?
&gt;&gt; question.
&gt;&gt; And Josh and I are are big proponents of
really really really [__] late. Yeah.
And you're and you're talking about like
Instagram for teens. Like how do you
approach Like there's there's two sides
to the coin, right? Of course make
Instagram safe. I'm sure that's
something that keeps you up at night.
But on this on the flip side of that
like
just like these constant dopamine hits,
no matter how safe Instagram is for
kids, phones in general. Like, do you
have a do you have a perspective on
that? Like, like, when should kids
really be downloading apps? When should
they be getting smartphones? Do you have
a perspective there? Yeah. I mean, I
would say a few different things. And
maybe I'll take off my Instagram hat for
a second and just focus on me, Adam, as
a dad.
I think it's important
to be honest about the fact that every
kid is different.
And their needs and their risks are
different. I wouldn't be surprised if I
don't feel that my three boys are all
ready at the same age for smartphones or
for social media.
Um I you know, they're so different. You
only have one, so you probably don't
know this yet, but you've got three.
There's no better lesson on the question
of nature versus nurture than having
three. And you're like, you are all
completely different. And I'm pretty
sure I raised you more or less the same.
Yeah. And so I think it's about one,
understanding your individual child's
needs.
Um and then two, trying to meet those
needs, but for me, I think what matters
is boundaries. I think it's super
important for parents to set boundaries
in general. My mom always used to tell
me when I went out of the house as a
college as a high school kid, she always
say moderation, which I thought was like
a reasonable but realistic ask.
But for me with my kids, they're not old
enough for social media, they're nine,
seven, and five. But they have iPads,
they play video games.
And for me, it's like, okay, well, what
are the rules, right? They have they can
only play it on the weekends.
They have to earn their time. So, you
know, for every 30 minutes of homework
that they do, they earn 30 minutes.
And I'll never take the time away cuz I
I used to do that and that was wildly
disregulating and that ended up really
badly for everybody.
Um but it's capped.
And so they know it, they know they're
not allowed to play until 7:00 a.m. so
they don't have an excuse to come into
my room at 5:00 a.m. and wake me up to
try to get on an iPad.
So I just create boundaries.
What's hard it's but but I would want to
acknowledge that it's much easier said
than done. We're trying as a platform to
provide tools to help parents enforce
those boundaries so you can actually say
my teen can only use Instagram on these
days or for this amount of time. You can
actually, you know, set that up and then
we will enforce it on your behalf.
But I think that combination of
understanding an individual child's
needs and risks and then
setting up clear boundaries, I think is
maybe the two most important pieces of
advice I would give a parent when trying
to decide when is your kid ready for a
phone or a lot of kids I know
um my kids don't have them yet. They're
getting like smartwatches cuz their
parent in the city wants to know where
the kid is.
&gt;&gt; Sure.
Um or, you know, access to
the internet. Like, my my kid wants
access to the computer now cuz he likes
to do research about Pokémon and things.
And honestly,
you know, if he can open up Safari, he
can and he's pretty smart, he can get he
can find anything. And so it's not just
about social media or even phones, it's
just if you have access to the internet,
you have access to anything that you
could find on the internet if you want
if you were looking for it. So,
you know, there's it's important for
parents to set up boundaries and to
educate their kids and to think about
their kids' individual needs. Yeah.
Isn't it crazy Pokémon was big for us
and now it's big for our kids.
&gt;&gt; I cannot believe how big it is. They
love it. They're obsessed. Yeah. My kid
can rattle off like the evolutions of
any random Pokémon from like any series.
He just like studies them
&gt;&gt; Wow. That's smart. for fun. Like my kid,
he just goes, "A shiny one." Oh, yeah.
I was I took notes. I was like,
[laughter] you got to meet your kids
where they're at. So I was like, explain
this to me. It's complicated.
&gt;&gt; It is. The card game is really
complicated. Yeah.
&gt;&gt; There's a lot going on.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; Okay, so before our final question, what
do you nut moment of the week, I just
want to say here officially, there is a
a such thing as shadow banning or there
isn't.
So it means different things to
different people. People use that term
to just say they're not getting as much
reach as they think they deserve.
There are instances in which we will
limit someone's reach. So if you posted
a bunch of content that got taken down
recently, if you're not
if you're posting content that doesn't
violate our community guidelines but we
don't but violates our recommendation
guidelines, so we won't show it to
people who don't follow you. Mhm. You
will have a limited reach, but you can
see it. You can go to profile settings,
account status, and you can see if there
are any
issues on your account and then you can
try to either appeal them if you think
we made a mistake or remove the content
if you, you know, see that that's why
you're not being recommended anymore.
And so you can go see it. Um so but yes,
your account can
have its reach limited, but you can go
to profile settings, account status, and
then
see what's going on and then act on that
information. And then once you correct
it, I find there's there've been a few
times and it's really the only times
that I've ever posted anything
political, I'll just see just it's just
a downtrend in in in reach. Yeah. After
I post any and it's rare, maybe every
couple years.
Um and then I just give it a couple days
and it like shakes out. Like it it sort
of has to find its medium, but it takes
like a week or two. So,
what's probably happening there without
looking into your specific account is
it's not that you're posting about
politics or like, no, we want to
downrank politics. We don't do that.
It's that a lot of people who followed
you because you don't normally post
about politics didn't follow you for
your political opinions. Right.
&gt;&gt; And so they maybe were less likely to
interact or like or share that when they
saw it. And so we just it looks like
it's doing less well to us than the
normal piece of content. We don't even
know if it's about politics.
It's just getting less engagement per
impression than your average post and so
it does less well cuz we just think it's
less interesting to other people.
Whereas there are accounts who post
about politics all the time and that's
why people follow them and they tend to
do well in general. So,
if you if you really pivot subjects
often, you know, either to or away from
something politics or otherwise, you you
can often see your reach go down because
it's just because that's not why people
followed you in the first place.
Wow.
&gt;&gt; Doesn't mean you shouldn't do it. You
should just know why it's happening.
Good to know. That's it. Uh no more
endorsements from Josh Peck.
&gt;&gt; Okay. It's it's funny. It's it's funny,
Josh. When I write a political megillah
on Instagram stories, it gets the most
reach out of anything. I'm not even
kidding. Like when I post when I post
like a static with text on stories, it
destroys. Interesting.
&gt;&gt; Versus when I do a video, it's so weird.
It's like I like like destroys. My my
reach will be like 30% of my followers.
Some people find photos and videos most
people find the opposite, but I
definitely hear regularly from creators
who find that either carousels in feed
with photos or stories or photos in
stories do better for them than videos.
I hear that regularly. Yeah, so
&gt;&gt; But my dear Ben, I must say you are like
I know you always say you're not
political. I would say you're political
adjacent and I don't think that's
negative, but I think you make sure when
you feel passionate about something you
speak up. 100%. Uh I guess it was more
to what Adam said, which is I don't
think anybody followed me for my
political opinions or or for my
commentary. So the fact that they do so
well had me thinking, is it simply the
format that I'm putting text on
like that it's not a video versus what
I'm actually saying. I don't I don't
know the answer. Um but I just always
found it incredibly interesting that
like
a story like that will get 400,000 views
and it's like that's a lot of views.
third of my reach. Like why is it why is
it so big? Yeah, because your feed is
like goes from look at this big caniche
to what's Gavin Newsom thinking?
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; YES, WE GOT HIM. THE OTHER WAY.
HONESTLY, that's
that's true. It goes from a salami to
Mom Donny.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; Should we get to what do you nut spin?
Absolutely, Adam. This is gripes with
people, places, and things, whatever's
sticking in your craw. San Francisco,
you're a walking woody and nuts. You
absolutely have one. Okay, you have one.
Uh Josh
&gt;&gt; want to think, we can go first. It's our
This is our final question. So, we we
each do one. Do you want to think about
it?
I can tell you the first one that came
to my mind, but I'm also happy to let
you guys go first [laughter] and see
what this is all about. Yeah, but if one
popped into your head that was good,
feel free.
&gt;&gt; I'll give you So I just I don't want to
sound like a bad dad, but but
but my 7-year-old is the first thing
that popped into my head. So my wife
doesn't get up early. I usually get up
before she does and I'm kind of on
breakfast duty when she comes down.
And at 7:00, I mean, it's all all
morning from from 6:00 a.m. on, it's
unbelievable what this one does. So
first,
he will
I don't know why I'm saying this on on
being [laughter] recorded, but he will
come into my room at around 6:00 on the
dot. He'll come into my bathroom and
he'll take his morning poop.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; Solid.
He has a bathroom. There's no reason for
him to be
At least now he's old enough, but he
used [laughter] to yell like, "Will
someone wipe my butt?"
That's how I wake up at like 5:50
[laughter] in the morning.
And then it's just a fight for the whole
for the next 90 minutes. It's like,
you know, he punches his friend his
brother in the back of the head for no
reason. He won't eat his whatever. It's
it's eggs and bacon. Who doesn't like
bacon?
And then the thing that really gets me
is that like 7:55, we leave at 8:00.
I'll be like, "All right. Everybody
out." Like shoes and socks. I'm like I'm
like done. I need to get you guys out of
the house.
Shoes and socks. Everyone shoes and
socks on. And then, you know, I know I
shepherd them over and he will just turn
around, walk straight to the couch, and
then pick up the remote and turn on the
TV and then yell at me, "Where's the
baseball game?" And I'm like, "What do
you
Nat What do you First [laughter] of all,
there's no baseball game. It's 8:00 in
the morning. Like, we just said everyone
your brother's by the He's getting his
shoes on. Like,
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; his ability to completely ignore me
entirely Great.
&gt;&gt; is unbelievable. I I have this this the
contrast between going to work
and saying the wrong thing and having 50
people go in the wrong direction for a
month and fighting for like fifth most
influential in my household. It goes
like my 7-year-old, my wife, my
9-year-old, my 5-year-old, and then me
and the nanny are battling for fifth on
a daily basis.
Is like unbelievable. I just wish like I
had a little bit more sway at home and a
little bit less at work. But he's the
one who's always humbling. It's just I
can say he just walks away. Just you're
like go left. He's like I'm going to go
right now and just walks away. It's I
I'm it drives me it drives me nuts. It's
different than what do you nuts? No,
it's perfect. And the next time he does
that you say, "What do you nuts?"
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Yeah. He'll throw that right at
me.
We're late for school. Shohei's pitching
a no-hitter.
&gt;&gt; Yes. Son, you're delusional. [laughter]
We got to go.
That's literally my life every morning.
Oh, I love it.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that's a great that's a great one.
Uh my what do you nuts moment, I was
I was at Equinox the other day on the
treadmill. And I was very proudly Josh
knows three and a half speed 12 incline
30 minutes. I'm
Nice.
&gt;&gt; I'm grooving. A good low intensity
steady state.
Corner of my eye, I see an older
gentleman, probably 60 years old. You
just see him.
Two drumsticks.
Drumming.
Drumming. He's sitting he's next to like
a machine. Air drumming. Drumming.
Drumming. All of a sudden I see he takes
a stick, throws it against the floor, he
tries to catch it, he misses it, it
bounces away. He goes back, he's
drumming. He throws it against the
floor, he tries to catch it, he misses
it. He's drumming, he throws it against
the floor, he finally catches it, he
goes, "Yeah!" And he [laughter] is just
practicing.
He is practicing drumming, AirPods in,
like full endurance level drumming at
the gym, fully air drums. What do you
nuts? Okay, this is Equinox. Do you know
where the [__] you are? Are you out of
your goddamn mind? Like what are you
even doing? Like everybody is looking at
him like, "This guy is This guy is
crazy." And he is just AirPods in.
Drumming. And like his foot, you can't
see my foot. They can see my foot. You
guys can't see my foot because of the
new Mac and the way it zooms in on my
face so close. He's like doing the pedal
with his foot and jamming his wrists.
Insanity. Completely nuts. I feel like
you got to say hi to that guy.
Yeah, he No, he's going to shiv me on
the way out. I have no interest in
saying hi to that guy. Literally a
little knife comes out of this one of
his drumsticks. I have no interest
[laughter]
in that crazy man. My what do you nuts
is um
as we all know, I'm a Costco daddy. Love
a Costco. Love a sample.
Look, one sample per person is what do
you nuts? If your sample is off the
charts, be proud and let me get another.
What do you nuts? Let me go for round
two. What's the big deal? It's a sample.
Like you're not going to go under from a
sample. And I don't cuz I do go for a
second and we got to do the no eye
contact, right? Just look away. [snorts]
And then I just go like I act like
[laughter] I'm on the phone or I'm
looking at my watch. And but like can't
I just like look you dead in the eyes
and go, "That was fabulous. I'll have
another." What do you nuts?
I used to do that, Josh. I'm sure you
did this too as a overweight youth. I
would I would walk around I would walk
around the mall and I would like grab
like a nice sesame chicken taster Yeah.
&gt;&gt; from the Chinese place and then I would
come back around with my hood up and I
would grab [laughter] another one. Oh my
god.
No.
And so are you in the Antifa? No, I'm
just fat. [laughter]
No, I'm I'm just
starving.
I would go back and I would I will go
back and I'll take two extra, but then
I'll also take the thing and buy it.
That's like my That's like my cover.
It's like, "All right, I will buy these
pop whatever popcorn things, but I'm but
I'm also going to take another couple
extra." I feel like that like gets me
the cover I need.
&gt;&gt; Smart.
It's why he's a person. It balances
[laughter] out well.
Thank you for doing this, man.
&gt;&gt; Adam, it's been an absolute pleasure,
Adam. Thank you so much for joining us.
Anything that you want to plug, anything
that you want to say before we hop off?
&gt;&gt; No, I just appreciate the time. I think
um it's
parenting is tough. Uh little humor goes
a long way, so I was excited to come and
meet you all. So thank you for having
me. Glad. Thanks. Adam Mosseri is a good
guy, folks. Listen to this podcast. This
is five stars. Otherwise, what do you
nuts? Listen to us wherever you get your
podcasts, watch us on YouTube, share our
clips, Instagram, and TikTok. Sorry.
Mondays and Thursdays
we will see you next time.