Welcome to another episode of the Mixed
Signals podcast from us here at
Semaphore. I'm Max Tony. I'm the media
editor at Semaphore. And with me as
always is our editor-inchief, Ben Smith.
Ben, how's it going? Do you like our new
theme music? What do you think about it?
&gt;&gt; I mean, I you know, I think it's great.
I think it captures the uh sophisticated
and yet engaged sensibility of this show
that we we told the AI to write for us.
I have to stop you right there because I
don't want the audience to even think
for a second that this was done by AI. A
human made these uh those sounds that
you were just hearing. Uh and uh they
also uh the audience also probably
picked up the fact that I am much more
invested in the theme music of the show
uh than you were.
&gt;&gt; That's that's why you're the executive
producer, Max.
&gt;&gt; That is true. That is why I am Yeah, I'm
I'm making all the uh the big calls on
the show. But this week, we are so
excited. I didn't make this call. You
actually did. Uh Ben, you booked our
guest uh who we're both extremely stoked
to have on uh Adami. He's the head of
Instagram and we're getting him on a
really interesting week uh in which they
have just rolled out this interesting
new feature in which you can basically
watch Instagram reels on your television
now. Uh Ben, this plays a little bit
into something that we have been talking
about a lot on the show uh it seems like
this year and recently. Yeah, you know,
I've been trying to get Adam on for a
long time because he's been right at the
middle of the Facebook Meta, Instagram
ch, you know, revolution in media. He
was he he ran newsfeed for for for
Facebook when I met him. He's, you know,
very close to Mark Zuckerberg, but he
also comes out of design. And I always,
he may take this as an insult, but I
always thought he was better at talking
to East Coast media types than many of
of his of his Silicon Valley peers and
seem to understand where the media
industry, where the news industry are
coming from. And now he has walked like
directly into our kill zone of is
everything becoming television because
it seems like maybe now Instagram is
becoming television with this this app
as you said, which will they're testing
it out on Amazon Fire TV. Sorry to
everyone to all the uh to all the all
the
&gt;&gt; Roku users
&gt;&gt; all the Roku users the Google Home users
but um
&gt;&gt; but I assume you know but but getting it
ready for a broader roll out and it's a
product that has among other things this
very strange and archaic feature known
as channels.
&gt;&gt; So um strange a lot is a footed
Instagram.
Yeah, I mean, we're obviously really
interested to ask him about those new
features, but also just broadly what
Instagram is in 2025. I feel like I've
been on uh my own kind of personal
Instagram journey. It used to be just
like this thing that I had kind of on
private for me and my friends and I
would post kind of like, you know, uh
pictures of my personal life that I
didn't necessarily want uh everybody to
see or just wanted only my friends to
see and, you know, kind of would post
jokes or whatever. and now it's like uh
my own personal branding uh platform and
I think that they've kind of uh torqued
it to be that way. So we really want to
ask him like where Instagram is now
compared to where it was 5 years ago and
also where it's going cuz I think you
know Adam has talked a lot about this.
It's going to change a lot with AI and
with the ways in which short form video
has just exploded. So it should be a
really interesting conversation.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. At some level the question really
is just like what is social media and
really is social media still a thing. So
I we can we can ask him those questions.
&gt;&gt; Yes, absolutely. We're going to take a
short break and we'll be right back with
Adami right after this.
Okay, Adam, we are so excited to have
you here with us. Uh, I wanted to start
out with kind of a basic question, but
one that Ben and I were both interested
in, which is what is Instagram in 2025?
We feel like it's changed a lot over the
past few years, and it's probably going
to change a lot more over the over the
next few. How would you describe what
Instagram is in 2025? So the mission has
been for a long time to inspire
creativity that connects people. But how
people connect with their friends, how
people create, how people entertain
themselves has changed a lot. So the how
changes constantly and I know that can
be a lot sometimes for people who are
used to things one way. I think the most
important things to understand about
Instagram in 2025 is that the primary
way that people actually share with
friends is through messages. It's not
through stories or feed. And the primary
way that people entertain themselves and
consume public content is video. Um, so
it's a lot of DMs and it's a lot of
reals right now. Um, and then the next
biggest surface is probably stories,
particularly for younger people.
&gt;&gt; So broadcast sharing, which is a term we
use for sharing with lots of people at
once, is still a thing. But that's for
most people primarily a stories pattern,
not a feed pattern. I
&gt;&gt; mean, is this like would you call this
thing a social network?
Yeah, for sure. I think one of our
strengths is the fact that you have your
friends there. Um, the way I think about
it is most uh media or attention
businesses have content that is
differentiated which is why you go and
then more content which might be why you
stay. So you you know maybe you
subscribe to Time Warner when I was a
kid on the East Coast to get to be able
to get access to HBO or maybe now you
subscribe to HBO to get access to a
specific show. Um, for Instagram, the
that that hook for a lot of people is
friend content. Um, so and their
friends. So it might be
&gt;&gt; sharing their biggest moments or sharing
lightweight moments and stories or it
might be them just sending them funny
comedy clips u in DMs, but that's like a
real motivator for people to show up
&gt;&gt; and then they can stay and spend a lot
more time on public content. So, but I
guess so we had actually like sort of an
adequate an etiquette question on on
this front from a mix signals listener
Kyle Chica of the New Yorker who who
wanted me to ask you like just a matter
of etiquette like should people still
post about their daily lives on there or
just DM their friends in private.
&gt;&gt; I think what is old is new is uh again
is definitely a bit of a pattern. We've
seen this with like uh disposable
cameras. Uh we've seen this in general
actually. I think that what's a bit of a
broader theme than than daily life to
grid is
the aesthetic
has just changed a lot. People think of
Instagram, they think of hyperpolished,
photoshopped, high saturation
landscapes, etc. But the content that
is, I think, driving the most cultural
relevance right now is kind of the
opposite of that. It's like unprocessed,
much more raw, much less, you know,
photo dumps. I think people in a world
where they're inundated with hyper
produced content are gravitating more
and more towards content that at least
feels more authentic. you're on today,
Adam, and I've been I've been chasing
you to come on this show for a while,
but you finally had some news to make,
which is Instagram rolling out an a an
app on the the Amazon Fire, which is
which is to say it's I mean, I noticed
it has not only not only will can I put
reels on a big screen, but it will have
channels like news, entertainment, and
and you know, a huge theme of this show
is is that everything is becoming
television. And like that really sounds
to me like wow Instagram is now becoming
television. What is what's going on?
&gt;&gt; So I don't know that I would say that
Instagram is becoming television, but I
we should definitely go deeper into
that. I think that we're just seeing
how important TV is as a format um and
as just a place where people spend time,
right? And historically we've been
fighting, you know, with some pretty
fierce competition for people's time on
mobile phones. Um, but obviously there's
an immense amount of time spent on TV,
particularly here in the US, but also in
Western Europe, also in India, where
we're not even really showing up and
some of our competition is showing up um
with force. So, for us, it's a bit more
about making sure that we're not um
ignoring such an important
media or medium.
&gt;&gt; Um, and honestly, I think we're late to
the game, so we've got a lot of catching
up to do. When when did this become
something that you wanted to do? When
you realized like okay uh you know
obviously plenty of people are watching
uh TV YouTube on their TVs and we'll get
to that but when did you decide that
this was something that uh both that you
wanted to do and that also that
Instagram could uh could do on
television in a way that would feel fun
and interesting and uh you know uh good
for the brand. I guess
&gt;&gt; we've wanted to do it for a long time. I
think it's about when we really decided
to actually do it. I mean, there's other
people who've been pushing for longer,
like um Chris Cox, our CPO, has been
like the most consistent advocate for
the longest, so he should get some
credit, I guess. Um, but we really spun
up a team. Um, I think it might have
been in the late spring of this year.
Uh, so sixish months ago. Um, TV is
difficult to build for. Uh, there's a
lot of fragmentation for all the
different devices. It's a completely new
format. Obviously, for us, the input
device is really difficult. So how do
you and we've all fought typing to our
TV you know your passcode when you can't
dictate you know so all these kind of
fun challenges that we're not used to
but so we started uh we wanted to start
on a um one or two platforms to start
but then quickly expand
&gt;&gt; um and we'll see this is look the first
version um that we're announcing now is
really just that it's a a first version
we we're going to learn a lot I'm sure
we'll get a bunch of things wrong but
we're going to iterate quickly um the
other thing I would say is over the
course of the year it became clear that
though I wish we had done this years ago
the technology is changing in a way that
is going to make this a lot easier right
so for instance um you know being able
to the uplifts in productivity from
engineers dri based on AIdriven tools is
much higher for client and server based
work than for machine learning or AI
based research or foundation based work
and this this type of building app is a
bit more client server Um also you know
the input you know our understanding of
language and input is obviously advanced
significantly by these large language
models which should allow us to do
things um that we would have been much
more difficult to build only two years
ago or even a year ago. So I'm hoping
that we can iterate quickly and get to a
good place quickly.
&gt;&gt; Has the smart TV era also meant kind of
a lot more knowledge about who's
watching ad targeting things like that?
Does that does that affect you?
&gt;&gt; Not too much. I I'm sure there's some of
that for the industry more broadly, but
obviously, you know, our our
understanding of users interest is
primarily based on their usage of our
our apps, which happens obviously on
mobile.
&gt;&gt; So, I don't know that I think we should
be able to bring a much more relevant
ads experience to the TV format than
traditional TV obviously. Um, you know,
we've all watched ads that were for
something that we were not interested in
or even for like the wrong gender
before. or like I grew up all the time
being like, "How is this a thing that
I'm getting an ad for as a [laughter] as
a as a 14-year-old kid?"
&gt;&gt; Um but um
&gt;&gt; it turns out it's cuz you're watching
cable news.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Turns out turns out they don't
know much about me.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. But you're I think of you, Adam,
like and maybe I realize that you might
take this sort of as an insult, but like
as sort of a something
&gt;&gt; I love that preamble before you even
tell me something guy among
technologists or at least somebody who
was always like bilingual. Well, I I
mean I spent when I was at BuzzFeed lots
of time in meetings with people where I
just felt like we really spoke totally
different languages and I always enjoyed
talking to you because I felt like you
were really bilingual and you came up in
design. But
&gt;&gt; but but it does feel to me like the
things that you have spent a lot of your
career building recommendation engines,
newsfeed, the structures around
Instagram and threads are technological.
But there's something about this like
television experience which is leaned
back fundamentally that feels more like
welcome to the media business, Adam. I
mean, do you feel like you've crossed a
threshold here?
&gt;&gt; Um,
if there was a threshold, I feel like
I've been stepping over it slowly for a
long time. I don't know if there's like
a Rubicon, so to speak, but
&gt;&gt; I do feel like this is going to be
humbling. Um, I think that we're going
to learn a lot that we don't know. And I
think that's going to be healthy.
I I'm constantly
concerned about our blind spots. What
are the things that we should be
concerned about or thinking about that
we are not? Uh, and I worry sometimes
that as an industry, we come into new
territories or industries with a lot of
hubris and a lot of confidence. And then
um so I'm I'm kind of expecting that
with us bringing an experience to the
TV. I'm sure there's something that's
going to seem silly obvious in
retrospect that we missed about just
designing the experience and making sure
it's relevant or making sure it's easy
to use. I mean, are you concerned that
what it's going to be is that like high
production scripted dramas like beat out
UGC and next thing you know you're like
competing with Netflix to buy the the
remake of The Office.
&gt;&gt; I really don't want to get into that
business. I think the more likely the
more likely tension would be I don't
know that this will be the case but we
have been very explicitly and
intentionally focused on short form
video on Instagram.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. My belief is that connecting
people with their friends and short form
video can be really symbiotic. You know,
because you see short form videos, you
want to send to your friends. For me,
it's, you know, comedy skits I send to
my brother or, you know, things about
architecture or art I send to my sister.
She's a designer.
&gt;&gt; Um, and then we have conversations. So,
those two things are, you know, they
help each other.
&gt;&gt; And then I think short form and long
form video can be symbiotic.
You know, you watch a couple short form
movies, maybe you watch a long one, you
go back to a couple shorts. Um, I do not
know that connecting people with your
friends and long form video can be
symbiotic. I'm a little bit worried
they're too far apart. You watch a
20-minute video, which doesn't even seem
like long, but in the Instagram world is
very long.
&gt;&gt; That's a lot of reels that you wouldn't
have seen and sent to a friend or seen a
story from a friend or sent a message to
somebody you know or love. M
&gt;&gt; so I think that if this one way this
might fail we'd like to do these
premortems like how how might this not
work before we even find out
&gt;&gt; is that it might turn out that maybe
like you said we'll need premium content
to work um I don't know I think YouTube
is not big into premium um and YouTube
on TVs is much bigger than YouTube TV
for TVs as far as we can tell but it
might be that we need long form video
and then if we need long form video what
does that mean for us because that's
literally been a market we've explicitly
decided not to enter historically.
&gt;&gt; Wait, so before we actually get into
YouTube, because I I can just I can feel
Ben chomping at the bit to to get into
it because we've done so much YouTube
this year. Yeah, he's ready for it. Uh I
want to ask like just a very basic
question here. How do you envision
people using this? Like, okay, so I've
hooked up Instagram now to my to my
television. I have an a we've got Amazon
Fire. This is this is awesome. Now, what
happens? We're just we're watching like
a few some reals. uh in a row. Why would
why wouldn't we just do it on on our
phone? Is it what is that what is the
habit supposed to look like? I guess
&gt;&gt; I don't think we know yet. Um but I have
two different ideas in mind. One is much
more like how you use Instagram but more
passive. So, you know, we all have been
in a place where we want to sort of hack
our mood or watch some funny videos or
whatever it might be and we sit back and
relax and it might just be nicer on a
bigger screen, you know, when you're
home alone. The one that I also think
will be less frequent but maybe more
delightful and exciting and valuable
would be something that was more social.
I mean I don't know if you do this but I
definitely have been in
uh a bunch of situations where like I
really want to watch a bunch of things
with a friend, you know. So with my
brother it's usually comedy because we
both just love standup and I think
laughing is just you know underrated.
you know with you know other people in
my life it's other topics where we sort
of wanted to go deep and rabbit hole
together on something. I think this is
often isn't in the first version but I
think it could be pretty exciting to do
that either in a directed way where you
say here this is the kind of content I
want and as content search gets better
we could deliver on that and then
eventually in a more personalized way
where we're like hey you know you two
are in the room do you want to do you
want to do you want a feed that's just
based on both of your interests. Um, I
don't know if you've ever used Blend,
but it's a pretty funny way to get a
little insight into your friend's
interests.
&gt;&gt; Do you do you see a world in which
people are creating content for uh, you
know, for Instagram on TV? This was
something that came up when we were
talking to Neil Mohan earlier this year
where he was talking about how, you
know, a lot of people, a lot of their
users on YouTube were uh, were were
creating content specifically uh, that
was meant to be watched on uh, you know,
your television screen in your living
room. Is that kind of the goal? Do you
want to get to that place?
&gt;&gt; I think that's not the goal, but I think
that would be a sign of success. I think
that if the volume uh of usage gets so
high that people would actually bother
to create content specifically for
Instagram on TV, that would be a sign
that we had reached scale. But I I think
that's step three or four. I mean, we
have to get something out the door. Then
we have to make it good. Then we have to
scale it across all the platforms. Then
we have to figure out how to grow it. Um
so there's a lot of steps between um now
and then. But that would be I think a
nice signal that we had reached enough
scale that it mattered enough to
somebody to even consider doing that. I
guess I have almost sort of the opposite
question, Adam, which is like it feels
like there was a period and you know I
think Max and I are both and and like
you are veterans of the first pivot to
video for Facebook Watch in which people
were making bespoke contents for each
platform and at BuzzFeed we felt like we
had real expertise on what worked better
on t on on you know Pinterest versus
Facebook or whatever. Um
&gt;&gt; now I think a lot of creators are
treating these as identical channels and
the same vertical video goes on. I mean,
this is certainly true for us and we
were pleased to see when you liked one,
you know, you subscribed to Semaphore on
Instagram for a video. I do think we
posted the identical video to Tik Tok
and to um to shorts.
&gt;&gt; True true story. True story.
&gt;&gt; And and how do you how do you fight that
sort of I mean that's a real that I mean
that sort of threatens to commoditize
you in a way like you
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So there's signals in both
directions. Um so we we care a ton about
creators. I mean the whole identity of
the brand is really around creativity.
We have seen that creators every year
seem to diversify more and more
gradually but steadily. So they use more
and more platforms. There's less and
less creators who are just completely
loyal to one platform. We have heard
both. We've had heard we have heard from
some people that they have a lot of
success in just reposting the same
content across platforms. We've also
found other creators who really believe
deeply in the fact that they've got
different audiences on different
platforms and they find a lot of success
in catering their content to those
audiences. Sometimes it's just slicing
the same content up, but often it's just
completely different content. I think it
probably varies by vertical. Um, and I
don't have a great sense of which
verticals that's true for and false for
and why. Um, but we defin I definitely
hear both a lot. Um, but it is very true
that creators are becoming savvy to the
fact that it's valuable for them to not
have all of their eggs in one basket, to
not be beholden to one algorithm or one
company or one risk of deplatform deep
being deplatformed and are trying to
make sure that they have um just a
diverse business which I think just
makes sense in terms of the risk to us.
Yeah, there's risk there. I think one of
our I mean there's there's things that
both Tik Tok and YouTube are better than
us at in the context of video creation
and distribution. I think Tik Tok is the
best in the industry at breaking new
talent from small names. I think YouTube
is the best in the industry at paying
out creators at scale in a sustainable
way. I think one of our unique strengths
though is we are often not only a video
creators distribution platform but also
a consumption one. I think a lot of
creators use us as a home base um to
consume content not just that's public
but also from their friends to message
people to network. Um, I can't tell you
how many creators I've met from how many
different industries that have made
really important professional
connections because they follow people
whose taste that they love and then end
up collaborating on something from
musicians to journalists to, you know,
film to um authors. So for for creators
with either Tik Tok and YouTube or with
Amazon and Netflix or with CBS and ABC,
like do you feel like you're in a a
competition whether monetary or
otherwise for their attention and time?
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I don't we I can't think of any
bidding wars where there's literally
something that we are bidding on, but we
are certainly in a lot of competition
with particularly YouTube and Tik Tok um
for creators time and attention. Um, and
I think of creators as particularly
important because I feel like across a
lot of industries, power is shifting
from institutions to individuals and so
they seem to be getting more and more
important over time. They punch above
their weight in terms of engagement as
well. Um, but just think about how
relevant athletes are relative to the
teams they play for compared to 10, 20,
or 30 years ago. how relevant
journalists are relative to the mad mast
heads that they work under compared to
10, 20 or 30 years ago. Um, now
obviously AI is a big topic and there's
a lot of concern around being
disintermediated or competing um with
AI, but I think people fundamentally
want to hear from other people um and so
we still feel like creators are one of
the most important audiences for us
across industries.
&gt;&gt; Well, we have a lot that we want to get
to [music] with Adam Masseri, but we
have to take a short break. We'll be
back right after this.
In this week's branded segment from
Think with Google, I spoke to Google's
VP of marketing, Josh Spaniard, about
whether there's space for CMOs in the
boardroom. Usually, when you look at a
corporate board, you see a lot of former
CEOs, CFOs, maybe a legal expert. Josh,
you at Google have been doing some
research which [music] uh which which
suggests that there is a blind spot when
it comes to the composition of corporate
boards.
&gt;&gt; So, that's right, Ben. I've been seeing
this fascinating research [music]
looking at the number of boards which
have a marketer, someone with deep
marketing expertise or a former CMO on
the board. Those companies that do have
a 6% higher growth rate over the study
period than companies that don't. Here's
the challenge and here's the opportunity
for marketing. Just [music] 16% of
boards in the United States have a
marketer or deep marketer on their
board. 84% of companies don't. That's a
real gap. That's the opportunity that
marketing can help with.
&gt;&gt; I suspect CMOs will be glad to hear this
data, but what specifically is it that
makes them valuable?
&gt;&gt; CMOs have always been the voice of the
customer inside [music]
corporations. They are closest to the
customer. They understand them to a deep
level. And in this moment of
unbelievable transformation in how those
customers are discovering your products,
how they're consuming their media, how
they're changing their behavior, having
a CMO who has got that insight directly
at the highest level of the company is
incredibly valuable. But second,
marketing is sitting at the intersection
of AI [music] and nearly every
department with the company. how AI is
transforming your actual products, how
AI is transforming your logistics, how
AI is transforming media [music] and
advertising and every part of what's
going on. Having a CMO who actually
understands those technologies and can
speak to the whole breadth of the
organization at the board level is
really valuable and is changing growth
trajectories.
&gt;&gt; Is there something CMOS ought to be
doing to make themselves more more
attractive board candidates?
&gt;&gt; They have to speak the language of
finance. They have to do all the things
that CMOs meant to be doing. A good
place to start is over at
thinkwithgoogle.com where they can get
the latest insights and learnings on AI
transformation and bring those [music]
insights collected across Google and
across hundreds of companies inside
their organizations.
&gt;&gt; Thanks Josh.
&gt;&gt; Thanks Ben.
&gt;&gt; You were on Peter Kofka's podcast a few
months ago and uh you were talking you
you said something which was interesting
uh to me. You said that Tik Tok was more
aggressive on data in general and just
now you mentioned uh that Tik Tok uh is
good at kind of breaking new uh new
stars or new people. What did you mean
by more aggressive on data and why do
you think Tik Tok has been better at
kind of breaking new people? What what
is it specifically think?
&gt;&gt; So those are related but two different
things happening um on data. I mean I'll
give you some examples of things that
they do that I don't think anybody else
in the industry does. Um, if you message
a Tik Tok video to a friend, that
creates a unique link so that they can
track it. And you can message in any
other app. You don't have to use Tik
Tok. So you can literally send a message
in WhatsApp, which is encrypted, or
Signal, which is encrypted. And then
when the receiver receives it um, and
then taps on it, that opens up Instagram
on the receiver side. So, if I messaged
Ben uh an encrypted message with a Tik
Tok link in WhatsApp and he opened it
and it opened up his Tik Tok, Tik Tok
knows that I sent it to him
&gt;&gt; and it recreates a message thread in Tik
Tok as if I had messaged Ben directly on
Tik Tok.
&gt;&gt; Wow.
&gt;&gt; That is a very aggressive thing to do in
an encrypted messaging world.
&gt;&gt; Um
&gt;&gt; so they are they are all in on those
types of tactics. on you know that's
about data but that's also about growth
&gt;&gt; on breaking talent I think that they
deserve a lot of credit even before bite
dance bought musically Alex and
musically were very leaned in on this
idea of not reinforcing the existing
establishment but helping new talent
grow in the world of ranking
there's something called
explorationbased ranking which is just
more difficult is much easier to find
something that I think you're going to
know a million other people like to find
like that you know only like 100 people
have even seen and but if but if you do
the latter more interesting things
happen and I think you really are kind
of living up to the whole promise of the
internet and niche interests so they
they did a lot and I wouldn't need to go
into the details if unless you want me
to on exploration based ranking systems
really early that the rest of the
industry is caught up on Okay, this is
what I wanted to ask about because I
learned I'm very knowledgeable about
explorationbased ranking in the sense
that I learned about it an hour ago when
I was prepping for this interview and
listening to you on another podcast. But
yes, exactly. So, I'm I've become an
expert. Uh, but Ben, you I'm curious. Do
you know have you do you know what
exploration based ranking is?
&gt;&gt; I do not.
&gt;&gt; Okay. So, then I think it is worth it
for Adam and Ben is a very informed
person. I I think it's worth it, Adam,
for you to explain that because I think
it is really I I'm really fascinated by
it and I'm also curious how you think
you've approached your exploration based
ranking versus what Tik Tok does and
versus what I imagine YouTube is
starting to do as well with YouTube
shorts.
&gt;&gt; The basic idea is that you want to give
every piece of content a chance
regardless of whether or not it's from a
big established account or not. Um, it
is much easier for us to drive up
engagement by showing a lot of photos
and videos from Selena Gomez and The
Rock because they're so big and we know
so many people like them. Um, it is much
more difficult to figure out that you
happen to be in like into afro beats and
you happen to be into like, you know,
crochet scarves, you know. Um, so the
way it works
&gt;&gt; is essentially almost like a little
competition
um where you reserve a certain number of
impressions to try things out. Um, and
you do this in different ways, but I'll
start with the content way, which is you
try to get every piece of content or
some subset of everything if you can't
get everything, you know, a hundred
views, call it, and you see how they do,
you know, even if you had no reason to
think it would be interesting to those
individuals. And then you take a look at
all of the things that you auditioned
and you see what did much better than
you expected. And then you graduate
those to a thousand views and you with
another percentage of your impressions
that you reserved for these auditions.
And then for the things that do
disproportionately well in that a
thousand you up you um graduate again to
call it 10,000 views and so on and so
forth. which is how you can see
something from someone with 50 followers
get millions of views in a couple hours
because they just created something that
happened to wildly outperform everything
else that day. And what is great about
this is you allow new entryants to
become to have hits, not just the
people, not just the sort of uh
established largest names. Um but you
know it comes with a lot of volatility.
It means reach is much more predictable.
It completely relies on unconnected
distribution. So seeing things from
accounts you do not follow which um eats
into the value of follow graphs which is
can be concerning and we get a lot of
complaints from both the creator side
and the consumer side um but also can
be really beneficial from a creator
perspective where you don't want a small
number of creators just to overly
dominate all the impressions. You want
to give new people and new ideas a
chance. And then from a platform
perspective, you have a chance to earn
some real sentiment from these small
creators who make it on your platform.
Um, it's much I think more practical to
try to break the next generation of
creators than to pull an existing
generation of creators over from another
platform. Um, so that's part of that's
one type of exploration based ranking
which is essentially this audition
system um that Tik Tok really pushed the
furthest the earliest but now is very
standard uh on Instagram on YouTube on
Facebook and others.
&gt;&gt; Have you seen them change in reaction to
what you guys are doing and uh you know
and what YouTube is doing? Again, I I'm
also kind of curious if we can to drill
down on what you see as the differences
between what besides the you know,
besides the messaging um you know uh
thing that you mentioned, which was
which was really interesting and the
data kind of uh you know, collection
that goes along with that. Um is there a
major difference in your uh you know,
exploration based ranking
&gt;&gt; um that I would share on a podcast? I'm
not sure. I would uh I got to think
about that a little bit. But I mean in
terms [laughter] of them borrowing from
us that tends to happen more on the
other side of the house on the friend
side, right? So they have
&gt;&gt; um they have adopted notes which you
might not use but are really heavily
used by uh teens and young adults um
essentially like AIM status for those of
us who are around for like the AOL and
some messenger days.
&gt;&gt; Um you know they've trying to been
trying to lean into stories more and
more um they have been leaning into
messaging more and more. that's where
where they've had the most success, but
they've definitely been trying for a
long time to consistently lean hard into
friends and and they've made some
progress the most with messaging um less
in other areas. You know, not always
copying us sometimes, you know, they
they basically made the friends tab be
real for six months when that was a
whole big moment.
&gt;&gt; Um they're very quick, which I'm very I
want to give them a lot of credit for,
to try things and to be bold and to see
what works and what doesn't. Um but you
know they are leading
they have a different commerce strategy
than us. So that's a big difference.
They're leaning a lot more into first
party commerce facilitating the
transactions themselves on platform
taking on things like even shipping etc.
We're more focused on third party um and
on sort of merchandising shopping
throughout the experience as opposed to
having sort of an
&gt;&gt; I don't know if you've gotten to the the
shop tab on Tik Tok recently but it's
basically Amazon now. you you're being
so kind of nice and and even-handed with
your your rivals here. Like, what do you
think is Tik Tok's Achilles heel? How
are you going to beat them?
&gt;&gt; Um, it's going to be hard to beat them.
Um,
I think that
&gt;&gt; the United States government.
&gt;&gt; No. Yeah. I mean, that that's a whole
other conversation. Um, I mean, look, I
think their rate of progress has slowed
down and I think in part of that was the
distraction with all of the regulatory
uh and policy concerns. So I don't think
they have been making progress as
quickly as they have in previous years
which gives us some a chance to catch up
on things like core ranking. I think
that they are
also I think we monetize way better than
them particularly if you look at not
just revenue but profits. Um but they're
you know their their revenue globally is
doing really really well but on the
profit side I think we're we're pretty
far ahead of them. Um and then I think
that what was the other one I was going
to share they um I don't know here's a
big question is like they are very much
applying learn lessons they've learned
in China to the rest of the world and
there's good and bad or pros and cons or
to that. So, one is the pro is they had
a massive faith in the short form video
format long before anybody else did.
Musically and the early versions of Tik
Tok were not retentive and they spent
billions of dollars a year dumping into
promoting it and it seemed crazy to the
rest of the industry.
&gt;&gt; But their faith from talking to people
at their competitors in China came from
the fact that they had proven the market
in China and they were they were
confident it would exist elsewhere and
they just needed to keep pushing to get
there.
So on one hand that's really interesting
right that's them seeing
into the future in a sort of another way
&gt;&gt; the flip side is you know the super apps
which are very popular in China are not
popular in the same way outside of China
and I think they're turning into a
Chinese super app um Tik Tok is and that
may or may not work outside of China and
so you know now
&gt;&gt; are they overly projecting one win on
the next or are they or am I you know, a
naive out of touch westerner who's
underestimating where the future's going
to be. Like, I I don't know. Um, but
that's that'll be interesting to see how
that plays out. Um, but that I feel like
Instagram's too complicated. And I love
I love Tik Tok. It's a great app, but it
is
&gt;&gt; really complicated at this point. Um,
and and increasingly kind of crazy. the
sort of to to get back to this question
about everything becoming TV like that
thesis and Derek Thompson had a really
interesting essay about it that we
talked to him about recently is partly
lit about kind of like literally staring
at the big screen but it is also about a
shift into kind of like a visual and
oral culture that I think Tik Tok led
the way to of that kind of more passive
consumption away from what at least I
think of as a social network but that
you you guys and others have chased um
[snorts] in which like you're just
consuming that that is shifting away
from a place where like fundamentally
society has kind of a shared truth and
grounding in facts and toward just this
like slurry of vertical video that you
know and I think an indirect sort of
concerning view turns us back into like
preiterate cavemen. Um and I wonder like
does does this concern you Adam?
&gt;&gt; Um I mean it's hard to say no when it's
framed that way. I [laughter] I mean
um I like to think that and we've tried
on Instagram to make video more lean in
than a lot of the competition, right? So
we try to bring your friends there,
right? So like you can see who else has
liked something. You can sends are a
huge part of Real's success, you know,
in a way that
&gt;&gt; they weren't part of Facebook's dive
into video in 2014 and 15. So, it's
actually grown the amount of people
actually see each other and talk to each
other, even though it's generally a
laid-back experience. We've got the
dedicated friends feed in the reels tab.
We've got blend. We've been trying to
create experiences that are a bit more
social, a little bit more participatory
and a little bit less leanback than like
just scrolling for an hour or watching a
Netflix show for an hour. Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Um but, you know, we'll see. Um maybe
that's a smaller market. Um,
&gt;&gt; I thought you were going to tell me that
threads was going to save us when when
it comes to kind of information and and
and truth and things like that.
&gt;&gt; You know, I try really hard. You've
known me for long enough to know I try
really hard never to overpromise and
underdel. So, that's not the kind of
thing that would come out of my mouth.
Threads is fun because threads is
about ideas and perspectives in a way
that, you know, Instagram is about
creativity and videos and photos. So
threads does seem to have detached from
the hyper hyperpolarized textbased
platforms. You know X which is
hyperpolarized in a lot of AI now blue
sky which is very very polarized also.
How do you how do you think about that
landscape?
&gt;&gt; Okay a few different things. One thing
that really helped us is out the gate
saying we wanted to be not like
kumbaya but just a more like civil
platform, you know, a a platform for all
perspectives implies that people can
share things without getting destroyed
for sharing them. And we try to build
tools to back that up, not just in
ranking, but you know, you can turn off
who can reply, you can turn off quote
posts, you know, giving people hidden
words, giving people some meaningful,
small, powerful tools because we always
knew threads was going to be
like Twitter in the sense that a small
number of people were going to dominate
the consumption, right? Like feedbased
apps are always this way, which you
know, a very small number of people will
post to a feed in a given day in the
steady state. And so it's going to be
for most of us to enjoy a select few
debating or sharing their perspectives
in a somewhat performative manner. Uh
and so we thought building tools for
that select few would matter a lot
because you don't need that many people
to use them for it to be valuable. You
just need the people who actually post a
lot to to to do it. So going out the
gate trying to say we wanted to be civil
I think helped set the tone. Um I think
X has done a couple things that have
helped. Um, obviously they've leaned a
lot into things that have been much more
divisive, but also they've gone a lot
after video over the last year or two. I
think they're a little enamored with
time spent. Um, and I think they
underestimate the costs of video. Um, so
that provides more space for us.
And then Blue Sky is interesting because
they're they're the most zealot on the
sort of um open architecture side, but
it's a it's not that it's all academic,
it's not, but they are heavily invested
on their sort of academic side on the
theoretical.
And then
they
maybe just based on our positioning and
exit's positioning have ended up with a
relatively small but very um
frustrated user base. Um, so it's, you
know, unless you have one particular
worldview, it's a pretty
tough place to be.
&gt;&gt; But the, it seems like threads though,
like is doing fine, but at the cost of a
certain kind of relevance, like there
aren't like the things that are being
discussed on cable news are rarely posts
to threads. They're often posts to X.
They're often posts to Blue Sky. Do you
miss that? I mean, you you annoyed
journalists early on by saying you
didn't really want us over there.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I know. I really made so many
friends. Well, we gave up on that in in
in a spectacularly public fashion
earlier this year. Um, there's a ton of
news on threads at this point. The
floodgates are open. Um, I think we
don't yet have the cultural re relevance
we aspired to, but I don't think it's
because of news necessarily. I think
some of it's just old habits die hard.
So if you look at different verticals
&gt;&gt; you can see there's certain areas where
we are either leading there certain
areas where we're behind and certain
areas certain industries where we're
basically nowhere compared to some of
the competition and so the question is
how do we close that gap um but you know
like for instance like NBA Twitter a
really longstanding deep community we're
actually making really good headway um
NBA threads had its own set of founders
at the beginning who weren't big names
and they have a ton of investment in
that community. But now that you're
seeing the players start to come over
too, there's this interesting
interaction um between the players and
that and the threads specific community
that's growing. Uh but still we have
certainly not toppled NBA Twitter. That
is a deep uh long-standing community. Um
so it really varies community by
community, but we think about this a
lot. How do you measure cultural
relevance? How do you define cultural
relevance? How do you
&gt;&gt; uh
&gt;&gt; and do you want it? It's not because I I
almost think sometimes these days
cultural re relevance is more trouble
than it were it's worth like it means
even when it comes to politics it really
means kind of [laughter] like political
food fights. You want it
&gt;&gt; I we want it but just to be super clear
there's a lot of cultural relevance that
isn't um the
primary
polarized political food fight. you
know, where is where is the conversation
about
um the playoffs for the NBA happening?
Where is the conversation about the
outfits on the red carpet at the Mecca
happening? Where is the conversation
about the upand cominging musicians, you
know, like Cameron Winters happening?
Um, that kind of cultural relevance I
don't think comes with the same cost as
whatever the
top headline
as combative as possible war cultural
war of the day is. Um, which I think is
just going to happen to us. Um, and so
we have to manage it responsibly. Um,
but not pretend like it's not going to
happen to us. H how do you think about
the AI? There's a lot a lot of the most
divisive stuff on X in particular seems
to be AI generated. How are you thinking
about AI generated content and slop on
on your platforms?
&gt;&gt; Wait, Ben, can I ask a more can I ask a
more pointed version of that question
too because I or I want to ask
&gt;&gt; say no ask a less pointed version of my
[laughter] Well, no, but but I want to
take it. No, because but Ben but no, but
Ben is being too leaned back here. Like
is AI content good for Instagram or or
not? Because like previously this was a
place where you you know you would
interact with your friends and it it
feels like it would change Instagram
pretty radically for it to be filled
with kind of a lot of different a lot of
AI that kind of AI slop that Ben's
talking about.
&gt;&gt; So in typical diplomatic fashion I'll
say that there are good and bad
consequences of it. But the thing that
I'll sort of maybe to push back a little
bit harder and be a bit um le I don't
want to be vanilla in the answer here is
I just don't really think the primary
type of AI content on the platforms is
what people usually mean when they say
AI content. They talk about AI slop.
They're talking about fully synthetic
content usually really bizarre weird
where like physics gets strange or
people's arms bend in weird ways. Mhm.
&gt;&gt; But the truth is, I think there's going
to be more content that is hybrid that
is AI is used to augment or enhance in
some way than is purely synthetic. I
think we're kind of already there.
&gt;&gt; Um because there's tons of ways in which
AI I think can help creators make more
content or make better content. Now, if
you're asking about the purely synthetic
content, I think it's going to be I
think there's in any kind of content AI
or not, there's going to be slop and
non-slop, right? And I think there's I
think an important question which is are
we doing a good job connecting you to
the valuable or content that you would
find valuable or interesting. Um whether
it's about knowing that it's AI
generated or not or you're just
interested in the topic or not because
it's a new type of content and so
naturally our systems aren't as versed
in it. So we're not as good at ranking
at it as we should be. So we're working
hard on being able to identify a
generated content at scale and then just
even just assess like how good are we at
ranking it. This is tough because as the
generative models get better and better
and better, it's going to be harder and
harder to detect that it was AI
generated. So, it might be a bit of an
arms race, but it will be. But we'll see
how we fare. Um, but I just think
there's a ton in the middle. Like every
time I post now, I have it translated
into Hindi, Spanish, and Portuguese. So,
if you go to one of my posts on
Instagram, you can just switch it and
see me speak Hindi. Uh, and it sounds
like me and the lips look like I'm
actually speaking Hindi. And it's by far
our largest user base. And now obviously
only about half the people in India
speak Hindi but that's a big number of
people. Um now they can actually
understand me when a lot of them
couldn't before. Like that's AI
generated but that's kind of exciting.
Whereas like the slot that you have in
your mind when you ask that question
probably is something that you would
wish you had never seen and you can't
take out of your brain.
&gt;&gt; I've seen some messmerizing stuff uh
recently uh like uh that that I I we
won't get into because we're almost uh
done here. But Ben, sorry to cut you off
on that last question. a better version.
[laughter]
&gt;&gt; I just had to go with the one that we
had agreed to ask in in the notes. Uh
but uh but because you have to go here,
Adam, uh we we did have a final question
that we wanted to ask um which is you
know, we wanted to kind of end where we
started, which is Instagram has changed
uh a lot over the last five or 10 years.
You know, it used to if you used to ask
people what Instagram was, it was if
anybody had people used to have to ask
uh you know, it used to be uh square
photos on a grid that you scroll
through. Right now, it's kind of uh
something uh a little bit more
complicated which you which you kind of
got at. Where do you think that
Instagram will be in the next five or 10
years? What what will it be? So in the
next five the it's I do think the
one of the big differences will be that
a lot of the technology and some of
these foundation models are going to
allow us to allow you to much more
proactively get your hands in there and
shape it. Right? So like we launched
your algorithm last week which only
applies to reals to start but that
allows you to see what we think you're
interested and to just tell us when
we're wrong add things remove things.
Um, but I feel like all the surfaces
across Instagram with the some of these
new technologies should allow you should
evolve in a way that you can kind of
touch metal where you can kind of go in
there and just tell it what you want or
make it what you want.
&gt;&gt; Um, whether that is shaping feed to give
you what you're interested in or going
deep in search to understand something
or creating something and being able to
really mold it into what you want more
proactively. I think that's going to
happen over the next two to four years.
Um, you'll start seeing it happen now,
but I think it's going to be feel
fundamentally different in two to four
years in a way that
&gt;&gt; I hadn't foreseen only a couple years
ago.
&gt;&gt; I think
&gt;&gt; I think it becomes more active. Just to
pause there for a second, you think
because I think feel like the my
experience of the internet has just
gotten more and more and more passive
through my whole life in a way until I'm
just sort of scrolling TikTok for reals.
Um, you you feel like people are going
to be it's going to be a more active
experience in the next few years. That's
really interesting.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Not all of it. I mean some of it
active in moments. So I assume the way
it would work if you could just shape
feed is you have active moments and then
you sit back and enjoy and then you have
active moments and you sit back and
enjoy as your interests change or your
mood changes. Whereas I assume that
content search which is growing quite
quickly on Instagram will be feel very
active in general where you're diving
into something. You're like I want to
know about James Terrell. Okay, I want
to see specifically the PS1
installation. Okay, I want to know like
how did he end up getting this idea and
you should be getting content and
context about this and just being able
to dive deep.
&gt;&gt; You know, that'll be much more active
whereas I think the primary experience
will be um more passive. But with these
moments of um much more hands-on shaping
um that will, you know, for some people
be daily, for some people be monthly,
for some people be never, for some
people be I don't know, every 10
minutes. um the 10 years out is much
crazier because that's when I think the
form factor, you know, goes to a place
that looks more like glasses probably
becomes more important than phones. Um
and then for a visual platform in a
medium where you probably want most of
your interactions with your smart
glasses to be audio only, um is a much
bigger, more open question that I think
we need to think about. Well, we'll have
to have you on uh again then to uh to
delve into more of the specifics, but uh
&gt;&gt; Adam's gonna have a lot of time on his
hands in 10 years when it's all when
when the visual medium has gone away.
&gt;&gt; I'm going to be [laughter]
my kids will be grown and I'll probably
be cooking and reading a book and like
reading, you know, reading you guys what
you have to say on what's going on in
the world.
&gt;&gt; Well, we really appreciate that. Uh and
um this was a really great conversation.
So, thanks. Thanks for taking the time.
&gt;&gt; Appreciate your time. You guys are
great. Thank you so much.
So, we are recording this the day after
our interview with Adam Masseri. Uh,
we've had a 24 hours to ruminate, really
let what he said, uh, sink in. Uh, why
don't why don't we get into it? Let's
tackle the big question first, which is
what do you think about his push back on
your thesis and the thesis of others who
have come on to this show uh, that
everything is television? This is the
thing you hear from all the smart media
types these days. Everything is
television. Derek was on here. You're a
you're a believer in this. Adam kind of
didn't believe that. Wh said he didn't
believe that while rolling out a
promotion for this new Instagram uh
Amazon Fire TV uh uh uh deal,
collaboration. What did you make? Do you
believe him? Is the action different
than words? What do you think?
&gt;&gt; You know, it is so interesting because I
think in some sense what's going on is
that everybody is seeing this pole in
the same direction. I mean in this case
just toward a large screen television
format and yet everybody is trying to
resist it in a different way and keep
some differentiation right like like I
think each of these companies and he
sort of acknowledged this is running the
risk that everything is becoming
undifferentiated and and if everything
is undifferentiated the platforms lose a
lot of power if I'm just putting the
same video on every place which which by
the way we in fact are um and so
you know what struck me was that his
impulse
was to resist long form and that and to
and to believe and I think with a lot
with really good reason that Instagram's
strength particularly its strength
against Tik Tok is messaging is per
personal connection where Tik Tok is
really a totally passive experience. Um
and I thought that was so interesting
that he said well personal connection
and short form video go together. You
send each other short form videos and
then short form video and long form
video go together kind of for obvious
reasons. it's an evolution of the form,
but that personal connection and long-
form video are too far apart and that
that in some that long form video breaks
Instagram. Um, I don't know. I think
that was just a very very interesting
observation. But it is true that even as
like social media as we knew it has
vanished. Meta's defense against its
competitors has been the social graph.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. And I think the other thing that
Instagram benefits from is the fact that
it's for a lot of people their kind of
uh their
homepage almost like the homepage of
their internet lives. Uh and that's why
he he mentioned that the thing the leg
up that they have on other platforms is
that like the pe their big creators the
celebrities or you know the just people
who are putting you know going viral all
the time on on Instagram are using it as
well as consumers. Right.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I think right I mean Instagram as
is essentially a cultural force is a
place where culture gets gets made and
shaped and then reflected elsewhere and
that's that is certainly a strength of
the platform. Of course that's also
that's also a hard can be a hard thing
to hold on to. What what did you make
you know it's funny when when I asked
about threads I almost thought he'd be
like ah that was a fun experiment never
mind threads because honestly from in my
own case I've I've kind of wandered off
threads. What what did you make of his
his enthusiasm his continuing enthusiasm
for threads? It's interesting. They've
created like the second most uh popular
kind of uh you know platform kind of uh
that's uh accomplishing what used to be
Twitter kind of uh behind Twitter. Uh
they're clearly bigger than in scale uh
than than Blue Sky and some other uh you
know some other platforms. And I think
it kind of seems like what they're doing
is kind of like hanging around in the
background until, you know, maybe Elon
uh messes with Twitter again and there's
this whole big kind of uh surge and they
don't they haven't really invested that
many resources in it by meta standards.
They said they have like what like a
hundred or something employees uh as as
a part of threads. So I I kind of I kind
of got the sense that if you're meta,
you can really pour a lot of resources
into a lot of these types of things.
They realize that they want to recapture
or they want to capture the kind of like
fervent uh uh taste maker, you know, uh
thought leader communities that exist
still and are hanging out on the kind of
decaying uh Twitter, they want to slowly
kind of siphon those uh onto threads.
And I think he rightly diagnosed the
fact that Blue Sky, while it has this
kind of fervent fan base, that fan base
is also alienating and user base, that
user base is also alienating to the vast
majority of people who uh I think might
wander back onto to threads. I thought
that was I thought what he had to say
was about threads and its feature was
really interesting. Ben, are you going
to go home and install Instagram on your
television?
&gt;&gt; I have I have a exotic projector
situation on my TV rather than Amazon
Fire, so I'm gonna have to wait. How
about you, Max?
I still don't see, you know, I I I just
I don't see the use case for it yet, but
uh they've proved me wrong before, so I
guess I guess we'll both have to wait
and see. Well, that is it for us this
week. Thank you so much for listening to
another episode of the Mix Signals
podcast from us here at Semaphore. Our
show is produced by Manny Videll and
Josh [music] Binsson with special thanks
to Chad Lewis, Rachel Oppenheim, Anna
Fazino, Garrett Wy, Jules Zern, and Tory
Core. Our engineer [music] is Rick Quan.
And our theme music, our new theme music
that Ben is so excited for, is by Steve
Bone. Our public editor is the algorithm
at the algorithmic feeds, whether Tik
Toks, which is better at using your
data, or Instagrams, [music] which is
getting better at using your data. As
Adam said, maybe we're not good enough
at using your data yet. And for and for
that reason, please please use our data.
Please uh f follow us wherever you get
your podcasts and subscribe to us on
YouTube.
&gt;&gt; And if you want more, you can always
sign up for 74's media newsletter which
is out every Sunday night.