It's lovely in here,
right? Make a little room for you.
Oh, yeah. [laughter] We try. We hated it
at first. We were like
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Cuz you got used to the old way.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that had a special juju. How long
are you in town? Just a day. Just a
couple hours?
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I got a couple things and then
it's my It's Nico, my 10-year-old's
birthday. So
&gt;&gt; Aw, happy birthday, Nico.
&gt;&gt; Buster Buster's.
&gt;&gt; 21st is his birthday, yeah. You can
tolerate Dave &amp; Buster's?
&gt;&gt; I put earplugs in.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Okay, I was going [laughter] to
say.
We have a mutual friend, Eric, who like
he kept wanting to do playdates there
with our daughters and last time I went
I was like, "Dude, I don't I don't know
what what's up with my sensory system,
but it's just way too much."
&gt;&gt; wildly over stimulating. Yeah, it's too
much. It makes me feel like I'm getting
attacked.
&gt;&gt; My 8-year-old wanted to go for his
birthday. This was like
uh November
and my wife signed up. She's like,
"Cool, we'll take the whole class, 25
kids."
&gt;&gt; Oh [snorts] my god.
&gt;&gt; And all the And she's like, "And we'll
guide them like no other parents."
&gt;&gt; [snorts]
&gt;&gt; She's ambitious.
&gt;&gt; yeah.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, yeah.
&gt;&gt; And so we had It ended up being like
five adults cuz a couple parents did
come and we went to the bus and she got
She's a genius. She got them all yellow
vests
&gt;&gt; Aw. to like label them. And they didn't
feel like that wouldn't have flown at my
birthday party. Like, "Mom, we look like
dorks, the crossing guards."
&gt;&gt; a good age. It was
&gt;&gt; They thought it was cool?
&gt;&gt; They were just like, "I don't care."
They didn't even think about it. I made
them like I was like, "You're like count
them, you know, off like 1 2 3 and like
I'm like, "What number are you?" He was
like, "I don't know." Oh, god. This is
an 8-year-old birthday party? Yeah. Wow,
you guys.
&gt;&gt; They're Yeah, what they were a minute
ago they're 10 7 and 4, but now they're
11 8
&gt;&gt; They're 10 So they're going to be 10 8
They're 10 8 and they're going to and 5
now. Five.
&gt;&gt; five. He'll be six soon. And what are
their names again? Nico, Blaze, and
Elio. Cute.
Really great.
&gt;&gt; They are They Yeah, they they're
wonderful and they also are just
exhausting. The youngest one is like the
brute. Really? Yeah, yeah. Cuz he like
he plays soccer with his brothers, they
don't take it easy on them, they just
beat him. Yeah.
&gt;&gt; And then he goes and plays soccer with
his own age and it's like
I took him to his older brother's soccer
game and he's like, "Oh, I scored a
goal." I was like, "Oh, cool. How many
goals did you score?" He goes, "I scored
15." Wow.
He's clearly lying. He's five. So, I
called his mom and she's like, "Oh, no,
he definitely scored." No way. I tell
that all the time on here, which is like
I thought I was so weak and so bad at
skateboarding cuz my brother's five
years older than me. And then I got to
school and was like, "Hold on a second.
I think I might be strong."
&gt;&gt; I think there's Someone told me
recently, I don't know if this is true,
uh but they told me that a
disproportionate number of successful
athletes are little siblings. I mean,
that would make sense cuz you're
competing with somebody so And you
immediately want to. It's like as soon
as they do it, you want to do it even if
you're way too young for it. So.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Well, Kristen and I ended up on a
trip and it was with all strangers. I
didn't know anyone. Yeah. And we got to
the airport, you were there. Yeah. And I
really felt like, "Oh, well, [__]
thank god. Adam's [laughter] here. I
know Adam." And I really, really loved
him as a guest. Like I do remember being
charmed by you like crazy.
&gt;&gt; I'm trying to It was I was really new to
the role cuz it must have been like
2019, 2020? I guess. That you were on?
&gt;&gt; That I was on. Yeah. Maybe 2019. It was
a long time ago. And I so I was new to
the role, so I was still trying to
figure out what was what, but I remember
having a lot of fun. Um but then we
hadn't seen each other in years before
that trip.
&gt;&gt; Right. Yeah, and you know, I was
watching, of course, uh some interviews
with you prior to your your arrival.
And I did I just wanted to start with a
little bit of compassion. You You have a
rough You have a hard job to talk about.
Mm. Cuz you're really at the forefront
of like a lot of things people are
concerned about.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; It's AI, it's social media, it's it's
politics, it's deep fakes, it's like
everywhere you're going, you're pretty
much
&gt;&gt; just hearing all those things?
Yeah, so we are at the intersection of
of a lot of contentious things and so it
is tricky.
But I I mean I used to work before I
worked at Instagram, I worked on
Facebook for a long time and I remember
a really long time ago, maybe 10, 15
years ago now,
I just
felt like we talked about this at the
company that we weren't participating in
the conversation and there was all these
conversations happening about tech,
about social media.
And so my position was like look, we got
to participate. Whether we want to or
not.
&gt;&gt; can put our heads in the sand but this
conversation's happening and we might as
well participate. And so I'm going to
get out there and I'm going to start
talking to people and I'm going to start
traveling and I showed up a lot on
Twitter cuz that's where all the
journalists were mhm and I was clear
internally I was like look, I'm going to
do this and hopefully it'll work and at
some point it won't, I'll say something
silly and everyone will hate me and I'll
stop.
&gt;&gt; yeah. That [laughter] was the
the the game plan?
&gt;&gt; would be better for having done it for a
couple of years but [laughter] before I
get destroyed.
&gt;&gt; Wait, can I say before we get too far
that you know, Adam said something very
nice about us on on Instagram, did you
see this?
He did his wrap up of of yeah, podcasts
he likes. But I but [laughter] I misread
the question.
&gt;&gt; I laughed so hard. Someone sent it to me
and was like, you're his favorite food
or whatever the [laughter] question was.
&gt;&gt; food. It's like what's your favorite
food and I must have like, I don't know
why I had podcast on the brain. I was
like, maybe the next question was about
podcast so I rattled off a couple pods I
love and then everyone like the comment
section was like, what's wrong?
I laughed so hard.
&gt;&gt; do them between meetings on Fridays.
It's not like a production.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, not very well thought out.
&gt;&gt; No, it doesn't need to be. That's okay.
I thought it was very funny and and
flattering.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, yeah.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; You used to be your favorite food.
I was like, oh god, that's not the best.
Yeah, what do we taste like? Is are we
salty or we sweet? Well, you guys are a
burger and a chili dog.
&gt;&gt; you're savory. I like to think.
&gt;&gt; you are.
I do too. There's some sweet stuff out
there. I I dabble on it.
&gt;&gt; Well, maybe there's some relish. Mhm.
There's some relish.
&gt;&gt; dog. There's some There's some garnish.
&gt;&gt; laid on the emphasis on the relish. The
relish. I think relish came up
yesterday. Oh, garnished it. Garnish. A
a gritty garnish.
&gt;&gt; That's right. Yeah, you know like that
and I thought it was pretty impressive.
&gt;&gt; I'd sleep on it and I like it now. Thuy,
I'm just really sympathetic to cuz not
only have you you have to go out and
talk about these issues and so often
you're being asked to be clairvoyant.
That's really what people want to know.
It's like, "Well, in 1 year, what will I
be doing? In 2 years, what's it going to
be?" And what will Instagram be in this
iteration? And it's like, "You don't
know any better than anyone else." I go
to these conferences, the [__] people
who are designing this [__] they don't
know.
Most of the good ones will admit that.
Like, "Nobody knows what the timeline
is."
&gt;&gt; Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. They don't know
what the ceiling of its aptitude is.
They don't No one knows.
But, you're you're being kind of we need
you to know. Yeah, yeah. I mean, that is
attention and I do think some of us in
this industry really pride ourselves on
being able to put pen to paper on what's
going to happen and
I tend to find that that sometimes feels
like false precision and it's just it's
a little bit more driven by
you know, our own wanting to be able to
do that and to be you know, prescient.
But, I think it's just good to always be
honest about what you know and you
don't. And then to
you know, also qualify things. Not in a
not in a way to couch, but to be like,
"Look, I think this is probably what's
going to happen and why."
But, if this other thing happens, maybe
we're going to go left instead of right.
The world's changing more and more
quickly. It's full of nuance. It's all
gray. And I think if you have you have
to embrace that ambiguity and that
uncertainty, otherwise I feel like
it's going to bite you. Okay, so now I
also want to This is the value of having
spent a weekend with you. Um
and I This wasn't clear to me the first
time we interviewed you, which I know
that you come from a design background.
But I really just like it didn't set in.
Yeah. And as I spent time with you, you
are a you're a very much an artist and a
designer. That's what you have wanted to
do uh set out to do. That is who you
are. It is it's almost weird you're in
this role in some way. Yeah, it is a
little weird. I mean, so I
I romanticize like the specialist, the
amazing architect or the amazing graphic
designer or the amazing machine learning
or AI engineer.
But it's just not my shape. I'm not
great at anything. I just have
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; a lot of range. Like that's my strength.
Generalist? Yeah, I'm a generalist, for
sure.
&gt;&gt; And so for me it's been
uh important and this happened maybe
when I was right around 30 to embrace
that about myself. Before 30, I was
always trying to be a designer. Um I'm
I'm the son of an architect. My mom's an
architect. My brother's [snorts] a
musician. My sister's a designer. So I'm
surrounded by I'm the suit. Yeah, you
guys are like a squid in the whale
family. You know, they're like you
they're like uh very you know, a New
York kind of intellectual artistic.
Yeah, yeah. Yeah, so I I do think it's a
bit ironic that you've ended up where
you Yeah, yeah. Can you tell people what
your role is just in case for some
reason?
&gt;&gt; Sorry. I lead the Instagram team. Uh so
I'm the head of Instagram uh at Meta.
Uh I also support um the Threads app as
well. We're going to get into how much I
made fun of you.
&gt;&gt; Ooh.
We just started it.
&gt;&gt; nothing. My running bit with him for 3
days was making fun of Threads, but
we're
&gt;&gt; did. He did. But it wasn't as bad as the
fact that my wife has not installed it.
It's like
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; Got to keep you humble. Well, she's at
an age I'm sure she's just like, "I'm
I'm done with the new I mean, that's how
I felt about TikTok. I'm like, "No, that
that I'm going to sit that out. I can't
do it.
&gt;&gt; she's got her what she uses and what she
doesn't and she does not care about my
world at all. It's great. But you do
have the title of CEO of Instagram,
yeah? That yeah, I mean we we we say
head of Instagram. Isn't that funny they
do all the tech companies have such a
they have their own fingerprint on what
they call people and what it's like it's
very specific. I find the world's very
interesting.
&gt;&gt; That's a very nice interesting is what
my mom would say when it's like she like
she like oh he's interesting. We are
particular and odd in our own special
ways for sure. I will acknowledge that.
&gt;&gt; Yeah and obviously there's enough social
science to back up the fact that
cultures are really important at
organizations but I think if you're at a
certain threshold of intelligence a lot
of it sounds condescending.
Yeah.
&gt;&gt; That's what I that's what triggers me
when it's like wait I'm I'm mopping up
the toilet you're calling me a partner
or whatever or buddy or whatever the
[__] you [laughter] know it's like
&gt;&gt; For us it's a little bit I'll give you
the context. For us it's a little bit
like Instagram is not its own company.
It's part of a bigger company and
there's pros and cons to that but
there's a lot of pros for us. Like
people move back and forth between the
teams we're built on top of the same
safety systems the same ad system etc.
And so we try to make sure we use
language that embraces the fact that
it's a part of a bigger company not its
own company. So that's the inside
baseball on on this on this language
bit.
Also just because it's important for
people to know. Like I don't want people
to be surprised that Instagram is owned
by Meta and Meta also owns Facebook and
WhatsApp and these other things. Yeah
yeah.
It's also very fascinating how much
public opinion can vary
within the offshoots of still the same
company. I grew up working for General
Motors and that had that as well. A
Cadillac is such a different vibe than
Chevrolet. It has a brand.
&gt;&gt; Saturn is your progressive [snorts]
younger consumer. Like it's all General
Motors and the [__] motors are coming
out of the same plant but it's just kind
of shocking how many
different opinions can Well, we build up
emotional, you know, affinity for these
different brands, right? And even it's
like, I mean, think about I don't know,
you might be
Like, what I'm trying to think of a good
example. Like, in in the world of like
soda and drinks, like, you know, how
many different companies does Coke own?
And like, you might be anti-Coke and pro
I forget which water is theirs. I'm sure
it's Smartwater or one of the I don't
know that that's it.
&gt;&gt; I'm going to get yelled at, but Dasani.
I was going to say that. I think it's
Dasani.
&gt;&gt; Oh, yeah, there are some people who
Yeah, I think it's Dasani. Yeah, I think
there might even be like a big war
between Aquafina and Dasani. Like, those
are the camps. Yeah, and I think they're
both Coca-Cola, but probably look it up.
Yeah.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; I'm saying it. Oh, and they have
electrolytes.
&gt;&gt; I'm serious. There's salt in it.
Electrolytes? No, I do love
electrolytes. What? Dasani is Coke,
Aquafina is Pepsi. Oh, yeah, they got it
backwards. Yes, yes, yeah, that's real.
That's shocking that I love Aquafina,
that that's my pick because I'm so I
bleed that Coke.
Oh, yeah.
See, again, as you're saying, the we're
we're proving your point.
&gt;&gt; through college on diet Coke. Acquired
just did a pod on them recently,
actually. I haven't listened to it yet,
but I'm excited to cuz those two guys
are really smart.
They also have different recipes for
different countries though, which I
think is interesting.
Coke in Mexico tastes pretty different
than Coke in the US, for instance.
&gt;&gt; And that supposedly is due to whether
it's cane sugar or high fructose, but I
don't I don't know. I don't want to get
sued by either Mexico or the US.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; The country of Mexico
sues Dax Shepard. Okay, so all to say,
I'm going to ask you all those similar
questions. And they probably will have a
tiny bit different bent coming from us,
but um
before that, I just want to I just want
to
double back on the the design fact.
Like, I think
as I watched you interact with people,
and I had to assess from afar what I
think your skill set is, is
um, you have a very very intuitive
aesthetic
Mhm. that you trust deeply.
And you're a great challenger of people
and hierarchies.
And with some kind of savvy that has
allowed you to still exist. So without
getting crushed.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, yeah. So I don't know. Yeah, tell
me a little
&gt;&gt; It'll happen eventually. Yeah, yeah.
Again, like you being in public, this
could be the day. This could be the last
day you
&gt;&gt; here we go. We got microphones ready.
Good place to end.
&gt;&gt; the loaded weapon.
&gt;&gt; going to if I'm going to go down, this
is a great place to go down.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; Can you agree with that assessment at
all?
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I mean, I'll I'll take the
compliment. The design is about
problem-solving
at a fundamental level. And I think you
can apply problem-solving to any
industry, right? So you try to identify
what you're trying to get done, what are
the different options, what are the
trade-offs. These are pretty standard
patterns that you can apply elsewhere.
And so that's the kind of structured
thinking that I have to do in my job,
even though I'm not designing anything
anymore,
even though I would like to. That lends
itself to being
comfortable in
dis- debate because you can have a a
position and a reason for that idea, and
you're comfortable articulating that
reason.
&gt;&gt; And it's not personal to you, obviously,
right? It's a function. You're arguing
how functional this is.
&gt;&gt; Exactly. But that's the thing that
designers, and I'm I'm I'm not an
exception, when I was a designer, often
struggle with is divorcing your sense of
self-worth from the worth of your work.
And critique is like a whole part of
design where you're going to go and
you're going to show your stuff, and
people are going to rip it apart, and
you have to embrace the signal and
understand that it's not an attack on
you, it's a way of actually it's a way
to support you by improving the work
itself.
&gt;&gt; Mhm. Uh and I didn't learn that properly
cuz I didn't go to design school really.
I learned that from a handful of young
designers who went to proper design
school who joined Facebook in the early
years
who brought that culture
to Facebook and I learned a lot from
them. Am I wrong that you did though you
had a couple of defining moments in your
career where you did challenge Mark on
something specific?
&gt;&gt; of a couple of things, yeah. Yeah, what
were the things? So okay, a couple
different ones. I'm trying to think
which ones I may have told you about but
I might just
share other things I'm not supposed to
share.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; Well look, I think careers are often
defined by a few major decisions which
may be informed or uninformed and for me
there were a couple.
The first one was I was a design
director at Facebook. I was managing a
bunch of designers and there was this
project that became the Facebook phone
and all the PM leadership ended up
leaving the company for different
reasons. Some personal, some
professional.
So there's this giant crater where the
leadership was
in what we call product management or
the PMs.
And I just
declared myself the PM which you can't
do anymore. You have to interview cuz
that's a reasonable thing
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; to do to have a job but this was you
know a long time ago, probably 13 years
ago.
And me and Mark definitely told me not
to do it. Mark was like, "No, you're a
designer. Like you shouldn't do that."
&gt;&gt; [clears throat]
&gt;&gt; But I did it
and actually he was nice about it. About
6 weeks later it was late on a Friday. I
was at the office
and he said to me
he was
he was complimenting me but it He said,
"You're doing a lot better in this role
than I thought you would."
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; It's a very Mark way of complimenting
someone.
&gt;&gt; which is great which I took I took I
took the signal.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; So there's been a couple instances like
that over the years. Some with Mark in
disagreement with him, some otherwise
where you make these decisions
and I wasn't doing it cuz I thought it
was a good career decision. I was doing
it because I was working on a project
there there a need and I just
was trying to fill that need. But I got
lucky because like I said before, I'm a
generalist and PMs are basically
generalists. You work with the
designers, the engineers, the comms
people, the the lawyers, the policy
people. You work with everybody.
&gt;&gt; now? You you have to be able to speak
each person's language well enough to
bridge all these communication gaps.
&gt;&gt; across everybody. If somebody doesn't
know something on your team that they
should know, it's probably on you.
Right.
&gt;&gt; And so my career
for a couple reasons, but one of the
this is probably the main one,
started taking off cuz I was in a role
that matched my skills much better. Cuz
I was
I was a I was a middle-of-the-pack
designer. I I made up for it with like
sheer work, like hours.
&gt;&gt; Abundance.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; But like in terms of like raw talent,
&gt;&gt; Yeah. middle-of-the-pack is maybe even a
little generous. Yeah.
&gt;&gt; And so I did well, but by sheer force of
will.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. And then when I kept working hard,
but my role embraced my strengths and
weaknesses, then things started to
accelerate. Okay, so Mike, I guess my
first question is
um how are you guys let's just leave
what's on the app alone for 1 second and
just how have you guys been able to
utilize AI in the running of the the
product? So a couple different things.
So one thing that we've been doing for a
long time is
and this is
controversial, so we rank content. We
try to show you the content we think
you're the most interested at the top.
And we've been using different forms of
AI for that for many, many years.
&gt;&gt; Okay. Um another thing we do with AI for
many years or forms of it is we try and
classify content. So is this uh it could
be something positive, like is this
about a certain topic that you're
interested in? Or it could be negative,
like is this in does this violate our
community guidelines therefore shouldn't
be on the platform? And that the AI
sifting through all that material and
trying to put those in buckets.
&gt;&gt; Cuz there
there's you know, however you want to
count with tens, hundreds, even billions
of things, millions or billions of
things uploaded a day. Yeah. We can't
have people review all of it. So, we use
technology to look at content at scale.
And to be clear, and this is changing,
but historically, I've said this before,
&gt;&gt; [snorts]
&gt;&gt; people are better at nuance, and
technology is better at scale. And so,
we've had to focus on things that are
less nuanced, like what our
&gt;&gt; rules are, because technology hasn't
been as good at understanding nuance
historically.
&gt;&gt; humans are so crafty at quickly figuring
out what is triggering the
the safety net. Oh, yeah. It's very
adversarial, because one challenge we
have is spammers who are constantly
trying to work around all of our safety
protections. Yeah.
&gt;&gt; And you know, you'll have
bots, for instance, but bots that don't
post every second 24 hours a day. They
pretend to go to sleep. They pretend to
go to work. They're inconsistent. They
add spelling mistakes. What's the
Japanese word for imperfection? I don't
know it. It's the second day in a row he
can't get it. Wabi sabi,
but it's not wabi
&gt;&gt; sabi, but it's not. It's the one that
has the gold that you piece together.
&gt;&gt; Uh-huh. Oh, that's a specific art form
where they take broken ceramics and they
put it back together with gold lining.
&gt;&gt; Correct. And it's like the
imperfection's really the beauty.
&gt;&gt; beautiful. And it has a name, and we're
all supposed to know it. It's called
&gt;&gt; is a There is a word that's not as
helpful um in Japanese for
Instagrammable, which I learned when I
was there recently, which is instabae.
Oh, really? Meaning it's like so
aesthetically pleasing it's worth
posting? Yes, exactly.
I'm like torn on how I feel about that,
but
that's a thing.
What's happening to us now, though, is
we're building AI products that are more
native AI into the product, into the
app. I say product, that's Silicon
Valley speak for like the apps. Mhm. But
the other thing that's happening to us
is we are also getting really disrupted
ourselves. Like how we build, how we
write code, how we do research, how we
analyze data is changing really quickly.
Yeah.
&gt;&gt; And so we are also having to reinvent
how we do what we do. Mhm. Um which I
think some people outside of the
industry don't realize cuz they're like
oh tech is just going to keep doing
tech. Right.
&gt;&gt; like it's very different.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; And it's going to get a lot more
different over the next year or two. And
so I don't I can tell you some of the
things that we're doing now, but
honestly I think it's all changing
really fast. People are very right to be
concerned because the
the power of these products is enormous
and they're like we've never seen this
before, right? So it is the most
powerful thing. So it does deserve the
most amount of scrutiny.
But also
nothing operates perfectly. Everything
is iterations built on previous mistakes
and correcting those mistakes. So the
notion that again people are going to be
able to be clairvoyant. Even like when I
listen to that rabbit hole about YouTube
and its algorithm of
increasing engagement. Everyone had
great intentions. No one really could
foresee oh it's going to radicalize
people. They didn't think oh well what
will be more exciting is more and more
radical content and it starts at Jordan
Peterson and then you're a white
nationalist. Like Yeah. Yeah. I'm I'm
sympathetic to that to some degree. No,
it has to be immediately corrected the
moment that's discovered everything has
to all hands on deck to fix that
problem. But again there's probably what
like what you're saying is this illusion
that because you guys are creating the
product that you're not also victims of
it all as well. No one's really immune
to the challenges of this AI. Yeah. No,
we're not immune. We're not immune to it
at all. I mean I would say two different
things. One on
the industry and the scrutiny and the
size is not only is it big and important
and obviously a lot of power in the
hands of a small number of companies. It
also grew really quickly. There are
other industries are equally important,
but they took decades or centuries to
get to their scale. And you know, I
don't know, railroad, the automobile
industry, electricity. Exactly. But like
we It was like, you know, 10-20 years
from not a thing to a big deal. And so
that's tough because
society doesn't have time to really
adapt or consider it or get comfortable
with it. Laws take much longer to happen
as well. So we're dealing with that now
as a sort of a backlog of of incoming
compliance work.
&gt;&gt; And the second they understand the tech
to legislate, it's changed. It's gone.
Yeah, exactly. Oh. Um but on the second
thing, it's um
an app like Instagram, you make a lot of
decisions um as the team running it and
you have a lot of responsibility.
Um but what you are mostly doing in some
ways is like is designing a a system
that has rules. You could almost think
about it as like a city, right? You
know, it's like, hey, where are the
roads? What are the speed limits? Where
are the traffic lights?
&gt;&gt; Mhm. But then people fill it and they
decide what to do. And that doesn't I'm
not trying to pass the buck. That
doesn't mean that you don't have
responsibility as the planner, but that
responsibility is different. Um it's
indirect. You have to set healthy
incentives. You have to
uh you know, in our case, you know,
moderate content effectively. You have
to In even outside of the world of like
really high scrutiny areas, the
decisions you make about the design of
Instagram will affect the vibe, how it
feels. Is it more positive? Is it more
negative? Is it more about debate? Is it
more about visual expression? Yes. And
you're right, it's a great point as the
city cuz it's like, yes, we'll install
these traffic lights at all these
intersections. And then people will blow
red lights and they'll drive drunk. And
it's questionable whether now the city
is responsible. The the light was hung.
Uh so it is really tricky to figure out
where the culpability lies.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I look I just think the
responsibilities
are shared and they're just different.
We have to understand how the system
works. We have to set healthy guidelines
and rules. We have to enforce those
rules effectively and consistently and
appropriately. But you know, people
could just decide not to open up
Instagram tomorrow or they could
[snorts] decide to try to abuse the hell
out of it tomorrow. But there is an
acknowledgement right that like
it's so hard to not open up Instagram.
Like and not and and I mean good job,
you know, but like it's it's built to
get you to keep pressing it. But I guess
if we were doing the metaphor about the
city, it's like okay, we hung the light
but we know everyone runs that light but
and
oh well.
Well, I don't think running the light is
using Instagram. I think running the
light is like posting something that's
against our rules.
But yes, obviously we are interested in
creating something that people are going
to use more. We think if you use it more
on average is a sign that it's valuable
to you in some way. But there's there's
well spent time and there's time poorly
spent and we're not we're not
we're not ignorant to that fact. So we
try not to use tactics that you're going
to make you use Instagram or convince
you to use Instagram that it's going to
make you regret using it later. And we
try to focus more on ones that you know,
are going to you're going to be more
excited about how you felt about the
product later. So we do things like
we don't just look at how many things
you like or how much time you spend. We
run these we have these like worth your
time surveys where actually we do a lot
of these where
we'll ask you was this thing worth your
time and we see if is the people are
people's answers to that question
trending up or trending down over time.
So it's a balance of different types of
of goals. It's funny too cuz yes, I'm
critical of that and then but when I
turn the the the the lens back onto us,
I go like, I don't feel guilty that
people would listen to our show 6 hours
a week. We put out 6 hours of content a
week. I would want them to listen to all
6 hours. That's that would be my dream.
You know, cuz I think what we're doing
is good. So, it's like it's tricky cuz I
believe in it and I'm not really too
concerned with how much times people are
spending or quote wasting on this, which
I believe in. Yeah, yeah. So, it's it's
a little hard for me to then
be critical of someone else that has a
creative endeavor that they also want
people to consume. It's tricky. It's
tricky, but I think you can do both.
Like I think you can I think you can be
I think the scrutiny is merited because
the importance is there and I think
there are responsibilities.
Um I just think that it's
evaluating how we do is not the same as
evaluating how a person behaves. It's
cuz it's a it's a it's a platform.
There's lots of people. You your what
you control and what you don't is
different. What's appropriate for you to
do and not do is different. Like I don't
think you want a tech company in Silicon
Valley deciding this topic is the most
important topic today or this news event
is the most important news event today
and we're pushing that out.
&gt;&gt; Or a dancing video is irrelevant and a
waste of everyone's time.
&gt;&gt; Exactly. But you also don't want us
to be agnostic. I'm under no I really
don't think that
you can pretend that, you know, we're
neutral. We make decisions. Those affect
how people use the product, what they
see, and therefore there's
responsibilities that come along with
those decisions.
Stay tuned for more Armchair Expert.
If you dare. We are supported by
Allstate. Checking Allstate first could
save you hundreds on car insurance.
That's smart. Not checking the pockets
of your jeans before doing laundry,
classic oversight. That mystery clunking
in the dryer, yeah, that was your lip
balm's final moments. And somehow
there's always one random receipt in
there to dissolve into confetti. Yeah,
checking first is smart. So, check
Allstate first for a quote that could
save you hundreds. You're in good hands
with Allstate. Potential savings vary
subject to terms, conditions, and
availability. Allstate North American
Insurance Co. and affiliates,
Northbrook, Illinois. We are supported
by HubSpot. Did you know that most
businesses, Monica, only use 20% of
their data?
&gt;&gt; That's like reading a book with most of
the pages torn out.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, or paying for a coffee that's 1/5
full. [snorts]
&gt;&gt; Yuck. Point is, you miss a lot unless
you use HubSpot. Their customer platform
gives you access to the data you need to
grow your business. The insights trapped
in emails, call logs, and transcripts,
all that unstructured data that makes
all the difference. Because when you
know more, you grow more. And when you
get a full cup of coffee, you can do
more, too. But I digress. Visit
hubspot.com today.
Have you guys ever approached this with
the
Daniel Kahneman framing of like thinking
of multiple selves? And uh for a
shortcut, we'll call one the
experiential self and one the narrative
self. So one is the you that lays in bed
at night and evaluates your day,
evaluates where you are in this broader
story of your life. Am I reaching my
goals? Am I the family member I want to
be? And that's your narrative self. And
then the experiential self is like ooh,
boobs, horsepower, right? Like that's
instantly the experience itself is a
self you have that you're servicing. And
I can almost think of your was this
useful to your time as being like trying
to strike a balance between that
narrative self and the experiential.
Well, the experiential's good, but also
it doesn't give you a a hangover from
having used it.
&gt;&gt; I talk about the tension as your
first-order preferences and your
second-order preferences. So I like Is
also Kahneman, yeah? Yeah, I like
chocolate.
&gt;&gt; [snorts]
&gt;&gt; Like it tastes good. That's a
preference. Yeah. I also want to be
healthy and I want to eat healthy and
that's a That is a
&gt;&gt; want diabetes.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, yeah, I don't want diabetes.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I, you know, [snorts] I want to
not want the chocolate. You know, like
And so that's a second-order preference.
And I think one of the things that the
industry needs to be honest about and
struggles with is that we optimize for
things that we can measure and it's much
easier to measure your first-order
preferences than your second-order
preferences. Did you like this thing in
the next 500 milliseconds is pretty easy
for us to tell.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. You know, did you talk about it
with a friend that night at the dinner
or did you feel good about it the next
day
&gt;&gt; go to the GoFundMe page and and and
donate money to that cause you were made
aware of on there?
&gt;&gt; You can measure these things. It's just
more difficult.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; And I have found in my time in this
industry there doesn't seem to be any
correlation between how easy something
is to measure and how important it is.
&gt;&gt; Mhm. But there is a strong correlation
between how easy something is to measure
and how much we optimize for it. Not out
of any malicious intent but just because
That's what's available. That's what's
available. So
I have to do is always push the teams to
get more creative about trying to
understand these
second-order preferences or this
narrative self Mhm. so that we can
actually lean into it. Like that's why I
really love the Dear Algo stuff.
Have you guys seen this yet?
&gt;&gt; No, what's that?
&gt;&gt; That's actually not the external name.
That's just how I say it. It's called
Your Algorithm. Two years ago there was
a meme on Threads where people were
writing letters to the algorithm making
requests. Oh, wow.
&gt;&gt; showing my high school friends kids'
photos. Like I do not care. Like that
kind of stuff.
And so that inspired this and then the
tech got to the place where we could do
it. So it's only in the Reels tab right
now. But if you go to the Reels tab in
the top right there's these little under
the US there's these little sliders with
these hearts and it will tell you what
we think you're interested in
and then you can make edits. And you can
say I am I actually want to see these
things. I don't want to see these other
topics.
&gt;&gt; Oh, wait. Where Where is it? Where's the
Reels tab? Ease. It's the second tab.
Just click on the little
uh
&gt;&gt; bottom.
Oh, boy. Okay.
&gt;&gt; Oh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah. We're going to do
it live. All right. This is going to be
great. All right. So, do you see in the
top right a little icon? Yeah. Wait. Up
top there? The hearts? With the hearts.
Yeah. Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Okay. Click it. Tap it. Let's see. This
is I love that we're doing this live.
&gt;&gt; Yes. This is annoying. What does it say?
It says, "Lately you've been into
&gt;&gt; Fashion.
&gt;&gt; Uh "Lately you've been into award show
glamour,
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; sweat sessions, and culinary
indulgences." It's pretty good.
&gt;&gt; sweat sessions? That's interesting. No.
Like workouts.
&gt;&gt; Workouts.
I do get served a lot of workouts.
&gt;&gt; you're into them. That's the experience
No, I'm sorry. Her narrative self knows
she's supposed to be working out more.
So, it's already servicing your
narrative. You can you can See, there's
a list of
&gt;&gt; Yeah. It says, "What you want to see
more of, based on your activity
summarized by AI. Golden Globes,
fashion, luxury fashion, fashion.
&gt;&gt; Monica fashion. Apple Podcasts, Los
Angeles food scene." Okay. Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Beauty, comedy, food, fitness,
motivation, Golden Globes. Pretty good.
But now, let's say we were wrong. Let's
say you're not into sweat sessions. You
can actually press that and move that to
the I don't want to see this thing.
&gt;&gt; want to see less of.
&gt;&gt; can get in your hands in there and you
can change it. Because also, sometimes
sometimes we might be misreading a
signal. Like You're like, you don't
really want to see it, but you can't
stop looking at it.
And another thing is sometimes your
interest can change. Like this is a
tragic example, but it one that I have a
friend who went through, which is
um she got pregnant, and she was going
deep on the nesting thing, and her
Instagram got all about all this baby
gear. Tragically, [clears throat] she
lost the pregnancy.
How How horrible [snorts] is it that
she's opening up Instagram and we're
pummeling you with baby stuff? Yes. Yes.
So that was one of the inspirations for
this, which is she should be able to go
in and be like
No, nothing nothing about nurseries.
Yeah. Okay, I like that.
&gt;&gt; by allowing you to get in there and not
only see what we think you're interested
in but you to tell us yes and no, that
then hopefully allows people to express
their second order preferences or the
narrative self. Um now again, not
everyone's going to do it
but one way to one way to learn about
these things is just to ask. So we we
pick up on your interests, we learn from
them and we adapt. But we don't have a
like we don't understand quite as
literally as people think we do what
you're interested in. So like for
instance,
like that joke, we don't understand that
that's a joke about race from a black
comic.
&gt;&gt; Right.
&gt;&gt; It's not nuanced.
&gt;&gt; It's The way it works is
uh
with uh
an approach we call embeddings. So
basically we The way you can think about
it is you can take any video and map it
into a space. You can It's not true to
measure but imagine there's a giant
two-dimensional map. Uh-huh. There's no
borders or boundaries or labels. It's
just a bunch of videos on a on a on a
big board.
&gt;&gt; Uh-huh. And you know, similar videos end
up in similar places on the board. They
concentrate in little areas. Yes,
exactly cuz the way the technology works
is similar things end up in similar
places.
&gt;&gt; Mhm. And so then if you like one video
or whatever it is, we look and find
videos near it in that space and show
you those videos.
&gt;&gt; What allows us to do the your algorithm
work is now we can embed topics into the
same map as the videos. Uh-huh. And so
we can be like, oh okay, cool. Like you
said you're into like men's vintage
fashion. That's here. Let's find the
videos near here. Mhm. said you don't
want to see, you know,
like, you know, bikini videos.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, yeah. That topic is here. Those
videos will won't show you any videos
that are near it over here.
&gt;&gt; So, you're giving it a low side,
basically.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, kind of, yeah.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. We couldn't do that effectively
even
uh 2 years ago. And so, that's how
that's actually how a lot of ranking
works is we're like, all right, you like
this thing, what is similar to it? We'll
show it to you. People think it's like,
oh, you know I'm into surfing. And it's
like,
2 years ago I could it would have just
been this giant number. I wouldn't have
been able to tell you what it means. Now
I can say, oh, that's pretty close to
surfing or to like skater culture or
whatever it is.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I appreciate you reading your
algorithm out loud, by the way. That
took some bravery. Thank you. I didn't I
didn't know it was coming, but I it's
good. Is there a way to add So, I see
you can drag, but can you like type in
&gt;&gt; Whatever you want.
&gt;&gt; But, do you think people should like the
things that are getting you angry on a
regular basis,
and figure out what words that are
associated with that anger, and and
block them out?
&gt;&gt; That's called hidden words. Yeah, you
can do that. You can do that for
comments, too, and you can also do that
for your messages. I like that one a
lot.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. It's just people they like to be
angry. This is where this and I and I
this isn't your issue,
but I don't see people wanting to get
rid of that cuz that's they want it.
Yeah. I think it depends. So, for
politics specifically,
uh this this research is a bit out of
date, but I remember when we were
writing about We say research, it's
usually surveys. We found that there was
a small percentage of people who really
wanted more politics, but most people
were like, I kind of want to see less
politics. Um and I think that's again
this tension between the narrative self
and what was the other self?
&gt;&gt; Experiential.
&gt;&gt; Experiential self. If they like saw it,
they got
&gt;&gt; It's engaging.
&gt;&gt; engaging. We they clicked on it, we
think they like it, but they don't but
they're they're narrative self or the
second-order preference was like, I just
need a break.
&gt;&gt; good. They know they don't feel good
afterwards. Yeah, and most people at
least with these surveys were in that
bucket. There's a very loud, call it 5
or 10% of people, I forget what the
number is specifically, so a meaningful
minority, but minority, that are like
all in. It also varies by platform. Like
Threads has a way more politics than
Instagram does. Not cuz it ranks for
politics, but because
you make these other decisions about how
the app works. Threads is designed
around back and forth conversation.
That's better for debate. That's going
to mean topics like politics are better
served.
&gt;&gt; I be right to say Threads is also
encouraging you to share thoughts, not
necessarily images?
&gt;&gt; I think Instagram is about, you know,
sharing a creative object, a visual
creativity, videos, photos. Threads is
about perspectives, your hot takes. And
you're going to have a lot of takes on
what's going on in politics. So the
percentage of Threads that is politics
is way higher than the percentage of
Instagram. I mean, that's yeah, that's
that's concerning to me, you know? I I
don't know that's doing anyone any good,
but whatever. I don't get to decide. Um
Okay, now let's talk about AI-generated
content.
&gt;&gt; Yes. It's a very uncontroversial
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; that I'm sure you have a perfect
succinct
&gt;&gt; put yourself out in the fire. I'm
impressed.
&gt;&gt; Well, you got to talk about these
things. I would way rather that
everything that you is in your mind that
you're worried about or that someone is
watching is thinking about we talk about
than to sweep anything underneath the
rug.
And I hope people have an appetite too.
We're not sure and we're doing the best
we can to monitor it and see as it
evolves. I hope there's some appetite
for that and some some
some latitude for that because that's
the reality of how this is kind of
unfolding. So I have a lot of questions
about it. One is we should start by
defining it, right? Cuz here's what's
tricky. You were asked during this
Bloomberg thing,
could you label everything that was AI
generated? That would be helpful for all
of us. And you're like, yes, we agree.
We did that. And what we were doing is
it'll read anything you do on Photoshop
or Adobe
as being AI generated. So it's like
where is this line? If someone uses some
Photoshop to brush up a pimple on their
face in the video, Yeah, yeah. that's
now AI. Where are we drawing the line?
So Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Maybe we should just kind of define it.
Like most complicated issues, the edges
are much easier to define. So there's
clearly a, you know, you used a film
camera and it took light and those
photons hit a piece of film and like you
captured a moment and it's not perfect,
but it's like I
authentic capture of a moment in
reality. And then there's I went to some
AI model and I came up with an idea with
and I expressed that as words and then
out came this crazy video of a hippo on
a tutu doing a backflip. Yes. That
clearly never ever happened. Yes. So
that's purely synthetic content and
then, you know, what I would call maybe
captured content.
Um but there's actually I think most
content's in the middle. So like with
all of our phones today, when you
capture, it's doing a lot of photo
processing. It some of it's using AI,
some of it's not, but it's like it's
trying to make sure, you know, you are
not wildly backlit. So if the sky's
bright in front of you, it might use AI
to brighten you up and darken the sky so
it looks more like you would perceive it
as opposed to a film camera where you
would never be able to see the person.
&gt;&gt; Yes, doing AI's doing color correction
like crazy. All sorts of stuff, right?
&gt;&gt; It's doing sometimes in some of the
default cameras, it's doing skin
smoothing. It's doing things that are a
little bit more contentious.
&gt;&gt; Really? Uh there's lots of work to try
to make sure lighting works properly for
different skin colors, which is another
interesting thing. That just happened to
me. I took a picture with a gal that was
working at a restaurant in Detroit that
I frequent.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; And, uh, as she held it for the selfie
and took the picture, I was like,
"What? I look 29 in this photo." Yeah.
And she looks much younger. I was like,
"Oh, her like her go-to camera is this
augmented
&gt;&gt; like an app or something she uses?
&gt;&gt; takes photos clearly through this app.
Oh, yeah. And I I looked at it as it
came out. I was like, "Well, that's
neither of us, but here we go. There's
There's your picture."
&gt;&gt; Yeah. When you do portrait mode,
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; it's recreating the bokeh effect you get
from a shallow depth of field from a
really wide-open lens.
&gt;&gt; Right.
&gt;&gt; Um, and so then it's like, "Okay, well,
if it's using this kind of model or this
kind of AI model, what's like what is
AI?" Is an interesting question. You
know, if I'm if I'm doing a spot clean
up for like a pimple, it might be just
literally copying pixels or might be
using AI to generate pixels. Do we call
that AI? And so,
I'm not trying to put my hands up in the
air and say we can't do anything. I'm
just saying the reality of the situation
is it is a spectrum.
&gt;&gt; Hard to define. And I almost impossible
to Yeah. So, there's that challenge, and
then there's another challenge which is
the models are getting so good that like
the work that we do now, and we do work
to try to detect things that are
automatically generated by AI,
you know, we'll get less and less
effective over time as the models get
better. Now, our models can get better,
too, but it's an arms race. Yeah. And I
actually think at this point we will
continue that race, but it might be more
practical to
essentially mark things that were
captured
when they when they are captured by the
camera with what's called like a
fingerprint,
um, and verify that those were actually
captured than verify that things were
actually generated. It might be easier
to identify what was actually captured
&gt;&gt; Uh-huh. by a camera by doing
industry-wide solutions around,
um, some of these interesting, uh,
technologies than to try and
automatically detect what was created
with an AI. Yeah. Um, so we're now
exploring that. So, you you could click
on something that you see on social
media and it could be like, "Hey, we
this, you know, this was signed by, you
know, the
Sony camera in a way that can't be
replicated or or forged by AI."
&gt;&gt; using like NFT technology to kind of
create that?
&gt;&gt; There's a couple different approaches
out there. I'm forgetting the name of
the the one that Adobe's leaned into
right now. I was reading about theirs
last week or the week before. But,
basically you work with manufacturers.
So, whether it's Apple or Google or
Samsung or Sony or Canon or whatever,
and they actually
put basically a Think of it as like a
signature in the file
that can't be replicated. Is there a way
in
to just require that whoever creates the
content, so instead of you guys having
to go in and decipher,
that who it's like illegal if you create
something from AI to not say it's like
that it's on the onus is on the creator,
not on you guys. Like the ad like ads
are like that, right? Where you have to
say this is an ad.
So, yes, but then the challenge is
enforcement.
&gt;&gt; have to police it, which puts them in
the situation that they're currently in.
So, like ads is a good example. So, in
the US, there is no law that says you
have to mark something as an ad if it's
an ad. In Germany, you do.
Actually, so in Germany, you'll see a
lot of creators who just put ad on
everything cuz they're worried that like
if they unintentionally there's like a,
you know, liquid death water in the
[snorts] background, they're going to
get in trouble.
And then the question is how does the
government police it?
Cuz you said illegal. We had a rule,
let's say you have to mark it as AI,
then we have to The rule doesn't matter
if unless we enforce it. Back to the
traffic light sort of analogy from
before. So, to enforce it, we need to be
able to detect it on our own and say
like, "Hey, you didn't label this."
And then again, what percentage are we
going to let slide? If is it 8%
synthetic, Yeah.
&gt;&gt; is it 12% synthetic? When do we enforce?
Am I Am I writing a ticket for five over
or 15 over? I want to give people
context to make more informed decisions.
So,
you know, we could maybe show you how
likely we think it is to be AI. We don't
know for sure, but we think there's a
70% chance. Or we could show you, oh,
this was actually signed, so we know
this was actually captured because it's
signed by this industry standard. Uh and
I think we're better for us to adopt a
standard than build our own that works
across the whole industry because
obviously people spend a lot of time on
a lot of social networks, not just
Instagram.
And I My bias is to not avoid the work,
but to do the work that is going to be
robust over the long run and then give
people information to decide what they
want to trust or not. But again, in this
same Bloom- Bloomberg interview, you
said
something I think is very profound and
and again, I think people in general
want everyone else to do the work that's
also their work. Uh whether that's your
kids not doing well in school, it's the
teacher's fault, but you've not done one
bit of homework with your kid. You know,
you're always everyone's always off. The
homework fights are hard. Yes, but you
you said what you do with your own boys.
There is some personal responsibility,
which is
we're maybe not asking the right
question. The question we're asking is
is this AI or not? And a better framing
of it for your own children, what you
tell your children, is is to ask them
who created it, Yeah.
&gt;&gt; what their incentives are, Yeah. and
what they're after. You You have to
identify that cuz that's really how
you're going to figure all this out.
&gt;&gt; I think that's what digital literacy is
going to become for our kids is in a
world where anybody can create something
that looks real, sure, you can be like,
does it have a signature or not? Is it
like generated by AI or not?
But it's still going to become much more
important to consider who said it and
why they might have said it.
And that is something that historically
isn't how we think, not just online but
offline, right? We just kind of evaluate
what we see
based on
exactly that, what we see. Exactly. We
will believe our eyes.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Yes, and then and of course we get
into the vast spectrum of skepticism
that people inherently have. What's
funny is we want to not have to do on
this platform what we do in real life,
which is you're telling me
you need $20 because you need a bus
ticket back to wherever cuz your kids
So, I'm evaluating, am I getting scammed
right now? Is this person genuinely
trying to get home or are they trying to
go get Mad Dog 20/20? I have to try to
figure that out and I have to
do my best to assess their intention.
And we're doing it all the time in all
of our interpersonal relationships.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. If a guy's selling you something,
you've got to consider the fact, well,
they're a salesman who gets paid on
units moved.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. And so I must keep in some, you
know, I can must keep that in mind when
I'm evaluating how effective this
product is or not. Yeah. And then we're
going to just have to do that
with the content we see.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. And then our role, I think, is
going to be to give you and make more
prominent, cuz some of this already
exists, but it's too hard to get to,
more information. This account is based
in this country. It was created two days
ago or 20 years ago or in our case 15
years ago. Like, you know, You used
yourself as an example.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, yeah. So, you could be like, okay,
Adam is this account is based in the US.
It has had no username changes ever and
it was, you know, it's been registered
for, call it, 13, 14 years. This is
reputation.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, exactly. And then we could add
other things like
this post was was recorded with a Sony
camera, authenticated by Sony, or this
post was created with AI. That might not
mean it's a bad post, but
&gt;&gt; Right, but then you just know.
&gt;&gt; You just know. When you said, and I
guess this is probably forthcoming, I
would be so supportive of this, is your
biases. So, you are left leaning. Yeah.
You are right leaning.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. You mentioned financial bias which
is incredibly pertinent.
&gt;&gt; But then there's even other things over
time. I mean we're talking about step
two, not three, four, five like
I think it would be interesting to be
like, okay, well this meme or this
narrative like where did it come from?
Right? Like who was the first person who
posted about this? Yes. Um you know,
that's interesting not just from a
safety perspective but from a the value
should go to the original creator
perspective. Creators, right? Like on
one hand it could be like, okay, this is
a this is a lie, who started it? But on
the other hand it could be like, this is
an amazing dance or bit, who came up
with it first? Yeah, yeah.
&gt;&gt; And like we like there all sorts of
really interesting things that we can do
under this umbrella of surfacing
information about what you're seeing so
that you can
either not just decide whether or not to
trust it but decide what it means. I can
tell you the one that scared me. I saw I
mean this was a breakdown, thank god
someone exposed this but this this video
that had gone very, very viral which was
it was a New York City police officer
confronting ICE agents Yeah. saying, you
don't have jurisdiction in this city. I
too am upholding the Constitution. And
it it was like it was compelling, it was
inspiring, it was action you know, you
wanted to take action when you saw it.
And it was
millions and millions and millions of
forwards. Yeah. And someone had the
wherewithal to zoom in on the badge on
the shoulder of the cop and it's not
real writing but I'm telling you I think
I'm quite good at seeing this stuff as
probably all of us think of the literacy
competency illusion.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, we're not good at it.
&gt;&gt; And I was like, oh now this this is
what's really [__] dangerous. This is
like a super inspirational video that
could make you leave your house and go
react to something that didn't happen.
&gt;&gt; And was designed to be. Like
it's not a coincidence that that thing
was sent around. It was designed to be
sent around. It was designed to invoke a
specific emotion. And I just think, man,
when you start having people responding
to atrocities that haven't even
happened, that's the scary part, I
think. Do you know, there's there's tons
of things that are [clears throat]
concerning and there's tons of things
that are exciting. I think this is it's
just
technologies has continued to change
more and more quickly. Yeah. And we're
just accelerating a lot right now. Like
this has been happening as a trend for a
long time, but this last year or two and
this next couple years is a real
inflection point in the speed at which
technology is changing. And there are
lots of things to be excited about.
&gt;&gt; Mhm. And there's lots of things to be
concerned about. Uh and our job as
platforms like Instagram is to consider
both, right? In what [snorts] way can AI
give people superpowers, make you help
you remember everything, process immense
amounts of information, produce more, be
more creative, get people who weren't
creative to be creative in the first
place.
&gt;&gt; Mhm. But also, how can it be abused?
Where do we have to make sure we're
giving people more context that we
didn't think about having to give people
just a year or two ago? You know, where
do we have to be more careful about how
it's going to be misused and then
preventatively or get ahead of that and
prevent those misuses from happening in
the first place?
&gt;&gt; Yeah. When invariably something happens
that we didn't plan on that's bad, how
can we react quickly?
&gt;&gt; Uh-huh. Uh and it's it's just the two
sides.
&gt;&gt; [__] job you've taken on.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, very. It is It is amazing It is a
It is very stressful and it's also
really amazing.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, it's just like the product itself.
Yeah, yeah. No, that is
It's not lost on me. What's like your
personal high from the job? I get to
meet amazing people.
Um which for me is
really energizing for two reasons. One,
I I love people. I'm an extrovert. Um
but two, I'm really curious about
different industries. I like I get to go
and be like
talk to a bunch of different podcasters
about how their world works. How does
the business work? How does the creative
process work? I get to do the same thing
in fashion. I get to do the same thing
with, you know, European footballers.
You're just exposed to everyone. I'm
lucky enough that I get to talk to
people who are amazing in all these
different worlds. Yeah. And all these
different countries. We have the same
upside of same job upside.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, yeah. For sure.
Yeah, yeah. That's one of my favorite
perks of this job.
&gt;&gt; keep walking away and she's like, "It's
impossible the amount of people we've
got to meet Yeah. in this one lifetime."
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; And you get to really talk to them. Yes.
In a world where not long after me, we
have
been part of moving the world to shorter
and shorter bits of information that are
consumed,
you all are part of this sort of almost
counter trend, which is like, "No, we're
just going to talk for an hour or two.
Yeah. And we're going to go deep. Yeah,
yeah. And people want that. Part of but
that, you know, I I get nervous because
even with what we do,
so much has changed in the past eight
years since when we started, where they
knew, like they would come and you'd
have to listen for the whole thing or
for most of it. But now, clips are such
a huge part of the
the
doing podcast, and I do worry. I'm like,
"Oh, no, it's just like back to the
thing that we were escaping, which is
like
late night
&gt;&gt; Yeah, literally we were
&gt;&gt; to the 140 characters. Yeah, and the
five-minute fun clip on on late night,
which we love, but the whole point is to
have like a real conversation. And now
it feels like we're almost reverting
back to that. I think what's key, and
you should tell me if I'm off base here,
cuz this is now your world, not mine.
Um is to not conflate
what I see as this, you know, more of
the marketing for the conversation and
then the actual conversation. And there
might be way more views of the short
clips on YouTube and Instagram and
elsewhere. Um but the core of the
business, I think, is still the long
form.
Both from a like who do you have the
deepest connection with as a creative,
but also from a business perspective.
Yeah, the real estate to sell is on the
long form.
&gt;&gt; Exactly.
That's a bummer, I think, sometimes
where I'm like, "Oh my god." I mean, I
ask so many people. I'm like, "Oh, did
you listen to that? Did you listen to
that?" Or they they say something let's
say they say something about Good Hang,
and I'm like, "Oh, did you listen?"
They're like, "I saw clips." I mean, "I
saw clips" is so common. Totally. And
there will be more people who see clips
than listen to the whole thing. But if
you're growing the the group of people
who listen to the whole thing by having
10 times as many people do clips, you're
still growing your core base.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I know. It's just hard to compete.
&gt;&gt; you But if that's shrinking, then it's
concerning. Right.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I don't have that fear. I don't
think we're losing listeners to clips. I
think we're getting exposed to more
people who don't do two-hour
shows, personally.
&gt;&gt; I also like about your world is you get
to participate
with just audio. Obviously, video's
become a big deal. This is why this
place is so beautiful.
But
like I listen to you guys when I'm on
the way to work, when I'm in the car,
when I'm like, you know, when I'm
working out. I can't do that with
Instagram. I can't do that with clips
and videos. And so you get to
participate in parts of people's lives
that
things and uh
products and the apps like Instagram
don't. I I agree. That's what I love
about it, but I I worry that it is it is
changing and moving more into because
our attentions are much shorter. Yeah,
yeah.
&gt;&gt; That it's like, "Oh, I got the gist."
&gt;&gt; Yeah, yeah, yeah. No, it's it's a it's a
real worry. I think people
underappreciate audio in general. Like
my whole industry does. Like I've been
trying to push it a little bit, which is
most time spent on Instagram is watching
videos now. That is half audio, right?
But we're not thinking about that
experience in any as much. What does
Instagram sound like is an interesting
question. Because the visual component
has just gotten better and better and
better and the audio experience is
really not.
&gt;&gt; And we tend to I think think more about
what we see than what we hear, but what
we hear I think can have just as strong
an emotional impact.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Another thing that I
was
sympathetic to is First of all, I think
it would might shock people to learn and
you do this great example when you have
a crowd of people it's very easy to
demonstrate the reality of this cuz when
you first say it you almost don't
believe it, but tell us where people
spend time on Instagram.
&gt;&gt; Oh, yeah. Yeah. Cuz you have basically
four options, right? You have the feed.
Yep. Uh you have reels.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. You have DMs.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Uh maybe is there three?
&gt;&gt; Stories.
&gt;&gt; And stories.
&gt;&gt; Stories a big one. Right. So you've got
these four columns. Yeah. And and also
just start maybe at the beginning what
it was and where we're at now. People my
age, I'm in my 40s, um
they think of Instagram almost always as
a feed of square photos cuz that's what
Instagram was when Instagram launched.
But if you look at how people spend
their time and even more if you look at
what people do, it's just not the core
part of Instagram anymore. People share
way more to stories than they do to
feed. People, particularly young people,
spend way more time in stories than they
do in feed. Um but the thing that people
do the most, particularly young people,
is actually message, is DM. Mhm.
&gt;&gt; Um teens will often and young people
will spend more time even in DMs than in
some of these other surfaces and they
definitely share way more. And forget
about all the text. If you just look at
photos and videos sent, Yeah. That's
interesting.
&gt;&gt; way more photos and videos sent in as
DMs than there are posted to stories or
or feed or even those two combined at
this point. Yeah. You ask everyone to
like put your hand up if you've sent a
DM on Instagram in the last day. And 90%
of the room puts their hand up. Great.
Now tell keep your hand up if you have
If you posted a story. I actually did
this just this one time at Bloomberg. I
made it up.
I was like you do you did you open up
Instagram today? You know, did you send
a DM today? Did you post a story today?
And it's like a bunch of hands went
down. Did you post a feed post today?
And it was like Every hand.
It was like two people. Did you post
today? I did.
Well, we didn't cuz we have a schedule.
[laughter]
Yeah, that's right.
But when you did it that way it really
sank in. Like oh oh yes, true. And then
and then what I appreciated was you
being honest about the fact that
we have that data, right? So had we only
stuck with feed and we said no, we're
feed only.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
I wouldn't be on this stage today. We
wouldn't be relevant because we see what
people want to do
and they would have gone to a place
where they could have done that. And
that's just the hard facts of the
business. Yeah. And so what I thought
about is we've had very few changes.
We went from audio to video and people
lost their [__] mind. Yeah. And then
the other crazy thing was we had you
could do it a week early if you join the
subscription. People lost their mind.
&gt;&gt; Also when we first went to Spotify,
people really freaked out. Yeah, but all
to say we've only had three or four
changes in eight years and it was very
difficult and people were very very
angry. Yeah. And so I was thinking like
how you're weathering the outrage and
and also the frustration despite what
everyone's saying, once they get over
the hurdle they like it. I think this
challenge of change management
was the first like
my first exposure to this sort of
controversy in the industry where you
know, I was the designer on a new design
of the home page of Facebook in late
2008, early 2009.
And like people lost their minds. Yeah,
[laughter] yeah, yeah. And I got I won't
I won't say on the right but I was
reading the comments, it [snorts] was
not a lot of threats. And I'm like 25.
I'm like And again, my self-worth is
totally tied up in my work. Like I have
&gt;&gt; Right. You're nothing if you're not
that.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, and I'm just just kidding. Punk.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. You ruined it. Yeah, I was just
like just devastated.
&gt;&gt; [snorts]
&gt;&gt; And you know, you you learn to accept
the fact that look, if you're going to
spend half an hour an hour using our
product a day, it's like I think of it
the analogy I used to use is like it's a
desk.
You wrote some letters, you organized
some photos, you did some things, and I
just came in and I just rearranged your
desk.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. You're going to tell me to F off
because
I didn't ask for permission and you
think of it as your desk.
&gt;&gt; Yes. But the the alternative is to
become irrelevant and I don't think
that's being bombastic.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Uh I'll give Mark a lot of credit
on this. Mark's always said that
companies usually fail by hitting their
goals all the way down.
&gt;&gt; [snorts]
&gt;&gt; Um and what that's about not really
defining success properly
and also not being willing to make hard
decisions. In that case, it's about
aiming high. But in this case, it's
about being willing to actually do
things differently. Yeah.
&gt;&gt; And I would rather lead Instagram during
however long I lead it for through a
bunch of changes and occasionally go too
fast, too far and get backlash than have
it become irrelevant under my watch.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that's fair.
Stay tuned for more Armchair Expert
if you dare.
This is relevant because my phone
updated last night.
&gt;&gt; Uh-oh.
&gt;&gt; Do Do have the new update?
&gt;&gt; I've been Japanese.
I hate it so I almost I was like I'm in
a bad mood today. Like I can't figure
out how to use this. I don't like the
way it looks. I'm so mad. We've pushed
you far. We've made mistakes. We've
experienced our fair share of of of of
of slaps for it. We're trying something
now that different that I don't know if
it's going to work or not, but we are
trying a version of Instagram that is
basically you open it up and it's just
stories and then you swipe straight into
Reels.
Um and if and when we launch it, there's
going to be all of the all of the energy
So there will be no grid post at all?
&gt;&gt; no. There'll just be you you can swipe
through them, too. You'd have to select
to be on the feed? The feed would just
feel more be more video. It'll still
support photos, but it'll be full screen
one at a time.
&gt;&gt; Oh, interesting. So you can't post a
photo
And how and the Reels tab and Shorts on
YouTube and all of it. Okay. Yeah, that
scares me. Yeah, I know. I don't want
you to do that.
Yeah, [laughter] so I don't know if it's
going to work, but
but we're doing it
when we try new things, we have to be
ready to answer questions cuz people see
it. Right.
&gt;&gt; So right now we are allowing people, not
everybody, but we're allowing people in
India to opt in
and
the idea is to
manage this if it's successful over a
year or even two
and keep making the experience better
and better and then see how many people
opt in and of the people who do switch,
how many of people keep it. Right.
&gt;&gt; And then when we get to a place where
let's say the majority of people switch
and the majority of them actually also
keep it, then we can consider moving
everybody else over, but that we need to
that creates a really healthy incentive
for us to make it something people want
to switch to, but it also takes a long
time. It's a trial. So we're trying it
out.
&gt;&gt; Is there a way to mass DM? Is there a
way to get people to like sign up for
or something where we DM them?
&gt;&gt; Channels.
You can create a channel, which is
basically a broadcast DM where people
can sign up and then you can just It's
basically like a group chat, but instead
of having every, you know, armchair in a
group chat, um you can just message all
of them and then they can reply to your
messages. So, it's kind of You can kind
of consume it.
&gt;&gt; But, it's not creating a message board.
No, it's just in DMs. I I think we
should do that and start sending out the
episodes. Yeah, it's not for Do you know
the understand about that? Is the number
of people who will sign up for that is
much smaller than the people who are
going to follow your account. Right.
&gt;&gt; for your most passionate people. And so,
the content strategy should match that.
Okay, so great. That brings up my It was
my grievance the first time we spoke
with you and it's continues to be my
grievance that I need to understand the
rationale behind it. Please.
&gt;&gt; Why can I put a link in stories and I
can't put a link anywhere else?
&gt;&gt; Yeah, we hate that.
&gt;&gt; can't I put a link in my feed? Yeah,
it's contentious. I get this one every
week. Um the [laughter]
Might Might be time to buckle. Yeah,
well, you know, I have buckled before.
If we do links for everybody everywhere,
I think what will happen is there'll be
a lot of links posted very quickly and
it'll change
how Instagram feels significantly and I
don't think it'll be for the better.
Well, when you get a lot more scam and
spam, cuz that's links are the vector
for all of that. You get a lot more
politics and you get a lot more news,
cuz they usually are link and text
oriented as opposed to photo and video
oriented.
Um and I think we become less
differentiated from other platforms like
Facebook.
And I want us to be about creativity.
And I think specifically Instagram is
about visual creativity. And I think
when we do links,
I think we become more about news and
publishers and politics and less about
um fashion and art and, you know, film.
And so, that's the That's the reason.
Yeah.
I don't expect that to be remotely
satisfying.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; Um
&gt;&gt; But, that is the reason.
&gt;&gt; Okay. Another quick thing I wanted to
ask you about is I watch a lot of your
two-camera posts, and they are generally
bits of advice for creators.
&gt;&gt; Oh, my my videos.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, yeah, yours. Your comfort level of
speaking directly to the lens is
outstanding. I I mean, the fact that
you're not in show business is
incredible because I suffer from that.
You get right on that [__] and
talk directly to the lens all the time.
And you're giving tips to creators. And
I was curious,
do you have a distinction in your mind
between the occasional poster who puts
the food or their vacation photos up
Yeah. versus someone who's making
content?
&gt;&gt; Yes. Those are two different
What would we call the two groups?
There's creators and then what? Just
average folks.
&gt;&gt; Users. And what percentage is on the
platform? Do you have any sense of that?
I mean, depends on how you define it,
but there definitely at the very least
tens of millions of creators.
&gt;&gt; Uh-huh. And there's over 3 billion
people who use Instagram. So, it's a
tiny minority. Yeah, but I mean, uh
&gt;&gt; hunch is because you're servicing them
so much, are they the lifeblood of the
platform?
&gt;&gt; They are very viable They're like very
viable for the platform. I think that
creators
took Well, a couple things. One, we
would define creators as individuals or
groups of people. Uh so, not like a
company or corporation or brand Mhm.
that produce original content
um with the intent to grow. So, like,
you know, you're trying to get something
done. Maybe you're trying to evangelize
a cause, maybe you're trying to get
elected, maybe you're trying to sell
some shoes, but there's a there's an
intent there to grow.
&gt;&gt; Right. So, if you're just posting
pictures of your vacations or the
occasional hobby, that's cool, but it's
not that we don't think of you as a
creator. You can be creative, that's
great. But, I believe and we believe, I
should say, that
power has been shifting from
institutions to individuals across
industries for years and we should be
leaning into that. Uh you know
athletes are much more relevant
relative to the teams that they play for
compared to like 10, 20, 30 years ago.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, or the fact that these college
kids are now incredibly well paid all
through that. Yeah. Yeah. Journalists
are becoming building their own brands
outside of the publications that they
work for. Yeah. You'll see actors have
their Instagrams explode when their new
Netflix show gets announced even before
it drops and I think this is because we
want to understand the world through the
eyes of people, people we admire or
trust or look up to
and that's what creators are. Yeah. And
so we think that we we should lean in
there cuz that's what people are most
interested in. Yeah. And they're that's
who's going to become more and more
important over time. This is so obvious
but I I didn't think of it until you
said it out loud which is you you said I
think it's useful occasionally to pull
all the way back and look at the very
big picture which is
what the internet the first iteration
gave rise to is prior to the internet
people could not self publish. Yeah. The
expense was too high or there were
institutions that controlled that. Yeah.
And so the first wave of the internet
was really allowing every human to be a
publisher. Yeah. And that's like a big
big concept and it's been great and
[__] us up cuz not everyone should be
publishing and we're hearing from a lot
of people that we wouldn't have
otherwise and they're very helpful. So
that's that's the We've given a lot of
power to everybody. Yeah. Very
democratized. Everyone's the
democratization of everything. Well,
this is what it looks like. Yeah. And
now the second wave is really producers,
production. So before studios and the
only could afford the Arriflex camera
that was 250,000 and the film you put in
it that was 35,000, the processing and
all the stuff that went into creating
content. Yeah. It was impossible for
someone to do it.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. That's been changing, but AI is
really now the insane breakthrough where
it's like your environment could be any
location. So, what we're now doing is
democratizing production. Yeah. Which is
a fascinating thought. Yeah.
My hope is that
the way we participate in this wave will
empower
human creativity. Right? Like, I think
that
there's versions of AI that will
disintermediate people and displace
people in jobs, but there's also
versions of AI that I think can
give people give creative people the
ability to do more of what they do so
well and to be more successful. And so,
my hope is that on Instagram, the ways
that we lean into AI with creative tools
and assistance and the ability to
understand your insights or to
understand the patterns for what works
and what doesn't or to recreate or
create whatever is in your imagination
will be really empowering. Um
but, you know, it's going to be this
it's the same construct. It's
the internet allowed anybody to publish
and reach an audience um because the
cost of distributing things went almost
to zero. Yeah. And AI is going to make
the cost of producing things go way way
way down as well. Yeah.
&gt;&gt; And so, you will just see more things.
More content.
&gt;&gt; Our job is to figure out the right way
and the responsible way to manage the
platform one of the platforms. Yes. Um
and I'm hoping that we can really
empower human creativity in how we lean
into that. But that's that's the big
question for us over the next couple
years.
&gt;&gt; Okay. Now, how have you
evolved in terms of monetizing the work
of those creators? And how does it How
is Instagram generating money for these
creators and how does it compare to say
a creator on YouTube? So, what creators
do and they're not the only who do this,
is they make content, people consume
that content, and then we sell ads,
obviously, between pieces of content.
Again, you know, you could think of it
as
selling ads against that sort of
attention.
&gt;&gt; It's really the old network television
model. You get this free show, Seinfeld,
and you're going to watch a Clorox
commercial.
&gt;&gt; Exactly. Now, YouTube has a historically
been more focused on long-form video,
and they show ads before and during the
video, and then they give creators uh a
cut. Mhm. Our videos are shorter, so we
don't put ads before. You don't get a
pre-roll on Instagram, which is like,
you know, [clears throat] you have to
watch this. Yeah. And you don't get ads
in the middle of the videos.
Um so, there's one challenge, which is,
you know, who deserves the credit.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. YouTube
is the best in the industry at creator
payouts, I think. And I mean,
specifically paying creators directly,
cuz creators can the the platform can
pay them, the fans can pay them, or
brands can pay them. In terms of the
platform paying them, YouTube does the
best. Yeah. Now, what we've done is
we've got tests in here, we've and think
it's currently in
the US, India, Japan, and Korea at
different times, we've tried to pay
creators
to for creating content.
&gt;&gt; Mhm. And what we keep finding,
particularly with videos, if we pay
creators, we're like, "Hey, if you make
this number of posts, we'll pay you this
number of dollars."
They do create more posts, but the posts
the incremental posts that they make are
not as good. Mhm. And they don't get
that many more so they actually don't
drive up the amount of time people use
Instagram that much. I was going to say
there's really no metric you can decide
on that it's not going to obscure the
output because it could either be number
of posts or it could be total views.
Well, now total views I'm incentivized
to be provocative. I'm incentivized to
be what the algorithm was on YouTube.
&gt;&gt; And but even if you ignored those
challenges, all the tests we have are
just burning money. If we if we invest
$10 million in a in a in a uh, bonus
program, we've never made anywhere near
$10 million back. I'd be happy just to
break even.
&gt;&gt; Sure, sure, sure.
&gt;&gt; Like, for me these things if we could
have this program break even,
um, have the eligibility be clear. So,
it's obvious how you get to be part of
it cuz it can't feel like a lotto. Yeah.
And ideally the payouts aren't
embarrassing. Yeah, yeah. And like, then
it's a success. Yeah.
It people create so much content on
their own that the incremental and the
incremental content that people create
when we pay them is not that high in
quality or quantity on average. I'm sure
some people are doing amazing things.
That we end up burning most of the
money. And I just
&gt;&gt; [clears throat]
&gt;&gt; We're a business. I want to be honest
about that. We're not just going to burn
the money.
&gt;&gt; So, we'll continue iterating cuz that
could change.
Or trying, I should say.
Um, but we focus more now on the other
ways we can help creators make a living.
How can we help with, um, fans paying
you directly? I was going to say you
have a Patreon-ish version that exists,
right?
&gt;&gt; We have subscriptions, which is
actually a quietly growing and doing
well. Where if you have
a platform where people are willing to
pay for your content, you can do that on
Instagram. You can set the price. You
know, we're not trying I think we just
cover the cost of running it. We don't
actually make money off that.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
And then the big one though is getting
paid by brands.
Um,
you know, last I checked was years ago.
It seemed like it was more than a $15
billion industry a year, which is
creators get making deals off platform.
Yeah. And getting paid by companies to
advertise their products.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. To do a post about a pair of
sneakers.
&gt;&gt; So, we've tried to support that. So, we
have the creator marketplace where you
can have brands and creators find each
other and suss each other out.
We have ads tools where the
ads can then use that creative and run
ads with that same creative with the
creator's permission. It's like a system
that integrates that perfectly into
that.
&gt;&gt; the advertiser can find out the value
that they're getting from actually
paying for this content.
&gt;&gt; Yes. Uh, we want creators to get paid,
but we can't just
burn money writing checks. So, we're
trying to find a balance. Yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
So interesting. [snorts and sighs]
We're going to do a hard pivot, I can
feel it. You make a prediction
dangerously, perhaps, but your 2026
prediction was looking forward to 2026,
one significant interesting is that
authenticity is becoming infinitely
reproducible. Yeah, this is a real
tension. Tell me about this statement. I
think I understand it, but I'm not sure.
It's abstract enough that you could deny
any implications of the statement.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; You've got in legal terms, this is like
real messy language.
I wrote that thing and I was like, I was
like, I should write more.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; And I wrote this thing and it was like
really boring. And then I was like, all
right, I should make it less boring and
then I rewrote it and I was like, now
this is purposely controversial. That's
annoying. [laughter]
That's just as boring, just different.
So, then I was like, all right, I should
just cut half of the stuff that I don't
have any business weighing in on anyway,
and I'll focus on the things that I care
most about. So, I don't know how it
turned out, but you read it, so that's
cool. I knew you had to do your homework
for this thing.
People think of Instagram's aesthetic,
particularly people my age, as these
perfect photos, sunsets, you know, skin
smoothing, makeup, all this whole thing.
Um, that is not
what is in the cultural zeitgeist today.
Um, what works even on Instagram is
content that is not is kind of very
purposely counter to that polished
aesthetic.
&gt;&gt; Messy. Messy, raw, pimples, blurry, you
know, like not cropped properly. Real.
Cuz people just want a little of
authenticity in this world where we're
inundated with processed, intense
information.
So, I think that there's this
interesting thing now where that perfect
aesthetic is becoming cheap because it's
easy to produce, and so the most savvy
creatives across a lot of industries are
kind of rebelling against that. Not
atypical of what happens in different
art worlds.
&gt;&gt; any person in a business, you're looking
for a hole in the market and you're
trying to fill it. So, if everything is
perfect and polished, what's Yeah.
available to exploit is this.
&gt;&gt; So, we're in this moment now, and I
don't know how long it'll last, where
imperfections
are a indication of authenticity. Mhm.
And [clears throat] that's one of the
reasons why they're working. They're
also relatable. Mhm. And so, it's a way
of being like, I'm not AI, or I'm not a
brand who's trying to sell you
something. I'm just a I'm just a person.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, a little [__] up mess.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, you know, I curse, I stutter over
my words, I make mistakes, just like
everybody else. So, that's kind of where
we are, and you're already starting to
see it.
&gt;&gt; AI's going to figure that out, right?
&gt;&gt; It's already recreating it. Like, if you
talk to chat GPT, like, you hear you
hear it take a breath. Ugh. It doesn't
need to breathe. Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Um, like, that's not a thing. Um, and
so, I think that you're going to be able
to create the illusion of the illusion
of that raw imperfections.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that's how it works.
&gt;&gt; you started, like, it's still starting
now, and that's going to that's going to
happen.
&gt;&gt; Adam, I called the front desk of the
hotel I was staying at in Detroit. Yeah.
Busy, busy, busy, busy. Then I went
online, I got the actual hard number to
the place and called on my phone. Yeah,
landlines now. It was like, "Hello,
thank you for calling such and such
hotel in blah blah blah." And it had a
bunch of imperfections in the thing.
Yeah. And I was talking for a while, and
I go, "I don't know what clued me in,
but I go, 'Hold on, are you a
computer?'"
No.
&gt;&gt; like, "I can see why you would ask
that." And I was like, "Oh, yeah. [__]
dude, this is nuts."
&gt;&gt; Yeah, yeah, yeah.
YEAH.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; IT'S A THING.
IT'S A THING.
&gt;&gt; YEAH, YEAH.
YEAH, YEAH. I talked FOR A WHILE BEFORE
I FIGURED OUT IT WAS A COMPUTER.
&gt;&gt; I KNOW.
BUT IN THAT IN THAT WORLD, you know,
what's left? You know, I think it's our
taste, it's our perspective, it's our,
you know, it's our opinions, um, that
are going to be the thing that makes
some piece of content be interesting or
not. But the other question for me is
how can you
point the technology
at what you want to get done, right?
There's a one way to think about it is
like it is an it, it is an algorithm, it
is AI and it is coming for you. There's
another way which is like, all right,
it's a bunch of tools, it's it doesn't
care about me, it's agnostic. Yeah. But
like what are the things that I want to
do that it can help me do more of,
better, faster, stronger, etc.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I mean, how do I figure out how to
do that? Cuz I mean, cuz it seems on one
hand, it's interesting to touch on. On
one hand, it's so technical, right? Like
you're talking about these giant, you
know, foundation models and these data
centers with all of these GPUs and
you're like all this like it's like
everyone's Anybody listening to this is
already like, I don't care what you
said. So, on one side, it's so
technical. On the other side, it makes
things so much more approachable. Like I
I used to like I said before, I'm not
good at anything. I used to program. I
used to write a lot of code. Uh,
really bad code. There's these some
engineers now who will go look up my
diffs. Just [laughter] to make you want
to throw up. Just to make fun It's just
like rage. Just just dunk on me on
internal forums.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; I can code again now because I can work
with an AI to program. I can speak to it
in English.
&gt;&gt; Wow, yeah.
&gt;&gt; And because I understand cuz I'm
technical enough, I can give it pretty
good direction. Yeah. But it's getting
easier and easier. And so, you know,
uh, a couple months ago, I started
programming and I was like, all right,
this will be fun. I haven't done this in
forever. Both, you know, my own stuff,
but also at work. And the way you did it
is you basically had an AI, you talked
to it and you watched it program.
That's not how people do it. Well,
that's how some people do it, but it's
not how I do it now, it's not how a lot
of people do it now. Now, I've got like
four
of them,
you know, that's like four engineers
basically and I talk to each one of
them. See who does it better. And I
know, I just check back. I do four
things in parallel or do two things and
see who does it better. Yeah.
&gt;&gt; But it's also it's a completely
different way of exercising your brain.
I'm multitasking aggressively. I've got
like four really junior employees that I
talk to every 10 minutes. Without any
civil uh civil deeds. I actually do. I
say please.
&gt;&gt; I know.
It's so weird.
&gt;&gt; And I heard that it's wasting like X
amount of money and
&gt;&gt; It does. I'm sure it's like burning
water and But like I do this cuz I have
always said please and thank you to
Alexa cuz my kids I want them to I want
them to only hear me barking orders and
their
personality. Yeah, yeah, yeah. So it's
it's definitely gotten into my my
program.
Why am I being so like like I'm sorry
that I gave you the wrong instructions
the last time. It's like
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; Oh I I know. It's so weird. Be
accountable to the computer. It's so so
ridiculous. But but I don't think it's
limited to programming. I think it's
going to make technical things, not just
programming,
more approachable to a bunch of people
cuz it can bridge. And that's an
interesting tension that I'm not sure I
know how to make sense of yet. Okay, my
last thing is Threads. So we were on
this trip and I was like, "What is
Threads?" You're trying to tell me about
Threads. I'm like, "That's so what's
Twitter?" I don't know you just what was
what are you doing? And then I don't
know. I think I want to say at that time
I was trying to remember cuz I said it
so often. I think you had 300 million
subscribers at that time. Is that
possible?
&gt;&gt; we had three about 300 million users,
yeah. Yeah, and I kept every morning I'd
ask where we were at and stuff like the
user account.
&gt;&gt; the the goal was to create
uh you know, a place for like the
healthy exchange of perspectives, of
ideas. Um it started really in reaction
to Twitter. We wanted to be a
It's not even it's not like a we don't
want to be like a Kumbaya super friendly
Twitter. People are going to argue. I
don't want to pretend otherwise. But we
just wanted to be more open for more
types of perspectives, more ideas, a bit
more civil.
Over the time it's evolved though and um
and now it's much more focused on trying
to support communities, trying to
support just the open exchange of ideas
and it's it's growing. We're doing
pretty well here in the US. We're
crushing right now in Japan, which is
interesting. You're doing a great job of
integrating it into Instagram because I
see headlines I can't resist but click
on and open threads.
&gt;&gt; That's our equivalent of clips.
Right. [clears throat]
&gt;&gt; little bits of threads in Instagram to
raise awareness. And I go. Yeah, and so
we look at two things. We look at how
many people use threads because of or
see threads because of its Instagram
integration and then we look at how many
people just go on their own. Right.
&gt;&gt; on their own is the core business. Yeah.
&gt;&gt; And there are more people who go cuz of
the Yeah, you still haven't gotten me to
go directly to threads.
&gt;&gt; And we might not ever. Yeah. Who We
haven't even gotten my wife to install
it, so.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; Well, where on threads if our listeners
want to Join the conversation.
&gt;&gt; It's follow. It's follow.
&gt;&gt; us.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; What is your evaluation of the X Twitter
platform? I don't want to underestimate
them. I mean, they've gone through a lot
of change. Have they grown, shrunk,
plateaued? What have they done?
&gt;&gt; It's hard to say.
&gt;&gt; Okay. Somewhere between plateaued and
shrunk a little. Um, but maybe they're
growing in some countries and shrinking
others. That's pretty normal for social
networks. Yeah. They've got
[clears throat] they obviously laid off
I think over 90% of their employees, so
they're that's kind [snorts] of scary.
It's also impressive. It's very
efficient. Um,
they've got some good people over there.
Um, I just want us to beat them. Yeah,
yeah,
yeah, yeah. That's honest and fair.
Yeah.
As I'm watching the Iran stuff and I'm
learning they've shut off all the social
media and they've shut off even WhatsApp
there. Yeah, we we got we got blocked
partially there years ago. We were
actually really big in Iran. Um, but
they do get the government there will
block certain social media networks,
certain websites and then you they'll
shut the whole internet down at times.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. That's what I wanted to ask just a
stupid question like how did they
mechanically decide what's on the
internet? To me, the internet seems like
this huge pipeline that you pull
different IP addresses out of. Like, how
does it How do they do it? How do they
shut off just some parts of the
internet?
&gt;&gt; They work with the internet service
providers
to block specific domains. So, like
you know, we you don't use Instagram by
going to instagram.com most likely. But,
behind the scenes there is an address.
It might be a number, it might be words
somewhere.
&gt;&gt; My app goes to that.
&gt;&gt; Your app goes to that to talk to the
servers. And so, they'll have the people
who provide internet
um block specific addresses. And then,
you can play this game of cat and mouse
where you can switch your addresses or
you can go through a VPN. And what about
Starlink? How does that factor in?
Obviously, there's no control over
Starlink. If you somehow have Starlink,
you do have access to everything, yeah?
Yeah, that would be yeah, straight from
space.
Okay. Crazy. It's the future. It's more
than half the satellites in orbit.
&gt;&gt; It's crazy.
&gt;&gt; The last two things I pride myself in
being able to look at someone and say
the exact car that they should own.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, you were right. And I spent this
time, Monica, with Adam and I said, "I'm
just going to say it, man. You need a
70s BMW 3.0 CSi." Yeah, yeah.
And by God, what I mean, I just need to
know what what availed you to that
advice? Cuz you went on a search.
&gt;&gt; on a hunt. I went on a hunt. I spent a
lot of time on bringatrailer.com.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; I don't know. I've never been like a
like a I've never been a car guy. Like,
I drive around a Toyota Sienna. I was
like, you can't be like a tech exec in a
Porsche. It's like too much of a
stereotype. It's just too much of a
cliché. I'm saying that out loud as I'm
thinking of friends of mine who
drive [laughter] Porsches, so I
apologize for saying this on the record.
&gt;&gt; used cliché. That was nice. I used
douchey.
So, I was like trying to find something
that would give me some pleasure that
wasn't like crazy. But, there also was
like a little bit if you know, you know,
like I drive that thing around and like
most people don't even look
but every once in a while someone is
like oh man, check out that [laughter]
89 and like they come over and they want
to talk. Wow, what color is it? It's
fjord blue, it's like this blue, it's a
little bit of a cult. Fjord blue? It's a
little bit of a cult pink color from the
early 70s.
&gt;&gt; Okay. I had said too blue would be my
pick for you. That's my favorite.
&gt;&gt; all the way through. It's blue on the
inside and blue on the outside and it's
it's it's tiny. It's like a gentleman's
coupe. Yeah. It's very art deco-y. It's
like very there's a mix of steel and
&gt;&gt; I love that car. So I should thank you
brought that I never would have bought
one. I would have been just driving the
Sienna around.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; Do your boys like it? Yeah, particularly
Blaze. He calls it the blueberry. He
calls it the blueberry. Okay, and then
the last thing I find so charming about
you is you are a hardcore Burning Man
person. What do you call yourselves?
Burners or something? I in a past life.
&gt;&gt; What do you mean in a past I I I have
kids now. I haven't gone in years.
&gt;&gt; How when's the last time you went?
&gt;&gt; I don't know, but I went I've been I've
been more times than I can count. So
you're not wrong. And he's Adam's the
type that goes Monica a week before and
[__] builds the enormous
contraptions. The build is for me the
most fun part cuz you like you go and
you're like building your camp. You're
really making a city in the middle of
the desert. Um by the end of the week
it's like chaos and it's a bit of a just
to get a little bit too messy for me.
I'm getting old. Uh
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; but like you know, to get out there and
to be using your hands and to like you
know, we built we built these yurts
which is what we sleep in or these giant
trapeze tents which is what we hang in
or the kitchen like Wow.
&gt;&gt; There's AC you you put
&gt;&gt; a shower, we built everything and then
you whip it all down. It's a lot of
work.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. But in this world where I'm on
glowing rectangles all day it's kind of
nice to be outside with no internet in
the desert with your hands all dirty
making and fabricating. Yeah.
Uh well Adam, I adore you. Uh, you'll be
back.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. That was round two. We'll do round
three. Uh, we'll be laughing at our
naivete in this conversation.
&gt;&gt; be irrelevant.
&gt;&gt; It will all In fact, the the
conversation will happen with our
avatars.
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
&gt;&gt; I believe in I believe in human
creativity.
All right. Well, thanks for coming. This
was a blast. Thanks for having me. It
was
&gt;&gt; so much fun.
&gt;&gt; [music]